<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4901">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03260140</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IIR 15-364</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>I01HX002113</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03260140</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>DVD Lifestyle Intervention</brief_title>
  <acronym>D-ELITE</acronym>
  <official_title>DVD Lifestyle Intervention (D-ELITE)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Most Veterans who receive VA healthcare have obesity (41%) or are classified as overweight&#xD;
      (37%), putting them at higher risk for multiple serious chronic health conditions. Providing&#xD;
      evidence-based behavioral weight management programs to Veterans with obesity is a priority&#xD;
      for the VA National Center for Health Promotion and Disease Prevention (NCP). While the VA&#xD;
      NCP's MOVE! program-primarily delivered with in-person group visits-helps Veterans with&#xD;
      obesity lose weight, its reach has been limited because of various barriers to care. Some&#xD;
      Veterans may do better with a program they can complete from home at their own pace. In this&#xD;
      trial, study investigators are examining the effectiveness among Veterans of a previously&#xD;
      proven self-directed lifestyle intervention (called DVD Lifestyle Intervention (D-ELITE))&#xD;
      that targets modest, clinically meaningful weight loss over the course of a year using&#xD;
      recorded video lessons (DVD or online streaming), written self-study aids, and optional&#xD;
      lifestyle coaching. The study will compare participants randomly assigned to receive D-ELITE&#xD;
      to those continuing in usual care on weight and self-reported general physical health status,&#xD;
      one year after enrollment. Secondary outcomes include weight and general physical health&#xD;
      status two years after enrollment; and obesity-related biometric measures (blood pressure and&#xD;
      HbA1c) and self-report psychological and behavioral factors such as physical activity and&#xD;
      sleep quality, at one- and two-years following enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Veterans with obesity living in the western US were identified using the VA Corporate Data&#xD;
      Warehouse (CDW), recruited to participate via mail and telephone, and randomly assigned to&#xD;
      receive the study intervention or usual care alone. The study uses CDW to assess weight&#xD;
      change and biometric outcomes. To assess self-report outcomes, participants completed&#xD;
      questionnaires, by mail or telephone, at baseline and 12 months after randomization, and are&#xD;
      currently completing 24-month follow-up questionnaires. The D-ELITE intervention focuses on&#xD;
      gradual lifestyle behavior change aimed at improving eating habits and increasing physical&#xD;
      activity. It encourages participants to gradually achieve and maintain a 5-10% loss of&#xD;
      baseline body weight and at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity physical activity, such&#xD;
      as brisk walking, each week. The D-ELITE intervention program consists of watching one video,&#xD;
      completing corresponding written self-guided learning materials, and tracking food intake and&#xD;
      physical activity each week for the first 12 weeks, then working through 10 additional&#xD;
      written handouts and continued food and activity tracking for the next nine months.&#xD;
      Intervention participants have access to a lifestyle coach, as desired, for the full 12-month&#xD;
      intervention period. In addition to patient outcomes, this study will examine the cost of&#xD;
      delivering the intervention, information relevant to decision-makers and potential future&#xD;
      dissemination. Evidence-based programs like this, which can be delivered remotely and with&#xD;
      likely minimal resources required from the VA healthcare system, are greatly needed,&#xD;
      especially now as the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic has required VA to rapidly transition to providing&#xD;
      more remotely-delivered care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Impact: The DELITE trial has potential to provide the evidence needed for deciding whether a&#xD;
      low-cost, low-technology, self-directed program can be used to expand the treatment of&#xD;
      obesity to a population-based level by improving access to obesity treatment regardless of&#xD;
      Veteran place of residence.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 15, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The investigators will randomly assign participants to one of two groups.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>body weight drawn from VA medical record</measure>
    <time_frame>all weights from 9 to 15 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare weights between intervention and control</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SF-12 PCS</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare general health status between intervention and control using the SF-12 PCS.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>International Physical Activity Questionnaire (IPAQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare physical activity between intervention and control using the International Physical Activity Questionnaire (IPAQ).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>&quot;Starting the Conversation&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare dietary quality between intervention and control using the &quot;Starting the Conversation&quot; questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS - Sleep Disturbance Survey change</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare sleep-related disturbance between intervention and control using the PROMIS - Sleep Disturbance Survey.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS - Sleep Related Impairment Survey change</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare sleep-related impairment between intervention and control using the PROMIS - Sleep Related Impairment Survey.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>modified &quot;PACE+ dietary self-efficacy&quot; change</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare dietary self-efficacy between intervention and control using questions modified from the PACE Adult Psychosocial Questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>biometrics drawn from VA medical record</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline through 27 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare blood pressure and Hb1Ac levels between intervention and control.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SF-12</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare general health status (PCS and MCS) between intervention and control using the SF-12.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>body weight drawn from VA medical record</measure>
    <time_frame>15-27 months post baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will compare body weight between intervention and control.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">500</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>behavioral lifestyle intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The investigators will provide participants with the the behavioral lifestyle intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>usual care control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>participant in this arm will continue with usual care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>behavioral lifestyle intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>The investigators will provide participants with the behavioral lifestyle intervention</description>
    <arm_group_label>behavioral lifestyle intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent VA primary care measured BMI between 30.0-44.9 kg/m2 (at facility in pacific or&#xD;
             mountain time zone)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to DVD player or internet&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to participate fully in all study protocol/procedures including informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to speak, read, or understand English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent weight loss interventions including use of prescription weight-loss&#xD;
             medications, participation in group or individual weight loss programs provided by&#xD;
             trained personnel, bariatric surgery (or plans for during the study period)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expected weight loss because of alternate explanations such as from illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High variability in weight due to fluctuations in volume status (ascites - liver&#xD;
             disease, chronic heart failure)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Safety and/or adherence concerns due to severe physical or mental health issues, or&#xD;
             life expectancy &lt;24 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant, lactating, or planning to become pregnant during the study period;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in other intervention studies&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Katherine D Hoerster, PhD MPH BA</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>VA Puget Sound Health Care System Seattle Division, Seattle, WA</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA Puget Sound Health Care System Seattle Division, Seattle, WA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98108</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hoerster KD, Collins MP, Au DH, Lane A, Epler E, McDowell J, Barón AE, Rise P, Plumley R, Nguyen T, Schooler M, Schuttner L, Ma J. Testing a self-directed lifestyle intervention among veterans: The D-ELITE pragmatic clinical trial. Contemp Clin Trials. 2020 Aug;95:106045. doi: 10.1016/j.cct.2020.106045. Epub 2020 May 28.</citation>
    <PMID>32473403</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 18, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 21, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>weight loss</keyword>
  <keyword>lifestyle</keyword>
  <keyword>diet</keyword>
  <keyword>exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>randomized controlled trial</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

