<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1941">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04586140</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ETHICOVID</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04586140</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Operation of the GHPSJ Clinical Ethical Reflection Assistance Group During the COVID-19 Period</brief_title>
  <acronym>ETHICOVID</acronym>
  <official_title>Operation of the Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint-Joseph Clinical Ethical Reflection Assistance Group During the COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Between March and May 2020, Ile-de-France hospitals faced an influx of patients infected with&#xD;
      the COVID 19 virus. Faced with the scale of the pandemic, the aggressiveness of this&#xD;
      pathology, severe respiratory complications and the shortage of resuscitation beds , the&#xD;
      teams had to make difficult decisions on the therapeutic strategy, the orientation of&#xD;
      patients in the event of respiratory distress and their intensive care status. To do this,&#xD;
      each establishment reflected in an emergency context on procedures for collegial deliberation&#xD;
      and assistance in ethical reflection, based on the recommendations of the National&#xD;
      Consultative Ethics Committee and learned societies such as the French Society. of Anesthesia&#xD;
      and Resuscitation or the French Society of Support and Palliative Care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some hospitals had already institutionalized the ethical approach upstream of the health&#xD;
      crisis. For example, the Groupe d'Aide à la Réflexion Éthique Clinique (GAREC) was created in&#xD;
      November 2005 within the Paris Saint-Joseph Hospital Group. GAREC is a collegial and&#xD;
      multidisciplinary entity, made up of 8 members who intervene at the request of caregivers&#xD;
      when a clinical situation turns out to be ethically complex. He gives an advisory opinion,&#xD;
      the decision belonging to the referring physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the start of the COVID period, GAREC changed its structure, organization and operation in&#xD;
      order to respond to the multiple issues posed by the complexity of the health situation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study seeks to analyze the adaptation mechanisms put in place by this group during the&#xD;
      epidemic period as well as the nature of the benefit provided to the caregivers who requested&#xD;
      it, to the patients and to their relatives.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adaptation mechanisms: during the COVID period, GAREC was extended to other paramedical&#xD;
           professions (psychologists, nurses), thus increasing from 8 to 15 members. It has set up&#xD;
           2 weekly meetings, an on-call duty and on-call duty. The requests were made easier: they&#xD;
           could be done by phone, by email, day or night. Several questions emerge: What were the&#xD;
           motivations for enlarging the group? How were the members integrated into this group?&#xD;
           What were its operating methods? How and by whom was it seized? For what purpose? Were&#xD;
           the intervention teams multidisciplinary?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Nature of the benefit provided by GAREC: it will be approached by semi-structured&#xD;
           interviews via a qualitative research method.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This work is part of a broader reflective perspective:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  What representation of ethics underlies this device?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Does the institutionalization of ethics help to enhance or make invisible what ethics&#xD;
           owes to daily healthcare practices?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To what extent does the institutionalization of clinical ethics make health institutions&#xD;
           more human and virtuous?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Under what conditions can a device like GAREC go beyond the role of ethical guarantor&#xD;
           and transform the institution and nursing practices in the service of a collective&#xD;
           reflective approach? This study will be carried out on patient data usually collected as&#xD;
           part of their care and on data collected through semi-structured interviews with&#xD;
           healthcare professionals. As such, it fits into the perspective of grounded theory.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 9, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Interest of GAREC</measure>
    <time_frame>Year 1</time_frame>
    <description>This outcome is to evaluate the benefit of nursing staff in the ethical process. In a qualitative study like this, no primary endpoint is established.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Ethics</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with COVID-19 infection</arm_group_label>
    <description>This study will be carried out on patient data usually collected as part of their care. The patients were infected with COVID-19 and hospitalized between 03/25/2020 and 05/07/2020, and who benefited from GAREC's intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Nursing staff AND GAREC Members</arm_group_label>
    <description>This study also concerns data collected in the context of semi-structured interviews with health professionals, in a prospective manner. These are caregivers who are members of GARED or who called on GAREC between 25/03/2020 and 07/05/2020.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients hospitalized for COVID-19 infection who benefited from GAREC's intervention&#xD;
        between 03/25/2020 and 05/07/2020.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Major&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hospitalized for a COVID-19 infection and for which GAREC intervened between&#xD;
                  03/25/20 and 05/07/20&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Caregivers:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  GAREC members (between 8 and 15 caregivers)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Having called on GAREC (between 10 and 20 caregivers)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient under guardianship or curatorship&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient deprived of liberty&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient under legal protection&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient objecting to the use of their data for this research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Caregivers o Caregiver opposing the use of their data for this research&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marie-Lorraine de WARREN, Nurse</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Marie-Lorraine de WARREN, Nurse</last_name>
    <phone>0681303984</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>mldewarren@adc.asso.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Helene BEAUSSIER, PharmD, pHD</last_name>
    <phone>0144127883</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>crc@ghpsj.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint-Joseph</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75014</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marie-Lorraine de WARREN, Nurse</last_name>
      <phone>0681303984</phone>
      <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
      <email>mldewarren@adc.asso.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.ccne-ethique.fr/sites/default/files/reponse_ccne_-_covid-19_def.pdf</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.coreb.infectiologie.com/UserFiles/File/procedures/rpmo-ethique-rea-covid-19-vf-24-corr26-mar20-2.pdf</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 30, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 30, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 31, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

