<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2833">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04647669</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SRD/ETH/20</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04647669</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>World Health Organization (WHO) COVID-19 Solidarity Trial for COVID-19 Treatments</brief_title>
  <acronym>SOLIDARITY</acronym>
  <official_title>WHO Public Health Emergency &quot;Solidarity&quot; Clinical Trial for COVID-19 Treatments</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of The West Indies</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of The West Indies</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In early 2020 there were no approved anti-viral treatments for COVID19 Infection. The&#xD;
      SOLIDARITY trial is a multicentre adaptive international randomised trial sponsored by Word&#xD;
      Health Organization to determine the efficacy of Remdevir (daily infusion for 10 days), or&#xD;
      Acalabrutinib (orally twice daily for 10 days), or Interferon β1a(daily injection for 6 days)&#xD;
      compared with local standard of care in patients admitted to hospital for COVID19 infection&#xD;
      on all-cause mortality, stratified by severity of disease at the time of randomisation. The&#xD;
      major secondary outcomes are duration of hospital stay and time to first receiving&#xD;
      ventilation (or intensive care).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Terminology: The novel coronavirus-induced disease first described in 2019 in China is&#xD;
      designated COVID-19 (or COVID), and the pathogen itself (an RNA virus) is SARS-coronavirus-2&#xD;
      (SARS-CoV-2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background: In early 2020 there were no approved anti-viral treatments for COVID, and WHO&#xD;
      expert groups advised that four re-purposed drugs, Remdesivir, Lopinavir (given with&#xD;
      Ritonavir, to slow hepatic degradation), Interferon (β1a), and hydroxychloroquine (HCQ)&#xD;
      should be evaluated in an international randomised trial. In addition, WHO provided&#xD;
      guidelines that local physicians may consider when COVID-19 is suspected on clinical&#xD;
      management of severe acute respiratory infection. However, following an interim analyses, the&#xD;
      interim results of HCQ vs standard of care and lopinavir/ritonavir vs standard of care from&#xD;
      the Solidarity/Discovery trials, the Solidarity trial Executive Group decided to stop the HCQ&#xD;
      and the Lopinavir/ritonavir arms on the 3rd of July, 2020 due to futility; leaving 3 arms,&#xD;
      i.e., remdesivir, Interferon (β1a), and standard of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the 6th of August 2020, due to a review of the rationale and clinical evidence, the&#xD;
      Executive Group of the Steering Committee of the Solidarity trial recommended that a new arm&#xD;
      should be opened in the Solidarity trial, to evaluate the clinical efficacy of Acalabrutinib.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Simplicity of procedures: To facilitate collaboration even in hospitals that have become&#xD;
      overloaded, patient enrolment and randomisation (via the internet) and all other trial&#xD;
      procedures are greatly simplified, and no paperwork at all is required. Once a hospital has&#xD;
      obtained approval, electronic entry of patients who have given informed consent takes only a&#xD;
      few minutes. At the end of it, the randomly allocated treatment is displayed on the screen&#xD;
      and confirmed by electronic messaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomisation: Adults (age ≥18 years) recently hospitalised, or already in hospital, with&#xD;
      definite COVID and, in the view of the responsible doctor, no contra-indication to any of the&#xD;
      study drugs will be randomly allocated between&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Local standard of care alone, OR local standard of care plus one of&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Remdesivir (daily infusion for 10 days)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Acalabrutinib (orally twice daily for 10 days)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Interferon β1a(daily injection for 6 days).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data reported before randomisation: Information is entered electronically on&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Country, hospital (from a list of approved hospitals) and randomising doctor&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Confirmation that informed consent has been obtained&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patient identifiers, age and sex&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patient characteristics (yes/no): current smoking, diabetes, heart disease, chronic lung&#xD;
           disease, chronic liver disease, asthma, HIV infection, active tuberculosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  COVID-19 severity at entry (yes/no): shortness of breath, being given oxygen, already on&#xD;
           a ventilator, and, if lungs imaged, major bilateral abnormality (infiltrations/patchy&#xD;
           shadowing)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Whether any of the study drugs are currently NOT AVAILABLE at the hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion from study entry: Patients will not be randomised if, in the view of the&#xD;
      randomising doctor, ANY of the AVAILABLE study drugs are contra-indicated (e.g., because of&#xD;
      patient characteristics, chronic liver or heart disease, or some concurrent medication).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Changing management of study patients: At all times the patient's medical team remains solely&#xD;
      responsible for decisions about that patient's care and safety. Hence, if the team decide&#xD;
      that deviation from the randomly allocated treatment arm is definitely necessary, this should&#xD;
      be done.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up: When patients die or are discharged, follow-up ceases and it is reported:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Which study drugs were given (and for how many days)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Whether ventilation or intensive care was received (and, if so, when it began)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Date of discharge, or date and cause of death while still in hospital. If no report is&#xD;
           received within 6 weeks of study entry, an electronic reminder is sent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Drug safety: Suspected unexpected serious adverse reactions that are life-threatening (e.g.,&#xD;
      Stevens-Johnson syndrome, anaphylaxis, aplastic anaemia, or anything comparably uncommon and&#xD;
      serious) must be reported within 24 hours of being diagnosed, without waiting for death or&#xD;
      discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Major outcomes: The primary outcome is all-cause mortality, subdivided by severity of disease&#xD;
      at the time of randomisation. The major secondary outcomes are duration of hospital stay and&#xD;
      time to first receiving ventilation (or intensive care).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data monitoring: A global Data and Safety Monitoring Committee will keep the accumulating&#xD;
      drug safety results and major outcome results under regular review.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Numbers entered: The larger the number entered the more accurate the results will be, but&#xD;
      numbers entered will depend on how the epidemic develops. If substantial numbers get&#xD;
      hospitalised in the participating centres, it may be possible to enter several thousand&#xD;
      hospitalised patients with relatively mild disease and a few thousand with severe disease,&#xD;
      but realistic, appropriate sample sizes could not be estimated at the start of the trial and&#xD;
      will depend on the evolution of the epidemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Heterogeneity between populations: If a study treatment does affect outcome, then this effect&#xD;
      could well differ between patients who had severe disease when randomised and those who had&#xD;
      less severe disease. It could also differ between younger and older patients, or between&#xD;
      patients in one or another country. If sufficient numbers are randomised, it may be possible&#xD;
      to obtain statistically reliable treatment comparisons within each of several different&#xD;
      countries or types of patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adaptive design: The WHO may decide to add novel treatment arms while the trial is in&#xD;
      progress. Conversely, the WHO may decide to discontinue some treatment arms, especially if&#xD;
      the Global Data and Safety Monitoring Committee reports, based on interim analyses, that one&#xD;
      of the trial treatments definitely affects mortality.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>All cause Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>Number of days from hospital admission up to 28 days post discharge</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of hospital stay</measure>
    <time_frame>Number of days from hospital admission to discharge up to 28 days post admission</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to first receiving ventilation</measure>
    <time_frame>Number of days from hospital admission to day of receiving ventilatory support up to 28 days post admission</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to admission to the intensive care unit</measure>
    <time_frame>Number of days from hospital admission to day of admission to intensive care unit up to 28 days post admission</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Local Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Local Standard of Care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Remdesivir</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Remdesivir (daily infusion for 10 days)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Acalabrutinib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Acalabrutinib (orally twice daily for 10 days)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Interferon</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Interferon β1a(daily injection for 6 days).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Remdesivir</intervention_name>
    <description>200 mg intravenous loading dose on Day 1, and 100mg intravenous once-daily for subsequent doses from Day 2 up to Day 10.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Remdesivir</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acalabrutinib</intervention_name>
    <description>100 mg capsules twice daily every 12 h for 10 days taken with or without food.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Acalabrutinib</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Interferon beta-1a</intervention_name>
    <description>Interferon ß-1a will be administered intravenously at the dose of 10 μg once daily for 6 days if oxygen dependent or subcutaneously at 44 ug Day 1, Day 3, and Day 6</description>
    <arm_group_label>Interferon</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard of Care</intervention_name>
    <description>Treatment according to local hospital protocol</description>
    <arm_group_label>Local Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  consenting adults (age ≥18) hospitalised with definite COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients without known allergy or contra-indications to any of the of the therapies&#xD;
             and without anticipated transfer within 72 hours to a non- study hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients admitted to a collaborating hospital Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  AVAILABLE study drugs are contra-indicated (e.g., because of patient characteristics,&#xD;
             chronic liver or heart disease, or some concurrent medication).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marvin Reid</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of the West Indies</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Univeristy of the West Indies</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kingston</city>
        <zip>7</zip>
        <country>Jamaica</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tomlin Paul</last_name>
      <phone>8769272556</phone>
      <email>tomlin.paul@uwimona.edu.jm</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marvin E Reid, MB BS PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Naydenne Williams, MBBS DM</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Jamaica</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 15, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 1, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferon-beta</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferon beta-1a</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

