<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1576">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04665752</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10000078</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>000078-EI</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04665752</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ocular Findings and Viral Persistence in Ocular Fluids in COVID-19 Survivors</brief_title>
  <official_title>Ocular Findings and Viral Persistence in Ocular Fluids in COVID-19 Survivors, a Natural History, Observational Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Eye Institute (NEI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some people who have had COVID-19 experience changes in the eye. Sometimes these changes are&#xD;
      subtle and may not affect vision. Researchers want to learn how many people experience these&#xD;
      eye changes and where in the eye they occur to better understand the outcomes of COVID-19 and&#xD;
      its treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To examine possible changes in the eye that might have occurred as a result of COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults age 18 and older who were diagnosed with COVID-19 and recovered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with a medical history and physical exam. They will have blood&#xD;
      tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have an eye exam. Their pupils will be dilated with eye drops. Eye pressure&#xD;
      and movements will be measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have optical coherence tomography. Pictures will be taken of the retina and&#xD;
      the inside of the eyes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may have fluorescein angiography and indocyanine green angiography. They will be&#xD;
      given a dye through an intravenous line. The dye will travel up to the blood vessels in their&#xD;
      eyes. Pictures will be taken of the dye as it flows through the blood vessels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may have electroretinography to test the retina. They will sit in the dark with&#xD;
      their eyes patched for 30 minutes. Then they will watch flashing lights while wearing contact&#xD;
      lenses that sense signals from the retina.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may have adaptive optics-assisted imaging. They will look at a specific location&#xD;
      while images are taken of the retina.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the study, participants will have blood drawn through a needle in their arm. Fluid or&#xD;
      tissue from the eye may be obtained if participants have a medically needed procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation will last for 12 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Description:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this study is to understand the rate and extent of ocular involvement in&#xD;
      COVID-19 patients and whether SARS-COV-2 can be detected in ocular fluids or tissue in&#xD;
      convalescent phase.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective: To investigate if COVID survivors show signs of anterior or posterior&#xD;
      segment inflammation or other retinochoroidal changes after recovery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To investigate if SARS-Cov-2 can be detected in the ocular fluids or tissues of survivors&#xD;
      among patients who undergo medically indicated ocular surgery or diagnostic procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory Objective: To investigate whether the use of chloroquine/Hydroxychloroquine for&#xD;
      treatment of COVID-19 is associated with ocular changes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Endpoint: Percentage of patients with Ocular exam abnormalities such as&#xD;
      conjunctival/corneal, anterior segment, choroidal, retinal lesions and subclinical findings&#xD;
      on OCT, FA and ICG&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Correlation of ocular findings with COVID severity (by history)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Proportion of patients with +SARS-COV-2 PCR in ocular fluid/tissues among COVID-19 survivors&#xD;
      and correlation to clinical characteristics and IgG levels&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Up to 150 COVID-19 survivors will be recruited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Description of Sites/Facilities Enrolling Participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This protocol will enroll participants at the NIH CC. De-identified samples may be received&#xD;
      from the New York Medical Center.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Duration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant Duration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participants will be asked to come to the NIH CC for one visit. A select subgroup of up&#xD;
      to 75 participants with positive findings may be asked to return in 12 months from their&#xD;
      initial visit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 11, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Over the study duration</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with ocular exam abnormalities, such as conjunctival/corneal anterior segment, choroidal, retinal lesions and subclinical findings on OCT, FA, and ICG.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation of findings</measure>
    <time_frame>Over the study duration</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation of ocular findings with COVID severity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients</measure>
    <time_frame>Over the study duration</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with +SARS-COV-2 PCR in ocular fluid/tissues among COVID-19 survivors and correlation to clinical characteristics and IgG levels.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Affected Participants</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants previously diagnosed with COVID-19.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Participants diagnosed with COVID-19 and at least 30 days symptom-free.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        In order to be eligible to participate in this study, an individual must meet all of the&#xD;
        following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Stated willingness to comply with all study procedures and availability for the&#xD;
             duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Male or female, aged 18 or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of positive PCR or positive IgG for SARS-CoV-2 cases and if known history of&#xD;
             COVID-19 infection, at least 30 days passed since a positive PCR for SARS-COV-2 and&#xD;
             have been asymptomatic for at least 10 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Willing to undergo study required testing and blood draw.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Willing to have blood samples stored for future research.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        An individual who meets any of the following criteria will be excluded from participation&#xD;
        in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Current symptoms consistent with COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Any condition or event that, in the PI s opinion, may substantially increase the risk&#xD;
             associated with study participation or compromise the study's scientific objectives.&#xD;
             Conditions that exclude a subject are considered to be unlikely, but an example would&#xD;
             include having an acute respiratory infection or recent exposure that would make it&#xD;
             unsafe to perform study procedures or obtain blood samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pregnant and decisionally impaired individuals will be excluded from participation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hatice N Sen, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Eye Institute (NEI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Dominic Obiyor, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 435-4556</phone>
    <email>dominic.obiyor@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_000078-EI.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>January 15, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 11, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Images</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

