<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="462">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04682041</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PICNIC Study</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04682041</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating the Impact of EnteraGam In People With COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>PICNIC</acronym>
  <official_title>Randomized Open-Label Clinical Study Evaluating the Impact of EnteraGam, a Nutritional Intervention Containing Bovine Plasma-Derived Immunoglobulin CoNcentrate, on Clinical Outcomes In People With COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Entera Health, Inc</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Lemus Buhils, SL</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Clinical Research Unit, IMIM (Hospital del Mar Medical Research Institute)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Entera Health, Inc</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19), caused by Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus&#xD;
      2 (SARS-CoV-2), emerged as a potentially life-threatening disease in Wuhan, China, at the end&#xD;
      of 2019. Since then, it has spread to almost 200 countries and infection rates are rapidly&#xD;
      accelerating.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Overactivation of T cells resulting in immune dysfunction, dysfunction of the renin&#xD;
      angiotensin system, and antibody-dependent enhancement are thought to contribute to the&#xD;
      cytokine storm that results in acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), culminating in&#xD;
      death. In addition to causing respiratory symptoms, SARS-CoV-2 can cause diarrhea and has&#xD;
      been isolated from the stool. SARS-CoV-2 binds to Angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) on&#xD;
      lung alveolar type 2 cells, but ACE2 is also expressed in the absorptive enterocytes from the&#xD;
      ileum and colon. The diarrhea may be caused by increased intestinal permeability due to&#xD;
      binding of these receptors by the SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thus, an intervention to attenuate this cytokine storm may improve clinical outcomes in&#xD;
      people with COVID-19. One such intervention is oral administration of serum bovine&#xD;
      immunoglobulins, which decreases interleukin-6 (IL-6) levels safely with minimal side&#xD;
      effects. Animal and human clinical studies have shown dietary supplementation with oral&#xD;
      immunoglobulins improves mucosal immunity, specifically respiratory/pulmonary and GI mucosa,&#xD;
      and decreases systemic inflammation, reducing the symptoms and severity of pulmonary&#xD;
      inflammation and viral infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dietary supplementation with EnteraGam® will decrease IL-6 levels and prevent disease&#xD;
      progression in SARS-CoV-2 infected individuals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate the effectiveness of the oral nutritional therapy EnteraGam® (serum-derived&#xD;
      bovine immunoglobulin/protein isolate) to prevent disease progression of COVID-19 and to&#xD;
      decrease IL-6 levels as compared to standard of care in subjects with COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomized open-label clinical study evaluating the effectiveness of EnteraGam® 10.0 g BID&#xD;
      (every 12 hours) added to standard of care, as compared to standard of care alone, in&#xD;
      subjects with COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Subject population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outpatient and inpatient male and non-pregnant females ≥18 years old, diagnosed with COVID-19&#xD;
      in the emergency department or admitted to the hospital but not requiring invasive mechanical&#xD;
      ventilation or in the ICU.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 420 subjects will be randomized (2:1 ratio), 280 in the EnteraGam® arm and 140&#xD;
      in the control (standard of care) arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nutritional intervention:&#xD;
&#xD;
      ImmunoLin is the active ingredient in EnteraGam®, a medical food developed and marketed by&#xD;
      Entera Health in the US since 2013. ImmunoLin is an edible bovine plasma-derived&#xD;
      immunoglobulin concentrate developed in 2001 as an immunoglobulin enriched plasma preparation&#xD;
      for the human dietary supplement market. ImmunoLin is Generally Regarded as Safe (GRAS)&#xD;
      following a letter of no objection from the US FDA in 2008. Physicians have prescribed&#xD;
      EnteraGam® for patients with a variety of GI-related conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical methodology:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Efficacy: Based on per protocol analysis. Subjects lacking an assessment at Week 2 will be&#xD;
      included in the analysis using the last available post-baseline data. Three pre-specified&#xD;
      secondary analyses will be performed: 1) restricted to subjects with a comorbidity considered&#xD;
      a major risk factor for hospitalization and disease severity (diabetes, cardiovascular&#xD;
      disease, chronic lung disease, chronic renal disease, immunocompromised state); 2) restricted&#xD;
      to age ≥ 50 years; 3) by inpatient only and outpatient only subgroups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additional analysis of covariance models with adjustment for Baseline characteristics and&#xD;
      interactions may be examined in supportive or exploratory analyses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety: All safety analyses will be based on all subjects who are randomized to EnteraGam and&#xD;
      subsequently receive at least 1 packet of investigational product. Safety assessments will be&#xD;
      analyzed by frequency of events/abnormalities for categorical values or summarized using&#xD;
      descriptive statistics (mean, standard deviation, median, range, and number of observations).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 22, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized open-label clinical study evaluating the effectiveness of EnteraGam 10.0 g BID added to standard of care, as compared to standard of care alone, in subjects with COVID-19. Eligible subjects will be randomized in a 2:1 ratio.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in plasma IL-6 levels</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of IL-6 levels measured in plasma</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 disease progression by Week 2</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of patients with COVID-19 who have disease progression by Week 2, defined as:&#xD;
For outpatients, return to emergency department for COVID-19 related manifestations or worsening of ≥1 level on the World Health Organization (WHO) 9-point ordinal scale.&#xD;
For inpatients, worsening of ≥1 level on the WHO 9-point ordinal scale.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in dyspnea</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of dyspnea presentation at Week 2 compared to baseline, assessed by daily symptoms questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in diarrhea</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of diarrhea presentation at Week 2 compared to baseline, assessed by daily symptoms questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in fever</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of fever presentation at Week 2 compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in neutrophil count</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of neutrophil count at Week 2 compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in lymphocyte count</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of lymphocyte count at Week 2 compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in neutrophil/lymphocyte ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of neutrophil/lymphocyte ratio at Week 2 compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in platelet count</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of platelet count at Week 2 compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in C-reactive protein</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of C-reactive protein levels at Week 2 compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in ferritin</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of ferritin levels at Week 2 compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in D-dimer</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of D-dimer levels at Week 2 compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in AST</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of Aspartate Transaminase (AST/GOT) levels at Week 2 compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in ALT</measure>
    <time_frame>At Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of Alanine Transaminase (ALT/GPT) levels at Week 2 compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to worsening clinical status</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Time elapsed between baseline and disease progression, defined as:&#xD;
For outpatients, return to emergency department for COVID-19 related manifestations or worsening of ≥1 level on the WHO 9-point ordinal scale.&#xD;
For inpatients, worsening of ≥1 level on the WHO 9-point ordinal scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to Week 2</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of serious and non-serious adverse events.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">420</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>EnteraGam + standard of care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive EnteraGam® (oral nutritional therapy) + standard of care for COVID-19 for 2 weeks. Total study duration (including the screening phase) will be approximately 4 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control (standard of care)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive standard of care for COVID-19 alone for 2 weeks. Total study duration (including the screening phase) will be approximately 4 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bovine Plasma-Derived Immunoglobulin Concentrate</intervention_name>
    <description>EnteraGam® 10.0 g, containing 5.0 g of serum-derived bovine immunoglobulin/protein isolate (SBI) BID (every 12 hours) for 2 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>EnteraGam + standard of care</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>EnteraGam®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard of care</intervention_name>
    <description>Standard of care PSMAR protocol for COVID-19 patients.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control (standard of care)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>EnteraGam + standard of care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject is ≥18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Male or female. Females of childbearing (reproductive) potential must have a negative&#xD;
             urine pregnancy test at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject with diagnosis of COVID-19 based on + RNA or immunoglobulin M (IgM) test or&#xD;
             compatible clinical presentation* who:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. is being discharged from the emergency department without hospitalization, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. is admitted to the hospital or was previously hospitalized and still in the&#xD;
                  hospital, does not require invasive mechanical ventilation and does not require&#xD;
                  management in the intensive care unit. Inpatients can be enrolled in the study at&#xD;
                  any time of their hospitalization, if they comply with the inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
             (*)Compatible clinical presentation will consider compatible symptoms (cough, fever,&#xD;
             myalgia, dyspnea, ageusia / anosmia) and examination of general condition, heart rate&#xD;
             and respiratory rate, oxygen saturation, cardiopulmonary auscultation, compatible&#xD;
             radiology.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Ability to consume EnteraGam.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject or surrogate decision maker is capable of understanding the requirements of&#xD;
             the study, understands the language of the informed consent form, and is capable and&#xD;
             willing to sign the informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Female subjects who are pregnant or breast-feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject is enrolled in another randomized clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject is taking anti-IL-6 treatment (e.g. tocilizumab), anti-IL-1 treatment (e.g.&#xD;
             canakinumab, anakinra), or other biologic immunomodulators or immunosuppressant drugs.&#xD;
             Note: Topical/inhaled immunomodulators and corticosteroids are not restricted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject has immediate need for GI surgery or intervention for active GI bleeding,&#xD;
             pancreatitis, peritonitis, intestinal obstruction, or intra-abdominal abscess.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject has active inflammatory bowel disease (e.g., ulcerative colitis, Crohn's&#xD;
             disease, or celiac disease), GI malignancy, GI obstruction, pancreatitis,&#xD;
             gastroparesis, carcinoid syndrome, amyloidosis, ileus, or cholelithiasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject has active gastric ulcer, duodenal ulcer, diverticulitis, colitis, enteritis,&#xD;
             infectious gastroenteritis, or GI neoplasm, other than benign polyps.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject has a history of allergy or intolerance to beef or to any ingredient in the&#xD;
             product.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject has active drug or alcohol abuse that in the opinion of the investigator may&#xD;
             interfere with the subject's ability to comply with this protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of uncontrolled psychiatric disorders (includes significant depression or&#xD;
             suicidal ideation), that in the opinion of the investigator may interfere with the&#xD;
             subject's ability to comply with this protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. In the opinion of the investigator, progression to death is imminent and highly likely&#xD;
             within the next 24 hours.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Roberto Güerri Fernández, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hospital del Mar (Barcelona, Spain)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Netanya S. Utay, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston (Houston, TX, USA)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Roberto Güerri Fernández, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+34 932483251</phone>
    <email>mailto:rguerri@psmar.cat</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Maria Tintoré</last_name>
    <email>mtintore@lemusbuhils.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital del Mar</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08003</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Roberto Güerri Fernández, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+34 932483251</phone>
      <email>rguerri@psmar.cat</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 22, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 23, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>Coronavirus</keyword>
  <keyword>Bovine Plasma-Derived Immunoglobulin</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulins, Intravenous</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

