<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="422">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04379063</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NSHA REB#1025690</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04379063</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19 Pandemic Short Interval National Survey Gauging Psychological Distress</brief_title>
  <acronym>COPING</acronym>
  <official_title>COVID-19 Pandemic Short Interval National Survey Gauging Psychological Distress Among Physicians (COPING Survey): A Longitudinal Survey</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Jon Bailey</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Nova Scotia Health Authority</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Nova Scotia Health Authority</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) pandemic is unprecedented in its scale of infection and&#xD;
      the response required to decrease the mortality rates. Disturbingly, the European and United&#xD;
      States experience demonstrates that health care systems in industrialized countries are at&#xD;
      risk of becoming overwhelmed. Physicians are already at risk of burnout under normal working&#xD;
      conditions, and in particular, when responding to crisis situations. During the 2003 severe&#xD;
      acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) outbreak, healthcare workers experienced high rates of&#xD;
      psychological distress that lasted years. However, there may be protective factors that may&#xD;
      decrease the rate or severity of psychological distress and burnout. This study seeks to&#xD;
      investigate the rates of physician burnout assessed at multiple time points during the&#xD;
      COVID-19 pandemic. Further, this study seeks to determine the factors that may increase or&#xD;
      decrease burnout and psychological distress in such a setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will be a national longitudinal survey of physicians in Canada. It will include&#xD;
      all physicians that currently hold a license to practice in Canada (whether in training or a&#xD;
      full license). Consenting participants will complete an initial survey gathering information&#xD;
      about their type of practice, health conditions, preparations the COVID-19 pandemic, burnout,&#xD;
      and psychological distress. Every month, participants will be asked to complete a follow-up&#xD;
      survey, describing their stressors, coping strategies, burnout, and psychological distress.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will analyze and report the initial results to help provincial and national&#xD;
      organizations support our physicians and mitigate burnout during this pandemic. The results&#xD;
      of the follow up surveys will be analyzed and reported following the pandemic. These findings&#xD;
      will help keep our physician workforce healthy under normal working conditions and during&#xD;
      future crises.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background It has become ubiquitous to describe the severe acute respiratory syndrome&#xD;
      coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) pandemic and the global measures to decrease mortality rates of&#xD;
      Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) as 'unprecedented'. The Public Health Agency of Canada (PHAC)&#xD;
      models released on April 8th predict that even with strict epidemiologic controls&#xD;
      934,000-1,879,000 people will be infected in Canada and 11,000- 22,000 will die.&#xD;
      Disturbingly, the European and United States experience demonstrates that health care systems&#xD;
      in industrialized countries are at risk of becoming overwhelmed. It has long been recognized&#xD;
      that physicians are at risk for burnout, which can negatively affect their ability to care&#xD;
      for patients, their colleagues and themselves. Infectious disease pandemics present many of&#xD;
      the same challenges for physicians as natural disasters and mass casualty events, with the&#xD;
      addition of a prolonged time frame, potential need for isolation away from family, and&#xD;
      concern of becoming infected or infecting loved ones. During the 2003 severe acute&#xD;
      respiratory syndrome (SARS) outbreak, 18-57% of health care workers (HCWs) experienced&#xD;
      measurable psychological distress. Even 1-2 years following the SARS pandemic HCWs in Ontario&#xD;
      experienced high levels of burnout (19-30%), psychological distress (30-45%), and PTSD&#xD;
      symptoms (8-13%). Despite the overall high rates, there are several mitigating factors that&#xD;
      may decrease the rate or severity of psychological distress and burnout.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given that these studies generally measure burnout and psychological distress at one or two&#xD;
      cross-sectional time points, it is difficult to tell how burnout develops over time.&#xD;
      Additionally, the bulk of the studies assessed HCWs following natural disasters, which tend&#xD;
      to present as a single time point with one large wave of patients. The current crisis is&#xD;
      distinct in its sustained level of demand on HCWs with potential for multiple waves of&#xD;
      patients or a sustained high number of patients outstripping the health care system resources&#xD;
      for months at a time. This study seeks to investigate the rates of burnout assessed at&#xD;
      multiple time points during the COVID-19 pandemic. Further, this study seeks to determine the&#xD;
      relationship between patient numbers, mitigating factors, and exacerbating factors and the&#xD;
      rates of burnout at various time points.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. What are the rates of psychological distress and burnout among physicians and residents&#xD;
           throughout the COVID-19 pandemic?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. What baseline factors are associated with reductions and increases in psychological&#xD;
           distress and burnout over time (trajectories)?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods This study will be a national longitudinal survey of physicians in Canada. The&#xD;
      sampling frame will be all physicians currently practicing in Canada, whether they hold a&#xD;
      full, provisional, or post-graduate in-training license. The survey will be distributed by:&#xD;
      1. Advertisements on Twitter, 2. Provincial physician associations, and 3. National specialty&#xD;
      groups for higher risk specialties (anesthesia, critical care, emergency medicine).&#xD;
      Recipients will be directed to the survey site hosted by Redcap. Cross-sectional results of&#xD;
      the initial survey to give immediate feedback to provincial and national organizations about&#xD;
      the threat of physician burnout and psychological distress. Longitudinal results will analyze&#xD;
      how burnout and distress change over time and will analyze the relationship to mitigating and&#xD;
      exacerbating factors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consenting participants will complete an initial survey gathering demographic information&#xD;
      (age, gender, trainee, years in practice, specialty, chronic health conditions, practice type&#xD;
      (academic, community, rural), preparatory information (prior to first COVID-19 suspected&#xD;
      case: COVID-19 pathways/procedures, simulation, designated areas, scheduling changes), and&#xD;
      baseline measures (Maslach Burnout Inventory - General Survey (MBI-GS) short form, Pandemic&#xD;
      Experience &amp; Perceptions Scale (PEPS), Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS),&#xD;
      stressors, resources, coping strategies). Participants will then receive follow up&#xD;
      questionnaires every month until there is a sustained period of no new cases in their&#xD;
      province (1 month without a new case) up to a maximum of one-year involvement. These follow&#xD;
      up questionnaires will measure burnout (MBI-GS), psychological distress (HADS), pandemic&#xD;
      specific stressors (PEPS), workplace stressors, and resources/coping strategies. A final&#xD;
      follow-up survey will be sought one year after the end of the short- interval surveys to&#xD;
      assess the long-term effects of responding to the COVID pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analysis Objective 1. Variables will be described using mean and standard&#xD;
      deviation when normally distributed or median and interquartile range when skewed as measured&#xD;
      by the Shapiro-Wilk test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective 2. The cross-sectional results of the initial survey will be analyzed using linear&#xD;
      regression to quantify the strength of relationship between factors and burnout. In the&#xD;
      longitudinal analysis, trajectory analysis using latent growth mixed modelling (LGMM) will be&#xD;
      used to identify trajectories of burnout and psychological distress amongst physicians over&#xD;
      time. LGMM is ideally suited to longitudinal data as it is robust to the effects of missing&#xD;
      data. Furthermore, LGMM may prove very useful in an unprecedented situation such as this in&#xD;
      which there is scant data on which to base hypotheses as LGMM allows trajectories to be&#xD;
      identified more empirically based on the data rather than through a priori conceptual models.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anticipated Outcomes The investigators will discover whether the characteristics of burnout&#xD;
      during this pandemic are comparable to the current body of knowledge about physician burnout&#xD;
      at baseline or during more limited periods of crisis. This will inform whether current&#xD;
      interventions for physician burnout are appropriate during widespread pandemic events, both&#xD;
      as physicians continue to deal with COVID-19 and in the future. Improved understanding of&#xD;
      stressors and protective factors will be essential not only for planning therapeutic studies&#xD;
      at an individual level but will also allow institutions to mobilize high yield supports for&#xD;
      physicians at risk.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 13, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Burnout</measure>
    <time_frame>Start of survey until there is a sustained period of no new cases in their province (1 month without a new case)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Maslach Burnout Inventory - General Survey (MBI-GS) short form. The MBI-SF has three subscales (exhaustion, cynicism, efficacy). Each subscale is scored from 0-6 indicating the frequency of work-related feelings. A higher score in both exhaustion and cynicism indicate burnout is more likely; whereas, higher scores in efficacy indicate burnout is less likely.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Psychological Distress</measure>
    <time_frame>Start of survey until there is a sustained period of no new cases in their province (1 month without a new case)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS). The HADS scores both symptoms of depression and anxiety using 14-item measure (7 item with possible scores 0-21 each). Higher scores suggest that depression and/or anxiety are more likely.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-traumatic stress symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>One year following the end of the survey (no new cases in their province, 1 month without a new case)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) Checklist for Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSM-5) (PCL-5). Symptoms suggestive of PTSD are scored using a 20-item measure with possible scores ranging from 0-80. Higher scores are more suggestive of PTSD.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-traumatic growth</measure>
    <time_frame>One year following the end of the survey (no new cases in their province, 1 month without a new case)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Post-traumatic Growth Inventory (PTGI-SF). The PTGI-SF is a 10-item measure with possible scores ranging from 0-50. Higher scores suggest that post-traumatic growth is more likely.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">342</enrollment>
  <condition>Burnout, Professional</condition>
  <condition>Psychological Distress</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Canadian physicians during COVID-19 pandemic</arm_group_label>
    <description>Any physician who is practicing in Canada during the COVID-19 pandemic, whether they hold a full, provisional, or post-graduate in-training license.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>COVID-19 pandemic</intervention_name>
    <description>Currently practicing during the COVID-19 pandemic</description>
    <arm_group_label>Canadian physicians during COVID-19 pandemic</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The membership of Canadian Medical Association (CMA) was 71,655 as of June 10, 2019. This&#xD;
        includes medical students and retired physicians. The total number of residents (8,681) and&#xD;
        practicing physicians (44,557) is 53,238 who could meet inclusion criteria. Response rates&#xD;
        by medical trainees to web-based surveys without incentives are approximately 60%, based on&#xD;
        previous survey studies. However, given the current situation and the potential for&#xD;
        overwhelmed healthcare systems and personnel, we expect a much lower response rate of&#xD;
        20-30%.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any physician who is currently practicing in Canada, whether they hold a full,&#xD;
             provisional, or post-graduate in-training license.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-physician healthcare providers, medical students, physicians without an active&#xD;
             license to practice will be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nova Scotia Health Authority</name>
      <address>
        <city>Halifax</city>
        <state>Nova Scotia</state>
        <zip>B3S 0H6</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 6, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 7, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 24, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 24, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 28, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Nova Scotia Health Authority</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jon Bailey</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Anesthesiolgist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Coronavirus</keyword>
  <keyword>Pandemic</keyword>
  <keyword>Outbreak</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Burnout, Professional</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

