<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1613">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04446104</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020/00561</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04446104</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Preventive Treatment for Migrant Workers at High-risk of COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Open-label Prophylaxis Trial Among Migrant Workers at High-risk of COVID-19 (DORM Trial)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National University Hospital, Singapore</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National University Hospital, Singapore</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In December 2019, a novel coronavirus, now called COVID-19, emerged as a global health threat&#xD;
      from Wuhan, China. Within weeks, the contagious virus spread within and between communities,&#xD;
      causing a lower respiratory tract infection dominated by symptoms of fever, cough and sore&#xD;
      throat. The incubation period was estimated at between 5 to 7 days, but could last as long as&#xD;
      14 days. Although COVID-19 causes a mostly mild and self-limiting disease, respiratory&#xD;
      involvement has been reported in about 5% of the population, requiring supplemental oxygen&#xD;
      and even ventilatory support to relieve hypoxia. Alveolar damage, fibrosis and consolidation&#xD;
      have been reported in radiologic and post-mortem studies. Existing data suggest a mortality&#xD;
      rate of COVID-19 is approximately 1-2%, higher among individuals with pre-existing&#xD;
      comorbidities and in healthcare systems with suboptimal access to ventilatory support.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given its high transmissibility, COVID-19 has quickly spread across the globe within a short&#xD;
      interval. By 27 April 2020, over 3 million people around the world have been diagnosed with&#xD;
      COVID-19, and more 200,000 have succumbed to the disease. As a proportion of patients&#xD;
      manifest mild or no symptoms, these numbers are likely an underestimate of the actual number&#xD;
      of patients with COVID-19. More disconcertingly, patients are known to shed viruses despite&#xD;
      mild or no symptoms, making it essential that a collective approach against COVID-19&#xD;
      incorporate active pharmacological treatment to prevent or mitigate virus pathogenesis prior&#xD;
      to its potential evolution to cause respiratory distress. To date, clinical trials have&#xD;
      focused on the treatment of hospitalised patients diagnosed with COVID-19; only few have&#xD;
      examined the clinical benefits of pharmacological agents despite few compelling in vitro&#xD;
      data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The relatively high transmission of COVID-19 in a closed dormitory environment of migrant&#xD;
      workers in Singapore presents a real-life scenario where a prophylaxis treatment could reduce&#xD;
      the impact of the disease. In Singapore, there are well grounded concerns an excess in cases&#xD;
      could pose the possibility of strain in healthcare system and mentally drain her workers. The&#xD;
      availability of an effective prophylaxis treatment is highly desirable to potentially reduce&#xD;
      this burden. Data from the current study could also have implications on how future outbreaks&#xD;
      in high-density areas should be managed, especially when residents are subjected to&#xD;
      quarantine and isolation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a pragmatic, open-label, randomised study with 4 interventional and 1 control arms.&#xD;
      Individuals will be recruited from migrant worker dormitories, and written informed consent&#xD;
      taken prior to enrolment. Randomisation will be done by the level within the dormitory&#xD;
      building and predetermined each day according to a randomisation schema done by an&#xD;
      independent statistician. This will obviate the potential for bias due to drug exchange&#xD;
      between study individuals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The 5 arms consist of:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Experimental arms&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Hydroxychloroquine tablet 400mg loading dose, followed by 200mg daily for 42 days&#xD;
                (1,000 study subjects)&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Ivermectin tablet 12mg single dose (1,000 study subjects)&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Zinc tablet 80 mg/vitamin C 500mg daily for 42 days (1,000 study subjects)&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. Povidone-iodine throat spray (3 times daily) for 42 days (1,000 study subjects)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Control arm 5) Vitamin C tablet 500mg daily for 42 days (1,000 study subjects)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study information sheet will be circulated in selected buildings within the dormitory 1-4&#xD;
      days before recruitment starts. All publicity materials and informed consent form will be&#xD;
      translated to the different languages (e.g. Tamil, Bengali, Chinese, Burmese and Malay). A&#xD;
      translator will be present to aid translation if necessary. Study subjects will be given&#xD;
      ample time to ask questions relating to the study. Prospective participants will respond by&#xD;
      showing up to recruitment stations at designated dates and times. Facilitators from the&#xD;
      dormitory will be engaged to assist with the ground crowd-control. Prospective videos will be&#xD;
      shown to inform the subject on the purpose, study inclusion and exclusion criteria, study&#xD;
      medications, blood taking, reporting of adverse effects and follow-up visits. Informed&#xD;
      consent will be taken before all study-related procedures are performed, including study&#xD;
      eligibility. Translators will also help translate the daily questionnaires.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the baseline recruitment,&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. History of symptoms, comorbidities and prior illnesses will be asked. Specific questions&#xD;
           include presence or absence of the following symptoms: Fever, chills, myalgia, headache,&#xD;
           diarrhoea, running nose, anosmia, loss of taste, sore throat, dry cough, shortness of&#xD;
           breath.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Measurements of study subjects' parameters such as weight, height, temperature, pulse&#xD;
           rate and blood pressure will be recorded. Subjects randomised to Ivermectin arm and&#xD;
           subsequently found to weigh below 60 kg will be randomised to other treatment arms.&#xD;
           Subjects randomised to hydroxychloroquine arm and found to have systolic blood pressure&#xD;
           &gt;150 mmHg and/or diastolic blood pressure &gt;90 mmHg and/or heart rate &gt;100 beats per&#xD;
           minute will also be randomized to other treatment arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. 12-lead electrocardiogram (ECG) will be performed in patients randomised to receive&#xD;
           hydroxychloroquine. Only those with corrected QT values less than 450 ms, no cardiac&#xD;
           arrhythmia and no ventricular hypertrophy will be allowed to receive hydroxychloroquine.&#xD;
           Those with corrected QT values more than 450 ms, cardiac arrhythmia and ventricular&#xD;
           hypertrophy will be randomised to other treatment arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Blood sample (20 mL) will be obtained to test Immunoglobulin G/M against SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
           Depending on the findings, additional tests will be performed to explore potential&#xD;
           biological reasons underpinning these observations. The choice of markers may include&#xD;
           pathway-specific biomarkers targeting inflammation, oxidative stress, lipid parameters,&#xD;
           as well as organ-specific ones such as renal and liver parameters. Given the large&#xD;
           sample size and high costs of analysis, the study team will prioritise more detailed&#xD;
           investigations in a targeted group of patients depending on the final findings. None of&#xD;
           these blood results is a screening criteria for study participation. The investigator&#xD;
           will share abnormal to the study subjects abnormal results of their renal and liver&#xD;
           parameters should these tests are tested following study completion. The extent on&#xD;
           investigation, however, depends on funding support. In this study, renal and hepatic&#xD;
           dysfunction will be based on physician-diagnosed and self-declaration on the part of the&#xD;
           study subject. All clinical information will be verified by a senior physician on-site.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Study medications will be packed with clear instructions written on the packing bag. The&#xD;
           package will be distributed to each subject based on the randomised treatment assigned.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Study participants will be given a study card to remind them to submit their symptoms&#xD;
           daily and to record the times when they consume their medications. They will also be&#xD;
           asked to present this card to doctors at the medical post or hospital should they seek&#xD;
           medical assistance. In the events of acute respiratory infection and hospitalization,&#xD;
           lab testing will be done as clinically indicated. Subjects on ventilator support who are&#xD;
           not able to take oral medications may discontinue taking the study drug. However,&#xD;
           subjects will remain in the study for collection of data on duration of mechanical&#xD;
           ventilation for analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During final study visit,&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. The study team, including investigators, will be present at the dormitory. A repeated&#xD;
           blood sample (20mL) will be collected for serological tests. Measurements of study&#xD;
           subjects' parameters such as weight (using Tanita BC-418 and Tanita BC-420MA for&#xD;
           bio-electrical impedance analysis), height, blood pressure will be taken. ECG will be&#xD;
           done only for subjects in hydroxychloroquine arm. History will be taken including&#xD;
           symptoms of fever, chills, myalgia, headache, diarrhoea, running nose, anosmia, loss of&#xD;
           taste, sore throat, dry cough, shortness of breath and the duration of such symptoms, if&#xD;
           any.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Balance medication and packaging retrieval to do medication accounting and checking for&#xD;
           adherence to assigned treatment arm&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Discharged from study if no adverse events to follow-up.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 13, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Laboratory-confirmed COVID-19 in treatment arms (hydroxychloroquine, ivermectin, zinc and povidone iodine)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study dosing, which is day 42</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acute respiratory illness in treatment arms (hydroxychloroquine, ivermectin, zinc and povidone iodine)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study dosing, which is day 42</time_frame>
    <description>Acute respiratory illness is defined by acute onset with any key respiratory symptoms including cough, shortness of breath, sore throat, runny nose and change in smell.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Febrile respiratory illness in treatment arms (hydroxychloroquine, ivermectin, zinc and povidone iodine)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study dosing, which is day 42</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of hospitalization for COVID-19 and non-COVID-19 related indications in treatment arms (hydroxychloroquine, ivermectin, zinc and povidone iodine)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study dosing, which is day 42</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of oxygen supplementation and mechanical ventilation in treatment arms (hydroxychloroquine, ivermectin, zinc and povidone iodine)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study dosing, which is day 42</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of oxygen supplementation and mechanical ventilation in treatment arms (hydroxychloroquine, ivermectin, zinc and povidone iodine)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study dosing, which is day 42</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of hospital stay in treatment arms (hydroxychloroquine, ivermectin, zinc and povidone iodine)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study dosing, which is day 42</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of laboratory-confirmed COVID-19 in treatment arms (hydroxychloroquine, ivermectin, zinc and povidone iodine)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study dosing, which is day 42</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events and serious adverse events in control arm (Vitamin C)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study dosing, which is day 42</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Drug discontinuation due to adverse events in control arm (Vitamin C)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study dosing, which is day 42</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">4257</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hydroxychloroquine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive hydroxychloroquine tablet 400mg loading dose, followed by 200mg daily for 42 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ivermectin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive ivermectin tablet 12mg single dose</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Zinc/ Vitamin C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive zinc tablet 80 mg/vitamin C 500mg daily for 42 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Povidone-iodine throat spray</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive povidone-iodine throat spray (3 times daily) for 42 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vitamin C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive vitamin C tablet 500mg daily for 42 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hydroxychloroquine Sulfate Tablets</intervention_name>
    <description>Hydroxychloroquine tablet 400mg loading dose, followed by 200mg daily for 42 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hydroxychloroquine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ivermectin 3mg Tab</intervention_name>
    <description>Ivermectin tablet 12mg single dose</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ivermectin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Zinc</intervention_name>
    <description>Zinc tablet 80 mg/vitamin C 500mg daily for 42 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Zinc/ Vitamin C</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Povidone-Iodine</intervention_name>
    <description>Povidone-iodine throat spray (3 times daily) for 42 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Povidone-iodine throat spray</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vitamin C</intervention_name>
    <description>Vitamin C tablet 500mg daily for 42 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vitamin C</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects must meet all the of following criteria to be included in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men residing in dormitory aged 21-60 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to understand instructions and consume study medications according to the study&#xD;
             protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weight more than 40kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Owns a mobile phone (with wireless fidelity and/or 3G connection and able to fill in&#xD;
             online forms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects who have any of the following criteria at baseline will be excluded from&#xD;
        participating in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptoms of acute respiratory illness (e.g. fever, runny nose, sore throat, cough,&#xD;
             breathlessness, loss of smell and loss of taste) for the past 30 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known current or history of SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to read English or any of the available local languages used for this clinical&#xD;
             trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cardiac or neurological diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of retinal diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of diabetes on insulin treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of depression&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of chronic alcohol use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of renal or hepatic dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of anaemia, after exposure to any given medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of thyroid disorder, hyperthyroidism, or sensitivity to iodine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergies with systemic presentation to any given medication (e.g.:&#xD;
             swelling of the face, throat, eyes and lips, respiratory disturbances, asthmatic&#xD;
             attacks, widespread skin blistering or urticaria (hives))&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant medication that may lead to cardiac arrhythmia (azithromycin,&#xD;
             amitriptyline, cimetidine, citalopram, nortriptyline, pantoprazole, quetiapine etc).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to comply with study dosing, instructions or restrictions.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tuas South Dormitory</name>
      <address>
        <city>Singapore</city>
        <country>Singapore</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Singapore</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 13, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 13, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ascorbic Acid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hydroxychloroquine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ivermectin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Povidone-Iodine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Povidone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

