<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="690">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04603664</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FMASU P82b/2020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04603664</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Role of NGAL and Cystatin C in Prediction of Acute Kidney Injury Covid-19 Infection</brief_title>
  <official_title>Role of Neutrophil Gelatinase-Associated Lipocalin (NGAL) and Cystatin C in Prediction of Acute Kidney Injury in Patients With Covid-19 Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ain Shams University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ain Shams University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Recent different biomarkers of acute kidney injury (AKI) have been manufactured by&#xD;
      pharmaceutical industry. Studies proved that Neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin&#xD;
      (NGAL) and cystatin c are effective predictive biomarkers for early acute kidney injury in&#xD;
      septic patients and in children after cardiopulmonary bypass. This study hypothesize that&#xD;
      both cystatin c and Neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin can predict AKI in patients&#xD;
      with COVID-19 before elevation of serum urea and creatinine which may help early&#xD;
      interference.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Since December 2019, a novel coronavirus called SARSCoV-2 (severe acute respiratory syndrome&#xD;
      coronavirus 2) has caused an international outbreak of respiratory illness described as&#xD;
      COVID-19. Among 85 patients with COVID-19 an incidence of acute kidney injury was reported to&#xD;
      be 23%. The kidney histology from autopsies of six patients showed severe acute tubular&#xD;
      necrosis with macrophage and lymphocyte infiltration. Another important paper revealed&#xD;
      prominent acute proximal tubular injury, accumulation of peritubular erythrocyte and&#xD;
      glomerular fibrin microthrombi after autopsy. However, this kidney injury was not detected by&#xD;
      routine measures (creatinine and/or BUN) in some patients denoting subclinical kidney injury.&#xD;
      The pathophysiology of AKI associated with COVID-19 could be due to specific mechanisms such&#xD;
      as direct cell injury from viral entrance through highly expressed renal ACE2 receptors. Also&#xD;
      pro-inflammatory cytokines, an imbalanced renin-angotensin-aldosterone system and thrombotic&#xD;
      events are accused in renal damage. Non-specific mechanisms include hypovolemia, haemodynamic&#xD;
      changes, right heart failure, high levels of PEEP in mechanically ventilated patients,&#xD;
      nephrotoxic drugs and nosocomial infections. A significant association between kidney failure&#xD;
      and death was documented in five studies. Hypoxemia and impairment of gas exchange has been&#xD;
      identified as elements associated with AKI in patients with acute respiratory distress&#xD;
      syndrome (ARDS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Studies focusing on AKI with COVID-19 are needed urgently in order to identify the mechanism&#xD;
      of renal affection and to predict the risk of AKI. Pharmaceutical industries with academia&#xD;
      have made a lot of progress in the field of sensitive and specific preclinical biomarkers of&#xD;
      kidney injury. Neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin (NGAL) is composed of 178 amino&#xD;
      acids. this glycoprotein is reabsorbed in the proximal tubules after its filtration through&#xD;
      the glomeruli.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a mouse model of renal ischemia, NGAL gene was rapidly expressed and upregulated within 3&#xD;
      hours of injury. The NGAL mRNA level increased more than 1000-fold 24-48 hours after injury.&#xD;
      Thus, NGAL can be a useful tool to diagnose infection mediated AKI. Nonglycosylated Cystatin&#xD;
      C is a protein produced by nucleated cells at constant rate. It is easily filtered through&#xD;
      the glomeruli due to its positive charge at physiological pH and its low molecular weight.&#xD;
      Then, it is reabsorbed and completely catabolized in the proximal tubules. Use of serum&#xD;
      cystatin C as a marker of glomerular filtration rate (GFR) is well documented, and some&#xD;
      authors have suggested that it may be more accurate than serum creatinine for this purpose.&#xD;
      Complete evaluation of the clinical and laboratory picture of COVID-19 associated AKI is&#xD;
      crucial to design preventive strategies and to suggest targeted interventions&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 30, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>measure both cystatin c and Neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin every other day for 3 times (NGAL) as recent biomarkers in prediction of AKI in patients with COVID-19.</measure>
    <time_frame>one week starting from hospital admission</time_frame>
    <description>biochmical tests for detection of NGAL and Cystatin c in Covid 19 patients</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>development of acute kidney injury lipocalin (NGAL) to AKI severity and prognosis of AKI in patients with COVID-19 infection</measure>
    <time_frame>one week starting from day of admission</time_frame>
    <description>increased serum creatinine or urea</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">88</enrollment>
  <condition>Biochemical Markers ,NGAL,Cystatin c, Acute Kidneyinjury, Covid 19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>study group</arm_group_label>
    <description>blood sampling and measduring of serum NGAL and cystatin c every other day and serum urea and creatinine every day</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>serum NGAL and cystatin c</intervention_name>
    <description>measuring serum NGAL and cystatin c every other day in patients with covid 19 for one week and compare results to serum creatinine and urea and signs of acute kidney injury</description>
    <arm_group_label>study group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      serum refrigerated and divideded into 3 allicots for measurment of NGAL,cystatin c and&#xD;
      creatinine&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        adult patients from 18-65 diagnosed as covid 19 infection by nasaopharyngeal swap&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  person with the one of the following symptoms: fever and respiratory symptoms with&#xD;
             radiological findings of pneumonia compatible with COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Respiratory distress (≥ 30 breaths/ min);&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Oxygen saturation ≤ 93% at rest;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Arterial partial pressure of oxygen (PaO2)/ fraction of inspired oxygen (FIO2) ≤&#xD;
                  300.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Cases with chest imaging that shows obvious lesion progression within 24-48 hours&#xD;
                  &gt; 50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Respiratory failure and requiring mechanical ventilation;&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Shock;&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. other organ failure that requires ICU care.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients classified as mild corona virsus disease, patients with end-stage renal&#xD;
             disease (ESRD) or on chronic regular dialysis, presence of AKI and anuria at the time&#xD;
             of ICU admission, history of chronic kidney disease, severe urinary tract infection,&#xD;
             kidney malignancy, and renal transplantation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>sanaa wasfy</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>lecturer</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>sanaa wasfy, lecturer</last_name>
    <phone>01061262757</phone>
    <email>sanaawasfy@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>eman wasfy, lecturer</last_name>
    <phone>01001880174</phone>
    <email>emanwasfy@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ainshams hospitals</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <zip>11591</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>sanaa fFM wasfy, MD</last_name>
      <phone>00201061262757</phone>
      <email>sanaawasfy@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>wael SO osman, MD</last_name>
      <phone>00201282269727</phone>
      <email>waelbehairy@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sanaa Wasfy</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Cairo</city>
        <zip>11865</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>sanaa wasfy, lecturer</last_name>
      <phone>01061262757</phone>
      <email>sanaawasfy@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Wael S Abdelmegied, professor</last_name>
      <phone>01282269727</phone>
      <email>sanaawasfy@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Diao, C.H. Wang, R.S. Wang, Z.Q. Feng, Y.J. Tan, H.M. Wang, et al. ( 2020 ) Human kidney is a target for novel severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2[SARS-CoV-2] infection [preprint posted online April 10, . medRxiv doi:10.1101/2020.03.04.20031120 Xu S, Fu L, Fei J et al (2020) Acute kidney injury at early stage as a negative prognostic indicator of patients with COVID-19: a hospital-based retrospective analysis. medRxiv 2020.03.24.20042408. https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.03.24.20042408 Darmon M, Schortgen F, Leon R et al (2009) Impact of mild hypoxemia on renal function and renal resistive index during mechanical ventilation. Intensiv Care Med 35:1031-1038. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00134-008-1372-5 Darmon M, Schortgen F, Leon R et al (2009) Impact of mild hypoxemia on renal function and renal resistive index during mechanical ventilation. Intensiv Care Med 35:1031-1038. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00134-008-1372-5</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 30, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 30, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ain Shams University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sanaa Farag Mahmoud Wasfy</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>lecturer of aneathesia</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cystatins</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

