<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="287">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04586413</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Med_Asst 33</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04586413</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Post Acute COVID-19 Quality of Life (PAC-19QoL) Tool Development and Patient Registry (PAC-19QoLReg)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Post Acute COVID-19 Quality of Life (PAC-19QoL) Tool Development and Patient Registry (PAC-19QoLReg)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medialis Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medialis Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) is a newly emerged disease, caused by severe acute&#xD;
      respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2). The COVID-19 pandemic is having a large&#xD;
      impact on the mental and physical health of patients, yet data on the quality of life of&#xD;
      post-COVID-19 patients is lacking. There are currently no post-COVID-19 specific measures for&#xD;
      quality of life, particularly none which include the views of post-COVID-19 patients&#xD;
      themselves. This observational study will recruit participants to contribute their&#xD;
      preferences to the creation of a post-COVID-19 specific patient-reported measure on&#xD;
      post-COVID-19 quality of life. Participants will be split into three groups: those who were&#xD;
      not hospitalised; those who were hospitalised but not in intensive care units; and those who&#xD;
      were hospitalised and in intensive care units. The creation of this measure will form phase 1&#xD;
      of the study, with 30-60 participants (10-20 in each group above) recruited to complete&#xD;
      online surveys to find out their preferences of areas of life to include in such a measure.&#xD;
      This will involve 3 online surveys, 1) to ask which areas of life they feel are impacted and&#xD;
      how; 2) to find consensus about the areas to be included; 3) to weight the relevance of these&#xD;
      areas in relation to each other. In phase 2 recruitment will open to additional participants&#xD;
      and all participants will be asked to complete the finalised post-COVID-19 quality of life&#xD;
      measure once a month for 12 months, aiming for a minimum of 100 participants at this stage.&#xD;
      All participants will also be asked to complete a demographic questionnaire to inform the&#xD;
      analysis of the data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This observational study will be conducted in two phases:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase 1 - the development of a post-COVID-19 patient reported quality of life measure Phase 2&#xD;
      - the longitudinal completion of the quality of life tool by post-COVID-19 patients each&#xD;
      month for 12 months All participants will complete an online informed consent form and a&#xD;
      demographic questionnaire at the start of their involvement with the study Phase 1 The study&#xD;
      will recruit a minimum of 30 participants and a maximum of 60 participants, 10-20 across&#xD;
      three groups: those who were not hospitalised; those who were hospitalised but not in&#xD;
      intensive care units; and those who were hospitalised and in intensive care units.&#xD;
      Investigators will take the first 10-20 participants who match in each group. If contact is&#xD;
      received from participants but their group is already full they will be asked if they are&#xD;
      still be happy to participate in phase 2 and an offer to contact them when that commences&#xD;
      will be made.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Firstly, a novel method (Jandhyala Method) will be used to elicit post-COVID-19 patients'&#xD;
      preferences for a post-COVID-19 quality of life tool. Participants will do this by completing&#xD;
      an Awareness Round survey, this means using free-text responses to ask participants about the&#xD;
      areas of their lives impacted by COVID-19 and those areas they see as most important to their&#xD;
      quality of life. The research team will collate and code these free text responses then&#xD;
      create a comprehensive list of all of those deemed important to participants who will then be&#xD;
      sent a Consensus Round survey to ask how far they agree or disagree with the inclusion of&#xD;
      those items in a quality of life tool. Researchers will then collate this information, group&#xD;
      it into relevant domains and develop a weighting tool to be sent to participants to ask them&#xD;
      to rate the relevant importance of the different areas to be included, which will be used to&#xD;
      create weighted domain and item scores to be used in a final quality of life tool. We expect&#xD;
      for the Awareness round surveys to be completed within a one month time period and then two&#xD;
      weeks will be allocated for the research team to analyse and finalise the Consensus round&#xD;
      survey; the Consensus round survey will then be open for two weeks, with prompting to&#xD;
      participants after one week if not completed. The research team will then have a further two&#xD;
      weeks to complete the weighting tool and participants will be given a further two weeks to&#xD;
      complete this. At this stage the research team will have a further two weeks to finalise the&#xD;
      Post-COVID-19 quality of life tool and then phase 2 will begin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In summary:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Awareness round online survey (hosted on Survey Monkey) - asking for areas of life which&#xD;
           the participants feel have been impacted by COVID-19, including details and examples of&#xD;
           those impacts&#xD;
&#xD;
           a. The research team will collate and code these responses and generate a list of&#xD;
           statements based on the information provided by participants&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Consensus round online survey (hosted on Survey Monkey) - the list of statements will be&#xD;
           sent to participants and they will be asked to rate how far they agree or disagree with&#xD;
           the inclusion of these areas in a post-COVID-19 quality of life tool&#xD;
&#xD;
           a. The research team will collate this information, group it into relevant domains and&#xD;
           develop a weighting tool&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Weighting tool (online Microsoft excel template) - participants will be asked to weight&#xD;
           the individual items and domains for the finalised post-COVID-19 quality of life tool&#xD;
           using an online excel spreadsheet template a. The research team will use this&#xD;
           information to develop the finalised post-COVID-19 quality of life measure to be&#xD;
           completed by participants and to develop the system to score this tool Phase 2 At this&#xD;
           stage the recruitment will be re-opened for additional participants, including those&#xD;
           with a clinical diagnosis regardless of test status, aiming for a minimum of 100 and a&#xD;
           maximum of 5000 at this stage, though this will be subject to review. Recruitment will&#xD;
           remain open for time 1 surveys for one year, with a another year following this to gain&#xD;
           the full 12 months of data from participants, again subject to review. The finalised&#xD;
           post-COVID-19 quality of life measure will be hosted on a secure online system (Castor&#xD;
           EDC tm) and participants will be allocated an ID number. They will be asked to complete&#xD;
           this measure at monthly intervals for a period of 12 months. The research team will&#xD;
           analyse the changes over time within and between groups. Statistical methods for this&#xD;
           will be finalised when the measure has been completed at the end of Phase 1 by our&#xD;
           biostatistician.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 7, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Design of PAC19QoL Measure (Phase One)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The design and creation of a Post-COVID-19 Quality of Life Measure</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Completion of PAC19QoL Measure monthly for 12 months (Phase Two)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Participants in Phase Two will complete the newly designed Post-COVID-19 quality of life measure each month for 12 months</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Non-hospitalised post-COVID-19 patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>This cohort will have had a confirmed positive test for COVID-19 or antibody test confirming they had COVID-19 but they were not hospitalised for this</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hospitalised post-COVID-19 patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>This cohort will have a confirmed diagnosis of COVID-19 and been hospitalised but were not in an Intensive Care Unit</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intensive care post-COVID-19 patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>This cohort will have a confirmed diagnosis of COVID-19 and been hospitalised in an Intensive Care Unit</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No intervention - quality of life measure</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be part of the creation of a Post-COVID-19 quality of life measure if involved in Phase One. In Phase Two participants will complete this post-COVID-19 quality of life measure monthly for 12 months</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hospitalised post-COVID-19 patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Intensive care post-COVID-19 patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Non-hospitalised post-COVID-19 patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Participants will have a confirmed diagnosis of COVID-19 from either a test while infected&#xD;
        or an antibody test post infection for Phase One. Participants in Phase Two will have&#xD;
        either confirmed test/antibody test or clinical diagnosis of COVID-19&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Phase One&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant has had either a confirmed COVID-19 test while infected or a confirmed&#xD;
             COVID-19 antibody test post-infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is aged 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is capable of providing informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant can read, write and converse in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant can comply with the study schedule&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant does not have a confirmed COVID-19 test or antibody test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is aged under 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is not capable of giving informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is unable to read, write and converse in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is unable to comply with study schedule data collection&#xD;
&#xD;
        Phase Two&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant has had either a confirmed COVID-19 test while infected or a confirmed&#xD;
             COVID-19 antibody test post-infection or a clinical diagnosis of COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is aged 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is capable of providing informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant can read, write and converse in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant can comply with the study schedule&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant does not have a confirmed COVID-19 test or antibody test or clinical&#xD;
             diagnosis of COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is aged under 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is not capable of giving informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is unable to read, write and converse in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is unable to comply with study schedule data collection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ravi Jandhyala</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Medialis Ltd.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rose Watson</last_name>
    <phone>44(0)7879994131</phone>
    <email>rose@medialis.co.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Ravi Jandhyala</last_name>
    <phone>44(0)7717 448656</phone>
    <email>ravi@medialis.co.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medialis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oxford</city>
        <zip>OX16 0AH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ravi Jandhyala</last_name>
      <phone>44(0)1744865</phone>
      <email>ravi@medialis.co.uk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 19, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Covid19</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
  <keyword>Post-Covid19</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>No IPD</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

