<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="710">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04584411</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>arrhythmias in COVID-19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04584411</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Patterns of Arrhythmias and Conduction Block in COVID-19 Patients and Its Relation to Myocardial Injury Detected by Cardiac Magnetic Resonance</brief_title>
  <official_title>Patterns of Arrhythmias and Conduction Block in COVID-19 Patients and Its Relation to Myocardial Injury Detected by Cardiac Magnetic Resonance</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Detection of the incidence and types of arrhythmia and conduction block in COVID - 19&#xD;
      patients Detection and description of CMR patterns of myocardial injury in COVID-19 patients&#xD;
      with arrhythmias.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      COVID-19 has been declared a global pandemic by the World Health Organization and is&#xD;
      responsible for hundreds of thousands of deaths worldwide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Early reports from China suggested an overall cardiac arrhythmia incidence of 17% in patients&#xD;
      hospitalized for COVID-19. A higher arrhythmia rate (44%) was observed in patients with&#xD;
      COVID-19 admitted to the intensive care unit (ICU). However, details of the type and burden&#xD;
      of arrhythmias in this population have not been elucidated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Myocardial injury is common in patients with COVID-19, accounting for 7%-23% of reported&#xD;
      cases in Wuhan, China. Among COVID-related myocardial injury, etiologies vary and can include&#xD;
      myocarditis, myocardial infarction, sepsis-related myocardial injury, and/or stress induced&#xD;
      cardiomyopathy. Myocardial injury is associated with high risk of developing all types of&#xD;
      arrhythmia including atrial fibrillation, supraventricular tachycardia, ventricular&#xD;
      tachycardia, ventricular fibrillation, and variable degrees of heart block. Sudden cardiac&#xD;
      death was also reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The pathophysiology of COVID-19-related myocarditis is a combination of direct viral injury&#xD;
      and cardiac damage due to the host's immune response. Although the pathophysiology of&#xD;
      arrhythmias is still speculative, clinicians should provide prompt monitoring and treatment.&#xD;
      The long term impact of COVID-19 myocarditis remains unknown&#xD;
&#xD;
      Meanwhile, cardiac magnetic resonance (CMR) imaging is an integral test in the diagnosis of&#xD;
      myocardial injury. It can safely be used as a first-line diagnostic tool in the workup of&#xD;
      myocardial injury associated with COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investigators believe that proper diagnosis and management of COVID 19 related arrhythmias&#xD;
      and their etiology can lead to both in-hospital and long term reduction of morbidity and&#xD;
      mortality of this dangerous presentation of the disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the incidence of arrhythmia and conduction block in COVID-19 patients using Holter</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of myocardial injury in COVID-19 patients using CMR.</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cardiac Magnetic resonance imaging</intervention_name>
    <description>The following basic sequences will be conducted:&#xD;
Cine imaging using SSFP sequence for cardiac structure and function.&#xD;
Tissue characterization imaging, T1 and T2.&#xD;
Myocardial perfusion imaging.&#xD;
Late gadolinium enhancement.&#xD;
Diagnosis of myocarditis will be based on the modified Lake Louise criteria:&#xD;
T2-weighted: any of the following standard T2 sequences: regional high signal standard T2 sequences: global signal intensity ratio (myocardium/skeletal muscle) ≥2 T2 mapping: increased T2 relaxation times T1-weighted: any of the following late enhancement imaging: non-ischemic (subepicardial or mid myocardial) late enhancement native T1 mapping: increased T1 relaxation times or extracellular volume supportive criteria: signs of pericarditis: effusion or pericardial late enhancement regional or global wall motion abnormalities[5]</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study will include 50 confirmed COVID-19 patients admitted to Assiut University Heart&#xD;
        Centre and critical care unit, internal medicine department within the next 6 months&#xD;
        complaining of arrhythmias and heart block. These patients will be followed-up for a period&#xD;
        of 6 months after discharge.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. COVID 19 suspected patients presented by chest pain, dyspnea, chest discomfort &amp;/or&#xD;
             palpitations&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ECG changes (LBBB, PVCs, ventricular tachycardia, AF, atrial flutter, ST-T changes,&#xD;
             and conduction defects).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Increased inflammatory markers and / or Tropnin-I.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. COVID 19 patients without ECG changes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients known to have the same pattern of arrhythmia or conduction system defects&#xD;
             before Covid-19 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients contraindicated for CMR.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Doaa A Fouad, Doctorate</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alaa A El-Moniem, Doctorate</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mohamed A.H Abdelhafez, Doctorate</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Shimaa S Khider, Doctorate</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ahmed AR Hassaan, bachelor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Maram M Shafiq, student</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ahmed AR Hassaan, bachelor</last_name>
    <phone>+201068115040</phone>
    <email>ahmed.hassaan1994@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Doaa A Fouad, Doctorate</last_name>
    <phone>+201001085828</phone>
    <email>fouaddoaa@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pirzada A, Mokhtar AT, Moeller AD. COVID-19 and Myocarditis: What Do We Know So Far? CJC Open. 2020 May 28;2(4):278-285. doi: 10.1016/j.cjco.2020.05.005. eCollection 2020 Jul. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32691024</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>A. Bhatla et al., &quot;COVID-19 and Cardiac Arrhythmias,&quot; Hear. Rhythm, no. July, pp. 6-11, 2020, doi: 10.1016/j.hrthm.2020.06.016.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shirazi S, Mami S, Mohtadi N, Ghaysouri A, Tavan H, Nazari A, Kokhazadeh T, Mollazadeh R. Sudden cardiac death in COVID-19 patients, a report of three cases. Future Cardiol. 2021 Jan;17(1):113-118. doi: 10.2217/fca-2020-0082. Epub 2020 Jul 3.</citation>
    <PMID>32615807</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>B. Siripanthong et al., &quot;Since January 2020 Elsevier has created a COVID-19 resource centre with free information in English and Mandarin on the novel coronavirus COVID- company ' s public news and information website . Elsevier hereby grants permission to make all its COVID-19-r,&quot; no. January, 2020.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ferreira VM, Schulz-Menger J, Holmvang G, Kramer CM, Carbone I, Sechtem U, Kindermann I, Gutberlet M, Cooper LT, Liu P, Friedrich MG. Cardiovascular Magnetic Resonance in Nonischemic Myocardial Inflammation: Expert Recommendations. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018 Dec 18;72(24):3158-3176. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2018.09.072. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30545455</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 10, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 10, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ahmed Abdel Rahim Hassaan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>resident</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Block</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

