<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4304">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04508868</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-02079</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04508868</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment of Depressive Symptoms in Older Individuals in Isolation During Covid-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>CoviDep</acronym>
  <official_title>Behavioral Activation and Mental Imagery Delivered Via Telephone for the Treatment of Depressive Symptoms in Older Individuals in Isolation During Covid-19: A Randomized Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Uppsala University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Västmanland County Council, Sweden</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Uppsala University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This research study is designed to investigate the effects of a brief psychological&#xD;
      intervention for improving depressed mood in older individuals (65 years and older) in&#xD;
      isolation during the Coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic. The treatment is delivered by telephone&#xD;
      and consists of four weekly individual sessions. Two therapeutic methods are used in&#xD;
      combination during this intervention: Behavioral activation (BA) and Mental Imagery (MI). BA&#xD;
      involves identifying and scheduling enjoyable and meaningful activities to improve mood and&#xD;
      reduce social isolation. To enhance BA efficacy and adherence, MI is paired with BA as MI is&#xD;
      known to activate emotion and motivation. The MI intervention in this study involves having&#xD;
      participants imagine, in vivid sensory detail, engaging in some of the activities that are&#xD;
      scheduled during BA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 154 individuals will participate in the study. Half of the participants will be&#xD;
      randomised to start the intervention immediately, while the other half of the participants&#xD;
      will be randomized to a control group receiving the intervention after 4 weeks. This&#xD;
      procedure makes it possible to evaluate the effects of the treatment while not disadvantaging&#xD;
      participants randomized to the control group. Participants will be asked to fill in&#xD;
      questionnaires before, during (at the end of each intervention week), and after treatment (or&#xD;
      waiting period for the control group). Questionnaires will also be sent 1-, 3- and 6 months&#xD;
      after treatment to follow up on the results. A smaller group of participants (10-15) will be&#xD;
      asked to participate in a more detailed interview about how they experienced the treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus (COVID-19) has become a worldwide pandemic. The mortality rates are highest in&#xD;
      the older age groups, particularly in those 70 years and older. In Sweden, the government&#xD;
      urges people 70 years and older to limit close contact with other people and to stay at home&#xD;
      as much as possible, a strategy called social distancing. From previous epidemics, such as&#xD;
      the SARS-epidemic, we know that quarantine and isolation leads to psychological symptoms such&#xD;
      as stress, irritability, depressed mood and sleep problems. About 30% of those subjected to&#xD;
      isolation and quarantine become depressed, and in a study from Hong Kong during SARS there&#xD;
      was a nearly 32% increase of suicide rates among individuals 65 years and older. In Sweden,&#xD;
      depression among the elderly was a major public health concern before the covid-19-pandemic -&#xD;
      Major depression occurred in 5-15 % of the older population in Sweden, and one third of the&#xD;
      women and a fifth of the men 65 years and older reported subclinical depressive symptoms.&#xD;
      Several mental health experts raise concerns that there will be an increase of psychiatric&#xD;
      illness during and after covid-19, particularly among the elderly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Depression in older individuals can be treated with antidepressant medication, psychological&#xD;
      interventions and physical activity. However, the majority of the older individuals state&#xD;
      that they would prefer psychological treatments to medication, which poses a challenge during&#xD;
      COVID-19 as such treatments are often delivered face-to-face. Psychological treatments&#xD;
      delivered via the Internet are as efficacious as face-to-face, but only 3-4% of the&#xD;
      individuals 65 years and above in Sweden use digital applications that replace physical&#xD;
      healthcare visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Psychological treatments have been shown to work when delivered via telephone, and since&#xD;
      practically every household in Sweden has access to a telephone, the investigators believe&#xD;
      this could be a feasible option. Preferably, the treatment should be brief yet effective, and&#xD;
      easily accessible for healthcare professionals. One such treatment is brief behavioral&#xD;
      activation (BA), which is aimed at increasing enjoyable and meaningful activities to improve&#xD;
      mood. BA has been shown to be feasible in as few as four sessions. Depression is often&#xD;
      accompanied by low motivation and lack of energy, which can pose a problem when trying to&#xD;
      increase activities. One way of increasing motivation in BA and the likelihood of performing&#xD;
      the planned activities is to add mental imagery (MI), where some of these activities are&#xD;
      imagined in detail during the calls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, there are to the investigators knowledge no studies of telephone-delivered brief BA&#xD;
      for older individuals, no studies of the combination of BA and MI for depression in the&#xD;
      elderly, and no studies of either of these during pandemics with isolation or quarantine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the present study is to investigate the feasibility, effect and experience of&#xD;
      telephone-delivered Behavioral Activation with Mental Imagery for the treatment of depressive&#xD;
      symptoms in individuals 65 years and older during the covid-19-pandemic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Study terminated due to changes in government restrictions. Collected data to be presented as a&#xD;
    pilot study.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 31, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 23, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 23, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in depressive symptoms using the Montgomery-Asberg Depression Rating Scale, MADRS-S</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline; Intervention Week 1; Intervention Week 2; Intervention Week 3; Intervention Week 4; 1 month post-intervention; 3 months post-intervention; 6 months post-intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>MADRS-S is a nine-item questionnaire used to measure severity of depression. The score ranges from 0-54.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in depressive symptoms using the Geriatric Depression Rating Scale 15, GDS-15</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline; Intervention Week 4; 1 month post-intervention; 3 months post-intervention; 6 months post-intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>GDS-15 is a 15-item questionnaire used to identify depression in the elderly. The score ranges from 0-15.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in depressive symptoms using the Patient Health Questionnaire 9, PHQ-9</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline; Intervention Week 4; 1 month post-intervention; 3 months post-intervention; 6 months post-intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>PHQ-9 is a nine-item questionnaire used to identify depression as well as measuring severity of depression. The score ranges from 0-27.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in depression diagnosis assessed using the Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview, MINI</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline; Intervention Week 4.</time_frame>
    <description>MINI is a structured clinical interview used to assess the presence/absence of common psychiatric disorders.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in anxiety symptoms using the Generalized Anxiety Disorder 7-item, GAD-7</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline; Intervention Week 4; 1 month post-intervention; 3 months post-intervention; 6 months post-intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>GAD-7 is a seven-item questionnaire used to identify generalized anxiety disorder as well as measuring severity of anxiety symptoms. The score ranges from 0-21.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in behavioral activation using The Behavioral Activation for Depression Scale - Short Form, BADS-SF</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline; Intervention Week 4; 1 month post-intervention; 3 months post-intervention; 6 months post-intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>BADS-SF is a nine-item questionnaire used to measure changes in avoidance and activation. The score ranges from 0-54.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in health and disability using The WHO Disability Assessment Schedule 12-item, WHODAS</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline; Intervention Week 4; 1 month post-intervention; 3 months post-intervention; 6 months post-intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>WHODAS-12 is a 12-item questionnaire used to assess disability due to health conditions. The total score ranges from 0-48.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse and unwanted effects of the experimental intervention using the Negative Effects Questionnaire, NEQ</measure>
    <time_frame>Experimental Intervention Week 4.</time_frame>
    <description>NEQ is a 20-item questionnaire used to assess adverse and unwanted effects of psychological treatments.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mental imagery is assessed at baseline using the Plymouth Sensory Imagery Questionnaire, Psi-Q</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline; Intervention Week 4.</time_frame>
    <description>Psi-Q is a 35-item questionnaire assessing the vividness of mental imagery. In this study we plan to use the visual subscale with five items, with a total score ranging from 0-50.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">41</enrollment>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <condition>Depressive Symptoms</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Brief Behavioral Activation with Mental Imagery</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Four weekly sessions of Brief Behavioral Activation with Mental Imagery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Minimal Attention Control Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Four weeks with weekly follow-up calls.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Brief Behavioral Activation with Mental Imagery</intervention_name>
    <description>Session 1:&#xD;
Provide psychoeducation about depression; Provide treatment rationale for BA; Provide rationale and instructions for activity log; Plan activities for coming week.&#xD;
Session 2:&#xD;
Review activity log; Discuss life goals and values; Plan activities aligned with life goals and values for coming week; Provide rationale for Mental Imagery (MI); Go through MI-exercise for one of the planned activities.&#xD;
Session 3:&#xD;
Review activity log; Troubleshoot any problems carrying out activities; Plan activities aligned with life goals and values for coming week; Go through MI-exercise for one of the planned activities.&#xD;
Session 4:&#xD;
Review activity log; Troubleshoot any problems carrying out activities; Review treatment; Stress the importance of continuing to engage in activities aligned with life goals and values; Referral to additional services if necessary.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Brief Behavioral Activation with Mental Imagery</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Minimal Attention Control Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Weekly call with follow-up of psychiatric symptoms and assessment of suicide risk.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Minimal Attention Control Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residing in the County of Västmanland&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to telephone&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fluent in written and spoken Swedish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reporting clinically significant depressive symptoms above cut-of on depression&#xD;
             measures and/or by structured clinical interview&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe depression&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Elevated risk of suicide&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current substance use disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or previous manic/hypomanic episodes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current psychotic disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current diagnosis of dementia/major neurocognitive disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently receiving psychological therapy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mattias Damberg, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>County of Vastmanland and Uppsala University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Adult Psychiatric Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Västerås</city>
        <state>Västmanland</state>
        <zip>72189</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 10, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 29, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 29, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 31, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Depressive Symptoms</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Social Isolation</keyword>
  <keyword>Coronavirus</keyword>
  <keyword>Pandemic</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>De-identified outcome measure IPD will be shared upon reasonable requests from academic researchers.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Study protocol to be shared before data collection is completed&#xD;
Statistical Analysis Plan to be shared before data analysis begin</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Data will be shared upon reasonable requests assessed by the investigators.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

