<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4857">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03710746</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HD093598-01A1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03710746</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Project Health: Enhancing Effectiveness of a Dissonance-Based Obesity Prevention Program</brief_title>
  <acronym>PH</acronym>
  <official_title>Enhancing Effectiveness of a Dissonance-Based Obesity Prevention Program</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Oregon Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Drexel University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Oregon Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This project seeks to improve the effectiveness of a novel dissonance-based obesity&#xD;
      prevention program that has reduced future BMI gain and overweight/obesity onset by (a)&#xD;
      experimentally testing whether implementing it in single- versus mixed-sex groups, which&#xD;
      should increase dissonance-induction that contributes to weight gain prevention effects, and&#xD;
      (b) experimentally testing whether adding food response and attention training, which&#xD;
      theoretically reduces valuation of and attention for high-calorie foods, increases weight&#xD;
      gain prevention effects. This randomized trial would be the first to experimentally&#xD;
      manipulate these two factors in an effort to produce superior weight gain prevention effects.&#xD;
      A brief effective obesity prevention program that can be easily, inexpensively, and broadly&#xD;
      implemented to late adolescents at risk for excess weight gain, as has been the case with&#xD;
      another dissonance-based prevention program, could markedly reduce the prevalence of obesity&#xD;
      and associated morbidity and mortality.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Prevention is key for combating obesity, but few programs have prevented future increases in&#xD;
      BMI and onset of overweight/obesity, particularly during late adolescence when youth often&#xD;
      assume responsibility for dietary intake and exercise choices. One exception is a brief 6-hr&#xD;
      dissonance-based program (Project Health) wherein participants make small lasting incremental&#xD;
      lifestyle changes to dietary intake and exercise to reach energy balance, and discuss costs&#xD;
      of obesity, an unhealthy diet, and sedentary behavior, and benefits of leanness, a healthy&#xD;
      diet, and exercise, which prompts them to align their attitudes with their publicly displayed&#xD;
      behavior. These activities promote the internalization of health goals and executive control&#xD;
      over lifestyle behaviors. Late adolescents randomized to Project Health showed fewer&#xD;
      increases in BMI and a 41% and 43% reduction in overweight/obesity onset over 2-yr follow-up&#xD;
      compared to a version of the program lacking dissonance induction activities and an obesity&#xD;
      education condition. Project Health appears to be the first program to produce these key&#xD;
      obesity prevention effects relative to an alternative intervention, but it is critical to&#xD;
      increase effects. A dissonance-based prevention program was more effective when implemented&#xD;
      in single- versus mixed-sex groups, theoretically, because it promoted greater participation&#xD;
      in dissonance-inducing discussions. Aim 1a is to test whether the weight gain prevention&#xD;
      effects will be larger when Project Health is implemented in single-sex groups; the&#xD;
      investigators will randomize 450 17-20-year-olds to complete Project Health in female, male,&#xD;
      or mixed-sex groups, assessing outcomes at pretest, post-test, and 6, 12, 24, and 36-month&#xD;
      follow-ups. Aim 1b is to test whether greater participation in dissonance-inducing&#xD;
      discussions and group cohesion mediate the effect of condition on any superior weight gain&#xD;
      prevention effects. Adolescents who show greater fMRI-assessed reward and attention region&#xD;
      responsivity to food images exhibit elevated future weight gain, implying that reducing this&#xD;
      responsivity may reduce future weight gain. In a pilot trial, late adolescents who completed&#xD;
      go/nogo, stop-signal, and respond-signal computer training in which they repeatedly inhibit&#xD;
      responses to high-calorie foods and respond to low-calorie foods, and dot-probe and&#xD;
      visual-search computer tasks that train attention away from high-calorie foods and to&#xD;
      low-calorie foods, showed a greater reduction in reward and attention region responsivity to,&#xD;
      palatability rating of, and willingness to pay for, high-calorie foods, suggesting reduced&#xD;
      valuation and attentional bias, as well as greater fat loss over 1-yr follow-up versus&#xD;
      controls who completed the training with non-food images. Aim 2a is to test whether adding&#xD;
      food response and attention training to Project Health will produce larger weight gain&#xD;
      prevention effects. Participants in the 3 conditions will be randomized to complete response&#xD;
      and attention training for 25-mins after each of the 6-sessions with either food or non-food&#xD;
      images. Aim 2b is to test whether reduced palatability ratings of, willingness to pay, and&#xD;
      attentional bias for high-calorie foods mediate the effect of training condition on any&#xD;
      superior weight gain prevention effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the COVID-19 shelter-at-home order, the investigators will not measure in person only&#xD;
      outcomes including BodPod assessments, and height and weight measurement for BMI calculation&#xD;
      for all participants that have assessments due during this order. The investigators will&#xD;
      continue to conduct intervention groups that will be administered on a virtual platform.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 8, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participants will be masked to their response training condition. Outcomes assessors will be masked to both participant conditions.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Body Fat</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 2 months, 8 months, 14 months, 26 months, and 38 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in percentage of body fat (Not collected during COVID-19 shelter-at-home order)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Body Mass Index (BMI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 2 months, 8 months, 14 months, 26 months, and 38 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in BMI (Not collected during COVID-19 shelter-at-home order)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Weight Concerns Scale from the Eating Disorder Examination Questionnaire (EDE-Q)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 2 months, 8 months, 14 months, 26 months, and 38 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in weight concerns. Scale scores range from 0 to 42 with higher scores being indicative of higher weight concerns.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Beck Depression Index (BDI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 2 months, 8 months, 14 months, 26 months, and 38 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in depressive symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Eating Disorder Interview (EDDI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 2 months, 8 months, 14 months, 26 months, and 38 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in eating disorder symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">450</enrollment>
  <condition>Overweight and Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mixed Group, Food Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will be assigned to receive Project Health in mixed-sex groups and will complete the food-focused response and attention training intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mixed Group, Generic Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will be assigned to receive Project Health in mixed-sex groups and will complete the generic response and attention training intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Female Group, Food Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will be assigned to receive Project Health in female-only groups and will complete the food-focused response and attention training intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Female Group, Generic Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will be assigned to receive Project Health in female-only groups and will complete the generic response and attention training intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Male Group, Food Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will be assigned to receive Project Health in male-only groups and will complete the food-focused response and attention training intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Male Group, Generic Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will be assigned to receive Project Health in male-only groups and will complete the generic response and attention training intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Project Health</intervention_name>
    <description>A brief dissonance-based obesity prevention program delivered in six one-hour weekly sessions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Female Group, Food Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Female Group, Generic Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Male Group, Food Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Male Group, Generic Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Mixed Group, Food Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Mixed Group, Generic Response Training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Response and Attention Training</intervention_name>
    <description>Individualized, computerized response and attention training consisting of five separate tasks designed to increase inhibitory control to reduce overeating.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Female Group, Food Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Female Group, Generic Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Male Group, Food Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Male Group, Generic Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Mixed Group, Food Response Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Mixed Group, Generic Response Training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current at least moderate weight concerns (response of moderate, severe or extreme to&#xD;
             the presence of weight concerns question)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI between 20 and 30&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current diagnosis of anorexia nervosa, bulimia nervosa, or binge eating disorder&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>17 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>20 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eric M Stice, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Oregon Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Eric M Stice, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>541-484-2123</phone>
    <phone_ext>2199</phone_ext>
    <email>estice@ori.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Paul Rohde, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>541-484-2123</phone>
    <phone_ext>2120</phone_ext>
    <email>paulr@ori.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oregon Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Eugene</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97403</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kasie Cloud, MSW</last_name>
      <phone>541-484-2123</phone>
      <phone_ext>2999</phone_ext>
      <email>kcloud@ori.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Drexel University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Meghan L Burtyn, Ph.D.</last_name>
      <phone>215-553-7108</phone>
      <email>mlb34@drexel.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Laura D'Adamo</last_name>
      <phone>215-553-7161</phone>
      <email>lad374@drexel.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.ori.org</url>
    <description>Oregon Research Institute Website</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://drexel.edu/coas/academics/departments-centers/well-center/</url>
    <description>Drexel University: WELL Center Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 8, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 16, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 18, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 8, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 8, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 10, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>obesity</keyword>
  <keyword>overweight</keyword>
  <keyword>prevention</keyword>
  <keyword>adolescence</keyword>
  <keyword>dissonance</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The investigators will share all study data via the NICHD Data and Specimen Hub (DASH), which is the centralized resource for researchers to store and access data from NICHD-funded research studies to use for secondary research. All data, with the exception of video recordings of the participants in treatment (which cannot be effectively de-identified), will be provided.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_time_frame>After all follow-up assessments are completed and the main project papers are published, a dataset stripped of identifiers prior to release will be made available without cost to researchers and analysts.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Individuals wishing to view IPD can create a free user account at DASH and submit a request which will be reviewed and approved through the NICHD Dash administrator.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

