<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1298">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04668170</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RC31/20/0187</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04668170</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Predictive Immune Biomarkers of COVID-19 Pathogenesis to Influence Therapeutic Management</brief_title>
  <acronym>IMMUNOMARKCOV</acronym>
  <official_title>Identification of Predictive Immune Biomarkers Based on the Understanding of COVID-19 Pathogenesis to Influence Therapeutic Management</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Toulouse</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Toulouse</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Persons infected with Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome (SARS) SARS-CoV-2 vary in severity&#xD;
      from being asymptomatic to having fever, cough, sore throat, general weakness and fatigue and&#xD;
      muscular pain and in the most severe cases, severe pneumonia, acute respiratory distress&#xD;
      syndrome and sepsis potentially leading to death. Predictive markers of clinical worsening&#xD;
      after admission are lacking. COVID-19 immunopathogenesis and relevant therapeutic strategies&#xD;
      are still under investigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although viral shedding peaks during the first week of symptoms, reports show that clinical&#xD;
      deterioration often coincides with the development of host antiviral immune responses. The&#xD;
      inflammatory response to SARS-CoV-2 infection may underpin COVID-19 pathogenesis leading to&#xD;
      aberrant and excessive immune responses that may enter the pulmonary circulation in large&#xD;
      numbers and play an immune damaging role causing lung functional disability resulting in&#xD;
      clinical worsening. Therapeutic strategies using corticosteroids or biotherapies targeting&#xD;
      IL-6 may be valuable in some patients. Based on a better understanding of COVID-19&#xD;
      immunopathogenesis, the identification of predictive biomarkers early in the disease process&#xD;
      would be of outstanding interest to tailor prompt therapeutic interventions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On these bases, the present project aims to unravel, using innovative integrated multimodal&#xD;
      immunological approaches, immunologic predictive markers by finely characterizing from their&#xD;
      admission innate and adaptive immune responses in two well described cohorts of COVID-19&#xD;
      patients that are being collected in Toulouse (COVID-BioToul) and Bordeaux (COLCOV-19&#xD;
      BX).Those two biological cohorts are connected with two clinical cohorts in Toulouse and&#xD;
      Bordeaux in order to have a very well defined population of COVID-19 patients and their&#xD;
      clinical outcome. In both cohorts, investigators harvest and cryopreserve biological samples,&#xD;
      including plasma and peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs), on admission and&#xD;
      longitudinally from patients evolving or not toward severe forms of the disease in Bordeaux&#xD;
      and Toulouse University Hospitals and will allow to investigate primary and secondary&#xD;
      objectives. Moreover in the two centers, there are also two clinical outpatients cohorts of&#xD;
      healthcare workers attending dedicated clinics in the frame of their surveillance medical&#xD;
      program, which constitute groups of patients with benign forms of COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of IMMUNOMARK-COV is to define an applicable immune signature&#xD;
      predicting clinical worsening on COVID-19 patient admission in order to help physicians to&#xD;
      take informed therapeutic decisions able to modify early the course of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the early dynamics of SARS-CoV-2-specific cellular immunity in patients&#xD;
           followed longitudinally&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the dynamics of gd T cells during COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Transcriptomic analysis of discrete and functionally major T cell populations&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess SARS-CoV-2-specific humoral immunity in patients upon recovery&#xD;
&#xD;
      Identification of early predictive biomarkers of worsening of COVID-19 patients is of&#xD;
      paramount importance. This goal is expected to be achieved through the fine analysis of&#xD;
      circulating immune effectors, and their dynamics, in categories of patients with very&#xD;
      different clinical outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To date, management of clinical worsening relies mainly on supportive care in ICU, leading to&#xD;
      prolonged stay and saturation of facilities. Earlier therapeutic intervention based on&#xD;
      identification of robust predictive biomarkers should:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Help physicians to take therapeutic decisions&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Improve prognosis of patients that suffered from clinical worsening&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Prevent clinical worsening and transfer to ICU&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Improve the burden relying on ICU facilities in a setting of overflow&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Improve the prevention and management of COVID-19 patients to be able to face in a near&#xD;
           future several other waves of COVID-19 Furthermore, identification of immune effectors&#xD;
           implicated in tissular damages may also help to identify new therapeutic targets.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 5, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Immune signature on admission : phenotypic profile of blood T-cells</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Immune signature will be compared between COVID-19 patients according to their clinical characteristics and outcome, together with SARS-CoV2 viral shedding (known for every patient in the cohort) on samples harvested on admission: a phenotypic profiling of blood T-cells by multicolor FACS analysis (using 30+ color panels analyzed by multiparametric flow cytometry) assessing T cell subsets (classical CD4 or CD8 T-cells as well as unconventional gdT-cells and regulatory T cells) through the expression of a wide range of surface and intracellular markers.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Immune signature on admission : inflammatory cytokines</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Immune signature will be compared between COVID-19 patients according to their clinical characteristics and outcome, together with SARS-CoV2 viral shedding (known for every patient in the cohort) on samples harvested on admission: An analysis on plasma samples of concentration of a wide range of inflammatory cytokines such as IFNa, IFNb and IL-6.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dynamics of cellular immunity: CD4 and CD8 T cells</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0, Day 4, Day 8, Day 12, Day 30 (or in discharge)</time_frame>
    <description>On samples harvested longitudinally from patients, analysis of the relative magnitude and dynamic and polyfunctional profile of SARS-CoV-2 specific CD8 and CD4 T cell responses by analyzing the capacity of T cells to produce simultaneously a variety of cytokines such as IFNa, IFNb and IL-6, will be performed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dynamics of cellular immunity: gd T cells</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0, Day 4, Day 8, Day 12, Day 30 (or in discharge)</time_frame>
    <description>On samples harvested longitudinally from patients, dynamics of gd T cells will be performed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dynamics of cellular immunity: T cell transcriptomic analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0, Day 4, Day 8, Day 12, Day 30 (or in discharge)</time_frame>
    <description>On samples harvested longitudinally from patients, transcriptomic analysis of different types of T cells will be performed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dynamics of cellular immunity: humoral immunity</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0, Day 4, Day 8, Day 12, Day 30 (or in discharge)</time_frame>
    <description>On samples harvested longitudinally from patients, humoral immunity will be performed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">340</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>hospitalized patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>very well-defined population of COVID-19 patients with the following outcomes:&#xD;
Patients with severe disease requiring on admission ICU management for SARS, Non-severe hospitalized patients with secondary clinical worsening requiring ICU management, Non-severe hospitalized patients without clinical worsening requiring ICU management.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>healthcare workers</arm_group_label>
    <description>mildly symptomatic patients among healthcare workers attending outpatient dedicated clinics will be recruited</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Blood collection on admission and longitudinally</intervention_name>
    <description>Samples already collected on admission (day 0) and longitudinally (day 4, 8 12 and in discharge)</description>
    <arm_group_label>hospitalized patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Blood collection on their first consultation and 10 to 14 days later</intervention_name>
    <description>Samples already collected on consultation (D0) and 14 days later</description>
    <arm_group_label>healthcare workers</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients hospitalized or healthy workers for COVID-19&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For COVID-19 hospitalized patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) proven SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation to Toulouse clinical cohort&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having signed consent for inclusion in the Toulouse biobanks For COVID-19 healthcare&#xD;
             workers attending dedicated clinics&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PCR proven SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having signed consent for inclusion in the Toulouse biobanks&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in another interventional clinical study involving exploratory treatment&#xD;
             or blood sampling.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>110 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pierre DELOBEL, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Toulouse</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Pierre Delobel, MD PhD</last_name>
    <phone>561779585</phone>
    <phone_ext>0033</phone_ext>
    <email>delobel.p@chu-toulouse.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Bordeaux</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bordeau</city>
        <zip>33000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Isabelle PELLEGRIN, MD</last_name>
      <email>isabelle.pellegrin@chu-bordeaux.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Toulouse</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toulouse</city>
        <zip>31059</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Pierre Delobel, PU-PH</last_name>
      <phone>561779585</phone>
      <phone_ext>0033</phone_ext>
      <email>delobel.p@chu-toulouse.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Guillaume Martin-Blondel, MD PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 11, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 16, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>predictive medicine</keyword>
  <keyword>pathophysiology</keyword>
  <keyword>immune responses</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

