<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4806">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04704570</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>KA-20110</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04704570</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Remote Exercise Programs and Preventive Training in Asymptomatic Individuals</brief_title>
  <official_title>Investigation of The Effects of Remote Exercise Programs and Preventive Training on Muscle Architecture and Functional Level in Asymptomatic Individuals</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hacettepe University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hacettepe University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In recent years, it has been emphasized that preventive approaches are a less costly and more&#xD;
      effective way to treat a pathology. Primary preventive approaches should become widespread,&#xD;
      especially in problems with changeable risk factors such as spine health. Various preventive&#xD;
      approaches and exercise training seem to be an effective way to prevent the development of&#xD;
      back and neck pain. Again, in recent years, the pandemic process has increased the interest&#xD;
      and need for tele-rehabilitation. As a result, scientific research results on&#xD;
      tele-rehabilitation are needed as a necessity to adapt to the Covid-19 epidemic and the&#xD;
      globalizing world. The aim of the thesis study planned in this context is to investigate the&#xD;
      effectiveness of remote exercise applications on lumbar and cervical region muscle&#xD;
      architecture and functionality in asymptomatic individuals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 25, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 29, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 29, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of Muscle Thickness with Ultrasonography</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes, through study completion, an average of 8 weeks, Change from Baseline Muscle Thickness at 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Ultrasonography is used to evaluate the architectural properties of the muscle (such as thickness) in chronic painful musculoskeletal problems such as neck-back pain. Muscle architecture measurements with ultrasound will be carried out before and after the exercise program by the specialist radiology doctor who is blind to the results of the study using 3.5-10 MHz convex and linear probes (Soundcam Mobile Ultrasound Device). Within the scope of our study, the muscle thickness of the spinal muscles will be evaluated in the resting position.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of Pennation Angle with Ultrasonography</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes, through study completion, an average of 8 weeks, Change from Baseline Pennation Angle at 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Ultrasonography is used to evaluate the architectural properties of the muscle (such as pennation angle) in chronic painful musculoskeletal problems such as neck-back pain. Muscle architecture measurements with ultrasound will be carried out before and after the exercise program by the specialist radiology doctor who is blind to the results of the study using 3.5-10 MHz convex and linear probes (Soundcam Mobile Ultrasound Device). Within the scope of our study, the muscle pennation angle of the spinal muscles will be evaluated in the resting position.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of Functional Capacity Level with Functional Capacity Assessment Test</measure>
    <time_frame>20 minutes, through study completion, an average of 8 weeks, Change from Baseline Functional Capacity Level at 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Functional capacity assessment evaluates the effectiveness (time to completion, weight it can handle) of each activity that includes different activities for neck pain. The test includes the activities of &quot;repetitive reaching out, lifting objects overhead, working overhead&quot;. The validity and reliability of the Functional Capacity Assessment Test in individuals with chronic neck pain has been shown. The time individuals can complete the tests will be recorded.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of Functional Capacity Level with Back Performance Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>10 minutes, through study completion, an average of 8 weeks, Change from Baseline Functional Capacity Level at 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The back performance test (Back Performance Scale) is a test that evaluates the effectiveness of each activity that includes 5 different activities (socks test, gathering test, righting test, fingertip-floor test, carrying test). The Back Performance Scale test is scored between 0-15 points. An increase in score indicates a poor result.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes, through study completion, an average of 8 weeks, Change from Baseline quality of life at 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of life Assessment: SF-36 SF-36 is a scale consisting of 36 questions that evaluates the health status of the person with 8 sub-items (physical function, role limitations, social function, mental health, vitality, pain, general health). Scoring between 0-100 is made separately for each sub-item. It indicates good health as the score approaches 100. The validity and reliability study, Koçyiğit et al. Made by.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of Exercise Adaptation Assessment: Exercise Adaptation Rating Scale (EUAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes, through study completion, an average of 8 weeks, Change from Baseline Exercise Adaptation Assessment at 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>It will be evaluated using the Exercise Adherence Rating Scale (EARS), which evaluates exercise compliance (52). The first 2 parts of the scale consist of 6 questions and the third part consists of 10 questions. The first part is not included in the scoring and the maximum score to be obtained from two parts is 64. An increase in score indicates an increased adaptation to exercise. The Turkish validity and reliability study of the scale was conducted in 2019 by Korkmaz et al.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of Difficulty of Functional Activities and Exercise Program Satisfaction (GAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes, through study completion, an average of 8 weeks, Change from Baseline Difficulty of Functional Activities and Exercise Program Satisfaction at 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>VAS is used in measurement by digitizing the values that cannot be measured numerically. It is a line measurement, often on a 10 cm long horizontal or vertical line, where the person indicates his condition. Pain is used in the literature to evaluate satisfaction. In the satisfaction evaluation, it is evaluated as &quot;0: there was no decrease in complaints, I am not satisfied, 10: complaints completely disappeared, I am very satisfied&quot;. In the study, the functional activity difficulty will be evaluated as &quot;0: Being unable to do the activity, 10: Being able to do the activity at the level before the neck pain started&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of kinesiophobia</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes, through study completion, an average of 8 weeks, Change from Baseline kinesiophobia at 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Kinesophobia Assessment: Tampa Kinesophobia Scale (TCS) It is a 17-question scale that evaluates injury avoidance and fear of movement, and Kori et al. developed by. The Turkish version is from Tunca-Yılmaz et al. Made by. Its scoring is scored with &quot;1 = Strongly disagree, 4 = Strongly agree&quot;. The score is calculated by reversing items 4, 8, 12 and 16. The total score is between 17 and 68. It is understood that the higher the score, the higher the kinesiophobia. A total score of more than 37 is considered to be a high degree of kinesophobia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy People</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Remotely Exercises 3 times a week, 8 weeks remotely (with video) spinal stabilization exercises</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Face to Face Exercises 3 times a week, 8 weeks face to face (in clinic) spinal stabilization exercises</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exercise</intervention_name>
    <description>Spinal stabilization exercise</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have not experienced back and neck pain for at least 3 months,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Between the ages of 18-55,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Literate,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are capable of understanding exercises (Montreal Cognitive Assessment&#xD;
             Scale (MOCA) (19) total score&gt; 21) will be included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having been diagnosed with cervical or lumbar region pathologies,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cervical radiculopathy, thoracic outlet syndrome,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Malignant condition,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have systemic diseases such as neurological, psychological, cardiovascular,&#xD;
             rheumatology and loss of function due to these diseases,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous surgery history in the spine and upper extremity, including the cervical and&#xD;
             lumbar region,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fracture in the spine and upper extremity, including the cervical and lumbar region,&#xD;
             with an inflammatory history,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute infection,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Continuing another rehabilitation program,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who do not agree to participate in the study and do not give written&#xD;
             consent will be excluded from the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yasemin Özel Aslıyüce</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ankara</city>
        <state>Sıhhiye</state>
        <zip>06100</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Özlem Ülger, Proffessor</last_name>
      <phone>05324027876</phone>
      <email>ozlemulger@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hacettepe University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Yasemin Özel Aslıyüce</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Research Assistant, Physiotherapist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>spinal stabilization exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>tele-rehabilitation</keyword>
  <keyword>muscle architecture</keyword>
  <keyword>functional level</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

