<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="954">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04668469</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Re96.2020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04668469</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Ivermectin for Treatment and Prophylaxis of COVID-19 Pandemic</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy and Safety of Ivermectin for Treatment and Prophylaxis of COVID-19 Pandemic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Benha University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Benha University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Up-to-date, there is no recognized effective treatment or vaccine for the&#xD;
      treatment of coronavirus disease (COVID-19) that emphasize urgency around distinctive&#xD;
      effective therapies. This study aims to evaluate the anti-parasitic medication efficacy&#xD;
      &quot;Ivermectin&quot; plus standard care (Azithromycin, Paracetamol, vitamin C, Zinc, Lactoferrin,&#xD;
      Acetylcystein, prophylactic or therapeutic anticoagulation if D-dimer &gt; 1000 and/or steroids)&#xD;
      in the treatment of mild/moderate and severely ill cases with COVID 19 infection versus&#xD;
      Hydroxychloroquine plus standard care, as well as Ivermectin prophylaxis of health care and/&#xD;
      or household contacts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subject and methods: 600 subjects; 400 symptomatic confirmed COVID-19 patients and 200 health&#xD;
      care and household contacts distributed over 6 groups; Group I: 100 patients with&#xD;
      Mild/Moderate COVID-19 infection received a 4-days course of Ivermectin plus standard care;&#xD;
      Group II: 100 patients with mild/moderate COVID-19 infection received hydroxychlorquine plus&#xD;
      standard care; Group III: 100 patients with severe COVID-19 infection received Ivermectin&#xD;
      plus standard of care; Group IV: 100 patients with Severe COVID-19 infection received&#xD;
      hydroxychlorquine plus standard care. Routine laboratory investigations and real time-&#xD;
      polymerase chain reaction (rt-PCR) were reported before and after initiation of treatment.&#xD;
      Group V stick to personal protective equipment (PPE) plus Ivermectin, and Group VI stick to&#xD;
      PPE only and both groups were followed for two weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      I-Technical design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design: interventional multicenter double blind randomized controlled clinical trial&#xD;
      (RCCT) study Study period: The study was carried out from 8th June to 15th September 2020.&#xD;
&#xD;
      *Study population (Sampling Design and Sample Size):&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study was conducted on 600 subjects; 400 patients and 200 health care and household&#xD;
      contacts that were divided into 6 groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Group I: 100 patients with Mild/Moderate COVID-19 infection received a 4-days course of&#xD;
           Ivermectin 400 mcg/kg body weight maximum 4 tablets (6mg / tablet) once daily dose&#xD;
           before breakfast plus standard care as issued by Egyptian protocol of COVID-19 treatment&#xD;
           (Azithromycin 500mg once daily/5days, Paracetamol 500mg as needed, vitamin C 1gm once&#xD;
           daily, Zinc 50 mg once daily, Lactoferrin 100mg sachets/12 hours &amp; Acetylcystein&#xD;
           200mg/8hours &amp; prophylactic or therapeutic anticoagulation if D-dimer &gt; 1000), (MOH&#xD;
           version 30 May 2020).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Group II: 100 patients with mild/moderate COVID-19 infection received hydroxychlorquine&#xD;
           (400 every 12 hours for one day followed by 200 mg every 12 hours for 5 days) plus&#xD;
           standard care (Azithromycin 500mg once daily/5days, Paracetamol 500mg as needed, vitamin&#xD;
           C 1gm once daily, Zinc 50 mg once daily, Lactoferrin 100mg sachets /12 hours &amp;&#xD;
           Acetylcystein 200mg sachets /8 hours &amp; prophylactic or therapeutic anticoagulation if&#xD;
           D-dimer &gt; 1000) as issued by Egyptian protocol of COVID-19 treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Group III: 100 patients with severe COVID-19 infection received a 4 days course of&#xD;
           Ivermectin 400 mcg/kg body weight maximum 4 tablets (6mg / tablet) once daily dose&#xD;
           before breakfast plus standard care (Azithromycin 500mg once daily/5days, Paracetamol&#xD;
           500mg as needed, vitamin C 1gm once daily, Zinc 50 mg once daily, Lactoferrin 100mg&#xD;
           sachets/ 12 hours &amp; Acetylcystein 200mg sachets/ 8 hours &amp; prophylactic or therapeutic&#xD;
           anticoagulation if D-dimer &gt; 1000) as issued by Egyptian protocol of COVID-19 treatment&#xD;
           for severe patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Group IV: 100 patients with Severe COVID-19 infection received hydroxychlorquine (400 mg&#xD;
           every 12 hours for one day followed by 200 mg every 12 hours for 9 days) plus standard&#xD;
           care (Azithromycin 500mg once daily/5days, Paracetamol 500mg as needed, vitamin C 1gm&#xD;
           once daily, Zinc 50 mg once daily, Lactoferrin 100mg/12 hours &amp; Acetylcystein 200mg&#xD;
           sachets/ 8 hours &amp; prophylactic or therapeutic anticoagulation if D-dimer &gt; 1000) as&#xD;
           issued by Egyptian protocol of COVID-19 treatment for severe ill patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Group V: 100 health care and or household patients' contacts received a prophylactic&#xD;
           dose of ivermectin 400 micrograms/kg single oral dose before breakfast to be repeated&#xD;
           after one week in addition to PPE (personal protective equipment).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Group VI: 100 health care and or household patients' contacts received only PPE&#xD;
           (personal protective equipment).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study methods and Tools:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients were subjected to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Full history and clinical examination taking, and laboratory assessment including liver&#xD;
           function tests, kidney function tests, full blood count, serum Ferritin level.&#xD;
           C-reactive protein (CRP), D-dimer, rt- PCR for COVID-19 and, radiological assessments&#xD;
           including CT chest.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Follow up: Patients were followed up daily clinically and by laboratory assessment for&#xD;
           two weeks but radiological assessment after two weeks or until one of the endpoints is&#xD;
           reached. Follow up the duration of treatment, swab conversion, hospital stay, the&#xD;
           clinical and radiological improvement was recorded.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 8, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 30, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 15, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A multicenter randomized double blind controlled clinical trial (RCCT) study design was carried out on on 600 subjects; 400 patients and 200 health care and household contacts at Benha and Kafrelsheikh University Hospitals.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Randomization A Block randomization method was used to randomize the study participants into two groups that result in equal sample sizes. This method was used to ensure a balance in sample size across groups over time and keep the numbers of participants in each group similar at all times.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>number of participants with improvement of clinical condition (symptoms and signs)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>improvement of dyspnea using mMRC scale, disappearance of fever using thermometer, Fatigue using Fatigue Assessment Scale (FAS), and improvement of Oxygen saturation using pulse oximeter.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction of recovery time, hospital stay days and mortality rate</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>recording days of clinical improvement (recovery time) , hospital stay days and mortality rate</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>improvement of laboratory investigations and 2 consecutive negative PCR tests taken at least 48 hours apart.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>improvement of laboratory investigations (CBC, CRP, Ferritin, D-dimer) and 2 consecutive negative PCR tests taken at least 48 hours apart.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ivermectin plus standard care in Mild/Moderate COVID-19 (Group I)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>100 patients with Mild/Moderate COVID-19 (Coronavirus disease) infection received a 4-days course of Ivermectin 400 mcg/kg body weight maximum 4 tablets (6mg / tablet) once daily dose before breakfast plus standard of care as issued by Egyptian protocol of COVID-19 treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>hydroxychlorquine plus standard care in Mild/Moderate COVID-19 (Group II)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>100 patients with mild/moderate COVID-19 infection received hydroxychlorquine (400 every 12 hours for one day followed by 200 mg every 12 hours for 5 days) plus standard care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ivermectin plus standard care and steroids in Sever COIVD-19 (Group III)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>100 patients with severe COVID-19 infection received a 4 days course of Ivermectin 400 mcg/kg body weight maximum 4 tablets (6mg / tablet) once daily dose before breakfast plus standard care and steroids</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>hydroxychlorquine plus standard care and steroids in Sever COVID-19 (Group IV)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>100 patients with Severe COVID-19 infection received hydroxychlorquine (400 mg every 12 hours for one day followed by 200 mg every 12 hours for 9days) plus standard care and steroids</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ivermectin plus personal protective measures in COVID-19 prophylaxis (Group V)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>100 health care and or household contacts received a prophylactic dose of ivermectin 400 micrograms/kg single oral dose before breakfast to be repeated after one week in addition to Personal Protective Measures ( (hand hygiene, social distancing measures, avoiding touching the eyes, nose and mouth, Masks, respiratory etiquette, and self-isolation)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Personal protective measures in COVID-19 prophylaxis (Group VI)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>100 health care and or household contacts received only Personal Protective Measures (hand hygiene, social distancing measures, avoiding touching the eyes, nose and mouth, Masks, respiratory etiquette, and self-isolation)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ivermectin</intervention_name>
    <description>evaluation of the anti-parasitic medication efficacy &quot;Ivermectin&quot; (Ivermectin 400 mcg/kg body weight maximum 4 tablets (6mg / tablet) once daily dose before breakfast) plus standard care in the treatment of mild/moderate cases with COVID 19 infection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ivermectin plus personal protective measures in COVID-19 prophylaxis (Group V)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Ivermectin plus standard care and steroids in Sever COIVD-19 (Group III)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Ivermectin plus standard care in Mild/Moderate COVID-19 (Group I)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Azithromycin</other_name>
    <other_name>Paracetamol</other_name>
    <other_name>Vitamin C</other_name>
    <other_name>Zinc</other_name>
    <other_name>Lactoferrin</other_name>
    <other_name>Acetylcystein</other_name>
    <other_name>prophylactic or therapeutic anticoagulation if D-dimer &gt; 1000</other_name>
    <other_name>systemic steroid if needed</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hydroxychloroquine</intervention_name>
    <description>evaluation of hydroxychlorquine (400 every 12 hours for one day followed by 200 mg every 12 hours for 5 days) plus standard care in the treatment of mild/moderate cases with COVID 19 infection</description>
    <arm_group_label>hydroxychlorquine plus standard care and steroids in Sever COVID-19 (Group IV)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>hydroxychlorquine plus standard care in Mild/Moderate COVID-19 (Group II)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Azithromycin</other_name>
    <other_name>Paracetamol</other_name>
    <other_name>Vitamin C</other_name>
    <other_name>Zinc</other_name>
    <other_name>Lactoferrin</other_name>
    <other_name>Acetylcystein</other_name>
    <other_name>prophylactic or therapeutic anticoagulation if D-dimer &gt; 1000</other_name>
    <other_name>systemic steroid if needed</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>personal protective Measures</intervention_name>
    <description>evaluation of personal protective Measures (hand hygiene, social distancing measures, avoiding touching the eyes, nose and mouth, wearing masks, and self-isolation) only as a prophylaxis for health care and or household contacts' from COVID-19 disease</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ivermectin plus personal protective measures in COVID-19 prophylaxis (Group V)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Personal protective measures in COVID-19 prophylaxis (Group VI)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: Patients who have been diagnosed with COVID-19 infection with at least&#xD;
        one positive rt-PCR result from nasopharyngeal/oropharyngeal swab, then subdivided patients&#xD;
        into mild, moderate and sever stages.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy and lactation, and critical cases defined as: occurrence of respiratory&#xD;
             failure requiring mechanical ventilation; Presence of shock; other organ failure that&#xD;
             requires monitoring and treatment in the ICU, [20].&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with hydroxychloroquine contra-indications: corrected QT interval (QTc) &gt; 500&#xD;
             m/sec, myasthenia gravis, porphyria, retinal pathology, epilepsy, glucose-6-phosphate&#xD;
             dehydrogenase (G6PD) deficiency, allergy to 4-aminoquinolone, chronic heart, kidney or&#xD;
             liver disease, and arrhythmias.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patient demonstrates worsening of symptoms; radiological progression with&#xD;
             virologically persistence within at least 7 days of the therapeutic evaluation period&#xD;
             of the study after exclusion of cytokine storm was considered as a clinical failure&#xD;
             and was shifted to the other management protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment was terminated at any time by a multidisciplinary team if a serious side&#xD;
             effect occurred, which was attributed to the medications used ,e.g. cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia, deteriorated liver or kidney function or unfortunately patient died.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ahmed G Elgazzar, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Peofessor of Chest diseases, Faculty of Medicine, Benha University, Egypt.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Benha Faculty of Medicine, Benha University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Banhā</city>
        <state>Qaluopia</state>
        <zip>13518</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 11, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 16, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Benha University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ahmed G Elgazzar</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Chest diseases and Tuberculosis</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Ivermectin</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Hydroxychloroquine</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acetaminophen</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ascorbic Acid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Zinc</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Azithromycin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hydroxychloroquine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ivermectin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lactoferrin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fibrin fragment D</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

