<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3836">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04356833</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>132151</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04356833</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Nebulised Rt-PA for ARDS Due to COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>PACA</acronym>
  <official_title>A Pilot, Open Label, Phase II Clinical Trial of Nebulised Recombinant Tissue-Plasminogen Activator (Rt-PA)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University College, London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University College, London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Some patients infected with COVID-19 require hospitalisation and develop patients a severe&#xD;
      form of a lung disease called respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). In these patients, the&#xD;
      lungs become severely inflamed because of the virus. The inflammation causes fluid from&#xD;
      nearby blood vessels to leak into the tiny air sacs in the lungs, making breathing&#xD;
      increasingly difficult. This fluid forms small clots in the air sacs, creating a barrier&#xD;
      until the cells regenerate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In some patients, this clot does not disappear in a timely fashion or interferes with the&#xD;
      development of the new cells. Furthermore, the small clots in the air sacs obstruct the air&#xD;
      and oxygen getting deep into the lungs, interfering with proper ventilation. The trial will&#xD;
      recruit patients with COVID-19 induced ARDS. Eligible patients (or if patients lack capacity,&#xD;
      their legal representative) will be provided with an information sheet and informed consent&#xD;
      will be sought. Eligibility will be mainly assessed via routine clinical assessments.&#xD;
      Patients will receive a nebulised version of a type of drug called tissue plasminogen&#xD;
      activator (rt-PA) that is inhaled using a nebuliser. This is normally a drug used to break&#xD;
      down blood clots. In this situation though, it might be useful for stopping clots forming in&#xD;
      the lungs, because these might lead to even more difficulties with breathing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first 12 consented patients will receive nebulised rt-PA in addition to standard of care&#xD;
      (SOC). The second group of 12 patients will receive SOC alone as a comparison. To evaluate&#xD;
      efficacy, the improvement of oxygen levels over time and safety will be be monitored&#xD;
      throughout. Blood samples will be taken to measure markers of clotting and inflammation in&#xD;
      both groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      From the end of the treatment phase (after Day 3) both groups will be followed up in&#xD;
      accordance with SOC.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase II, open label, single centre, uncontrolled, repeated dose, pilot trial of&#xD;
      nebulised rt-PA in patients with COVID-19 ARDS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will recruit patients requiring either IMV or NIV. Eligible patients (or if&#xD;
      patients lack capacity, their legal representative) will be provided with an information&#xD;
      sheet and informed consent will be sought. Eligibility will be assessed via routine clinical&#xD;
      assessments, which may have been done prior to consent. The only exceptions are a pregnancy&#xD;
      test (blood or urine), and possibly any assessments that were not done as per routine care.&#xD;
      These must be done following consent, and all screening assessments must have been done&#xD;
      during the 24-hour period before dosing with rt-PA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first 12 consented patients will receive nebulised rt-PA in addition to SOC. The second&#xD;
      group of 12 patients will receive SOC alone as observational arm, to ensure that any changes&#xD;
      are not entirely due to disease resolution. Within each group 6 patients will be receiving&#xD;
      IMV and another six will be receiving NIV.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A statistically powered randomised controlled trial (RCT) would be ideal to define the&#xD;
      magnitude of benefit and impact on overall survival and is the typical design in patients&#xD;
      with ARDS. Although there is clinical data on the safety of nebulised rt-PA, but there is no&#xD;
      clinical data in this clinical condition to facilitate a sample size calculation. There is&#xD;
      data from a small RCT that has used another fibrinolytic agent, but the doses are not&#xD;
      comparable. When a patient is randomised to receive no treatment, this precludes&#xD;
      participation in other interventional studies which might decrease the risk of mortality. The&#xD;
      most recent figures suggest a 50% mortality in patients receiving IMV there is 50% mortality.&#xD;
      Currently there is a concerted effort to introduce multiple therapies based on our&#xD;
      understanding of the pathophysiologic basis of disorder. Further, if this pilot study shows&#xD;
      significant effect in a subset of patients, there would be justification to progress to a&#xD;
      statistically powered RCT. In the event of major adverse drug reactions or minor improvement&#xD;
      in the oxygenation as assessed by PaO2/FiO2 , there are minimal gains to be had with a larger&#xD;
      randomised control study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For patients in the rt-PA group, 10 mg of rt-PA dissolved in 5 ml of diluent will be given&#xD;
      every 6 hrs for 66 hrs. Dose modifications will not be permitted. Efficacy will be assessed&#xD;
      by the monitoring of arterial oxygen saturation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety monitoring will be performed by assessment of the incidence and severity of bleeding&#xD;
      events, and by the monitoring of plasma fibrinogen levels and routine coagulation parameters.&#xD;
      Additional samples will be taken for exploratory assessment of potential biomarkers,&#xD;
      including (but not restricted to) PAI- 1, alpha 2 antiplasmin and a range of inflammatory&#xD;
      cytokines and coagulation proteins. All other monitoring will be done as per SOC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      From the end of the treatment phase (after Day 3) both groups will be followed up in&#xD;
      accordance with SOC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although there is extensive experience with the use of nebulised rt-PA in the context of the&#xD;
      underlying inflammation, safety measures been included. A gap of 24hrs will be maintained&#xD;
      between first and second patient. At 24hrs if patient 1 has no evidence of major pulmonary&#xD;
      bleeding suggesting exaggerated alveolar fibrinolysis and no evidence of fibrinogen reduction&#xD;
      of more than 50%, suggestive of systemic absorption a second patient will be dosed. Both&#xD;
      patients will be evaluated for 72 hrs for major pulmonary bleeding and if no bleeding is&#xD;
      noticed than the rest of the cohort can be recruited after the review of the safety data by&#xD;
      the trial management group comprised of the investigators. If there are any concerns with the&#xD;
      data this will be referred to the DMC for review. If the safety profile is acceptable, dosing&#xD;
      of the third and subsequent patients in the rt-PA group will resume with no required interval&#xD;
      between patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Efficacy will be described as a relative improvement in PaO2/FiO2 (or SaO2/FiO2) ratio&#xD;
      assessed at day 5 and day 7 after start of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A Data Monitoring Committee (DMC) will be set-up to review safety data within the trial along&#xD;
      with the final study results and advise on progressing from a pilot study to a randomised&#xD;
      control trial based on the safety and efficacy data that is collected. The DMC will receive&#xD;
      weekly reports on bleeding complications, both major and minor along with fibrinogen levels.&#xD;
      If at any time a patient has major pulmonary bleeding, further dosing of patients will be&#xD;
      stopped and an adhoc DMC review will be arranged before resuming dosing (see section 12.2&#xD;
      Data Monitoring Committee).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 22, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 14, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 14, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>phase II, open label, single centre, uncontrolled, repeated dose, pilot trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>treatment efficacy - Percentage change in PaO2/FiO2 ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>144 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage change in PaO2/FiO2 ratio from baseline and to day 5 (96 hrs ± 2 hrs) post treatment and day 7 (144 hrs ± 4hrs) in the groups receiving rt-PA</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety as measured by bleeds</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence and severity of major bleeding events</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety as measured by other (non-bleed related) adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence and severity of adverse events&#xD;
More than 1 treatment-emergent serious adverse event (SAE) during and up to 24 hours of the treatment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety as measured by fibrinogen levels</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Decrease in fibrinogen levels over 72 hrs post initiation of treatment (&gt;50%).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute change in PaO2/FiO2 ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Absolute change in PaO2/FiO2 ratio post treatment assessed at day 5 (96 hrs ± 2 hrs) and day 7 (144 hrs ± 4hrs)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in respiratory compliance</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in respiratory compliance from baseline and absolute values at day 5 (96 hrs ± 2 hrs) and day 7 (144 hrs ± 4hrs), as measured by PIP (Peak inspiratory pressure) minus PEEP (Positive end-expiratory pressure) at each timepoint</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical status as determined by a 7 point ordinal scale</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical status as assessed by a 7-point WHO ordinal scale at baseline and daily up to day 7. Points on the scale are:&#xD;
Death&#xD;
Hospitalized, on invasive mechanical ventilation or ECMO&#xD;
Hospitalized, on non-invasive ventilation or high flow oxygen devices&#xD;
Hospitalized, requiring low flow supplemental oxygen&#xD;
Hospitalized, not requiring supplemental oxygen - requiring ongoing medical care (COVID-19 related or otherwise)&#xD;
Hospitalized, not requiring supplemental oxygen - no longer requires ongoing medical care&#xD;
Not hospitalized</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sequential Organ Failure Assessment (SOFA) score</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Mean daily Sequential Organ Failure Assessment (SOFA) score at baseline through up to day 7 (done daily)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Follow up period - oxygen free days</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of oxygenation free days, up to 28 days or death or discharge, whichever occurs first.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Follow up period - ventilator free days</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>In follow up period, ventilator free days, up to 28 days or death or discharge, whichever occurs first.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Follow up period - intensive care stay</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>In follow up period, intensive care stay, up to 28 days or death or discharge, whichever occurs first.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>New oxygen via ventilation use - incidence</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of either new oxygen use via ventilation in the first 28 days. These include non-invasive ventilation or high flow oxygen devices</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>New oxygen via ventilation use - duration</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Total duration of new oxygen use via ventilation in the first 28 days. These include non-invasive ventilation or high flow oxygen devices.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of new mechanical ventilation use</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of new mechanical ventilation use during in the first 28 days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of new mechanical ventilation use</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of new mechanical ventilation use during in the first 28 days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>In hospital mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>In hospital mortality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>nebulised recombinant tissue-Plasminogen Activator (rt-PA)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>For patients in the rt-PA group, 10 mg of rt-PA dissolved in 5 ml of diluent will be given every 6 hrs for 66 hrs, in addition to standard of care for COVID-19 acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). 6 patients will be receiving Invasive mechanical ventilation and another six will be receiving Non Invasive ventilation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard of care for COVID-19 acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). 6 patients will be receiving Invasive mechanical ventilation and another six will be receiving Non Invasive ventilation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>nebulised recombinant tissue-Plasminogen Activator (rt-PA)</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients in the rt-PA group will receive the first dose as soon as possible after registration. 10mg rt-PA in 5mL diluent will be administered by nebulisation every 6 hours for 66 hours, resulting in a total dose of 120mg.</description>
    <arm_group_label>nebulised recombinant tissue-Plasminogen Activator (rt-PA)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with COVID-19 confirmed by PCR&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ≥16 years and &lt; 70 yrs&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Willing and able to provide written informed consent or where patient doesn't have&#xD;
             capacity, consent obtained from a legal representative&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients on IMV must meet both the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. PaO2/FiO2 of ≤ 300 (definition of ARDS)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Intubated &gt; 24 hrs but less than seven days&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients on NIV must meet all the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. PaO2/FiO2 ≤ 300 or equivalent imputed by non-linear calculation from SpO2/FiO2&#xD;
                  (see look-up table in appendices)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. In-patient &gt;24 hours and being actively treated&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. On non-invasive ventilator support with continuous positive airway pressure&#xD;
                  (CPAP) OR high flow oxygen (HFO &gt;15L/min) with venturi or mask&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Females who are pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients receiving anticoagulation with therapeutic doses&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Concurrent involvement in another experimental investigational medicinal product&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Known allergies to the IMP or excipients of IMP&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. A pre-existing bleeding disorder (e.g. severe haemophilia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pre-existing severe cardiopulmonary disease (e.g. incurable lung cancer, severe&#xD;
             chronic obstructive lung disease, cardiomyopathy, heart failure or impaired&#xD;
             contractility &lt;estimated 40% LVEF or RVEF )&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Fibrinogen &lt; 2.0 g/L at time of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients considered inappropriate for critical care (prior decision re ceiling of care&#xD;
             established)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients with active bleeding in the preceding 7 days&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients who in the opinion of the investigator are not suitable&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mark Phillips</last_name>
    <phone>0208 016 8111</phone>
    <email>mark.phillips@nhs.net</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Royal Free Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mark Phillips</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Pratima Chowdary</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 28, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 28, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 30, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Plasminogen</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tissue Plasminogen Activator</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

