<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="261">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04741386</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NL76215.042.20</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04741386</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The REnal Patients COVID-19 VACcination Immune Response (RECOVAC IR) Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>RECOVAC-IR</acronym>
  <official_title>The Immune-response and Safety of COVID-19 Vaccination in Patients With Chronic Kidney Disease, on Dialysis, or Living With a Kidney Transplant - A Prospective, Controlled, Multicenter Cohort Study by the RECOVAC Consortium</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Medical Center Groningen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Erasmus Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Radboud University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Academisch Medisch Centrum - Universiteit van Amsterdam (AMC-UvA)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Medical Center Groningen</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Rationale: COVID-19 is associated with severely increased morbidity and mortality in patients&#xD;
      with severely impaired kidney function, on dialysis or alive with a kidney transplant.&#xD;
      Therefore, effective SARS-CoV-2 vaccination would be of great clinical importance in these&#xD;
      patients. However, SARS-CoV-2 vaccination studies have excluded patients with chronic kidney&#xD;
      disease (CKD) so-far.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: To assess the efficacy and safety of SARS-CoV-2 vaccination in patients with CKD&#xD;
      stages 4/5, on dialysis or alive with a kidney transplant as compared to controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design: prospective, controlled multicenter study Study population: 175 patients with&#xD;
      CKD stages 4/5 (eGFR &lt; 30 ml/min/1.73m2), 175 on dialysis , 300 alive with a kidney&#xD;
      transplant and 200 controls (partners or sibblings of patients) Intervention: SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      vaccination according to standard of care. Blood will be drawn at 4 different time points&#xD;
      (baseline and at day 28, month 6 and year 1 after vaccination).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main study parameters/endpoints: The primary endpoint is the antibody based immune response&#xD;
      on day 28 after the second vaccination. Participants will be classified as responders or&#xD;
      non-responders. The definition of response will be based on the latest available data from&#xD;
      the pivotal studies and will be defined prior to data analyses and the first database lock.&#xD;
      The percentage of responders of each patient cohort will be compared with the percentage&#xD;
      responders in the control group. Safety is a secondary endpoint which will be reported in&#xD;
      terms of percentage of solicited local and systemic adverse events (AEs)graded according to&#xD;
      severity. Other secondary endpoints include longevity of the immune response at 6 and 12&#xD;
      months and levels of SARS-CoV-2 specific T and B cell responses.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      OBJECTIVES&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess the antibody response after SARS-CoV-2 vaccination in patients with CKD stages 4/5,&#xD;
      on dialysis or alive with a kidney transplant as compared to controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess in these groups of subjects after SARS-CoV 2 vaccination:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  durability of the antibody response&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the SARS-CoV-2-specific T and B cell response&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  adverse events&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess in these groups of subjects after SARS-CoV 2 vaccination:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the association between baseline (immune) parameters and the immune response to&#xD;
           SARS-CoV-2 vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the neutralizing capacity of anti-COVID-19 antibodies&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the incidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection and outcome of COVID-19 disease during 12 months&#xD;
           after SARS-CoV-2 vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY DESIGN&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a prospective, controlled multicenter cohort study to evaluate the efficacy and&#xD;
      safety after SARS-CoV-2 vaccination in patients with CKD4/5, dialysis patients and kidney&#xD;
      transplant recipients as compared to controls. Therefore, 4 cohorts will be included in this&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort A: Patients with CKD stages 4 and 5 (eGFR &lt;30 ml/min*1.73m2) (n = 175)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort B: Patients on hemodialysis and peritoneal dialysis (n = 175)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort C: Kidney Transplant Recipients (n= 300)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort D: Controls (n = 200)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment of immune response:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood samples will be collected at baseline (i.e. prior to first vaccination) and 28 days,&#xD;
      and 6 and 12 months after the second vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Evaluation other parameters:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate hematology parameters, liver and kidney function, additional blood samples will&#xD;
      be collected at baseline, and 28 days and 6 months after the second vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Information on clinical course, incidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection, outcome of COVID-19 will&#xD;
      be collected up to 12 months after vaccination for descriptive purposes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main study parameter/endpoint:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint is the antibody based immune response to vaccination against COVID-19 on&#xD;
      day 28 after the second vaccination as compared to controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary study parameters/endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Duration and in-depth assessment of immune response through:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Measurement of SARS-CoV2 specific antibodies at 6 and 12 months after vaccination&#xD;
                to test the durability of response&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Assessment of SARS-CoV2 specific T and B cell response, 28 days, and 6 and 12&#xD;
                months after the second vaccination using a high throughput Interferon ɣ, IL-21&#xD;
                SARSCoV-2 specific T cell ELISPOT and SARS-CoV2 specific B cell memory ELISPOT.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Safety assessment through:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Incidence and severity of solicited AEs during 7 days after each vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory study parameters:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Baseline (immune) parameters associated with vaccination response&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Neutralizing capacity of antibodies to test functionality&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In-depth flow-cytometric analyses for functional and phenotypical characterization of&#xD;
           SARS-CoV-2 specific T cell responses will be performed followed by assessment of&#xD;
           proliferative capacity, cytokine production and phenotypical markers in a subset of&#xD;
           patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Information on incidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection and outcome of COVID-19 disease during&#xD;
           12 months after vaccination will be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In a substudy in Radboudumc nasal strips will be collected and mucosal antibody response&#xD;
           to COVID-19 analysed&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 5, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Year</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The antibody based immune response to vaccination against COVID-19 as compared to controls</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days after the second vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>The definition of response will be based on the latest available data from the pivotal studies</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Longevity of the antibody based immune response</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months after the second vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>The definition of response will be based on the latest available data from the pivotal studies</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SARS-CoV2 specific T and B cell response</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days, 6 and 12 months after the second vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>using a high throughput Interferon ɣ, IL-21 SARSCoV-2 specific T cell ELISPOT and SARS-CoV2 specific B cell memory ELISPOT</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence and severity of solicited adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>during 7 days after each vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Using questionaires</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">850</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Kidney Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort A</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with CKD stages 4 and 5</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort B</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients on hemodialysis and peritoneal dialysis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort C</arm_group_label>
    <description>Kidney Transplant Recipients</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort D</arm_group_label>
    <description>Controls</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SARS-CoV-2 vaccination</intervention_name>
    <description>All participants will receive two vaccinations against COVID-19 according to the manufacturer's instructions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort D</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      In total 4x10 ml heparin blood, 15 ml EDTA blood and 10 mL serum will be drawn.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        -  At all four participating centers (UMCG, ErasmusMC, Radboudumc and Amsterdam UMC)&#xD;
             out-patient clinics with at least 100 patients with CKD4/5 are available for&#xD;
             recruitment in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At all three participating centers approximately 50-100 hemodialysis and peritoneal&#xD;
             dialysis patients are being treated, from this population eligible patients will be&#xD;
             included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Kidney transplant recipients at UMCG, Erasmus MC, Radboudumc and Amsterdam UMC will be&#xD;
             eligible. In each participating center 130 to 200 patients receive a kidney transplant&#xD;
             yearly, and per center 1000-2000 kidney transplant recipients are under regular&#xD;
             outpatient follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Partners, siblings or family members of participating patients will be asked as&#xD;
             controls.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. All patients should be eligible for COVID-19 vaccination as described by the&#xD;
             instructions of the manufacturer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age of 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Capable of understanding the purpose and risks of the study, fully informed and given&#xD;
             written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Either&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CKD4/5, with an eGFR &lt;30 ml/min*1.73m2 by CKD-EPI&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemodialysis, or peritoneal dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  KT recipient at least 6 weeks after transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Partner, sibling or family member of participating patient&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe adverse reaction associated with a vaccine and/or severe allergic&#xD;
             reaction (e.g. anaphylaxis) to any component of the study intervention(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Multi-organ transplant recipients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous or active COVID-19 disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active (haematological) malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inherited immune deficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infection with Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bleeding diathesis or condition associated with prolonged bleeding that would, in the&#xD;
             opinion of the investigator, contraindicate intramuscular injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional exclusion criterion for patients with CKD stages 4/5, on dialysis and controls:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Individuals who receive maintenance treatment with immunosuppressive therapy in the 6&#xD;
        months before inclusion, including cytotoxic agents or systemic corticosteroids.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional exclusion criterion for controls:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - severely impaired kidney function, with an eGFR &lt; 45 ml/min*1.73m2 by CKD-EPI&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jan-Stephan F Sanders, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University Medical Center Groningen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ron T Gansevoort, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Medical Center Groningen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Luuk B Hilbrands, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Radboud University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marlies EJ Reinders, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Erasmus Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Frederike J Bemelman, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Amsterdam University Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jan-Stephan F Sanders, MD PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+31503616161</phone>
    <email>j.sanders@umcg.nl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lianne Messchendorp, MD PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+31503616161</phone>
    <email>a.l.messchendorp@umcg.nl</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Radboud university medical center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nijmegen</city>
        <state>Gelderland</state>
        <zip>6525 GA</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Luuk B Hilbrands, MD PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Amsterdam University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Amsterdam</city>
        <state>Noord-Holland</state>
        <zip>1105 AZ</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Frederike J Bemelman, MD PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Erasmus Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rotterdam</city>
        <state>Zuid-Holland</state>
        <zip>3015 GD</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marlies EJ Reinders, MD PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Medical Center Groningen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Groningen</city>
        <zip>9713 GZ</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ron T Gansevoort, MD PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ahn C, Amer H, Anglicheau D, Ascher NL, Baan CC, Battsetset G, Bat-Ireedui B, Berney T, Betjes MGH, Bichu S, Birn H, Brennan D, Bromberg J, Caillard S, Cannon RM, Cantarovich M, Chan A, Chen ZS, Chapman JR, Cole EH, Cross N, Durand F, Egawa H, Emond JC, Farrero M, Friend PJ, Geissler EK, Ha J, Haberal MA, Henderson ML, Hesselink DA, Humar A, Jassem W, Jeong JC, Kaplan B, Kee T, Kim SJ, Kumar D, Legendre CM, Man K, Moulin B, Muller E, Munkhbat R, Od-Erdene L, Perrin P, Rela M, Tanabe K, Tedesco Silva H, Tinckam KT, Tullius SG, Wong G. Global Transplantation COVID Report March 2020. Transplantation. 2020 Oct;104(10):1974-1983. doi: 10.1097/TP.0000000000003258.</citation>
    <PMID>32243281</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gansevoort RT, Hilbrands LB. CKD is a key risk factor for COVID-19 mortality. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2020 Dec;16(12):705-706. doi: 10.1038/s41581-020-00349-4.</citation>
    <PMID>32848205</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gezondheidsraad. Strategieën voor COVID-19-vaccinatie. Den Haag: Gezondheidsraad, 2020; publicatienr. 2020/23</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hilbrands LB, Duivenvoorden R, Vart P, Franssen CFM, Hemmelder MH, Jager KJ, Kieneker LM, Noordzij M, Pena MJ, Vries H, Arroyo D, Covic A, Crespo M, Goffin E, Islam M, Massy ZA, Montero N, Oliveira JP, Roca Muñoz A, Sanchez JE, Sridharan S, Winzeler R, Gansevoort RT; ERACODA Collaborators. COVID-19-related mortality in kidney transplant and dialysis patients: results of the ERACODA collaboration. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2020 Nov 1;35(11):1973-1983. doi: 10.1093/ndt/gfaa261.</citation>
    <PMID>33151337</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hodgson SH, Mansatta K, Mallett G, Harris V, Emary KRW, Pollard AJ. What defines an efficacious COVID-19 vaccine? A review of the challenges assessing the clinical efficacy of vaccines against SARS-CoV-2. Lancet Infect Dis. 2021 Feb;21(2):e26-e35. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30773-8. Epub 2020 Oct 27. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>33125914</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Katerinis I, Hadaya K, Duquesnoy R, Ferrari-Lacraz S, Meier S, van Delden C, Martin PY, Siegrist CA, Villard J. De novo anti-HLA antibody after pandemic H1N1 and seasonal influenza immunization in kidney transplant recipients. Am J Transplant. 2011 Aug;11(8):1727-33. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-6143.2011.03604.x. Epub 2011 Jun 14.</citation>
    <PMID>21672157</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kotton CN. Immunization after kidney transplantation-what is necessary and what is safe? Nat Rev Nephrol. 2014 Oct;10(10):555-62. doi: 10.1038/nrneph.2014.122. Epub 2014 Jul 29. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25072119</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mahase E. Covid-19: Vaccine candidate may be more than 90% effective, interim results indicate. BMJ. 2020 Nov 9;371:m4347. doi: 10.1136/bmj.m4347.</citation>
    <PMID>33168562</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reddy S, Chitturi C, Yee J. Vaccination in Chronic Kidney Disease. Adv Chronic Kidney Dis. 2019 Jan;26(1):72-78. doi: 10.1053/j.ackd.2018.10.002. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30876620</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>van Besouw NM, Yan L, de Kuiper R, Klepper M, Reijerkerk D, Dieterich M, Roelen DL, Claas FHJ, Clahsen-van Groningen MC, Hesselink DA, Baan CC. The Number of Donor-Specific IL-21 Producing Cells Before and After Transplantation Predicts Kidney Graft Rejection. Front Immunol. 2019 Apr 9;10:748. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2019.00748. eCollection 2019.</citation>
    <PMID>31024571</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Williamson EJ, Walker AJ, Bhaskaran K, Bacon S, Bates C, Morton CE, Curtis HJ, Mehrkar A, Evans D, Inglesby P, Cockburn J, McDonald HI, MacKenna B, Tomlinson L, Douglas IJ, Rentsch CT, Mathur R, Wong AYS, Grieve R, Harrison D, Forbes H, Schultze A, Croker R, Parry J, Hester F, Harper S, Perera R, Evans SJW, Smeeth L, Goldacre B. Factors associated with COVID-19-related death using OpenSAFELY. Nature. 2020 Aug;584(7821):430-436. doi: 10.1038/s41586-020-2521-4. Epub 2020 Jul 8.</citation>
    <PMID>32640463</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University Medical Center Groningen</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>J.S.F. Sanders</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD PhD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2 vaccination</keyword>
  <keyword>Antibody based immune response</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2 specific T and B cell response</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

