<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3846">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04160975</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB19-1424</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04160975</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Persuasion in Medicine: Experimental Evidence on Sender and Signal Effects</brief_title>
  <official_title>Persuasion in Medicine: Experimental Evidence on Sender and Signal Effects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Harvard University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Stanford University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Harvard University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the study is to identify what sender/signal combinations are most persuasive in&#xD;
      encouraging low socioeconomic males living in the U.S. to take-up seasonal flu vaccination.&#xD;
      The investigators plan to recruit male subjects and randomly assign them to four persuasion&#xD;
      treatments: three of which vary dimensions of the sender of a medical recommendation (racial&#xD;
      concordance, gender concordance, and authority treatments) and one which varies the signal&#xD;
      (standard vs. empathetic). Specifically, the investigators will show subjects videos of&#xD;
      either Black or white actors/actresses providing scripted information on the flu vaccination.&#xD;
      The investigators will randomize the race of the sender and if the subject is Black, also&#xD;
      randomize the authority of the sender, with the actor portraying either a doctor or a&#xD;
      layperson. Conditional on project funding, subjects assigned to a concordant sender will have&#xD;
      the gender of the sender randomized. In addition, the investigators will vary the script used&#xD;
      in the experiment between one that acknowledges past injustices (indicated as an empathetic&#xD;
      script hereafter) and one that does not (indicated as a standard script hereafter). The&#xD;
      investigators will provide subjects a free flu shot coupon and elicit the price at which&#xD;
      subjects would be willing to give up this coupon for a cash reward. Lastly, in light of the&#xD;
      relevance of vaccination take-up in combating COVID-19 pandemic, the investigators will&#xD;
      assess demand for information about a COVID-19 vaccine, with subjects invited to receive&#xD;
      results of a safety and efficacy review from a trusted or standard source. The design&#xD;
      requires collection of baseline and endline surveys combined with administrative data from&#xD;
      pharmacies about coupon redemption. The primary outcomes of interest are posterior beliefs&#xD;
      about seasonal flu vaccination, demand and willingness-to-pay (WTP) for a free flu shot&#xD;
      coupon, redemption of the coupon, and demand for information about a COVID-19 vaccine.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigators will recruit approximately 3350 African-American or Caucasian adult males&#xD;
      with a high-school diploma or less. A pilot study, which ran during the 2019-20 flu season,&#xD;
      recruited approximately 850 subjects, and a planned scale-up will recruit an additional 2500&#xD;
      subjects during the 2020-21 flu season. The investigators will oversample African American&#xD;
      individuals, emphasizing low-income and minority men because these characteristics are&#xD;
      correlated with lower relative take-up of flu vaccination. After informed consent is&#xD;
      obtained, subjects will be asked about sociodemographic information (age, education, income&#xD;
      and marital status), healthcare experience and past medical history, knowledge and beliefs&#xD;
      about flu vaccination, and location of the nearest pharmacy. The investigators will then&#xD;
      randomly assign the adult male subjects to videos which contain one of Black or white actors&#xD;
      playing the role of either a doctor or a layperson as well as different scripts. The content&#xD;
      of the infomercial will be the safety and effectiveness of adult seasonal flu vaccination.&#xD;
      After the video, the investigators will obtain information on beliefs regarding vaccination,&#xD;
      feedback on the video, attention to the video and willingness-to-pay for a flu shot coupon.&#xD;
      The final baseline module will consist of a randomly assigned invitation to receive the&#xD;
      results of an upcoming review of a COVID-19 vaccine, with subjects assigned to receive&#xD;
      information from a trusted or standard source. The investigators will track flu coupon&#xD;
      redemption, which is redeemable at most pharmacies nationwide.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 20, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Posterior beliefs about the risk/benefits of the flu shot</measure>
    <time_frame>This outcome will be assessed during Baseline survey, which takes approximately 20 minutes.</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will examine whether a subject updated their beliefs about the risk and benefits of the flu shot after watching the infomercial video.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Demand for information about a COVID-19 vaccine</measure>
    <time_frame>This outcome will be assessed during Baseline survey, which takes approximately 20 minutes.</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will examine whether subjects invited to receive information on COVID-19 vaccine safety and efficacy from a concordant source exhibited higher demand for such information.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Willingness-to-pay (WTP) for a free flu shot coupon</measure>
    <time_frame>This outcome will be assessed during Baseline survey, which takes approximately 20 minutes.</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will elicit and measure a subject's flu shot coupon valuations.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of attention and recall from the infomercial video during Baseline survey</measure>
    <time_frame>This outcome will be assessed during Baseline survey, which takes approximately 20 minutes.</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will measure a subject's level of attention and recall from the infomercial video, which could potentially affect their belief updating and decisions on coupon redemption.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of attention and recall from the infomercial video during Endline survey</measure>
    <time_frame>This outcome will be assessed during Endline survey, which takes approximately 2 weeks to 3 months after the intervention (depending on the characteristics of the flu season).</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will measure a subject's level of attention and recall from the infomercial video, which could potentially affect their belief updating and decisions on coupon redemption.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Redemption of said coupon</measure>
    <time_frame>This outcome will be assessed during the time between Baseline and Endline survey (approximately 2 weeks to 3 months time gap, depending on the characteristics of the flu season).</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will collect information indicating whether a subject redeemed a flu shot coupon after watching the infomercial video.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>11</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">3350</enrollment>
  <condition>Flu, Human</condition>
  <condition>Influenza, Human</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Black R/Race C/Gender C/Doctor/Standard Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Video which contains a racially and gender concordant actor playing a doctor and reading a standard script. The receiver of the message will be Black.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Black R/Race C/Gender D/Doctor/Standard Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Video which contains a racially concordant and gender discordant actor playing a doctor and reading a standard script. The receiver of the message will be Black.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Black R/Race C/Gender C/Layperson/Standard Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Video which contains a racially and gender concordant actor playing a layperson and reading a standard script. The receiver of the message will be Black.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Black R/Race D/Gender C/Doctor/Standard Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Video which contains a racially discordant and gender concordant actor playing a doctor and reading a standard script. The receiver of the message will be Black.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Black R/Race D/Gender C/Doctor/Empathetic Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Video which contains a racially discordant and gender concordant actor playing a doctor and reading an empathetic script. The receiver of the message will be Black.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>White R/Race C/Gender C/Doctor/Standard Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Video which contains a racially and gender concordant actor playing a doctor and reading a standard script. The receiver of the message will be White.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>White R/Race C/Gender D/Doctor/Standard Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Video which contains a racially concordant and gender discordant actor playing a doctor and reading a standard script. The receiver of the message will be White.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>White R/Race D/Gender C/Doctor/Standard Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Video which contains a racially discordant and gender concordant actor playing a doctor and reading a standard script. The receiver of the message will be White.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 Information, Concordant Source</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Message inviting subject to receive the results of a COVID-19 vaccine review from the National Medical Association (NMA). The receiver of the message will be Black.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 Information, Discordant Source</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Message inviting subject to receive the results of a COVID-19 vaccine review from the National Medical Association (NMA). The receiver of the message will be White.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 Information, Standard Source</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Message inviting subject to receive the results of a COVID-19 vaccine review from the Food and Drug Administration (FDA). Receivers of the message will be White or Black.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Video about safety and effectiveness of adult seasonal flu vaccination</intervention_name>
    <description>The investigators will show subjects videos of either Black or white male actors providing scripted information on the flu vaccination. The content of the video will be the safety and effectiveness of adult seasonal flu vaccination. The videos contain one of Black or white actors playing the role of either a doctor or a layperson as well as different scripts.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Black R/Race C/Gender C/Doctor/Standard Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Black R/Race C/Gender C/Layperson/Standard Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Black R/Race C/Gender D/Doctor/Standard Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Black R/Race D/Gender C/Doctor/Empathetic Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Black R/Race D/Gender C/Doctor/Standard Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>White R/Race C/Gender C/Doctor/Standard Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>White R/Race C/Gender D/Doctor/Standard Script</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>White R/Race D/Gender C/Doctor/Standard Script</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Message directing subjects to information on COVID-19 vaccine safety and efficacy</intervention_name>
    <description>The investigators will show subjects text directing subjects to an expert review of COVID-19 vaccine safety and efficacy. The review will either be authored by individuals affiliated with the National Medical Association (NMA), an association of Black physicians, or the Food and Drug Administration (FDA).</description>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 Information, Concordant Source</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 Information, Discordant Source</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 Information, Standard Source</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age: See above.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Education: Less than a college degree.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gender: Male.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Race: Caucasian or African American.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Miscellaneous: Has not received the flu shot in the current flu season yet.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Miscellaneous: Has sound on his device turned on.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fast survey-taking: subjects who are among the 5% fastest in terms of total time spent&#xD;
             on survey within race and treatment group.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Nonsense answers (those that do not have decipherable English) in the open text&#xD;
             sections that suggest low effort.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inconsistent responses to questions (such as being willing to give up $10 to receive a&#xD;
             flu coupon but not $1).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Repeat survey takers as indicated by duplicate emails or IP addresses in survey data.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>The investigators will only recruit male subjects.</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>51 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Harvard University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cambridge</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02138</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 8, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 13, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 12, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 12, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Harvard University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Marcella Alsan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Belief Updating</keyword>
  <keyword>Preventive Care</keyword>
  <keyword>Racial Disparity</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

