<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1909">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04732767</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>08-20-20E</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04732767</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of COVID-19 IgG Antibodies in Maternal and Cord Blood Samples</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prospective Study of Maternal and Umbilical Cord Blood Collection to Evaluate for Presence of COVID-19 Antibody Response in COVID-19 Positive Women</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Atrium Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Atrium Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Protocol Summary&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design: Prospective cohort study of pregnant COVID-19 positive patients at delivery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Objective: To collect umbilical cord blood and placenta samples at the time of delivery&#xD;
      in COVID-19 positive women and evaluate for presence of COVID-19 virus and maternal antibody&#xD;
      response.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion/Exclusion Criteria: Women admitted for delivery who are known or suspected COVID-19&#xD;
      positive who have had standard nasal swab testing for COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Procedures: Informed consent for patients will be obtained. Maternal blood will be&#xD;
      collected for viral and antibody tests for COVID-19. Following delivery of the neonate, cord&#xD;
      blood and placenta samples will be collected and sent for viral PCR and maternal antibody&#xD;
      analysis. Neonatal testing will be done as per existing clinical protocol for infants born to&#xD;
      PUI/COVID-19 positive women.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analysis: Statistical analysis for this study will include descriptive analysis&#xD;
      and quantitative statistics of findings.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      The clinical syndrome of coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19), caused by the severe acute respiratory&#xD;
      2 virus (SARS-CoV-2) first began in Wuhan China in December 2019 and subsequently spread&#xD;
      globally at an exponential rate. The disease was officially classified by the World Health&#xD;
      Organization as a pandemic on March 11, 2020. The first death from COVID-19 was reported in&#xD;
      the United States on February 28, 2020.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In general, pregnancy is a state of relative immunosuppression, and alterations in immunology&#xD;
      and physiology during pregnancy increase the risks of significant respiratory complications&#xD;
      and associated obstetrical complications from severe illness. To date, data to guide&#xD;
      understanding of the impact of COVID-19 on pregnancy is relatively limited. With any viral&#xD;
      illness in pregnancy, there is potential for maternal-fetal transmission. As of now, there&#xD;
      have been very few reported cases of suspected vertical transmission. Moreover, there have&#xD;
      been few cases of neonatal transmission, even in patients acutely ill with COVID-19 at the&#xD;
      time of delivery. However, a recent case report highlighted a 19 week pregnancy loss in a&#xD;
      COVID-19 positive patient where placenta pathology showed presence of COVID-19 by PCR,&#xD;
      although fetal samples were negative.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As the United States begins to expand testing from viral to antibody testing, opportunity&#xD;
      exists to determine if maternal antibodies are present in neonates. If present, these&#xD;
      antibodies may confer protection for neonates born to infected mothers. During the course of&#xD;
      any infection, IgM antibodies are formed with subsequent development of IgG antibodies.&#xD;
      Regardless of source, maternal IgM antibodies do not readily cross the placenta barrier,&#xD;
      while maternal IgG antibodies easily cross the placenta during pregnancy. Fetuses are capable&#xD;
      of initiating an IgM response to infection in utero. Cord blood serves as a non-invasive&#xD;
      source of neonatal blood that can be easily obtained at delivery and allows assessment of the&#xD;
      neonate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis&#xD;
&#xD;
      We hypothesize that cord blood collected from COVID-19 positive women will show presence of&#xD;
      IgG antibodies against COVID-19 which may confer protection for the infant in the neonatal&#xD;
      period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective&#xD;
&#xD;
      To collect: 1. maternal blood samples for COVID-19 IgG antibodies on admission to labor and&#xD;
      delivery; 2. cord blood samples for COVID-19 IgG antibodies at the time of delivery; 3.&#xD;
      placenta pathology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Type:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prospective cohort study of pregnant COVID-19 positive patients at delivery admission or at&#xD;
      any point during the pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible patients will be invited to participate in the study during pregnancy or on&#xD;
      admission to labor and delivery. Eligible patients will have had a positive COVID-19 PCR test&#xD;
      at some time during pregnancy or on the delivery admission. Informed consent will be obtained&#xD;
      by admitting physician from patients who agree to participate. A maternal blood sample will&#xD;
      be obtained with routine admission labs by nursing staff. This sample will be sent for&#xD;
      immunoassay for qualitative assessment for COVID-19 IgG antibodies. C-reactive protein will&#xD;
      also be measured as this is an indicator of severe disease. At delivery, cord blood and&#xD;
      placenta samples will be obtained as per routine collection methods by the delivery&#xD;
      physician. Cord blood will be sent for the same analysis as the maternal blood sample. The&#xD;
      placenta will be sent to pathology. Results will be obtained through the patient's medical&#xD;
      record. Data will be collected into a Redcap database by research personnel. Neonatal data&#xD;
      will be obtained from the neonate's medical record and entered into the Redcap database by&#xD;
      research personnel. Any publications resulting from this study will use de-identified patient&#xD;
      data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The benefit of this study will be contribution to the limited data that exists around&#xD;
      COVID-19 infection and pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis for this study will include descriptive analysis and quantitative&#xD;
      statistics of findings.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 20, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Presence of COVID-19 IgG antibodies by immunoassay in maternal and cord blood samples.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Immunoassay will be used to detect qualitative levels of COVID-19 IgG antibodies in maternal and cord blood.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Pregnancy Related</condition>
  <condition>Antibody Response</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Samples obtained during the study will include maternal and cord blood samples. These samples&#xD;
      will be stored for potential future studies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Pregnant patients at greater than age 18 who have had a positive COVID-19 PCR test during&#xD;
        pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Women admitted for delivery who are known or suspected COVID-19 positive and women were&#xD;
        positive at any time during pregnancy who have had standard nasal swab PCR testing for&#xD;
        COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Patients less than 18 years of age. Patients unable to give consent. Patients who are&#xD;
        immunocompromised.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>pregnant</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ngina K Connors, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Atrium Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ngina K Connors, MD</last_name>
    <phone>704-403-4189</phone>
    <email>ngina.connors@atriumhealth.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lorene Temming, MD</last_name>
    <phone>704-403-4189</phone>
    <email>lorene.temming@atriumhealth.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Atrium Health</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ngina K. Connors</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MFM Division Director, Ob/Gyn Interim Department Chair</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

