<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1299">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04598347</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IIBSP-COV-2020-59</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04598347</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of the Possible Vertical Transmission of SARS-CoV-2 Through Study of Amniotic Fluid and Chorionic Villi of Affected Pregnant Women for the COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Valuation of the Possible Vertical Transmission of SARS-CoV-2 Through Study of Amniotic Fluid and Chorionic Villi of Affected Pregnant Women for the COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fundació Institut de Recerca de l'Hospital de la Santa Creu i Sant Pau</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fundació Institut de Recerca de l'Hospital de la Santa Creu i Sant Pau</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Longitudinal prospective study in pregnant women withpositive serology or PCR for SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      and indicationinvasive technique (amniocentesis or chorionic biopsy) that has the objective&#xD;
      to evaluate the possible vertical transmission of SARS-CoV-2in the amniotic fluid or&#xD;
      chorionic villi of pregnant women affected by coronavirus in the different periods of&#xD;
      gestation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients will be recruited at the time theypresent an indication to perform a&#xD;
      techniqueinvasive (amniocentesis or chorion biopsy). Eitherscreening for first or second&#xD;
      trimester aneuploidies ofhigh risk, due to the presence of fetal malformation, due toearly&#xD;
      intrauterine growth retardation (ICR) or due tosuspected chorioamnionitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study population will be pregnant women diagnosed with SARS-CoV-2 infection(by PCR on&#xD;
      nasopharyngeal aspirate or serology)that have an indication to perform an invasive&#xD;
      technique(chorionic biopsy or amniocentesis) along thegestation.The sample size will depend&#xD;
      on the duration of theSARS-CoV-2 pandemic.Initially we propose a study period of 18 months in&#xD;
      which we would have an approximate total of 225 pregnant women with indication of invasive&#xD;
      technique.It is planned to conduct a PCR study for SARS-CoV-2 in amniotic fluid or chorionic&#xD;
      villi to those pregnant women diagnosed with SARS-CoV-2 infection(approximately 5% of the&#xD;
      total pregnant womenwith indication of invasive technique (11-12 pregnant women)).This&#xD;
      determination is made as part of theroutine clinical practice in the context of the study&#xD;
      ofscreening for perinatal infections.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 8, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 23, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 8, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>18 Months</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Perinatal SARS-CoV-2 infection</measure>
    <time_frame>15 days</time_frame>
    <description>Presence of SARS-CoV-2 in amniotic fluid or villichorionics from pregnant women with positive serology or PCR in nasopharyngeal aspirate duringgestation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">225</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Pregnancy Related</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pregnant women diagnosed with SARS-CoV-2</arm_group_label>
    <description>Pregnant women diagnosed with SARS-CoV-2 infection(by PCR on nasopharyngeal aspirate or serology)that have an indication to perform an invasive technique(chorionic biopsy or amniocentesis) along thegestation.The sample size will depend on the duration of theSARS-CoV-2 pandemic.Initially we propose a study period of 18months in which we would have an approximate total of 225pregnant women with indication of invasive technique.It is planned to conduct a PCR study for SARS-CoV-2 in amniotic fluid or chorionic villi to thosepregnant women diagnosed with SARS-CoV-2 infection(approximately 5% of the total pregnant womenwith indication of invasive technique (11-12 pregnant women)).This determination is made as part of theroutine clinical practice in the context of the study of screening for perinatal infections</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      umbilical cord blood, samples from the neonatal nasopharynx, the amnio-chorion interface, and&#xD;
      placental tissue&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        regnant women diagnosed with SARS-CoV-2 (by PCR in aspiratenasopharyngeal or serologies)&#xD;
        that indicate an invasive technique(chorionic biopsy or amniocentesis) throughout pregnancy&#xD;
        either due to high riskof aneuploidies in the first or second trimester screening, due to&#xD;
        the presence offetal malformation, due to diagnosis of early intrauterine growth&#xD;
        retardation (ICR)or for suspected chorioamnionitis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women diagnosed with SARS-CoV-2 (by PCR in aspiratenasopharyngeal or&#xD;
             serologies)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients indicated for an invasive technique(chorionic biopsy or amniocentesis&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who do not meet the inclusion criteria&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Obdulia Alejos Abad, PhD, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+34935537041</phone>
    <email>oalejos@santpau.cat</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital de la Santa Creu i Sant Pau</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08025</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Obdulia Alejos, MD</last_name>
      <email>oalejos@santpau.cat</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Obdulia Alejos, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu Z, McGoogan JM. Characteristics of and Important Lessons From the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Outbreak in China: Summary of a Report of 72 314 Cases From the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention. JAMA. 2020 Apr 7;323(13):1239-1242. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.2648.</citation>
    <PMID>32091533</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Breslin N, Baptiste C, Gyamfi-Bannerman C, Miller R, Martinez R, Bernstein K, Ring L, Landau R, Purisch S, Friedman AM, Fuchs K, Sutton D, Andrikopoulou M, Rupley D, Sheen JJ, Aubey J, Zork N, Moroz L, Mourad M, Wapner R, Simpson LL, D'Alton ME, Goffman D. Coronavirus disease 2019 infection among asymptomatic and symptomatic pregnant women: two weeks of confirmed presentations to an affiliated pair of New York City hospitals. Am J Obstet Gynecol MFM. 2020 May;2(2):100118. doi: 10.1016/j.ajogmf.2020.100118. Epub 2020 Apr 9.</citation>
    <PMID>32292903</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Garg S, Kim L, Whitaker M, O'Halloran A, Cummings C, Holstein R, Prill M, Chai SJ, Kirley PD, Alden NB, Kawasaki B, Yousey-Hindes K, Niccolai L, Anderson EJ, Openo KP, Weigel A, Monroe ML, Ryan P, Henderson J, Kim S, Como-Sabetti K, Lynfield R, Sosin D, Torres S, Muse A, Bennett NM, Billing L, Sutton M, West N, Schaffner W, Talbot HK, Aquino C, George A, Budd A, Brammer L, Langley G, Hall AJ, Fry A. Hospitalization Rates and Characteristics of Patients Hospitalized with Laboratory-Confirmed Coronavirus Disease 2019 - COVID-NET, 14 States, March 1-30, 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020 Apr 17;69(15):458-464. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.mm6915e3.</citation>
    <PMID>32298251</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Di Mascio D, Khalil A, Saccone G, Rizzo G, Buca D, Liberati M, Vecchiet J, Nappi L, Scambia G, Berghella V, D'Antonio F. Outcome of coronavirus spectrum infections (SARS, MERS, COVID-19) during pregnancy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Obstet Gynecol MFM. 2020 May;2(2):100107. doi: 10.1016/j.ajogmf.2020.100107. Epub 2020 Mar 25. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32292902</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schwartz DA. An Analysis of 38 Pregnant Women with COVID-19, Their Newborn Infants, and Maternal-Fetal Transmission of SARS-CoV-2: Maternal Coronavirus Infections and Pregnancy Outcomes. Arch Pathol Lab Med. 2020 Mar 17. doi: 10.5858/arpa.2020-0901-SA. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>32180426</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Khan S, Jun L, Nawsherwan, Siddique R, Li Y, Han G, Xue M, Nabi G, Liu J. Association of COVID-19 with pregnancy outcomes in health-care workers and general women. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2020 Jun;26(6):788-790. doi: 10.1016/j.cmi.2020.03.034. Epub 2020 Apr 8.</citation>
    <PMID>32278081</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sutton D, Fuchs K, D'Alton M, Goffman D. Universal Screening for SARS-CoV-2 in Women Admitted for Delivery. N Engl J Med. 2020 May 28;382(22):2163-2164. doi: 10.1056/NEJMc2009316. Epub 2020 Apr 13.</citation>
    <PMID>32283004</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Della Gatta AN, Rizzo R, Pilu G, Simonazzi G. Coronavirus disease 2019 during pregnancy: a systematic review of reported cases. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2020 Jul;223(1):36-41. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2020.04.013. Epub 2020 Apr 18.</citation>
    <PMID>32311350</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Qiancheng X, Jian S, Lingling P, Lei H, Xiaogan J, Weihua L, Gang Y, Shirong L, Zhen W, GuoPing X, Lei Z; sixth batch of Anhui medical team aiding Wuhan for COVID-19. Coronavirus disease 2019 in pregnancy. Int J Infect Dis. 2020 Jun;95:376-383. doi: 10.1016/j.ijid.2020.04.065. Epub 2020 Apr 27.</citation>
    <PMID>32353549</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yang Z, Wang M, Zhu Z, Liu Y. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) and pregnancy: a systematic review. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med. 2020 Apr 30:1-4. doi: 10.1080/14767058.2020.1759541. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>32354293</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Li N, Han L, Peng M, Lv Y, Ouyang Y, Liu K, Yue L, Li Q, Sun G, Chen L, Yang L. Maternal and Neonatal Outcomes of Pregnant Women With Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Pneumonia: A Case-Control Study. Clin Infect Dis. 2020 Nov 19;71(16):2035-2041. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciaa352.</citation>
    <PMID>32249918</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>CDC COVID-19 Response Team. Preliminary Estimates of the Prevalence of Selected Underlying Health Conditions Among Patients with Coronavirus Disease 2019 - United States, February 12-March 28, 2020. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2020 Apr 3;69(13):382-386. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.mm6913e2.</citation>
    <PMID>32240123</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mullins E, Evans D, Viner RM, O'Brien P, Morris E. Coronavirus in pregnancy and delivery: rapid review. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol. 2020 May;55(5):586-592. doi: 10.1002/uog.22014. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32180292</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Karami P, Naghavi M, Feyzi A, Aghamohammadi M, Novin MS, Mobaien A, Qorbanisani M, Karami A, Norooznezhad AH. WITHDRAWN: Mortality of a pregnant patient diagnosed with COVID-19: A case report with clinical, radiological, and histopathological findings. Travel Med Infect Dis. 2020 Apr 11:101665. doi: 10.1016/j.tmaid.2020.101665. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>32283217</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hantoushzadeh S, Shamshirsaz AA, Aleyasin A, Seferovic MD, Aski SK, Arian SE, Pooransari P, Ghotbizadeh F, Aalipour S, Soleimani Z, Naemi M, Molaei B, Ahangari R, Salehi M, Oskoei AD, Pirozan P, Darkhaneh RF, Laki MG, Farani AK, Atrak S, Miri MM, Kouchek M, Shojaei S, Hadavand F, Keikha F, Hosseini MS, Borna S, Ariana S, Shariat M, Fatemi A, Nouri B, Nekooghadam SM, Aagaard K. Maternal death due to COVID-19. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2020 Jul;223(1):109.e1-109.e16. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2020.04.030. Epub 2020 Apr 28.</citation>
    <PMID>32360108</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Elshafeey F, Magdi R, Hindi N, Elshebiny M, Farrag N, Mahdy S, Sabbour M, Gebril S, Nasser M, Kamel M, Amir A, Maher Emara M, Nabhan A. A systematic scoping review of COVID-19 during pregnancy and childbirth. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2020 Jul;150(1):47-52. doi: 10.1002/ijgo.13182. Epub 2020 May 17.</citation>
    <PMID>32330287</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yan J, Guo J, Fan C, Juan J, Yu X, Li J, Feng L, Li C, Chen H, Qiao Y, Lei D, Wang C, Xiong G, Xiao F, He W, Pang Q, Hu X, Wang S, Chen D, Zhang Y, Poon LC, Yang H. Coronavirus disease 2019 in pregnant women: a report based on 116 cases. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2020 Jul;223(1):111.e1-111.e14. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2020.04.014. Epub 2020 Apr 23.</citation>
    <PMID>32335053</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Li J, Wang Y, Zeng Y, Song T, Pan X, Jia M, He F, Hou L, Li B, He S, Chen D. Critically ill pregnant patient with COVID-19 and neonatal death within two hours of birth. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2020 Jul;150(1):126-128. doi: 10.1002/ijgo.13189. Epub 2020 May 27.</citation>
    <PMID>32369616</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Qiu L, Liu X, Xiao M, Xie J, Cao W, Liu Z, Morse A, Xie Y, Li T, Zhu L. SARS-CoV-2 Is Not Detectable in the Vaginal Fluid of Women With Severe COVID-19 Infection. Clin Infect Dis. 2020 Jul 28;71(15):813-817. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciaa375.</citation>
    <PMID>32241022</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wang W, Xu Y, Gao R, Lu R, Han K, Wu G, Tan W. Detection of SARS-CoV-2 in Different Types of Clinical Specimens. JAMA. 2020 May 12;323(18):1843-1844. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.3786.</citation>
    <PMID>32159775</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Baud D, Greub G, Favre G, Gengler C, Jaton K, Dubruc E, Pomar L. Second-Trimester Miscarriage in a Pregnant Woman With SARS-CoV-2 Infection. JAMA. 2020 Jun 2;323(21):2198-2200. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.7233.</citation>
    <PMID>32352491</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Penfield CA, Brubaker SG, Limaye MA, Lighter J, Ratner AJ, Thomas KM, Meyer JA, Roman AS. Detection of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 in placental and fetal membrane samples. Am J Obstet Gynecol MFM. 2020 Aug;2(3):100133. doi: 10.1016/j.ajogmf.2020.100133. Epub 2020 May 8.</citation>
    <PMID>32391518</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dong L, Tian J, He S, Zhu C, Wang J, Liu C, Yang J. Possible Vertical Transmission of SARS-CoV-2 From an Infected Mother to Her Newborn. JAMA. 2020 May 12;323(18):1846-1848. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.4621.</citation>
    <PMID>32215581</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Alzamora MC, Paredes T, Caceres D, Webb CM, Valdez LM, La Rosa M. Severe COVID-19 during Pregnancy and Possible Vertical Transmission. Am J Perinatol. 2020 Jun;37(8):861-865. doi: 10.1055/s-0040-1710050. Epub 2020 Apr 18.</citation>
    <PMID>32305046</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kimberlin DW, Stagno S. Can SARS-CoV-2 Infection Be Acquired In Utero?: More Definitive Evidence Is Needed. JAMA. 2020 May 12;323(18):1788-1789. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.4868.</citation>
    <PMID>32215579</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 21, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 22, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 22, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>A specific database will be created for the study in which each patient will beAnonymously encoded in such a way that it is not identifiable.The person responsible for database creation, data entry and analysisstatistician will be Dra. Obdulia Alejos Abad.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

