<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1397">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04592510</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>y66cyyg6</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04592510</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Impact of COVID-19 on Pediatric Dental Practice During First and Second Wave In Egypt.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Impact of COVID-19 on Pediatric Dental Practice During First and Second Wave In Egypt : A Cross -Sectional Study Among Egyptian Pediatric Dentists</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Assessment of attitude of Pediatric dentists if they changed their approach in pediatric&#xD;
      dental care during first and second wave of pandemic covid-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      On the 11th of March, 2020, COVID-19 (SARS-CoV-2) was declared as a pandemic by the World&#xD;
      Health Organization. SARS-CoV-2 is an unpredictable virus that is rapidly transmitting from&#xD;
      one country to another, and unfortunately as of today, there is no effective medication or&#xD;
      vaccine for the disease control. This virus has gone on to cause one of the most rapidly&#xD;
      expanding pandemics with over 9 million people being infected worldwide including the&#xD;
      pediatric population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to the unique nature of dentistry, most dental procedures generate significant amounts of&#xD;
      droplets and aerosols, posing potential risks of infection transmission. Recent studies have&#xD;
      demonstrated the role of the oral mucosa in COVID-19 infection, in addition to expressing the&#xD;
      ACE2 receptor in salivary glands in the asymptomatic process in infected saliva, thus being&#xD;
      one of the main sources of viruses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical features of COVID-19 in children include fever and cough, but a large proportion of&#xD;
      infected children appears to be asymptomatic and may contribute significantly to&#xD;
      transmission. Therefore, it can be assumed that, at this stage in the pandemic, all children&#xD;
      and their parents/carers are potentially infective with the potential of cross-infection to&#xD;
      dental stuff, parents and the public. This has, in theory, an impact on medical and dental&#xD;
      procedures that are Aerosol Generating Procedures.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Ecologic or Community</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Attitude of pediatric dentists toward treating patients in time of COVID-19.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measuring device by Questionnaire (Ahmadi, Ebrahimi &amp; Ghorbani, 2020) and (Sinjari et al., 2020). The primary outcome is measured using 5-point likert scale scoring to evaluate pediatric dentists' attitudes</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">345</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV2</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Egyptian pediatric dentists regardless of their place of work, in either private clinics or&#xD;
        educational hospitals.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Graduated dentists who specialized in pediatric dentistry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Work place located in Egypt.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who refuse to participate.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adel El Bardissy</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Faculty of Oral and dental medicine, Cairo university</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Shaimaa Sabry</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Faculty of Oral and dental medicine, Cairo university</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Fatma Essam El-Deen</last_name>
    <phone>01150035515</phone>
    <email>fatma_essam@dentistry.cu.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.rcseng.ac.uk/-/media/fles/rcs/fds/guidelines/paediatric-dentistry-covid19.pdf.</url>
    <description>Royal college of surgeons England 2020. Recommendations for paediatric dentistry during COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ahmadi H, Ebrahimi A, Ghorbani F. The impact of COVID-19 pandemic on dental practice in Iran: a questionnaire-based report. BMC Oral Health. 2020 Dec 3;20(1):354. doi: 10.1186/s12903-020-01341-x.</citation>
    <PMID>33272261</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Al-Halabi M, Salami A, Alnuaimi E, Kowash M, Hussein I. Assessment of paediatric dental guidelines and caries management alternatives in the post COVID-19 period. A critical review and clinical recommendations. Eur Arch Paediatr Dent. 2020 Oct;21(5):543-556. doi: 10.1007/s40368-020-00547-5. Epub 2020 Jun 16. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32557183</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>BaniHani A, Gardener C, Raggio DP, Santamaría RM, Albadri S. Could COVID-19 change the way we manage caries in primary teeth? Current implications on Paediatric Dentistry. Int J Paediatr Dent. 2020 Sep;30(5):523-525. doi: 10.1111/ipd.12690.</citation>
    <PMID>32722881</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cook TM. Personal protective equipment during the coronavirus disease (COVID) 2019 pandemic - a narrative review. Anaesthesia. 2020 Jul;75(7):920-927. doi: 10.1111/anae.15071. Epub 2020 Apr 28. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32246849</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dong Y, Mo X, Hu Y, Qi X, Jiang F, Jiang Z, Tong S. Epidemiology of COVID-19 Among Children in China. Pediatrics. 2020 Jun;145(6). pii: e20200702. doi: 10.1542/peds.2020-0702. Epub 2020 Mar 16.</citation>
    <PMID>32179660</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Frauenfelder C, Butler C, Hartley B, Cochrane L, Jephson C, Nash R, Hewitt R, Albert D, Wyatt M, Hall A. Practical insights for paediatric otolaryngology surgical cases and performing microlaryngobronchoscopy during the COVID-19 pandemic. Int J Pediatr Otorhinolaryngol. 2020 Jul;134:110030. doi: 10.1016/j.ijporl.2020.110030. Epub 2020 Mar 30.</citation>
    <PMID>32278168</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Qiu H, Wu J, Hong L, Luo Y, Song Q, Chen D. Clinical and epidemiological features of 36 children with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) in Zhejiang, China: an observational cohort study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020 Jun;20(6):689-696. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30198-5. Epub 2020 Mar 25.</citation>
    <PMID>32220650</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sinjari B, Rexhepi I, Santilli M, D Addazio G, Chiacchiaretta P, Di Carlo P, Caputi S. The Impact of COVID-19 Related Lockdown on Dental Practice in Central Italy-Outcomes of A Survey. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020 Aug 10;17(16). pii: E5780. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17165780.</citation>
    <PMID>32785056</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sundaram M, Ravikumar N, Bansal A, Nallasamy K, Basavaraja GV, Lodha R, Gupta D, Odena MP, Ashwath RNR, Jayashree M; Intensive Care Chapter of Indian Academy of Pediatrics. Novel Coronavirus 2019 (2019-nCoV) Infection: Part II - Respiratory Support in the Pediatric Intensive Care Unit in Resource-limited Settings. Indian Pediatr. 2020 Apr 15;57(4):335-342. Epub 2020 Mar 29.</citation>
    <PMID>32238613</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Xu J, Li Y, Gan F, Du Y, Yao Y. Salivary Glands: Potential Reservoirs for COVID-19 Asymptomatic Infection. J Dent Res. 2020 Jul;99(8):989. doi: 10.1177/0022034520918518. Epub 2020 Apr 9.</citation>
    <PMID>32271653</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Fatma Essam El-Deen Abdel Rahim</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>pediatric dentistry</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

