<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4685">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04487483</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SleepAppEvaluation</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04487483</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Exploring the Impact of a Sleep App on Sleep Quality</brief_title>
  <official_title>Exploring the Impact of a Sleep App on Sleep Quality: a Randomised Controlled Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University College, London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of California, Los Angeles</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University College, London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Sufficient sleep is crucial for good health, yet a third of UK adults have impaired sleep&#xD;
      quality. Therefore, there is urgent need for population-level sleep interventions. However,&#xD;
      many sleep interventions (such as Cognitive Behavioural Therapy for Insomnia) are resource&#xD;
      intensive and not widely available. Research demonstrates that smartphone interventions are&#xD;
      an effective way to reach the wider population. However, many commercially available&#xD;
      smartphone sleep applications focus on one technique, and hence do not tailor to the diverse&#xD;
      needs of individuals. A new sleep app offers six different techniques, allowing individuals&#xD;
      to shape their own journey to improved sleep quality. The investigators aim to test the sleep&#xD;
      app's efficacy and gather user experience data to allow app optimisation. The study is a&#xD;
      two-arm pilot randomised control trial (RCT). After recruitment and screening, baseline&#xD;
      measurements will be taken: subjective sleep quality data will be collected using the&#xD;
      Insomnia Severity Index (ISI) and the Consensus Sleep Diary from all participants and&#xD;
      objective accelerometry data via an Oura Ring (worn on finger for a week) on a subsample of&#xD;
      participants. Participants will then be randomised to the intervention or control.&#xD;
      Intervention participants will be given free use of the sleep app for 3 months. Controls will&#xD;
      be informed that they will not receive access to the intervention and will be asked to&#xD;
      abstain from using any other digital sleep-based intervention during the 3 months. All&#xD;
      participants will be given the ISI after each month and will be given the Consensus Sleep&#xD;
      Diary to fill out for one week again after 2 months. The planned Oura ring follow-up after 2&#xD;
      months for participants who wore the Oura ring at baseline has been cancelled due to&#xD;
      COVID-19. User engagement will be assessed using the Digital Behaviour Change Intervention&#xD;
      Engagement Scale. Telephone interviews will also be conducted with 20-30 participants to&#xD;
      explore experience of using the app, how the comparison group felt about being allocated to&#xD;
      the control group and how the COVID-19 pandemic may have affected their sleep and other&#xD;
      measures of the study. Change in self-reported sleep will be the primary outcome and&#xD;
      qualitative user data secondary. Appropriate tests (such as an ANOVA or linear regression&#xD;
      controlling for baseline sleep and testing for effect of group when using continuous data)&#xD;
      and thematic analysis of qualitative interview data will be conducted.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 13, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 15, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 17, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The study is a two-arm pilot RCT where participants are randomly assigned to either the intervention or control group.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in self-reported sleep quality</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline/1 month/2 months/3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using the Insomnia Severity Index. The scores from the Insomnia Severity Index range from 0 to 28, where higher scores indicate worse sleep quality.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in self-reported sleep</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline/2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using the Consensus Sleep Diary.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Engagement with the sleep app</measure>
    <time_frame>Once a week for 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Participant's responses to the Digital Behaviour Change Intervention Engagement Scale (only applicable to participants in the intervention group). The scores from the Digital Behaviour Change Intervention Engagement Scale range from 8 to 56, where higher scores indicate higher engagement.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Telephone interview qualitative user data</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Participant's qualitative responses to telephone interview questions about their experience of using the sleep app, how the comparison group felt about being allocated to the control group, and how the COVID-19 pandemic may have affected their sleep and other measures of the study (on a subsample of 20-30 participants).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">101</enrollment>
  <condition>Sleep</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sleep App</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this condition will receive full free access to the &quot;Pro&quot; version of the sleep app and asked to use the app every day for three months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this condition will be asked to continue their life as normal and abstain from downloading or using any sleep aid and/or sleep tracker app for three months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sleep App</intervention_name>
    <description>A sleep app offering 6 evidence based techniques to improve sleep (such as Cognitive Behavioural Therapy for Insomnia, Progressive Muscle Relaxation and Mindfulness Meditation), allowing for a personally tailored journey of sleep aids within the app.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sleep App</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 18 or above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Own a smartphone&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having a clinically diagnosed sleep disorder for which they are currently being&#xD;
             treated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Frequent use (once a week or more) of any sleep medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Enrolment on another sleep trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being unwilling to cease usage of other sleep apps for the duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Abi Fisher</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University College, London</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University College London</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>WC1E 7HB</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 22, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 7, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 7, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 11, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University College, London</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Abi Fisher</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Physical Activity and Health</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Pilot study and the investigators plan to disseminate findings in a peer reviewed publication and a masters thesis.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>August 7, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/83/NCT04487483/SAP_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

