<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4496">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04708457</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ANZIC-RC/AB V3.1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04708457</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The REDEEM Pilot Study: A Feasibility RCT of Early ECMO in Severe Acute Respiratory Infection, Including COVID-19, WHO</brief_title>
  <acronym>REDEEM</acronym>
  <official_title>A Pilot Feasibility RCT of Early ECMO to DE-sedate, Extubate, and Mobilise in Severe Acute Respiratory Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Australian and New Zealand Intensive Care Research Centre</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Alfred</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Australian and New Zealand Intensive Care Research Centre</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients who are critically ill in intensive care with moderate to severe acute respiratory&#xD;
      infection often require mechanical ventilation. Prolonged ventilation increases the risk of&#xD;
      lung damage and other side effects as a result of long term use of sedation medications.&#xD;
      Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation therapy (ECMO), is a relatively new technology that uses&#xD;
      a pump to remove blood from the body and return it back to the body after adding oxygen and&#xD;
      removing carbon dioxide. ECMO can be used on patients who require mechanical ventilation and&#xD;
      can function without the need for ongoing mechanical ventilation, thus reducing risk of side&#xD;
      effects. Participants will be randomised into either the early ECMO therapy group or will&#xD;
      continue standard treatment involving mechanical ventilation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This pilot study aims to determine if a phase 3 Randomised Control Trial (RCT) is feasible&#xD;
      for the use of early ECMO therapy to treat patients with Severe Acute Respiratory Infection&#xD;
      (SARI). The success of the study will be determined by the successful recruitment of adult&#xD;
      patients, that there is a difference between ECMO utilisation between groups and that there&#xD;
      are no safety issues.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Prolonged mechanical ventilation is standard care for SARI and is associated with long term&#xD;
      functional complications: Current guidelines recommend that mechanical ventilation, including&#xD;
      protective lung strategies such as low tidal volumes, low peak pressures and titrated peak&#xD;
      end expiratory pressure (PEEP), should form the mainstay of treatment for severe respiratory&#xD;
      failure. While these strategies have been shown to reduce mortality, the application of&#xD;
      invasive mechanical ventilation in the setting of SARIs may in fact propagate ongoing lung&#xD;
      injury. Ventilator induced lung injury (VILI) results from the high pressures, over&#xD;
      distension, and shear injury used by the ventilator to maintain gas exchange. Invasive&#xD;
      ventilation can lead to secondary bacterial infection from poor clearance of sputum by&#xD;
      sedated patients. And &quot;air hunger&quot; - the rapid and deep injurious breathing pattern by&#xD;
      patients with severe lung injury - can lead to patient self-induced lung injury (P-SILI).&#xD;
      Taken together, these factors can lead to a vicious cycle - the VILI Vortex - where lung&#xD;
      damage leads to shrinkage of the functional lung unit, reduced compliance, higher&#xD;
      transpulmonary pressures, worsening inflammation, further shrinkage, and ultimately even more&#xD;
      severe lung damage and gas exchange failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Current strategies to facilitate mechanical ventilation include prolonged heavy sedation to&#xD;
      assist patient-ventilator synchronization, and neuromuscular blockade (to prevent any&#xD;
      spontaneous respiratory effort), often for weeks at a time. These interventions, plus the&#xD;
      underlying lung damage, contribute to significant long term complications, including&#xD;
      immobility and ICU myopathy, delirium, respiratory muscle weakness and tracheostomy, leading&#xD;
      to significant delays in ICU and hospital discharge, rehabilitation, and return to home.&#xD;
      Survivors of prolonged mechanical ventilation have been shown to have high rates of&#xD;
      functional disability, immobility, psychological injury, and reduced health related quality&#xD;
      of life - and these outcomes can persist for up to 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thus, conventional treatment with mechanical ventilation, deep sedation, and/or neuromuscular&#xD;
      paralysis is likely to adversely impact long term functional outcomes in patients with SARI.&#xD;
      There is a clear unmet need for novel strategies that facilitate safe lung ventilation, while&#xD;
      also limiting the intensity and duration of these interventions and complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ECMO is an external machine that oxygenates the blood in addition to a mechanical ventilator.&#xD;
      Venous cannulae drain blood out of the body and return it back after an oxygenator adds&#xD;
      oxygen and removes carbon dioxide. Venovenous (VV) ECMO supports patients with respiratory&#xD;
      failure, by providing the body with sufficient oxygen and by removing all the carbon dioxide&#xD;
      (CO2) in the blood (causing a respiratory alkalosis), which reduces the drive to breathe and&#xD;
      permits &quot;lung rest&quot;. Resting the lungs avoids VILI, reduces pulmonary and systemic&#xD;
      inflammation, and reduces extra-pulmonary organ dysfunction. Traditionally, ECMO was employed&#xD;
      very late in the course of the disease as a &quot;rescue therapy&quot;, when patients already had&#xD;
      severely damaged lungs, due to fears of complications such as bleeding that would worsen the&#xD;
      patients multi organ failure. However advances in modern ECMO technology mean it is&#xD;
      associated with a lower complication rate (&lt;10% cannula site bleeding) and its use has&#xD;
      doubled over the last five years. ECMO now offers the ideal platform to prevent&#xD;
      ventilator-induced lung damage in patients that are less severely unwell, and earlier in the&#xD;
      disease process, while also reducing the need for heavy sedation and/or neuromuscular&#xD;
      blockade. It facilitates safe de-sedation without VILI as well as extubation, and&#xD;
      physiotherapy-which is difficult to carry out adequately when a patient is sedated and&#xD;
      ventilated. All these factors have been associated with improved long term health outcomes&#xD;
      for patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study aims to determine if a large RCT looking at use of early ECMO to treat patients&#xD;
      with SARI is feasible.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants who have SARI and have been mechanically ventilated for at least 5 days.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The number of participants who have SARI and have been mechanically ventilated for at least 5 days but no more than 7 days are eligible to participate in this study. The number of patients that meet this criteria will help assess the feasibility of this study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Mechanical Ventilation Complication</condition>
  <condition>Severe Acute Respiratory Infection</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Early ECMO</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Early ECMO therapy for patients who have SARI and have been mechanically ventilated for 5-7 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with SARI who are already mechanically ventilated will continue to receive the standard intensive care therapies, including ECMO if required.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>VV-ECMO</intervention_name>
    <description>Early use of VV-ECMO in SARI patients.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Early ECMO</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Laboratory confirmed severe acute respiratory infection (SARI) pneumonitis such as&#xD;
             Coronavirus disease of 2019 (COVID-19) or influenza, AND&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ≥5 days of mechanical ventilation, AND&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Moderate to severe respiratory failure as shown by either the ratio of partial&#xD;
             pressure of oxygen and the fracture of inspired oxygen (PaO2:FiO2 Rati)o &lt;150 for &gt;6&#xD;
             hours OR the potential of hydrogen (pH) &lt;7.30 with carbon dioxide (CO2) &gt;50mmHg for 6&#xD;
             hours, AND&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Are unable to pass a spontaneous breathing trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥70 year old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Extubation likely in next 24-48 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Duration of mechanical ventilation ≥7days&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. ≥2 non-pulmonary organ failures (as scored by the sequential oxygen failure assessment&#xD;
             (SOFA) score)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Need for immediate VV ECMO (as per EOLIA (research study) criteria*)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Requirement for VA ECMO&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Clinical frailty or ≥2 major comorbidities&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. The physician deems the study is not in the patient's interest&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  EOLIA criteria (P:F &lt;50 for 3 hours, P:F&lt;80 for 6 hours, pH&lt;7.25 with carbon&#xD;
                  dioxide partial pressure (PCO2) &gt;60 for &gt;6 hours&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aidan Burrell, MBBS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The Alfred</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Anne Mather</last_name>
    <phone>99030151</phone>
    <email>anne.mather@monash.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Tony Trapani</last_name>
    <phone>0409798892</phone>
    <email>tony.trapani@monash.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Alfred Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Melbourne</city>
        <state>Victoria</state>
        <zip>3004</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Meredith Young</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Aidan Burrell</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Charite Universitatmedizin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berlin</city>
        <zip>10117</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Inka Gotthardt</last_name>
      <phone>+49 30 450 553 485</phone>
      <email>inka.gotthardt@charite.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Intensive Care Unit</keyword>
  <keyword>ECMO</keyword>
  <keyword>Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation</keyword>
  <keyword>Mechanical ventilation</keyword>
  <keyword>Early ECMO</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

