<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1957">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04732819</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2012002872</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>3U54AG063546-02S2</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>Pro00048627</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04732819</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Improving COVID-19 Vaccine Uptake in Nursing Homes</brief_title>
  <official_title>IMPACT-C: Improving Vaccine Uptake in Skilled Nursing Facilities</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Brown University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute on Aging (NIA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hebrew SeniorLife</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Insight Therapeutics, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>New York University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Brown University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      SARS-CoV-2 vaccine, now being administered to skilled nursing facility (SNF) residents and&#xD;
      staff, has highly variable acceptance between facilities. The investigators need to develop&#xD;
      and disseminate effective strategies to increase vaccination immediately. For SNF residents&#xD;
      and staff, the investigators will develop and implement a scalable multi-pronged intervention&#xD;
      that educates, builds trust and supports the informed consent process aimed to increase&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will conduct a cluster randomized trial to compare the effect of electronic&#xD;
      messaging and education (i.e., usual care) versus a multi-pronged 'high touch' intervention&#xD;
      to reduce vaccine hesitancy in skilled nursing facility staff and residents among a random&#xD;
      sample of facilities across four SNF chains. As part of the 'high touch' intervention, the&#xD;
      investigators will identify and train local opinion leaders. The investigators will offer&#xD;
      these leaders assistance through real-time support for questions and provide consenting&#xD;
      specialists. During the second wave of vaccination, the investigators will provide the&#xD;
      intervention facilities with positive reinforcement for staff and will identify local&#xD;
      champions to garner support and empowerment of staff. Finally, in the intervention&#xD;
      facilities, the investigators will provide additional funds to support COVID-19 testing, in&#xD;
      order that facilities have access to enough testing kits for patient or staff who develops&#xD;
      symptoms following vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This trial will be randomized within four SNF chains in order to evaluate the effect of a&#xD;
      multi-pronged strategy to improve SARS-CoV-2 vaccine acceptance among direct care staff and&#xD;
      long-stay nursing home residents. In four chains, eligible facilities will undergo&#xD;
      randomization between usual care versus adding the 'high touch' intervention, implemented in&#xD;
      two waves. Randomization and roll out of the intervention will occur at the facility level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesize that: (1) the intervention will increase vaccination of SNF&#xD;
      residents by at least 10 percentage points versus facilities usual care alone; (2) staff of&#xD;
      SNFs with the intervention will have at least a 10 percentage point greater vaccine uptake of&#xD;
      vaccine than staff in SNFs that do not participate in the high touch intervention; and (3)&#xD;
      within intervention SNFs, improvements in vaccine uptake will be similar across staff and&#xD;
      resident race/ethnicities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigators will conduct a cluster randomized trial to compare the effect of electronic&#xD;
      messaging and education (i.e., usual care) versus a multi-pronged &quot;high touch&quot; intervention&#xD;
      to reduce vaccine hesitancy in skilled nursing facility (SNF) staff and residents among a&#xD;
      random sample of facilities across four SNF chains. This will be a cluster randomized trial&#xD;
      where the intervention is applied at the facility level. The primary interest is the effect&#xD;
      of this intervention on SNFs that are characterized by having a relatively high proportion of&#xD;
      residents who are Black or Latinx. The four SNF chains that have been selected have already&#xD;
      given assent to participate in this trial. The facilities will then be stratified into three&#xD;
      categories based on racial composition of residents:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. &lt; 25% Black and Latinx residents&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. 25-40% Black and Latinx residents&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. &gt; 40% Black and Latinx residents&#xD;
&#xD;
      Facilities will undergo constrained randomization within each chain and stratum to ensure&#xD;
      that the proportion of Black and Latinx residents is balanced across the intervention arms. A&#xD;
      total of 60 SNFs will be randomized to the intervention, allocated proportionally across the&#xD;
      strata. The SNFs that were removed due to institutional instability will be compared&#xD;
      separately to the control arm to assess potential bias due to selection into the study. Staff&#xD;
      in facilities randomized to intervention arm will be informed by corporate leadership that&#xD;
      they will be participating in a program to maximize COVID 19 vaccination among staff and&#xD;
      residents. They will not be informed that this is part of a trial. Individual SNFs will be&#xD;
      randomized to the intervention or usual care; randomization will be stratified by chain and&#xD;
      by the proportion of minority residents based on three groups: &lt;25%, 25%-40%, &gt;40%. The&#xD;
      research implementation team will not be masked to facility assignment. However, the PIs, the&#xD;
      lead statistician, and programmers will be masked.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All SNFs in the four chains are prepared to receive electronic messaging and educational&#xD;
      material (i.e., usual care) through the American Health Care Association (AHCA). Within the&#xD;
      four SNF chains that have agreed to participate in the trial, the investigators will ask the&#xD;
      CEOs if there are any facilities that should be excluded due to leadership instability or&#xD;
      other inability to participate in the multi-pronged intervention. Remaining facilities will&#xD;
      be randomized to additionally receive the multi-pronged intervention versus continuing usual&#xD;
      care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The entire trial will take place over 11-15 weeks: each facility in the high touch&#xD;
      intervention will be involved in approximately 1-3 week start up activities, 6-8 weeks of&#xD;
      vaccine administration (three scheduled deliveries for vaccine approximately 3-4 weeks a&#xD;
      part), and 4 weeks of data collection. Facilities in the usual care group will follow the&#xD;
      same timeline for enrollment and data collection. During the start-up period in the high&#xD;
      touch facilities, the research team works with the leadership and opinion leaders in each SNF&#xD;
      to optimize program roll-out within each unique environment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Among four SNF chains, the research team will randomize eligible facilities to receive an&#xD;
      additional &quot;high touch&quot; intervention. These high touch facilities will receive the electronic&#xD;
      messaging and educational material described above. In addition, these facilities will work&#xD;
      with the research team on the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Facility Opinion Leader. At each intervention facility, the research team will work with&#xD;
           the facility administration to identify local opinion leaders among nursing assistants&#xD;
           (NA), nursing, dietary, and housekeeping. The opinion leaders will participate in the&#xD;
           following activities: 1) Participate in an initial informational meeting with the&#xD;
           research team and other facility opinion leaders; 2) Identify a local champion who could&#xD;
           help participate in educational materials; 3) Participate in the social media messaging&#xD;
           described in the Electronic Messaging section above; 4) Engage the research team for&#xD;
           support and problem solving.&#xD;
&#xD;
           The research team will invite all of the opinion leaders to participate in a one hour&#xD;
           virtual informational meeting with members of the research team and other facility&#xD;
           leaders. Meetings will be organized by discipline (e.g., nursing, dietary) and SNF&#xD;
           chain. The research team will offer a few make-up sessions for staff who are unable to&#xD;
           attend. During these meetings, basic information on vaccine safety and efficacy will be&#xD;
           covered, leaving the majority of time for an open question and answer session. These&#xD;
           sessions will NOT be recorded. Opinion leaders who participate in these meetings will be&#xD;
           given a gift card for their time.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Our research team will provide opinion leaders with direct contact information (email&#xD;
           and phone number) of the research team so that they may ask questions during&#xD;
           implementation. Insight Therapeutics will also work to identify a support team that can&#xD;
           offer guidance and problem solve during implementation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Consenting Specialist. Through Insight Therapeutics, the research team will employ&#xD;
           external staff members to facilitate the clinical consent for vaccination process. Each&#xD;
           facility will make up to ten referrals of residents who were not vaccinated during the&#xD;
           first of the three available vaccine dates to the consenting specialists. Consenting&#xD;
           specialists will contact each proxy, review risks and benefits of the vaccine, and&#xD;
           answer questions. The research team will provide a 1-800 number for proxies who have&#xD;
           additional questions/hesitancy and will offer a group Zoom call for interested proxies&#xD;
           to review risks and benefits. As indicated, this consenting process will be a clinical&#xD;
           consent for the vaccination itself - not a study-specific informed consent process to&#xD;
           participate in research. The investigators are seeking a waiver of informed consent for&#xD;
           the overall intervention study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Building Trust Locally. The facility opinion leaders will be encouraged to identify well&#xD;
           respected persons in the community (e.g., minister, teacher, government leader) who are&#xD;
           willing to provide a message promoting trust in the vaccine. Through Insight&#xD;
           Therapeutics, the research team will reach out to these leaders and coordinate the video&#xD;
           messages and implementation plan. Messages will be distributed widely within a facility&#xD;
           by email, website, text and/or social media. Further, the research team will prepare the&#xD;
           community leaders to serve as an additional support for the facility opinion leaders&#xD;
           during implementation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Positive Reinforcement. The research team will create and distribute buttons, T-shirts,&#xD;
           and masks that promote awareness about vaccination (e.g., Ask me about the COVID-19&#xD;
           vaccine! OR Vaccinated for You!). These items will be distributed through facility&#xD;
           leadership at each facility, with recommendations to give each staff member these&#xD;
           goodies when vaccinated.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Testing Supplies. The research team will provide funds to each facility in the high&#xD;
           touch intervention arm, that the facility may use to acquire additional COVID-19 testing&#xD;
           kits. This will enable frequent testing of any residents and staff that experience&#xD;
           symptoms following vaccination. Given the cost of most point-of-care testing kits, these&#xD;
           funds will support the cost of approximately 200 test kits. The research team will&#xD;
           suggest that facilities follow the CDC recommendations for testing following&#xD;
           vaccination. The research team will additionally facilitate kits for facilities that are&#xD;
           experiencing difficulty securing the test kits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The high touch intervention will be implemented in two waves. The first cycle of vaccine&#xD;
      administration, the research team will focus on identifying opinion leaders and positive&#xD;
      reinforcement. During the second round, the research team will add building trust locally, a&#xD;
      consenting specialist, and testing supplies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nursing home data are collected prior to the start of the study for descriptive purposes and&#xD;
      to inform the development of a list of eligible facilities for recruitment. These include&#xD;
      elements from Nursing Home Compare, including: the number of beds, hospital-based, special&#xD;
      care dementia unit, nursing and nursing assistant hours/resident/day, and number of&#xD;
      deficiencies on state inspections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Resident data is already being collected for all facilities within the four chains as part of&#xD;
      the RADx-UP supplement. Existing data transfer agreements from all four chains have been&#xD;
      signed and authorized. The research team plans to use data from the electronic medical&#xD;
      record, as well as data from the Minimum Data Set (MDS) for this study. Resident&#xD;
      characteristics will be obtained during baseline only (that is during the 3 months before the&#xD;
      vaccine is first delivered to the facility) whereas vaccination data will be obtained during&#xD;
      the 6-8 weeks of implementation and 4 weeks of follow-up. Resident and outcome data will be&#xD;
      aggregated at the level of the facility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis that will be tested is whether facilities that receive the high touch&#xD;
      multi-pronged intervention will achieve a greater number of staff and residents vaccinated as&#xD;
      compared with facilities randomized to usual care. The research team will use an&#xD;
      intention-to-treat approach as the primary analytic approach, including all facilities that&#xD;
      were randomized to the intervention regardless of implementation of the intervention&#xD;
      components. Additional exploratory analyses will estimate a complier average causal effect to&#xD;
      assess the effect of the intervention on those SNFs who fully engage in the intervention. A&#xD;
      similar approach will be used to determine the effect of the high touch intervention on staff&#xD;
      vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The logistic model described for the primary analysis will be extended to include race and&#xD;
      ethnicity indicators as well as interaction terms, to better understand if the treatment&#xD;
      effect is heterogeneous across different subgroups of residents.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 4, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 19, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 19, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient vaccine counts</measure>
    <time_frame>15 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>A binary measure (Yes or No) indicating whether a long stay nursing home resident received any dose of a SARS-CoV-2 vaccine, identified by the electronic medical records (EMR) within the 15-week study period.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Staff vaccine counts</measure>
    <time_frame>15 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>A binary measure (Yes or No) indicating whether a staff member received any dose of a SARS-CoV-2 vaccine, identified by the facility log within the 15-week study period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">22500</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19 Vaccines</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Facilities in the 'usual care' arm will be offered electronic messaging and education regarding the COVID-19 vaccine. This material stems from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) and AMDA - The Society for Post-Acute and Long-Term Care Medicine (AMDA) resources and represents a suggested approach to reduce vaccine hesitancy in staff and residents/proxies (e.g., legally authorized representatives, powers of attorney). This electronic quality improvement (QI) material will be developed as part of a QI initiative and disseminated by the American Health Care Association (AHCA) to the SNF chains and using social media.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>High touch</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Facilities in the 'high touch' arm will receive the same electronic messaging and educational material as in the 'usual care' arm but will receive an additional high touch multi-pronged behavioral intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>High touch multi-pronged behavioral intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>In this intervention, facilities will work with our research team to accomplish the following:&#xD;
Identify and engage a Facility Opinion Leader.&#xD;
Employ Consenting Specialists to facilitate the clinical consent for vaccination process.&#xD;
Engage well respected persons in the community who are willing to provide messages that promote trust in the vaccine and that will be distributed widely within a facility by email, website, text and/or social media.&#xD;
Distribute buttons, T-shirts, and masks that promote awareness about vaccination (e.g., Ask me about the COVID-19 vaccine!) through facility leadership.&#xD;
Acquire additional COVID-19 testing kits using funds provided by our research team.</description>
    <arm_group_label>High touch</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residents: Long-stay residents who have been in one of our participating skilled&#xD;
             nursing facilities (SNFs) for at least 100 days and who are alive on the date that the&#xD;
             second round of vaccines is available.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Staff: Staff providing care in one of our participating skilled nursing facilities for&#xD;
             at least 2 shifts per week for at least 3 weeks in the previous month.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Facilities: Facilities with evidence of institutional instability at time of&#xD;
             recruitment or otherwise determined by the SNF CEO to be unable to participate in the&#xD;
             high touch intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residents: Residents who have been in one of our participating SNFs for less than 100&#xD;
             days or who died or were transferred between the baseline date and the date the second&#xD;
             vaccine was delivered to the facility.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Staff: Staff who are not a &quot;usual&quot; provider within the SNF (for instance, a visiting&#xD;
             hospice provider).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sarah D Berry, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Hebrew SeniorLife</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sarah D Berry, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>617-971-5355</phone>
    <email>SarahBerry@hsl.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Vincent Mor, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>401-863-2959</phone>
    <email>Vincent_Mor@brown.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mission Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33629</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Cheri Kauset</last_name>
      <phone>813-367-3350</phone>
      <email>ckauset@missionhealthcommunities.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nexion Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sykesville</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21784</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Meera Riner</last_name>
      <phone>410-552-4800</phone>
      <email>mriner@nexion-health.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vetter Senior Living</name>
      <address>
        <city>Elkhorn</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68022</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Shari Terry</last_name>
      <phone>402-895-8165</phone>
      <email>sterry@vhsmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Genesis HealthCare</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kennett Square</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19348</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carolyn Blackman, MD</last_name>
      <phone>610-444-6350</phone>
      <email>carolyn.blackman@genesishcc.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Skilled Nursing Facilities</keyword>
  <keyword>Nursing Homes</keyword>
  <keyword>Health Personnel</keyword>
  <keyword>Vaccine Hesitancy</keyword>
  <keyword>Vaccine Uptake</keyword>
  <keyword>Vaccine Acceptance</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data will be aggregated at the level of the facility. We will provide aggregated data to the RADx-UP Coordination and Data Collection Center (CDCC); however, given the nature of this data it will not be identifiable or linkable. The CDCC will facilitate cross-site pooling of data, whenever possible, and create a publicly available dataset with this information.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The IPD and supporting documentation will be available through the CDCC within 6 months of the completion of the trial.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Staff and patient data will be aggregated at the level of the facility. This data will be shared with the RADx-UP CDCC, who plans to make a central database that will ultimately be publicly available.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

