<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1678">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04396067</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>COVID-19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04396067</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Aerosol Combination Therapy of All-trans Retinoic Acid and Isotretinoin as A Novel Treatment for Inducing Neutralizing Antibodies in COVID -19 Infected Patients Better Than Vaccine : An Innovative Treatment</brief_title>
  <acronym>Antibodies</acronym>
  <official_title>Aerosol Combination Therapy of All-trans Retinoic Acid and Isotretinoin as A Novel Treatment for Inducing Neutralizing Antibodies in COVID -19 Infected Patients Better Than Vaccine : An Innovative Treatment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kafrelsheikh University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Damietta University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kafrelsheikh University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Aerosol Combination therapy of All-trans retinoic acid and Isotretinoin as A novel Treatment&#xD;
      for Inducing Neutralizing Antibodies in COVID -19 Infected Patients better than vaccine : An&#xD;
      innovative Treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mahmoud ELkazzaz(1),Tamer Haydara(2), Mohamed Abdelaal(3), Ahmed M. Kabel(4), Abedelaziz&#xD;
      Elsayed(5) ,Yousry Abo-amer(6) ,Hesham Attia(7)&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Department of chemistry and biochemistry, Faculty of Science, Damietta University,Egypt.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Department of Internal Medicine,Faculty of Medicine, Kafrelsheikh University, Egypt&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Department of Cardiothoracic Surgery,Faculty of Medicine, Kafrelsheikh University, Egypt&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Department of Clinical Pharmacy, Faculty of Medicine , Tanta University,Egypt.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Department of Pharmaceutical Biotechnology, Faculty of Pharmacy,Tanta University,Egypt.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Hepatology,Gastroenterology and Infectious Diseases Department, Mahala Hepatology&#xD;
           Teaching Hospital,Egypt&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Department of Immunology and Parasitology, Faculty of Science, Cairo University, Egypt.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Study Chair ((( Dr.Tamer Hydara))), Department of Internal Medicine,Faculty of&#xD;
                Medicine, Kafrelsheikh University, Egypt Contact: Dr.Tamer Hydara-Tel:&#xD;
                00201142233340 Mail: tamerhydara@yahoo.com&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Principal Investigator ((( Mahmoud Elkazzaz))), Faculty of Science, Damietta&#xD;
                University,GOEIC,Egypt Contact:Tel: 00201090302015 Mail:&#xD;
                mahmoudramadan2051@yahoo.com&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Study coordinator ((Prof/Dr Mohamed Abdelaal)), Department of Cardiothoracic&#xD;
                Surgery,Faculty of Medicine, Kafrelsheikh University, Egypt Contact:Tel:&#xD;
                00201001422577 Mail: Malaal2@hotmail.com&#xD;
&#xD;
      Abstract&#xD;
&#xD;
      The pandemic of COVID-19 which is caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2&#xD;
      (SARS-COV-2) has infected over 20,000,000 people causing over 700,000 deaths .It has no&#xD;
      currently approved treatments. In this clinical study we confirm that combination of&#xD;
      isotretinoin and All trans retinoic acid can be used in the treatment of SARS-COV-2 better&#xD;
      than vaccine according to the findings of previous studies and researches. Retenoic acid can&#xD;
      induce neutralizing antibodies in case of corona virus (COVID-19) by restoring inhebited and&#xD;
      exhausted T cells via inhebiting both CD13 and Angiotensin-converting enzyme-2 (ACE2). CD13&#xD;
      amyloid receptor which abundantly overexpressed on cell surface of lymphocyte, Dentritic&#xD;
      cell, Macrophage, granulocytes and monocytes and is ubiquitous in respiratory tract&#xD;
      epithelial cells, smooth muscle cells, fibroblasts, epithelial cells in the kidneys and small&#xD;
      intestine, activated endothelial cells, and platelets In addition inhibing of&#xD;
      Angiotensin-converting enzyme-2 (ACE2) , Angiotensin T1 protein and Angiotensin II-mediated&#xD;
      intracellular calcium release pathway which is responsible for COVID-19 cell fusion and&#xD;
      entry.ACE2-expressing cells are prone to SARS-CoV-2 infection as ACE2 receptor facilitates&#xD;
      cellular viral entry and replication. A study demonestrated that patients with hypertension&#xD;
      and diabetes mellitus may be at higher risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection, as these patients are&#xD;
      often treated with ACE inhibitors (ACEIs) or angiotensin II type-I receptor blockers (ARBs),&#xD;
      which have been previously suggested to increase ACE2 expression.Butisotretinoin was found to&#xD;
      be the strongest down-regulator of ACE 2 receptors.and this will give hope for diabetic&#xD;
      patients or patients with hypertension infected with COVID-19.Therefore we suggest that&#xD;
      Retinoic Acid will help in inhabiting factors which may enhance antibody dependent&#xD;
      enhancement (ADE), A phenomenon caused by covid-19 which expected to lead to failure of&#xD;
      vaccination specially in case of corona virus (covid-19) as a hyper mutatated COVID-19&#xD;
      antigens can lead to (ADE) phenomenon in which IgG antibodies facilitate viral entry and&#xD;
      fusion with infected cell through uptake of the virus-IgG complex via the Fc receptors and&#xD;
      later viral fusion with antigen presenting cells like Dentric cells, macrophages and B cells&#xD;
      via FcR , through the neonatal FcR instead of antibodies induced viral agglutination and this&#xD;
      is known as antibody dependent enhancement (ADE)(2) ADE can hamper vaccine development, as a&#xD;
      vaccine may cause the production of antibodies which, via ADE, worsen the disease the vaccine&#xD;
      is designed to protect against. ADE in COVID-19 infection can be caused by high mutation rate&#xD;
      of the gene that encodes spike (S) protein. In this clinical study we suggest that Hyper&#xD;
      mutated spike protein ,lymphopenia, and impaired dentreic cells all these factors can help in&#xD;
      and lead to delayed antibodies response and appearing after a period of covid -19 symptoms&#xD;
      onset and this may be responsible for antibody dependent enhancement (ADE)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Keywords: COVID 2019 , Retinoic acid, Lymphopenia ,T Cells, Dentric cells , ADE, Vaccine&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 2, , randomized (1:1:1), placebo-controlled, 2-weeks, proof-of-concept study&#xD;
      to evaluate the safety and tolerability as well as the mechanistic effect of oral&#xD;
      administration of potent inhibitor of neutrophil elastase(Inhaled All trans retinoic acid and&#xD;
      inhaled isotretinoin in subjects infected with COVID -19&#xD;
&#xD;
      Unfortunately, all of the vaccinated monkeys treated with the Oxford vaccine known as ChAdOx1&#xD;
      nCoV-19, is undergoing human trials in Britain.became infected when challenged as judged by&#xD;
      recovery of virus genomic RNA from nasal secretions,&quot; said Dr William Haseltine, a former&#xD;
      Harvard Medical School professor who had a pivotal role in the development of early HIV/Aids&#xD;
      treatments. and in general future COVID-19 vaccination which depends on inactivated viral&#xD;
      vaccine will be restricted to healthy people with strong immunity and It will not be given to&#xD;
      patients with History of contact with a SARS-CoV-2 infection (positive in nucleic acid test).&#xD;
      In addition to the COVID-19 viral antigens lead to stimulate antibodies formation of IgM in&#xD;
      acute phase and IgG type in chronic phase which is facilitate viral entry and fusion with&#xD;
      infected cell through uptake of the virus-IgG complex via the Fc family of receptors and&#xD;
      later viral fusion with antigen presenting cells like macrophages, B cells, monocytes via FcR&#xD;
      family, and vascular endothelium through the neonatal Fc receptor (nFcR) instead of&#xD;
      antibodies induced viral agglutination and this is known as antibody dependent enhancement&#xD;
      (ADE)(2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are various hypotheses on how ADE happens and there is a likelihood that more than one&#xD;
      mechanism exists. In one such pathway, some cells of the immune system lack the usual&#xD;
      receptors on their surfaces that the virus uses to gain entry, but they have Fc receptors&#xD;
      that bind to one end of antibodies. The virus binds to the antigen-binding site at the other&#xD;
      end, and in this way gains entry to and infects the immune cell. Dengue virus can use this&#xD;
      mechanism to infect human macrophages, if there was a preceding infection with a different&#xD;
      strain of the virus, causing a normally mild viral infection to become life-threatening.(3)&#xD;
      An ongoing question in the COVID-19 pandemic is whether-and if so, to what extent-COVID-19&#xD;
      receives ADE from prior infection with other coronaviruses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ADE can hamper vaccine development: ADE can hamper vaccine development, as a vaccine may&#xD;
      cause the production of antibodies which, via ADE, worsen the disease the vaccine is designed&#xD;
      to protect against. Vaccine candidates for Dengue virus and feline infectious peritonitis&#xD;
      virus (a cat coronavirus) had to be stopped because they elicited ADE.(4)&#xD;
&#xD;
      ADE in coronavirus infection can be caused by high mutation rate of the gene that encodes&#xD;
      spike (S) protein. A thorough analysis of amino acid variability in SARS-CoV-2 virus&#xD;
      proteins, that included the S-protein, revealed that least conservative amino acids are in&#xD;
      most exposed fragments of S-protein including receptor binding domain (RBD).(5) Delayed&#xD;
      antibodies response and secretion after covid -19 symptoms onset is responsible for antibody&#xD;
      dependent enhancement (ADE)&#xD;
&#xD;
      A study shows the first seroconversion day of IgA was 2 days after onset of initial symptoms,&#xD;
      and the first seroconversion day of IgM and IgG was 5 days after onset. The positive rate of&#xD;
      antibodies in the 183 samples was 98.9%, 93.4% and 95.1%, for IgA, IgM and IgG, respectively.&#xD;
      The seroconversion rate for IgA, IgM or IgG was 100% 32 days after symptom onset. According&#xD;
      to the cumulative seroconversion curve, the median conversion time for IgA, IgM and IgG was&#xD;
      13, 14 and 14 days, respectively. (6)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Because this immune response takes a while to show up, antibody tests will be negative for&#xD;
      those newly infected with COVID-19, which is why they're not used for diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      &quot;If it's the beginning of the infection, you don't pick it up, it's something that only&#xD;
      develops later,&quot; Dr. Melanie Ott, a virologist and immunologist at the Gladstone Institutes&#xD;
      and a professor at the University of California, San Francisco.(7)&#xD;
&#xD;
      So, the principal investigator expects that delayed antibody response and delayed&#xD;
      immunoglobulin class switching are the main reason for antibodies infectivity and&#xD;
      non-specificity in the highly mutated covid-19 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
      High-affinity IgG antibodies may efficiently resolve Covid -19 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
      The more than 100 COVID-19 vaccines in development mainly focus on another immune response:&#xD;
      antibodies. These proteins are made by B cells and ideally latch onto SARS-CoV-2 and prevent&#xD;
      it from entering cells. T cells, in contrast, thwart infections in two different ways. Helper&#xD;
      T cells spur B cells and other immune defenders into action, whereas killer T cells target&#xD;
      and destroy infected cells. The severity of disease can depend on the strength of these T&#xD;
      cell responses(1).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Studies on humoral responses to infections have been mainly geared toward the production of&#xD;
      high-affinity IgG antibodies that efficiently resolve an infection. It has been well&#xD;
      recognised, however, that humoral immune response to infection can be a double-edged sword&#xD;
      that either serves as a protective mechanism to resolve the infection or aggravates the&#xD;
      tissue injury, e.g. IgG response causes fatal acute lung injury by skewing&#xD;
      inflammation-resolving response in SARS .(8)&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the case of respiratory infection, while IgM and IgG isotypes have been the primary&#xD;
      emphasis in characterising immunity, mucosal and systemic IgA responses that may play a&#xD;
      critical role in the disease pathogenesis, have received much less attention.(9),(11)&#xD;
&#xD;
      High neutrophils in covid-19 infection may be the reason of delayed antibody response and&#xD;
      severe complications&#xD;
&#xD;
      Humoral immune response, especially production of neutralizing antibody, plays a protective&#xD;
      role by limiting infection at later phase and prevents reinfection in the future. In&#xD;
      SARS-CoV, both T and B cell epitopes were extensively mapped for the structural proteins, S,&#xD;
      N, M and E protein.(12) A limited serology details of SARS-CoV-2 was reported. In a&#xD;
      preliminary study, one patient showed peak specific IgM at day 9 after disease onset and the&#xD;
      switching to IgG by week 2.25 Interestingly, sera from 5 patients of confirmed COVID-19 show&#xD;
      some cross-reactivity with SARS-CoV, but not other coronavirus. Furthermore, all sera from&#xD;
      patients were able to neutralize SARS-CoV-2 in an in vitro plaque assay, suggesting a&#xD;
      possible successful mounting of the humoral responses.(13) Whether the kinetic/titer of&#xD;
      specific antibody correlates with disease severity remains to be investigated.(14)&#xD;
&#xD;
      In severe cases of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), viral pneumonia progresses to&#xD;
      respiratory failure. Neutrophil extracellular traps (NETs) are extracellular webs of&#xD;
      chromatin, microbicidal proteins, and oxidant enzymes that are released by neutrophils to&#xD;
      contain infections. However, when not properly regulated, NETs have potential to propagate&#xD;
      inflammation and microvascular thrombosis - including in the lungs of patients with acute&#xD;
      respiratory distress syndrome. While elevated levels of blood neutrophils predict worse&#xD;
      outcomes in COVID-19, the role of NETs has not been investigated. We now report that sera&#xD;
      from patients with COVID-19 (n = 50 patients, n = 84 samples) have elevated levels of&#xD;
      cell-free DNA, myeloperoxidase(MPO)-DNA, and citrullinated histone H3 (Cit-H3); the latter&#xD;
      two are highly specific markers of NETs.(15)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Neutrophils Are Sophisticated Cells Able to Adapt to Changing Inflammation&#xD;
&#xD;
      Neutrophils are not simple bags of enzymes sent to kill pathogens before the adaptive immune&#xD;
      cells move in. In fact, they are able to respond to altered inflammatory status; neutrophils&#xD;
      can produce cytokines , alter their gene expression during inflammation and throughout&#xD;
      &quot;aging&quot; and survive for significantly longer than traditionally thought, with one study&#xD;
      placing lifespan from bone marrow at 5.4 days . As a consequence, neutrophils are able to&#xD;
      adapt to changing conditions and direct other cells' behaviour-a task which they can perform&#xD;
      with some sophistication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are a number of murine models in which the T cell responses can be exacerbated by&#xD;
      depleting neutrophils, implying they have a regulatory role . This suppression of T cell&#xD;
      responses by neutrophils requires close contact and development of an immunological synapse&#xD;
      -perhaps as the mediators thought responsible, reactive oxygen species and H2O2 do not&#xD;
      diffuse far. Uptake of apoptotic or necrotic neutrophils also inhibits DC antigen&#xD;
      presentation and co-stimulation, resulting in reduced T cell responses-a situation which can&#xD;
      be exploited by pathogens. For example, neutrophils capture L. major and are subsequently&#xD;
      engulfed by DCs, suppressing antigen presentation and T cell priming&#xD;
&#xD;
      NE was also shown to inhibit maturation and function of dendritic cells, including expression&#xD;
      of the costimulatory molecules CD40, CD80 and CD86 Inflammatory Lung Secretions Inhibit&#xD;
      Dendritic Cell Maturation and Function via Neutrophil Elastase.(16)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inhibitor of elastase in covid-19 infection :&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Alvelestat was developed as treatment for lung diseases like Chronic Obstructive&#xD;
           Pulmonary Disease. Alevelestat works by blocking certain proteins in the body that are&#xD;
           responsible for inflammation and damage to the lungs that can lead to COPD symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Alvelestat Inhibitor of elastase stimulate murine B lymphocyte differentiation into IgG-&#xD;
           and IgA-producing cells via immunoglobulin class switching and inducing also known as&#xD;
           isotype switching, isotypic commutation or class-switch recombination (CSR), is a&#xD;
           biological mechanism that changes a B cell's production of immunoglobulin from one type&#xD;
           to another, such as from the isotype IgM to the isotype IgG&#xD;
&#xD;
           A study demonstrated that depletion of neutrophils improves the production of mucosal&#xD;
           IgA and IgG after sublingual immunization with Bacillus anthracis edema toxin as&#xD;
           adjuvant. These past studies also demonstrated that an inverse correlation exists&#xD;
           between the number of neutrophils and production of IgA by B cells. Using specific&#xD;
           inhibitors of elastase, we addressed whether the elastase activity of neutrophil could&#xD;
           be the factor that interferes with production of IgA and possibly other immunoglobulin&#xD;
           isotypes. We found that murine splenocytes and mesenteric lymph node cells cultured for&#xD;
           5 days in the presence of neutrophil elastase inhibitors secreted higher levels of IgG&#xD;
           and IgA than cells cultured in the absence of inhibitors and also,This treatment&#xD;
           however, increased the frequency of CD4+ T cells.(17) As a mucosal targeted virus,&#xD;
           SARS-CoV-2 would be expected to generate secretory IgA (sIgA) and induce strong mucosal&#xD;
           immunity. Indeed, the mucosal anti-viral immunity has been shown to result in part from&#xD;
           the IgA-mediated interactions with the pathogenic microorganisms to prevent pathogens&#xD;
           from adhering to the cell surface.(17) Upregulated IgA production may be the result of&#xD;
           increased levels of TGF-β and IL-10 that promote antibody switching in SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
           infection.(17) A study reported that depletion of neutrophils before systemic injection&#xD;
           of vaccines increased the magnitude of antigen-specific CD4+ T cell responses, and the&#xD;
           levels of antigen-specific serum IgG responses .(18)&#xD;
&#xD;
           Alvelestat and Sivelestat were found to stimulate AID mRNA synthesis. The NE inhibitors&#xD;
           also induced expression of BAFF, APRIL and IL-10 mRNA in a dose-dependent manner.&#xD;
           Neutrophil elastase and the related serine proteases cathepsin G and proteinase 3, were&#xD;
           shown to regulate cytokine responses through activation or degradation of cytokines,&#xD;
           cytokine receptors, or toll-like receptor .(18) This is consistent with our finding that&#xD;
           NE inhibitors stimulate IL-10 expression, but also BAFF and APRIL in cultures of&#xD;
           splenocytes. IL-10 was reported to regulate expression of AID for induction of Ig CSR.&#xD;
           (19) and it is wellestablished that IL-10 facilitates Ig class switching for production&#xD;
           of IgA (20). Thus, these data suggest that NE inhibitors stimulate antibody production&#xD;
           through stimulation of AID and inhibition of the activation/degradation of cytokines and&#xD;
           cytokine receptors by elastase. NE was also shown to inhibit maturation and function of&#xD;
           dendritic cells, including expression of the costimulatory molecules CD40, CD80 and CD86&#xD;
           .(21). Thus, the presence of neutrophil inhibitors may have promoted the maturation of&#xD;
           dendritic cells and their expression BAFF and APRIL and perhaps costimulatory molecules&#xD;
           (i.e., CD40) for enhanced antibody production. Although Alvelestat and Sivelestat are&#xD;
           specific NE inhibitors, one should consider that they might also inhibit related&#xD;
           elastase-like enzymes. In this regard, activated human B cells were reported to express&#xD;
           a trypsin-like serine protease on the cell surface .(22) Concluding remarks It was&#xD;
           previously shown that neutrophil peptide defensins enhance IgG, but not IgA responses&#xD;
           against nasally co-administered vaccine antigens .(23) Here, the study have shown that&#xD;
           the serine protease activity of neutrophil elastase, and possibly other serine protease&#xD;
           such as B cell elastase, also participate in the regulation of B cell biology and&#xD;
           adaptive immunity. However, unlike neutrophil peptide defensins, NE negatively regulate&#xD;
           differentiation of B lymphocytes into IgG and IgA secreting cells. The presence of AID&#xD;
           generally improves antibody-based immunity.(24).&#xD;
&#xD;
           High Neutrophils in COVID -19 infected patients are capable of causing severe damage to&#xD;
           the lung tissue by releasing toxic proteases and reactive oxygen species if not&#xD;
           counterbalanced by the antiproteases.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. All-trans retinoic acid (RA) has beneficial effects when used in a variety of&#xD;
           inflammatory skin conditions. In a study, the authors found that RA inhibited superoxide&#xD;
           anion production and proteolytic enzyme release by human and rat neutrophils.&#xD;
           Concomitantly, the authors found that RA-treated neutrophils were less able than&#xD;
           untreated neutrophils to injure endothelial cells in culture even though the adhesion of&#xD;
           the RA-treated neutrophils to endothelial cell monolayers was not diminished. Inhibition&#xD;
           of cytotoxicity occurred over the same range of concentrations that inhibited oxygen&#xD;
           radical formation and protease release. In additional studies, it was observed that&#xD;
           pretreatment of endothelial cells with RA-induced resistance to subsequent injury by&#xD;
           activated neutrophils. Finally, in vivo studies showed that pretreatment of rats for 3&#xD;
           days with RA (1-10 mg/day, IP) reduced the degree of injury in the lungs and skin sites&#xD;
           after treatment with bovine serum albumin and antibodies to bovine serum albumin in the&#xD;
           reverse-passive Arthus reaction. Thus, RA can modulate neutrophil-mediated endothelial&#xD;
           cell injury by an effect on both the neutrophils and their target cells. Together, these&#xD;
           effects may underlie the reduction in immune complex-mediated injury seen in&#xD;
           experimental animals. The beneficial effects that retinoids have in a variety of&#xD;
           inflammatory skin diseases may likewise be a reflection of their effects on the&#xD;
           physiology of both neutrophils and endothelial cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Oral retinyl palmitate or retinoic acid corrects mucosal IgA responses toward an intranasal&#xD;
      influenza virus vaccine in vitamin a deficient mice. Retinoids inhibit inflammatory TH17 T&#xD;
      cell responses, promote regulatory T cell (Treg) responses, and regulate expression of&#xD;
      toll-like receptors (TLRs) .(57)&#xD;
&#xD;
      So, the principal investigator expects that retinoic acid will be effective in covid -19&#xD;
      patients better than the other neutrophil elastase inhibitor like Alvelestat because Attia et&#xD;
      al (2018) demonstrated that Sivelestat reduced secretion of IgM in a dose-dependent manner ,&#xD;
      IgM type of antibodies which is very important in viral neutralization and on the other hand&#xD;
      retinoic acid stops neutrophil-mediated endothelial cell injury by an effect on both the&#xD;
      neutrophils and their target cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Seconed drug is Isotretinoin(13cis RA) and ATRA may be able to inhibit COVID 2019 infection&#xD;
      via inducing the antiviral immunity and this is discussed as follow :&#xD;
&#xD;
      A study demonstrated that 13 cis retinoic is used in treating Emphysema (emphysema is a lung&#xD;
      condition that causes shortness of breath), Since an effective immune response against viral&#xD;
      infections depends on the activation of cytotoxic T cells that can clear infection by killing&#xD;
      virus-infected cells , boosting the numbers and function of T cells in COVID-19 patients is&#xD;
      critical for successful recovery. A recent study reported that the 82.1% of COVID-19 cases&#xD;
      displayed low circulating lymphocyte counts. A CoV infects macrophages, and then macrophages&#xD;
      present CoV antigens to T cells. This process leads to T cell activation and differentiation,&#xD;
      including the production of cytokines associated with the different T cell subsets (Th17),&#xD;
      followed by a massive release of cytokines for immune response amplification. The continued&#xD;
      production of these mediators due to viral persistence has a negative effect on NK, and CD8 T&#xD;
      cell activation.(25)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recent study of 522 COVID patients and 40 healthy controls from two hospitals in Wuhan, China&#xD;
      demonstrated that T cell numbers are negatively correlated to serum IL-6, IL-10 and TNF-α&#xD;
      concentration, with patients in decline period showing reduced IL-6, IL-10 and TNF-α&#xD;
      concentrations and restored T cell counts. T cells from COVID-19 patients have significantly&#xD;
      higher levels of the exhausted marker programmed cell death protein(PD-1) as compared to&#xD;
      health controls. Moreover, increasing PD-1 and Tim-3 expression on T cells could be seen as&#xD;
      patients progressed from prodromal to overtly symptomatic stages, further indicative of T&#xD;
      cell exhaustion. T cell exhaustion is a progressive loss of effector function due to&#xD;
      prolonged antigen stimulation, characteristic of chronic infections. Dendritic cell&#xD;
      inhibition is connected to exhaustion of CD8+ T cell polyfunctionality during chronic&#xD;
      hepatitis C virus infection. CD8 T cells produce very effective mediators to clear&#xD;
      nCoV2019.(26)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dendritic cells (DCs) play a key role in innate immune and adaptive immune responses. As the&#xD;
      strongest antigen presenting cells in the organism, they effectively stimulate the activation&#xD;
      of T lymphocytes and B lymphocytes, thus combining innate and adaptive immunity. Immature DCs&#xD;
      have strong migration ability, and mature DCs can effectively activate T cells in the central&#xD;
      link of startup, regulation, and maintenance of immune responses. Thus, once the maturation&#xD;
      process of DCs is blocked, it directly affects the initiation of subsequent adaptive immune&#xD;
      response. MERS-CoV-2 is able to affect human dendritic cells and macrophages in-vitro&#xD;
      .Productive replication of Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus in monocyte-derived&#xD;
      dendritic cells modulates innate immune response.(27)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Another study proposed that C -C chemokine receptor type 4 (CCR4) contributes to T cell lung&#xD;
      homing imprinting. It was found that lung DCs induce the expression of CCR4 on T cells. Lung&#xD;
      DCs-activated T cells traffic more efficiently into the lung and protect against influenza&#xD;
      more effectively compared with T cells activated by DCs from other tissues. Lim and&#xD;
      colleagues suggested that CXCR4 plays a role in CD8+ T cell migration to airway tissues.(28)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dendritic cell inhibition is connected to exhaustion of CD8+ T cell polyfunctionality during&#xD;
      chronic hepatitis C virus infection. CD8 T cells produce very effective mediators to clear&#xD;
      nCoV2019.(29)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Presence of RA in different tissues is very imprtant for immune induction and fighting viral&#xD;
      infection, for example, RA is present at high concentrations in the small intestine due to&#xD;
      metabolizing dietary vitamin A by gut epithelial cells. In this local environment, RA&#xD;
      activate and primes dendritic cells (DCs) to become CD103+ DCs that produce RA.3, 4CD103+ DCs&#xD;
      are migratory cells that activate naive T cells in mesenteric lymph nodes to become effector&#xD;
      T cells that contribute to both intestinal homeostasis and immunity.and also RA is an&#xD;
      important signal that induces IgA-producing B cells. The gut homing T cells and B cells play&#xD;
      essential roles in protecting the digestive tract from pathogens.(30) Retinoic acid (atRA)&#xD;
      can inhibit the spontaneous apoptosis of activated human T lymphocytes in vitro. 13-cis RA&#xD;
      activates Th2 cytokine production Enhanced circulating dendritic cell numbers.(40)&#xD;
&#xD;
      So, according to this previous studies the principal investigator suggests that T cells&#xD;
      lymphopenia and exhaustion may be resulted by Dendritic cells (DCs) infection and inhibition&#xD;
      by MERS-CoV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Retinoic acid has profound effects on cellular proliferation and differentiation. Moreover,&#xD;
      it has been reported that ATRA exhibits both anti-inflammatory and immunoregulatory effects.&#xD;
      Recent studies have shown that FOXP3 expression and the immune function of Regulatory T cells&#xD;
      (Tregs ) can be enhanced by ATRA in the immune system of both patients and mic.13Retinoic&#xD;
      acid (RA) is produced by a number of cell types, including macrophages and dendritic cells,&#xD;
      which express retinal dehydrogenases that convert vitamin A to its main biologically active&#xD;
      metabolite, all-trans RA. All-trans RA binds to its nuclear retinoic acid receptors that are&#xD;
      expressed in lymphoid cells and act as transcription factors to regulate cell homing and&#xD;
      differentiation. RA production by CD103+ dendritic cells and alveolar macrophages functions&#xD;
      with TGF-b to promote conversion of naive T cells into Foxp3+ regulatory T cells and,&#xD;
      thereby, maintain mucosal tolerance.(50) So, principal investigator expects high inducing of&#xD;
      Dendritic cells (DCs) by retinoic acid treatment which will lead to T cells activation and&#xD;
      migration with less exhaustion phenomenon.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Researchers from Wenzhou, China looked at clinical laboratory features including lipid levels&#xD;
      of patients with COVID 19. They found dramatic reductions in the cholesterol levels of&#xD;
      patients infected with COVID 19, compared with healthy controls .The study provides data to&#xD;
      suggest that cholesterol levels decline quite rapidly during the early stages of infection&#xD;
      and increase as the patient starts to recover. Therefore, indicating that cholesterol may&#xD;
      have an important role to play in defending the body against such infections According to our&#xD;
      protocol depending on previous studies the principal investigator demonstrated that there is&#xD;
      a strong relation between immune system and cholesterol levels . :-&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cellular cholesterol is a component of the plasma membrane and is also essential in cell&#xD;
      proliferation. Regulation of intracellular cholesterol levels has been proposed as a&#xD;
      mechanism to regulate T cell and macrophages proliferation. Intracellular cholesterol level&#xD;
      is regulated by two competing pathways, cholesterol uptake and efflux, and ABCA1 plays a&#xD;
      major role in the cholesterol efflux pathway. The ATRA induces ABCA1 expression and&#xD;
      ABCA1-dependent cholesterol efflux in activated primary human CD4+ T cells implying that RA&#xD;
      could affect T cell functions by regulating the cellular cholesterol levels.(51) ATRA&#xD;
      upregulates ABCA1 expression only in activated CD4+ T cells, indicating that induction of&#xD;
      ABCA1 by ATRA and 13 cis Retinoic Acid may play an important role in immune response.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Retinoic acid and liver X receptor agonist synergistically inhibit HIV infection in CD4+ T&#xD;
      cells by up-regulating ABCA1-mediated cholesterol efflux.(52)(53)&#xD;
&#xD;
      RA also acts directly on macrophages at both mucosal sites and other immunological sites.&#xD;
      AtRA modulates peritoneal macrophage activation by endotoxin and IFN-γ by suppressing TNF&#xD;
      production and nitric oxide (NO) synthesis .In addition, at RA inhibits the expression of&#xD;
      PGE2 and COX-2 and the release of TNF, which are induced by bacterial lipopolysaccharide&#xD;
      (LPS) in murine peritoneal macrophages .(54)&#xD;
&#xD;
      A study reported recently that substance (ATRA) have preventive effects on pulmonary fibrosis&#xD;
      by inhibiting IL-6-dependent proliferation and TGF-β1-dependent trans differentiation of lung&#xD;
      fibroblasts. Also, another studies demonstrated that 13-cis-retinoic acid and other retinoid&#xD;
      analogs inhibit IL-1-induced IL-6 production and that this effect is analog-specific and, at&#xD;
      least partially, transcriptionally mediated. This effect was dose-dependent with an IC50 of&#xD;
      10(-7) M RA and significant inhibition being noted with doses of RA as low as 10(-8) M. IL-10&#xD;
      production was inhibited by ATRA administration.(55)&#xD;
&#xD;
      A study demonstrated that TLR3(-/-), TLR4(-/-), and TRAM(-/-) mice are more susceptible to&#xD;
      SARS-CoV than wild-type mice but experience only transient weight loss with no mortality in&#xD;
      response to infection. In contrast, mice deficient in the TLR3/TLR4 adaptor TRIF are highly&#xD;
      susceptible to SARS-CoV infection, showing increased weight loss, mortality, reduced lung&#xD;
      function, increased lung pathology, and higher viral titers . New studies showed that the&#xD;
      high level of IFN-α/β produced from the TLR3-IRF3/IRF7 pathway and IFN-β is the reason for&#xD;
      inhibiting DENV replication. 13Cis retinoic Acid induced significant upregulation of&#xD;
      toll-like receptor 3 (TLR3) resulting in an immune response to dsRNA intermediate which can&#xD;
      be partially generated during CoV-2 replicationTLR3 sensitized by dsRNA and cascades of&#xD;
      signaling pathways (IRFs and NFκB activation, respectively) are activated to produce type I&#xD;
      IFNs.(56)&#xD;
&#xD;
      .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Oral retinyl palmitate or retinoic acid corrects mucosal IgA responses toward an intranasal&#xD;
      influenza virus vaccine in vitamin a deficient mice. Retinoids inhibit inflammatory TH17 T&#xD;
      cell responses, promote regulatory T cell (Treg) responses, and regulate expression of&#xD;
      toll-like receptors (TLRs) .(57) In vitro treatment of normal human monocytes with all-trans&#xD;
      retinoic acid (ATRA) down-regulates TLR-2 expression (58), but this effect has not been&#xD;
      examined in patients treated with systemic retinoids. Isotretinoin (13-cis retinoic acid;&#xD;
      13-cis RA) is the only drug capable of inducing a long-term or permanent remission of acne;&#xD;
      however, the mechanisms leading to this durable response are unknown. Given the role of TLR-2&#xD;
      in initiating immune responses to P. acnes, we hypothesized that down-regulation of TLR-2 on&#xD;
      monocytes and/or the induction of Treg responses in vivo may represent mechanisms by which&#xD;
      isotretinoin exerts its long-term effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Isotretinoin(13cis RA) may be able to inhibit COVID 2019 entry via down regulation of ACE2 ,&#xD;
      AT1 protein and Ang II-mediated intracellular calcium release rather than inhibition of&#xD;
      interleukin-6 (IL-6) and this is discussed as follow :&#xD;
&#xD;
      Many authors misunderstands the difference between ARBs, which block ATR1 receptors and the&#xD;
      hypothesised drug that could block the COVID-19 binding site on ACE2 receptor, which is&#xD;
      totally different from ATR1 and 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The COVID-19 pandemic caused by SARS-COV-2 has infected over 2,000,000 people causing over&#xD;
      150,000 deaths.(59) A key host cellular protein required for the virus entry is&#xD;
      angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) whose expression has been demonstrated in many tissues&#xD;
      including alveolar epithelial type II cells in lungs, oral mucosa and intestine, heart,&#xD;
      kidney, endothelium and skin. ACE2-expressing cells can act as home cells and are prone to&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 infection as ACE2 receptor facilitates cellular viral entry and replication.(60) A&#xD;
      study demonestrated that patients with hypertension and diabetes mellitus may be at higher&#xD;
      risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection, as these patients are often treated with ACE inhibitors (ACEIs)&#xD;
      or angiotensin II type-I receptor blockers (ARBs), which have been previously suggested to&#xD;
      increase ACE2 expression.(61) In another study by Sinha et al who analyzed a publicly&#xD;
      available Connectivity Map (CMAP) dataset of pre/post transcriptomic profiles for drug&#xD;
      treatment in cell lines for over 20,000 small molecules, isotretinoin was the strongest&#xD;
      down-regulator of ACE 2 receptors. On the other hand, they found 6 drugs in CMAP that are&#xD;
      currently being investigated in clinical trials for treating COVID-19 (chloroquine,&#xD;
      thalidomide, methylprednisolone, losartan, lopinavir and ritonavir, from clinicaltrials.gov),&#xD;
      none of which was found to significantly alter ACE2 expression (P&gt;0.1) Moreover, another&#xD;
      study demonstrated that isotretinoin is a Potential papain like protease (PLpro) inhibitors&#xD;
      which is a protein encoded by SARS-CoV-2 genes and considered one of the proteins that should&#xD;
      be targeted in COVID-19 treatment by performing target-based virtual ligand screening.As&#xD;
      Principal Investigator discussed before that (13cRA) is the strongest down-regulator of ACE2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The principal investigator expects that 13cRA can inhibit or dowenrgulat ACE2 by direc&#xD;
      interaction and binding with the transmembrane ACE2, Suggesting its therapeutic potential in&#xD;
      preventing the entry of COVID 2019 to the host cell.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previous studies on the related severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV) and&#xD;
      SARS-CoV FP FP have shown that calcium (Ca2+) plays an important role for fusogenic activity&#xD;
      via a Ca2+ binding pocket with conserved glutamic acid (E) and aspartic acid (D)&#xD;
      residuesdemonstrated that intracellular Ca2+ enhances MERS-CoV WT PPs infection by&#xD;
      approximately two-fold and that E891 is a crucial residue for Ca2+interaction. Electron spin&#xD;
      resonance revealed that this enhancement could be attributed to Ca2+ increasing MERS-CoV FP&#xD;
      fusion-relevant membrane ordering. Intriguingly, isothermal calorimetry titration showed that&#xD;
      MERS-CoV FP binds one Ca2+, as opposed to SARS-CoV FP which binds to two Ca2+ ion.(62)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Angiotensin II increases the intracellular calcium activity in podocytes of the intact&#xD;
      glomerulus. The L-type Ca2+ channel blocker nicardipine did not influence the Ang II-mediated&#xD;
      [Ca2+] increase and it has been postulated that SARS-CoV-2 binding to ACE2 may attenuate&#xD;
      residual ACE2 activity, skewing the ACE/ACE2 balance to a state of heightened angiotensin II&#xD;
      activity leading to pulmonary vasoconstriction and inflammatory and oxidative organ damage,&#xD;
      which increases the risk for acute lung injury (ALI). AngII via AT1 receptors upregulates&#xD;
      many proinflammatory genes, such as vascular cell adhesion molecule-1 (VCAM-1), intercellular&#xD;
      adhesion molecule-1 (ICAM-1), interleukin-6 (IL-6).30 but 13cis RA specifically&#xD;
      down-regulated the AT1 protein in a dose- and time-dependent manner. Down-regulation of the&#xD;
      AT1 expression leads to reduced AngII-mediated intracellular calcium release Similarly with&#xD;
      receptor down-regulation, Treatment with 13cRA resulted in a significant reduction in AT1&#xD;
      mRNA .(63)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Finally, the principal investigator expects that Isotretinoin will help in antibody induction&#xD;
      against COVID-19 via inducing different types of antiviral immune factors and also,&#xD;
      decreasing of COVID -19 hyper mutation by blocking its ACE2 receptors and preventing the&#xD;
      virus from cell entry and replication and this will give the immune system time to recognize&#xD;
      COVID -19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>lung injury score</measure>
    <time_frame>at 7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of lung injury score decreased or increased after treatment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum levels of CRP, ESR ,IL-1,IL-6,TNF and Type I interferon</measure>
    <time_frame>at day 7 and 14 after randimization</time_frame>
    <description>Serum levels of CRP, ESR ,IL-1,IL-6,TNF and Type I interferon</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum level of COVID19 RNA</measure>
    <time_frame>at day 7 and 14</time_frame>
    <description>Serum level of COVID19 RNA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>d-dimers</measure>
    <time_frame>within 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>less than 250 ng/mL, or less than 0.4 mcg/mL of blood sample</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute lymphocyte counts</measure>
    <time_frame>at day 7 and 14 after randimization</time_frame>
    <description>lymphocyte counts</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The immune correlates of protection against future exposure to SARS-CoV-2</measure>
    <time_frame>within 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the immune correlates of viral clearance (Antibody Titres sufficient for viral clearance and neutralizing ) against future exposure to SARS-CoV-2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunological profile</measure>
    <time_frame>within 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of CD4 HLA-DR+ and CD38+, CD8 lymphocytes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total duration of mechanical ventilation, ventilatory weaning and curarisation</measure>
    <time_frame>at day 7 and 14</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of adverse event related to immunoglobulins</measure>
    <time_frame>at day 14</time_frame>
    <description>Kidney failure, hypersensitivity with cutaneous or hemodynamic manifestations, aseptic meningitis, hemolytic anemia, leuko-neutropenia, transfusion related acute lung injury (TRALI)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>IgG, IgA and IgM against COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>at day 7 and 14</time_frame>
    <description>serum levels of IgG and IgM against COVID-19</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ACE2 expression in patients with COVID-19 infection</measure>
    <time_frame>at day 7 and 14</time_frame>
    <description>ACE2 expression in patients with COVID-19 infection</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All cause mortality rate [</measure>
    <time_frame>at day 7 and 14</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ventilation free days</measure>
    <time_frame>at 14 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ICU free days</measure>
    <time_frame>at 14 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">360</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>COVID 19 infected patients will receive one dose daily of Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid in gradual doses increases froms 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled 13 cis retinoic acid therapy for 14 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>All trans retinoic acid</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>COVID 19 infected patients will receive one dose daily of Aerosolized All trans retinoic acid in gradual doses increases froms 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled All trans retinoic acid therapy for 14 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>4 Placebo tablets twice daily by mouth for 2 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid</intervention_name>
    <description>The infected patients will receive Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid in gradual in one dose increases froms 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled 13 cis retinoic acid therapy for 14 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Aerosolized All trans retinoic acid</intervention_name>
    <description>The infected patients will receive Aerosolized All trans retinoic acid in gradual one dose increases froms 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled all trans retinoic acid therapy for 14 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>All trans retinoic acid</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo is a pill or tablet that does not contain any study drug.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adult SARI patients with 2019-ncov infection confirmed by PCR; Absolute value of&#xD;
        lymphocytes &lt; 0. 6x 109/L; Severe respiratory failure within 48 hours and requires&#xD;
        admission to ICU. (severe respiratory failure was defined as PaO2/FiO2 &lt; 200 mmHg and was&#xD;
        supported by positive pressure mechanical ventilation (including non-invasive and invasive&#xD;
        mechanical ventilation, PEEP&gt;=5cmH2O))&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Age &lt; 18 Pregnant Allergic to experimental drugs and patients have the following&#xD;
        conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Hypercholesterolemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Hypertriglyceridemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Liver disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Renal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Sjögren syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Depressive disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Body mass index less than 18 points or higher than 25 points&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Contraindications for hormonal contraception or intrauterine device.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Autoimmune diseases A history of organ, bone marrow or hematopoietic stem cell&#xD;
             transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients receiving anti-hcv treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Permanent blindness in one eye&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. History of iritis, endophthalmitis, scleral inflammation or retinitis 15-90 days of&#xD;
             retinal detachment or eye surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. The competent physician considered it inappropriate to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. HIV infection or other immunodeficiency or with an absolute neutrophil count ≤1.0 ×&#xD;
             109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Abnormal liver biochemistry (alanine aminotransferase, aspartate aminotransferase,&#xD;
             gamma-glutamyl transferase) &gt;1.5 × upper limit of normal or total bilirubin &gt; upper&#xD;
             limit of normal (unless Gilbert's disease with normal conjugated bilirubin)&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Any of the following laboratory abnormalities are present at baseline:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count &lt;150×109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum albumin ≤ 3.5 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  INR ≥1.2&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CPK ≥ ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Significant liver fibrosis as evidenced by Fibrosis-4 (FIB-4) score &gt;3.25&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. History of hypersensitivity to retinoic acid or any of its excipients or the class of&#xD;
             neutrophil elastase inhibitors Known hypersensitivity to medications used in the study&#xD;
             procedures (e.g. midazolam, fentanyl, and lidocaine for bronchoscopy)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>M.Sc. Mahmoud Elkazzaz, B.Sc of biochemistry</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Damitta University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr.Tamer Hydara, Lecturer of Internal Medicine</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Kafr Elshiekh University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mahmoud Elkazzaz, B.Sc of biochemistry</last_name>
    <phone>00201090302015</phone>
    <email>mahmoudramadan2051@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Dr.Tamer Hydara, Lecturer of Internal Medicine</last_name>
    <phone>00201142233340</phone>
    <email>tamerhydara@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 20, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Damietta University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mahmoud Ramadan mohamed Elkazzaz</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID 2019</keyword>
  <keyword>Isotretinoin</keyword>
  <keyword>Endosomal toll-like receptor 3</keyword>
  <keyword>T Cells</keyword>
  <keyword>IFN type1</keyword>
  <keyword>AT1</keyword>
  <keyword>ACE2</keyword>
  <keyword>Alvelestat</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tretinoin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Isotretinoin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

