<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3969">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04402957</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AB002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04402957</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>LSALT Peptide vs. Placebo to Prevent ARDS and Acute Kidney Injury in Patients Infected With SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Multicenter, Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Proof of Concept Study of LSALT Peptide as Prevention of Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome (ARDS) and Acute Kidney Injury in Patients Infected With SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Arch Biopartners Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Arch Biopartners Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the proportion of subjects alive and free of respiratory failure (e.g. need for&#xD;
      non-invasive or invasive mechanical ventilation, high flow oxygen, or ECMO) and free of the&#xD;
      need for continued renal replacement therapy (RRT) on Day 28. The need for continued RRT at&#xD;
      Day 28 will be defined as either dialysis in the past 3 days (Day 26, 27, or 28) or an eGFR&#xD;
      on Day 28 &lt;10 mL/min/1.73 m2.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a global, multicenter, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, proof of concept&#xD;
      study of LSALT peptide as prevention of acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) and acute&#xD;
      kidney injury in patients infected with SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19). Following screening and after&#xD;
      establishing baseline parameters such as lung and renal function, clinical chemistries,&#xD;
      coagulation, hematology, and urinalysis, and satisfying all inclusion and exclusion criteria,&#xD;
      patients will be randomized to one of two blinded treatment regimens:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. 100 mL of 5 mg IV LSALT peptide infusion over 2 hours daily&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. 100 mL drug-free IV saline infusion over 2 hours daily.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thirty (30) patients will be randomized to active drug (LSALT peptide) and 30 patients will&#xD;
      be randomized to matching placebo. Patients and, if necessary, the Legal Authorized&#xD;
      Representative (LAR), the Investigational Staff, and the Sponsor and its representatives will&#xD;
      not know the randomization schemata. The Pharmacist at the site will be unblinded and prepare&#xD;
      drug/placebo for injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This double-blind, placebo-controlled, proof-of-concept Phase 2 study is designed to evaluate&#xD;
      LSALT peptide compared with placebo in a defined number of adult hospitalized patients with&#xD;
      the diagnosis of COVID-19. This is a 1:1 randomization comparing 5 mg LSALT peptide daily&#xD;
      with matching placebo. LSALT peptide or drug-free saline will begin immediately once the&#xD;
      patient meets all inclusion/exclusion criteria at the start of hospitalization and followed&#xD;
      with daily physical exams, blood chemistries, coagulation, and hematology; ECGs will be&#xD;
      recorded at Baseline, Day 3, and EOS. Patients will be maintained on standard of care,&#xD;
      including prophylaxis or treatment for VTE, per institutional guidelines throughout the&#xD;
      study. Questionnaires (APACHE II, SOFA, Berlin Definition, and modified Medical Research&#xD;
      Council Dyspnea Scale) will be assessed at Baseline, when clinically indicated, and at EOT&#xD;
      and EOS. Dosing will end on Day 14, or at cure or increasing severity of ARDS, or at death.&#xD;
      Patients will be followed clinically, and safety and efficacy measures will be recorded at&#xD;
      end of study (EOS; Day 28) or death, whichever occurs first.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Duration of therapy will be a maximum of 14 days. Patients will be maintained on the standard&#xD;
      of care for the treatment of COVID-19 as defined by the institutional guidelines.&#xD;
      Co-morbidities and concomitant medications will be reviewed daily and documented in the&#xD;
      patient's eCRF. The risk of venous thromboembolism (VTE), a potential consequence of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 infection, will be assessed daily and prophylaxis will be included as standard of&#xD;
      care for every patient. Please refer to antithrombotic therapy in patients with COVID-19&#xD;
      (COVID-19 Treatment Guidelines Panel, 12-May-2020).&#xD;
&#xD;
      A Data and Safety Monitoring Board (refer to the DSMB Charter) will evaluate patients on a&#xD;
      continuing basis for primarily safety assessments but also the adequacy of treatment based&#xD;
      upon clinical data of the patient, target drug concentrations, and data obtained from the&#xD;
      AB001 PK study in healthy subjects to offer recommendations to the Sponsor. In the absence of&#xD;
      adverse events or any safety issues during the course of study, the DSMB may recommend&#xD;
      continuance or suspension of the study due to futility or safety issues. The DSMB will meet&#xD;
      at least monthly if not more frequently based upon enrollment throughout the study period.&#xD;
      Per protocol, at no time will patients be dosed for more than 14 days of therapy. The DSMB&#xD;
      Charter will outline all processes for changes to the protocol and protocol design prior to&#xD;
      the first patient being enrolled into study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 14, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Development of Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome (ARDS) and Other Organ Injuries</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the efficacy of intravenous LSALT peptide plus standard of care to prevent the progression of COVID-19 to mild, moderate or severe ARDS, acute kidney injury, cardiomyopathy, acute liver injury, coagulopathy, or death in patients infected with SARS-CoV-2 compared with placebo plus standard of care.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ventilation-free days</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>High-frequency oscillatory ventilation, with its rapid delivery of low tidal volumes and a respiratory rate in the range of 60 to 900 breaths/minute, has also been utilized in ARDS patients.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time on nasal cannula or oxygen masks</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Oxygen therapy provided as non-invasive therapy for ARDS patients.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>28 day mortality - all cause and attributable</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>28 day mortality - all cause and attributable</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ICU and hospitalization length of stay (days)</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>ICU and hospitalization length of stay (days)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SARS-CoV2 testing</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Swab (nasopharyngeal, nasal, throat, sputum, or lower respiratory tract) at baseline (Day 1) and every 3 days thereafter until eradication → virologic clearance rate</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Need and duration for extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO)</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO) is often used for severe ARDS to allow lung healing/repair and reverse respiratory failure.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vasopressor free days</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Vasopressor free days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Radiographic pulmonary assessments</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Chest X-rays performed at Baseline, Day 3, at clinical improvement, and end-of-treatment (EOT) and study (EOS) to determine presence of bilateral opacities.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in modified Medical Research Council (mMRC) dyspnea and Sequential Organ Failure Assessment (SOFA) scores</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Change in daily mMRC dyspnea and SOFA scores (0 to 4) with 4 being the most severe outcome</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of non-lung disorders</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of other organ (non-lung) disorders</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measures of liver dysfunction</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Change in liver function tests (ALT, AST, and total bilirubin levels) from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measures of kidney dysfunction</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Change in SCr and eGFR from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measures of cardiac dysfunction</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Change in highly-sensitive troponin (hs-troponin) from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measures of coagulopathies</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline ACT, aPTT, and/or PT/INR levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in immunogenic responses</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Change in baseline antiviral immunoglobulins (IgG, IgM) at EOS.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Healthcare outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in total healthcare costs from admission to discharge between treatment groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Molecular changes in pro-inflammatory pathways</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Change in serum cytokines including IL-1α, IL-1ß, IL-1ra, IL-5, IL-6, IL-8, IL-12, TNFα, CXCL10/IP10, MCP-3, and ferritin drawn at the same time as LSALT peptide levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics of LSALT peptide</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Pharmacokinetics of LSALT peptide over the study period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID</condition>
  <condition>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Sars-CoV2</condition>
  <condition>Acute Kidney Injury</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>100 mL drug-free IV saline infusion over 2 hours daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>LSALT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>100 mL of 5 mg IV LSALT peptide infusion over 2 hours daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>LSALT peptide</intervention_name>
    <description>LSALT, a peptide drug with the sequence NH3-LSALTPSPSWLKYKAL-COOH, binds to dipeptidase-1 (DPEP-1) but does not inhibit its biologic enzymatic activity, potentially minimizing off-target or other adverse effects. LSALT peptide inhibits leukocyte recruitment in multiple experimental disease models through the direct inhibition of leukocyte adhesion to DPEP-1 present in lungs, kidney, and liver. DPEP-1 represents a new molecular pathway for leukocyte adhesion discovered by Arch Biopartners scientists.</description>
    <arm_group_label>LSALT</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Metablok</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>0.9% saline solution</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male and female hospitalized patients between 45 and 80 years of age at time of&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Clinical and laboratory diagnosis of COVID-19 infection. Patients must be positive for&#xD;
             the SARS-CoV-2 by Real-Time Reverse Transcriptase (RT)-PCR&#xD;
&#xD;
             Diagnostic Panel as well as two of the following three symptoms:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fever (oral temperature ≥ 100.4 °F [&gt; 38 °C]) with or without chills&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Dyspnea or difficulty breathing (≤ 2 on mMRC dyspnea scale)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Nonproductive cough&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients must present with moderate to severe illness as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Moderate illness: Patients who have evidence of lower respiratory disease by&#xD;
                  clinical assessment or imaging and an oxygen saturation (SpO2) &gt; 93% on room air&#xD;
                  at sea level&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Severe illness: Patients who have a respiratory frequency &gt; 30 breaths per minute&#xD;
                  (bpm), SpO2 ≤ 93% on room air at sea level, ratio of arterial partial pressure of&#xD;
                  oxygen to fraction of inspired oxygen (PaO2/FiO2) &lt; 300, or lung infiltrates &gt;&#xD;
                  50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. APACHE II score &lt; 20&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Therapies which have been shown to be beneficial and are included in standard COVID-19&#xD;
             treatment guidelines (e.g. those of WHO or NIH) are permitted&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Sexually active women of child-bearing potential (WCBP) must be using a medically&#xD;
             acceptable method of birth control throughout the study and for at least 1 day&#xD;
             following the end of study, and have a negative urine pregnancy test at the Screening&#xD;
             visit. A WCBP is defined as a female who is biologically capable of becoming pregnant.&#xD;
             A medically acceptable method of birth control includes intrauterine devices in place&#xD;
             for at least 3 months, surgical sterilization, or the implant. In patients who are not&#xD;
             sexually active, abstinence is an acceptable form of birth control and urine will be&#xD;
             tested per protocol. Women who are of nonchild-bearing potential, i.e.,&#xD;
             post-menopause, must have this condition captured in their medical history. Pregnant&#xD;
             women and nursing mothers are excluded from this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patient or LAR is available and willing to give written informed consent, after being&#xD;
             properly informed of the nature and risks of the study and prior to engaging in any&#xD;
             study-related procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Known sensitivity, allergy, or previous exposure to LSALT peptide.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Exposure to any investigational drug or device &lt;90 days prior to entry into study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Treatment with immunomodulators or immunosuppressant drugs, including but not limited&#xD;
             to IL-6 inhibitors, TNF inhibitors, anti-IL-1 immunomodulators, and JAK inhibitors&#xD;
             within five half-lives or 30 days (whichever is longer) prior to randomization and&#xD;
             throughout the study period. However, should any of these treatments become&#xD;
             standard-of-care and incorporated into clinical treatment guidelines (e.g. those of&#xD;
             WHO or NIH), the treatment is permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Anticipated transfer to another hospital or medical center within 72 hours, which is&#xD;
             not a study site.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Uncontrolled of poorly treated active hepatitis B (HBV), hepatitis C (HepC), or HIV&#xD;
             infection. Those subjects who are positive for HBV, HepC, or HIV but are&#xD;
             well-controlled with low viral loads are allowed to participate in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HBV low viral load defined as &lt;20,000 IU/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HepC low viral load defined as &lt;800,000 IU/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HIV low viral load defined as &lt;5000 copies/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Participation in another drug or device study at any time during this study, for&#xD;
             example:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ulinastatin 200,000 IU or greater&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  High dose intravenous Vitamin C&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Budesonide and formoterol&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bevacizumab to prevent ARDS&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Dornase alfa to reduce hypoxemia in ventilated trauma patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. As indicated in the inclusion criteria, pregnant female patients are excluded from&#xD;
             study. Further, female patients who are nursing are excluded from study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Has any medical condition considered to be clinically significant and could&#xD;
             potentially affect patient safety or study outcome, including but not limited to:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acute or chronic kidney disease (stage-4 or -5 renal impairment; eGFR&lt;30&#xD;
                  mL/min/1.73 m2 or hemodialysis)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  End-stage malignancy undergoing treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Immunocompromised patients or those with medical/surgical conditions (e.g., solid&#xD;
                  organ transplantation) which require chronic immunosuppression&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chronic hematologic disease which, in the opinion of the PI, prohibits the&#xD;
                  patient from entering into study&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acute liver injury with AST and/or ALT levels greater than 3x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of coagulopathy within the last year as defined by abnormal ACT, aPTT,&#xD;
                  and/or PT/INR values at least 2-fold outside normal limits, and/or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  End-stage lung disease, acute lung injury, severe chronic obstructive pulmonary&#xD;
                  disease (COPD), or mechanical ventilation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Daniel A Muruve, MD</last_name>
    <phone>403-220-2418</phone>
    <email>info@archbiopartners.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Richard Muruve</last_name>
    <phone>647-428-7031</phone>
    <email>info@archbiopartners.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA San Diego Healthcare System</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92161</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Steve Carter</last_name>
      <phone>858-552-8585</phone>
      <phone_ext>2893</phone_ext>
      <email>smcarter@vapop.uscd.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mark Hepokoski, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Broward Health Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Lauderdale</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33316</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Laura Hudson</last_name>
      <phone>954-468-5237</phone>
      <email>lhudson@browardhealth.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sunil Kumar, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>LSU Health Shreveport</name>
      <address>
        <city>Shreveport</city>
        <state>Louisiana</state>
        <zip>71103</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kim Hutchinson</last_name>
      <phone>318-675-6682</phone>
      <email>Ksmit9@lsuhsc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Steven Conrad, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Calgary</name>
      <address>
        <city>Calgary</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Wilna Bouwer</last_name>
      <phone>403-614-9431</phone>
      <email>wilna.bouwer@ucalgary.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alain Tremblay, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ankara City Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ankara</city>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>İrem Akın</last_name>
      <phone>0533 052 8862</phone>
      <email>irem.akin@monitorcro.net</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>H.Rahmet Güner, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istanbul University Cerrahpasa</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <zip>34098</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Cansu Çiçek</last_name>
      <phone>0531 260 6687</phone>
      <email>cansu.cicek@monitorcro.net</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ömer Fehmi Tabak, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>Turkey</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

