<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4814">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04406363</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CONFI-LOMB</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04406363</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Confinement Effect on Low Back Pain Intensity in Chronic Low Back Pain Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>CONFI-LOMB</acronym>
  <official_title>Confinement Effect on Low Back Pain Intensity in Chronic Low Back Pain Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Angers</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Angers</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The current situation, linked to the pandemic of the new coronavirus SARS-CoV-2 generates&#xD;
      health concerns, but is also accompanied by many other psychological, social, economic,&#xD;
      professional, etc. consequences as well as numerous changes in behavior and lifestyles,&#xD;
      notably due to confinement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While the prevention of chronic low back pain and its management are primarily based on the&#xD;
      practice of regular physical and sports activity, other psychological factors (stress,&#xD;
      anxiety, depression), socioeconomic (low level of education, resources), professionals&#xD;
      (physical workload, job dissatisfaction), etc. also have a major role in the onset and the&#xD;
      persitence of low back pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thus, it is to be supposed that the current context, and more particularly the confinement to&#xD;
      which the population has been constrained for almost 2 months, have and will have notable&#xD;
      consequences on the evolution of lumbar symptoms in chronic low back pain patients. However,&#xD;
      the entanglement of different factors related to containment will potentially have different&#xD;
      consequences depending on the individual. It therefore seems difficult to predict how the&#xD;
      lumbar symptoms will develop in this population. Indeed, if it can imagined that the decrease&#xD;
      in regular physical activity and the increase in anxiety in this context of insecurity could&#xD;
      lead to an increase in pain, it could just as well consider that the decrease in stress work,&#xD;
      strenuous physical work or travel time from work to home can, on the contrary, have a&#xD;
      favorable effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this study is to assess the confinement effect on low back pain intensity in&#xD;
      chronic low back pain patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is an observational, descriptive, transversal and pluricentric study conducted by a&#xD;
      single questionnaire.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients who consulted one of the study investigators (rheumatologist and algologist) for the&#xD;
      management of a common chronic low back pain between January 1, 2020 and March 17, 2020&#xD;
      (begining of the French confinement) and who meet inclusion criteria will be offered to&#xD;
      participate to the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible subjets will be preselected by the study investigators (from the medical file). The&#xD;
      initial solicitation of a potential subject will be made by a phone contact by the&#xD;
      investigator who treat him/her for his chronic low back pain. Subjects who agree to&#xD;
      participate in the study will be offered to respond to a questionnaire by phone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The questionnaire (no more than 10 minutes) will assess the sociodemographic status, the&#xD;
      confinement conditions, the new coranavirus infection status, changes in low back pain&#xD;
      intensity during the confinement, incapacity related to low back pain, physical activities&#xD;
      practice before and during the confinement, anxiety and depression, continuation of&#xD;
      occupational activity and teleworking practice during the confienment .&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective of this study is to assess the impact of confinement on change in low back&#xD;
      pain intensity. The main endpoint is the proportion of subjects with a significant change in&#xD;
      their low back pain during confinement, defined by the items &quot;much worse&quot; and &quot;moderately&#xD;
      worse&quot;, or &quot;much improved&quot; and &quot;moderately improved&quot; respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives are to assess:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. the association between the conditions of confinement and low back pain intensity;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. the association between the confinement conditions and disability related to low back&#xD;
           pain;&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. the association between infection with the new SARS-CoV-2 coronavirus and change in low&#xD;
           back pain intensity;&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. the association between the confinement conditions and the quality of life as well as&#xD;
           the state of psychological health;&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. the impact of confinement on the use of care and the consumption of medication and&#xD;
           psychoactive substances for low back pain;&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. the association between working conditions and / or teleworking and the low back pain&#xD;
           intensity;&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. the association between socio-economic factors and modalities as well as the experience&#xD;
           of confinement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given the exploratory nature of this study, the required number of subjects is empirically&#xD;
      estimated at 350 subjects in total.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Qualitative and quantitative data will be described (averages or percentages). A chi² test&#xD;
      will be performed to compare the percentages between the different subgroups studied. A&#xD;
      Student test will be carried out to compare the means between the different subgroups&#xD;
      studied. An alpha risk of less than 5% will be considered significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For each of the parameters of interest studied, the bivariate analysis may be supplemented by&#xD;
      a multivariate analysis adapted to the criterion to be explained if the conditions of&#xD;
      validity of this multivariate analysis are met.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 2, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 21, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact of confinement on the low back pain intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>at inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of subjects having a significant change in their low back pain intensity during confinement, defined by the items &quot;much worse&quot; and &quot;moderately worse&quot;, or &quot;much improved&quot; and &quot;moderately improved&quot; respectively.The meaning of this significant change (worsening or improvement) will also be described.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between confinement conditions and low back pain intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>at inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Change in low back pain intensity between before and during confinement evaluated by a numerical pain scale rated from 0 to 10 (0 = no pain ; 10 = worst imaginable pain). Confinement conditions (alone or in a group, space, etc.) and the practice of physical and sporting activities during confinement (weekly duration, etc.)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between confinement conditions and disability related to low back pain</measure>
    <time_frame>at inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Disability measured by the &quot;incapacity&quot; sub-score of the &quot;Core Outcome Measures Index&quot; (COMI) questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between infection with the new SARS-CoV-2 coronavirus and change in low back pain intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>at inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Occurrence of a SARS-CoV-2 infection and its level of severity (confirmed diagnosis, few or no symptoms, symptoms severely limiting daily activities, hospitalization in a conventional service or in intensive care)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between confinement conditions and quality of life as well as psychological health</measure>
    <time_frame>at inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of life and levels of anxiety and depression evaluated with the COMI-AD sub-score (modified version of the COMI integrating the state of psychological health);</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact of confinement on the use of care and the consumption of medication and psychoactive substances for low back pain</measure>
    <time_frame>at inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Use of care, drug consumption and psychoactive substances (tobacco, cannabis, alcohol, anxiolytics) for low back pain</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between working conditions and / or teleworking and low back pain intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>at inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Modalities of the the ocupational activity continuation (continuation of the activity, evolution of the working time, telework and modalities of establishment)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between socio-economic factors and modalities as well as the experience of confinement</measure>
    <time_frame>at inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Experience of confinement. Socio-economic characteristics of the participants (age, sex, department, job and socio-professional category).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Low-back Pain</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>non interventional</intervention_name>
    <description>non interventional</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients who consulted one of the study inestigators (rheumatologist or algologist) for the&#xD;
        management of common chronic low back pain between January 1, 2020 and March 17, 2020&#xD;
        inclusive and who meet the inclusion criteria.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major patients (men and women) with common chronic low back pain (i.e. without&#xD;
             identified underlying cause)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who benefited from a consultation with a specialist doctor (rheumatologist or&#xD;
             algologist) from the recruitment centers for common chronic low back pain between&#xD;
             January 1, 2020 and March 17, 2020 (begining of the French confinement) included&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who received information with non-opposition&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pain other than spinal pain not allowing to discriminate low back pain (fibromyalgia,&#xD;
             chronic pain syndrome, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Low back pain of secondary origin (infectious, tumor, fracture, inflammatory, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Comorbidities limiting the practice of physical and sporting activities (severe heart&#xD;
             or respiratory failure, arteriopathy of the lower limbs with lameness, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Poor understanding of the French language&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant, lactating or parturient women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vulnerable adults within the meaning of the law&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person deprived of their liberty by judicial or administrative decision&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person under psychiatric care under duress&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person admitted to a health or social establishment for purposes other than that of&#xD;
             research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person subject to a legal protection measure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person out of state to express consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person opposed to participating in the research&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Petit</name>
      <address>
        <city>Angers</city>
        <zip>49000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Audrey Petit, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>00 33 2 41 35 49 81</phone>
      <email>aupetit@chu-angers.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 6, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 27, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 27, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 27, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>confinement</keyword>
  <keyword>chronic low back pain</keyword>
  <keyword>changes in pain intensity</keyword>
  <keyword>bio-psycho-social and occupational factors</keyword>
  <keyword>physical activity</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

