<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4638">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04719468</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>275588</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04719468</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PD-Ballet: Effectiveness and Implementation in Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy of Ballet Dancing on Motor and Non-motor Symptoms of Parkinson's Disease: a Hybrid Type 2 Effectiveness-implementation Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>King's College Hospital NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>King's College London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>King's College Hospital NHS Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Current literature consistently demonstrates beneficial motor effects of dance-based&#xD;
      therapies in Parkinson's disease, along with improved quality of life. Little is known about&#xD;
      the non-motor gains following such therapy. To date, no RTC has been conducted to investigate&#xD;
      the benefits of ballet dancing in Parkinson's disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators aim to recruit 160 people with Parkinson's to either: participate in a&#xD;
      12-week ballet-based dancing intervention followed by a 'social Tea and Biscuit' session, or&#xD;
      12-week usual treatment monitoring and 'social Tea and Biscuit' sessions taking place after&#xD;
      each intervention session. This study employs a randomised, controlled, single-blind, hybrid&#xD;
      type 2 design with a hybrid implementation protocol to investigate both clinical efficacy of&#xD;
      the programme and implementation aspects. The project's primary outcome measure is centered&#xD;
      around non-motor symptoms of PD. Other measures include motor assessments, wearable sensors&#xD;
      and quality of life assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to COVID-19 pandemic, the delivery of the sessions will be a hybrid model - virtual&#xD;
      sessions will be the primary method, with some capacity for in-person delivery when possible&#xD;
      and deemed safe.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Parkinson's Disease is a neurodegenerative condition currently affecting over 120,000 people&#xD;
      in the UK and this number is set to double by 2065. The current treatment is based around&#xD;
      symptomatic pharmacotherapy with levodopa being the gold standard. Currently there is some&#xD;
      evidence for non-pharmacological treatments outlined by NICE guidelines, with no&#xD;
      recommendations to specific adjuvant non-pharmacotherapies to aid PD symptoms, other than&#xD;
      referral for physiotherapy. However, physical exercise has been shown to improve balance,&#xD;
      strength, coordination and gait, leading to a significant improvement in quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While a clear benefit of physical exercise on the motor symptoms is evident, few studies to&#xD;
      date focused on the effects of group classes and on non-motor effects. Dance is emerging as a&#xD;
      therapeutic option with cognitive, functional and psychosocial benefits, due to it being a&#xD;
      multi-dimensional activity offering auditory, visual and sensory stimulation, musical&#xD;
      experience, social interaction, memory, motor learning and emotional perception, expression&#xD;
      and interaction and as such stimulating multiple pathways. To date, no research has explored&#xD;
      acute and chronic effects of exercise based interventions (such as dance therapy with ballet)&#xD;
      in comparison to the conventional therapy-based management of Parkinson's.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a randomised, controlled, single-blind study involving 160 PwP across all stages of&#xD;
      the disease. Participants will be allocated to either standard therapy plus 12 weekly&#xD;
      sessions of ballet-based dancing followed by 'Tea and Biscuit' session or standard therapy&#xD;
      with 'Tea and Biscuit' session on a 2:1 ratio. Non-motor symptoms, motor symptoms and quality&#xD;
      of life will be measured using validated scales, questionnaires and wearable sensor&#xD;
      recordings (Parkinson's KinetiGraph, GaitSmart). Furthermore, electrophysiological measures&#xD;
      will be performed to determine the effects on cortical activity in a subgroup of&#xD;
      participants. Assessments will be performed by a blinded rater at baseline and at the end of&#xD;
      the intervention. The project will also explore the possibility of implementation of such&#xD;
      therapy into the current pathways.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to COVID-19 pandemic, the delivery of the sessions will be a hybrid model - virtual&#xD;
      sessions will be the primary method, with some capacity for in-person delivery when possible&#xD;
      and deemed safe.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Blinded rater</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of the Movement Disorders Society Sponsored Non-Motor Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness Primary Outcome Measure, higher score indicate worse non-motor symptomatology, the maximum score is 1008.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of Intervention Measure</measure>
    <time_frame>post intervention (week 12)</time_frame>
    <description>Implementation Effectiveness Primary Outcome Measure - a 4 item, 5-point likert scale</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of the Unified Parkinson's Disease Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. A higher score indicates worse motor condition</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of 10-meter walk test</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. Time taken to walk 10 meters is calculated and compared at specific timepoints.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of King's Parkinson's Pain Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. A higher score indicates worse levels of pain</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of Timed Up and Go test</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. Time taken to carry out the test measured. A change between timepoints will be measured.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of Montreal Cognitive Assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. Maximum score 30. Lower scores indicate cognitive impairment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Impression of Severity Index for Parkinson's disease</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>provides a clinical judgment on Parkinson's disease (PD) severity based on motor symptoms and complications, cognitive status, and disability</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of Parkinson's Disease Sleep Scale 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. Higher score indicates worse sleep quality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of Parkinson's Disease Questionnaire-8</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. A higher score indicates worse quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score and sub-scores of Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. Higher score indicates worse anxiety and depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of Schwab and England Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. A higher score indicates higher level of independence in performing activities of daily living.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of EQ-5D-5L questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. A lower score indicates better quality of life</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of Parkinson's Fatigue Scale-16</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. A higher score indicates more fatigue.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of Physical Activity Scale for the Elderly</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. A higher score indicates more activity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of Starkstein Apathy Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. Higher score indicates more apathy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of Wearing Off Questionnaire-9</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. Higher score indicates worse wearing-off.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total score of Zaritt Burden Interview</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness. A higher score indicates more carer burden.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Electrodiagnostic Measures - Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation paired with Electroencephalography and electromyography.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness - exploratory measure. EMG data are analysed via Spike2 software (Cambridge Electronic Design). Peak-to-peak MEP amplitudes are measured for each trial and averaged per condition. SICI is calculated as the ratio of mean conditioned MEP to mean unconditioned MEP. TMS-evoked EEG potentials will be calculated by averaging artifact-free EEG trials for each experimental condition (i.e., before and after intervention). To smooth the signal a low-pass filter of 45 Hz will be applied to TEPs. The aim is to evaluate drug-induced changes for the 5 typical TEPs components (P = Positive, N = Negative) in accordance with the literature: N15-P25, N45, P70, N100, and P180.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the scores of Parkinson's KinetiGraph parameters (bradykinesia, dyskinesia, tremor, immobility)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Effectiveness, objective artigraphy based wearable sensor worn at home for 6 days at each time point.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of Intervention Measure (FIM)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Implementation Effectiveness - a 4-item, 5-point likert scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention Appropriateness Measure (IAM)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Implementation Effectiveness - a 4-item, 5-point likert scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustainability scale (NOMAD)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Implementation Effectiveness - a 19 item implementation science survey (Finch et al., 2015)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Implementation costs</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (week -4 to 0), end of intervention (week 12-14) and up to 24 weeks post intervention depending on participant availability</time_frame>
    <description>Health Economics - questionnaire regarding the potentially incurred costs related to clinical care for a person with Parkinson. The investigators will measure the potential change in direct and indirect costs incurred from clinical care.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">160</enrollment>
  <condition>Parkinson Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>usual treatment with the addition of joining 'Tea and Biscuit' sessions remotely</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dance with ballet elements</intervention_name>
    <description>Ballet-based dance sessions will be delivered by trained artists within the English National Ballet group in a professional dance space/ delivered remotely, COVID-19 permitting.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Effectiveness investigation eligibility criteria (PwPs only)&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Inclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Age of 18 and upwards&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  diagnosis of idiopathic Parkinson's disease (PD) according to the UK PD Brain&#xD;
                  Bank criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hoehn Yarhr stages I-V&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Exclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  diagnosis or suspicion of other causes for parkinsonism&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  advanced-stage therapy consideration (deep brain stimulation, continuous levodopa&#xD;
                  duodenal infusion, and continuous subcutaneous apomorphine infusion)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  any condition interfering with the ability to give the informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Indication of dementia through a score of ≤21 on MoCA&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  enrolment in a simultaneous investigational trial&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  inability to travel to the weekly sessions&#xD;
&#xD;
        Implementation science investigation eligibility criteria f) Inclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People with Parkinson's - patients with a formal diagnosis of PD who have participated&#xD;
             in the PD-Ballet intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Family members of PwP - relatives/carers/nominated person of the patients with a&#xD;
             formal diagnosis of PD who have participated in the PD-Ballet intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinicians (Referrers) - neurologists/geriatricians/neuropsychiatrists/SALT/OT, as&#xD;
             well as PD specialist nurses, physicians and research staff experienced in PD&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dance leaders (Deliverers) - English National Ballet dancers involved in the PD-Ballet&#xD;
             project&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Support staff (Supporters)- other parties involved with the PD-Ballet project&#xD;
&#xD;
             g) Exclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People with Parkinson's - parkinsonism other than PD, lack of involvement in the&#xD;
             PD-Ballet project&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinicians - Neurologists/geriatricians/neuropsychiatrists/SALT/OT, as well as PD&#xD;
             specialist nurses, physicians and research staff experienced in PD&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dance leaders - English National Ballet dancers not involved in the PD-Ballet project&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Support staff - other parties not involved with the PD-Ballet project&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>K Ray Chaudhuri, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>King's College London</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Aleksandra Podlewska, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>02032997189</phone>
    <email>aleksandra.podlewska@nhs.net</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>King's College Hospital NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>SE5 9RS</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Aleksandra Podlewska, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>02032997189</phone>
      <email>aleksandra.podlewska@nhs.net</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Lucia Batzu, MD</last_name>
      <phone>02032997189</phone>
      <email>l.batzu@nhs.net</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>dance</keyword>
  <keyword>ballet</keyword>
  <keyword>complementary therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>multimodal</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

