<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="536">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04651790</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>200708006</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04651790</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy, Safety, and Immunogenicity of an Inactivated Vaccine Against COVID-19 in High Infection Risk Adults</brief_title>
  <acronym>CoronaVac3CL</acronym>
  <official_title>Multi-center, Phase 3, Double-blind, Randomized, Placebo-controlled, Clinical Study to Evaluate the Efficacy, Safety, and Immunogenicity of an Inactivated Vaccine Against the SARS-CoV-2 Infection in High Risk of Infection Adults</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pontificia Universidad Catolica de Chile</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ministry of Health, Chile</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sinovac Biotech Co., Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pontificia Universidad Catolica de Chile</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study will evaluate the efficacy, safety, and immunogenicity of an inactivated vaccine&#xD;
      against the SARS-CoV-2 infection in high risk of infection adults. Two doses of the vaccine&#xD;
      or placebo will be administered in an 0 and 14 days schedule. Follow-up of safety and&#xD;
      efficacy will be implemented by 12 months after the first dose. Immunogenicity will be&#xD;
      studied in a subgroup of participants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will evaluate the efficacy, safety, and immunogenicity of an inactivated vaccine&#xD;
      against the SARS-CoV-2 infection in high risk of infection adults. This study will be&#xD;
      performed in 9 centers. Two doses of the vaccine or placebo will be administered at days 0&#xD;
      and 14 days, in a 1:1 ratio. Then, follow-up of safety and efficacy will be implemented up to&#xD;
      12 months after administering the first dose. The collection of the data will be through the&#xD;
      electronics Case Report Form. Immunogenicity will be studied in a subgroup of participants.&#xD;
      Initially, three thousand volunteers will be recruited.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 27, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of symptomatic cases of virologically confirmed COVID-19 two weeks after the second vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>Two weeks after second dose up to one year after first dose</time_frame>
    <description>Vaccine efficacy to prevent virologically confirmed COVID-19 two weeks after the second vaccination will be determined</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of solicited and unsolicited local and systemic adverse reactions during the period of one week after vaccination according to age group in adult (18-59 years old) and elder (60 years of age or older) subjects.</measure>
    <time_frame>During the first 7 days after each dose of vaccine/placebo</time_frame>
    <description>The frequency of solicited and unsolicited local and systemic adverse reactions will be registered. This will be measured during the first 7 days after each vaccination. These adverse reactions will be registered according to the age group in adult (18-59 years old) and elder (60 years of age or older) subjects.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of cases of virologically confirmed COVID-19 after administration of at least one dose of vaccine/placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>Since first dose and up to 12 months after</time_frame>
    <description>The incidence of cases confirmed through PCR for COVID-19 after administration of at least one dose of vaccine/placebo will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of severe cases of COVID-19 virologically confirmed two weeks after the second vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>Since two weeks after the second dose up 12 month after first dose</time_frame>
    <description>The incidence of severe cases of COVID-19, confirmed through PCR, two weeks after the second vaccination, will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of hospitalized cases of COVID-19 two weeks after the second vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>Since two weeks after the second dose and up 12 month after first dose</time_frame>
    <description>The incidence of hospitalized cases of COVID-19 two weeks after the second vaccination will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of deaths due to COVID-19 two weeks after the second vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>Since two weeks after the second dose up 12 month after first dose</time_frame>
    <description>The incidence of deaths due to COVID-19 two weeks after the second vaccination will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse reactions to the vaccine, local and systemic, solicited and unsolicited, within the period of four weeks after each dose of vaccination, according to the age group, adults (18-59 years old) and elder (60 years or older) subjects.</measure>
    <time_frame>Four weeks after each dose of vaccine/placebo</time_frame>
    <description>The incidence of adverse reactions to the vaccine, both local and systemic, solicited and unsolicited will be determined. These adverse reactions will be measured within the period of four weeks after each dose of vaccination. These adverse reactions will be registered according to the age group in adult (18-59 years old) and elder (60 years of age or older) subjects.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of severe COVID-19 cases in participants who received at least one dose of vaccine/placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>Since first dose up to 12 month after</time_frame>
    <description>The frequency of severe COVID-19 cases in participants who received at least one dose of vaccine/placebo will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of serious adverse events (SAE) and adverse events in participants who have received at least one dose of the vaccine</measure>
    <time_frame>Since first dose up to 12 month after</time_frame>
    <description>The occurrence of serious adverse events (SAE) and adverse events of special interest in participants who have received at least one dose of the vaccine, will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants that show a significant increase in SARS-CoV-2 specific T cells after vaccination, determined by flow Cytometry and ELISPOT</measure>
    <time_frame>Since first dose up to 4 weeks after second dose</time_frame>
    <description>The cellular immune response in a subgroup of participants, before and two and four weeks after the administration of each dose of the vaccine, will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants with a significant increase of anti-SARS-CoV-2 antibodies, determined by ELISA</measure>
    <time_frame>Since first dose up to 2 weeks after second dose</time_frame>
    <description>The presence of anti-SARS-CoV-2 antibodies in a subgroup of participants, before and two weeks after the administration of each dose of the vaccine, will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2300</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Vaccines</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Inactivated vaccine against SARS-CoV-2 2 doses on day 0 and 14</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Aluminum hydroxide, disodium hydrogen phosphate, sodium dihydrogen phosphate, sodium chloride 2 doses on day 0 and 14</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SARS-CoV-2 inactivated vaccine</intervention_name>
    <description>The vaccine contains inactivated SARS-CoV-2 virus, aluminum hydroxide, disodium hydrogen phosphate, sodium dihydrogen phosphate and sodium chloride.The final product will be supplied in a pre-filled syringe containing 0.5 ml of solution for injection that corresponds to a dose of the vaccine.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Coronavac</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>The placebo contains aluminum hydroxide, disodium hydrogen phosphate, sodium dihydrogen phosphate, 0.5mL sodium chloride / dose, intramuscular injection, two doses administered two weeks apart. The final product will be supplied in a pre-filled syringe containing 0.5 ml of solution for injection that corresponds to a dose of the placebo.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults over 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Health professionals who provide care to people with possible or confirmed COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Demonstrate the capacity to understand and sign the Informed Consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agree to comply with the study procedures and visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of confirmed symptomatic SARS CoV-2 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant (confirmed by positive urine pregnancy test) or breastfeeding females, and/or&#xD;
             expressing intention to have sexual practices with reproductive potential without&#xD;
             using contraceptive methods in the three months following vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of an allergic reaction to the vaccine or components of the study vaccine or&#xD;
             placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of uncontrolled neurological, cardiac, pulmonary, hepatic, or renal disease,&#xD;
             according to anamnesis or physical examination; Significant changes in treatment or&#xD;
             hospitalizations due to worsening of the condition in the last three months are&#xD;
             indicators of uncontrolled disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diseases that impair the immune system including neoplasms (except basal cell&#xD;
             carcinoma), congenital or acquired immunodeficiencies, and uncontrolled autoimmune&#xD;
             diseases not controlled according to anamnesis or physical examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Behavioral, cognitive, or psychiatric illness that, in the opinion of the principal&#xD;
             investigator or his medical representative, affects the participant's ability to&#xD;
             understand and collaborate with the requirements of the study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of immunosuppressive therapies six months before inclusion in the study or its&#xD;
             scheduled use within two years of inclusion. Immunosuppressive therapies will be&#xD;
             considered: antineoplastic chemotherapy, radiation therapy, immunosuppressants to&#xD;
             induce tolerance to transplants, among others.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have received an immunosuppressive dose of corticosteroids in the last three months&#xD;
             before inclusion in the study or scheduled administration of an immunosuppressive dose&#xD;
             of corticosteroids for the three months following inclusion in the study. The dose of&#xD;
             corticosteroids considered immunosuppressive is equivalent to prednisone at a dose of&#xD;
             20 mg/day for adults for more than a week. The continuous use of topical or nasal&#xD;
             corticosteroids is not considered immunosuppressive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of asplenia, either anatomic or functional.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of bleeding disorders, as deficiency of clotting factors, coagulopathy,&#xD;
             platelet dysfunction, or previous history of bleeding or significant bruising after IM&#xD;
             injection or venipuncture.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any alcohol or drug abuse in the last 12 months before inclusion in the study that has&#xD;
             caused medical, professional, or family problems, as indicated by clinical history.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have received blood products (transfusions or immunoglobulins) in the last three&#xD;
             months before inclusion in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have received any vaccine with a live attenuated virus in the last 28 days or&#xD;
             inactivated vaccine in the last 14 days before their inclusion in the study, or have&#xD;
             immunization scheduled for the first 28 days after their inclusion in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in another clinical trial with product administration under&#xD;
             investigation during the six months before its inclusion in the study or scheduled&#xD;
             participation in another clinical trial in the two years following inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous participation in a COVID-19 vaccine evaluation study or previous exposure to&#xD;
             a COVID-19 vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fever (&gt;37.8°C) within 72 hours before vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other condition that, in the opinion of the principal investigator or his medical&#xD;
             representative, could jeopardize the safety or rights of a potential participant or&#xD;
             that would prevent him from complying with this protocol.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Katia Abarca, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Pontificia Universidad Catolica de Chile</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Katia Abarca, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+56996797787</phone>
    <email>katia@med.puc.cl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Carolina Iturriaga, Nurse</last_name>
    <phone>+56991292169</phone>
    <email>citurriaga@med.puc.cl</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centro de Especialidades Médicas, Red de Salud UC Christus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Santiago</city>
        <state>RM</state>
        <zip>7770228</zip>
        <country>Chile</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alvaro Rojas, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+56934056808</phone>
      <email>arojasgo@uc.cl</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>María Soledad Navarrete, Nurse</last_name>
      <phone>+56975288431</phone>
      <email>msnavarr@uc.cl</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Chile</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 1, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 3, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 1, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 1, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 3, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Clinical trials</keyword>
  <keyword>Covid19</keyword>
  <keyword>Inactivated vaccine</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>October 23, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/90/NCT04651790/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

