<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2029">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04701528</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NL73762.058.20</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04701528</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Anti-Viral Effects of Voclosporin in COVID-19 Positive Kidney Transplant Recipients</brief_title>
  <acronym>VOCOVID</acronym>
  <official_title>An Open-Label Study Evaluating Anti-Viral Effects of Voclosporin in SARS-CoV-2 Positive Kidney Transplant Recipients - the VOCOVID Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Leiden University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Aurinia Pharmaceuticals Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Leiden University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      An open-label, 56 day, single-center, exploratory, proof-of-concept study of the anti-viral&#xD;
      effect of voclosporin (VCS) with an extended safety follow-up, up to 1 year. Study population&#xD;
      are adult KTRs with positive SARS-CoV-2 infection with mild to moderate symptoms. At study&#xD;
      entry, subjects are on standard therapy of dual immunosuppressive treatment of prednisone and&#xD;
      tacrolimus (TAC), following randomization, 10 out of 20 subjects will remain on this therapy&#xD;
      for the duration of the study, while the other 10 subjects will switch to VCS.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Calcineurin inhibitors (CNIs) are general immunosuppressive agents commonly used in the&#xD;
      setting of transplantation to prevent solid organ rejection. CNIs form the cornerstone of&#xD;
      immunosuppressive treatment in kidney transplant recipients (KTRs) including the 1st&#xD;
      generation CNI Cyclosporin-A (CsA) and the most commonly employed 2nd generation CNI&#xD;
      tacrolimus (TAC). It is of interest that CNIs, especially CsA, also exert anti-viral effects&#xD;
      in addition to immunosuppressive effects. Common side effects of CNIs are hypertension,&#xD;
      new-onset diabetes, renal insufficiency and neurotoxicity. Therefore, in the recent&#xD;
      decennium, efforts have been directed at developing a novel CNI, voclosporin (VCS), that has&#xD;
      improved pharmacodynamic (PD) and pharmacokinetic (PK) attributes with respect to calcineurin&#xD;
      inhibition as well as an improved safety profile to common side effects. VCS has been&#xD;
      extensively studied in KTRs demonstrating equivalent efficacy to TAC with respect to&#xD;
      prevention of rejection while showing a reduction in CNI-related toxicity. Most recently, VCS&#xD;
      as a component of multitargeted therapy demonstrated superior efficacy compared to standard&#xD;
      of care in lupus nephritis (LN) patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In 2011, a pivotal study from Leiden University Medical Center (LUMC) demonstrated in vitro&#xD;
      anti-viral effect of CsA on Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus-1 (SARS-CoV-1).&#xD;
      Subsequently, VCS has been shown to have a more potent anti-viral effect on norovirus&#xD;
      compared to CsA. The anti-viral effects of CNIs have a different mechanism of inhibition in&#xD;
      each virus but mainly through inhibiting cyclophilins, an essential protein for viral&#xD;
      replication. The SARS-CoV-1 interacts with human cyclophilins, however the role of these&#xD;
      proteins in infection remains elusive. Different reports stablished interactions between nsp1&#xD;
      or nucleocapsid proteins with Cyps and hypothesize its influence in viral replication and&#xD;
      viral entry. Unlike VCS and CsA, TAC binds to FK binding proteins rather than cyclophilin A&#xD;
      (CypA). Given the current COVID-19 pandemic, the LUMC has very recently demonstrated&#xD;
      anti-viral effects of CNIs on SARS-CoV-2 infected cells in vitro: a 2-log reduction of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 viral titers in Calu-3 2B4 bronchial cell cultures was observed when incubated&#xD;
      with ~3 μM VCS compared to 25μM CsA and 25μM TAC. In each experiment Remdesivir was taken as&#xD;
      positive control as it inhibits viral replication by &gt;4log at 10 μM concentration. As such,&#xD;
      VCS becomes an attractive and potentially feasible CNI to use or switch to in COVID-19&#xD;
      infected KTRs who are already using CNIs as part of their chronic immunosuppressive therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Because subjects will be randomized to either VCS or TAC as immunosuppressive agent during&#xD;
      COVID-19 infection, the burden of the study is two-fold: first, subjects will need to switch&#xD;
      to a novel CNI which intrinsically will harbour an uncertainty. However, from a clinical&#xD;
      point-of-view VCS is proven equivalent to TAC with respect to organ rejection and safety&#xD;
      monitoring of adequate drug levels is incorporated in the study. Secondly, subjects will need&#xD;
      to agree to self-assessments including monitoring of vital signs and collection of saliva&#xD;
      samples and a throat swab in the first 56 days. We believe that it is actually in the&#xD;
      interest of subjects to undergo this intensive monitoring because current standard practice&#xD;
      is for KTRs with mild symptoms to not be hospitalized and stay at home until recovery without&#xD;
      further monitoring. In addition, blood sampling (10 x 38.5 mL), urine sampling and additional&#xD;
      hospital visits will take place which are outside of normal clinical practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The potential advantage of the study to KTRs is that VCS may lead to a quicker reduction of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 viral load and quicker relief of symptoms. Altogether, we believe the burden of&#xD;
      the study is minimal and outweighed by the potential benefit of the treatment on COVID-19&#xD;
      infection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 25, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 25, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>single-center, proof-of-concept</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to viral clearance of SARS-CoV-2</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 56</time_frame>
    <description>measured by first negative reverse transcription quantitative polymerase chain reaction (RT-qPCR) with a CT value of &gt;37 over 56 days</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to 2 consecutive negative RT-qPCR tests with CT-value &gt;37</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 56</time_frame>
    <description>negative test is defined as a CT-value above 37</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to reduction in viral load</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 56</time_frame>
    <description>below 3 log copies</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to 2 consecutive negative RT-qPCR tests with CT-value &gt;24</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 56</time_frame>
    <description>negative test is defined as a CT-value above 24</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to clinical recovery</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 56</time_frame>
    <description>defined as free of symptoms for five days or more</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to clinical symptom relief</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 56</time_frame>
    <description>defined as free of symptoms for one day or more</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to hospital discharge</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 56</time_frame>
    <description>for hospitalized subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of treatment failures</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 56</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of COVID infection requiring hospitalization for non-hospitalized subjects OR Worsening of COVID infection for hospitalized subjects requiring admittance to the ICU or death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Kidney Transplant Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Voclosporin (VCS)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Prior to or at study entry, subjects are reduced in their standard immunosuppressive therapy to dual therapy with prednisone and tacrolimus according to current local guidelines.&#xD;
In the experimental arm tacrolimus is switched to voclosporin 6 capsules (of 7.9 mg each) BID for a treatment period of minimal 56 days with a possible extension up to 1 year.&#xD;
Safety drug monitoring will take place during the study to ensure that VCS trough levels are maintained between 30-60 ng/mL. If trough levels are not within these levels, dose adjustments will take place.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Tacrolimus (TAC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Prior to or at study entry, subjects are reduced in their standard immunosuppressive therapy to dual therapy with prednisone and tacrolimus according to current local guidelines.&#xD;
In the Active comparator arm tacrolimus dosage is maintained.&#xD;
Safety drug monitoring will take place during the study to ensure that TAC trough levels are maintained between 3-7 ng/ml. If trough levels are not within these levels, dose adjustments will take place.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Voclosporin</intervention_name>
    <description>Temporarily switching of tacrolimus maintenance immunosuppression to voclosporin maintenance immunosuppression with possible additional anti-viral activity</description>
    <arm_group_label>Voclosporin (VCS)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Specimen collection for Nuclear acid testing (NAT) on SARS-CoV-2</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tacrolimus</intervention_name>
    <description>Comparator</description>
    <arm_group_label>Tacrolimus (TAC)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Specimen collection for Nuclear acid testing (NAT) on SARS-CoV-2</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Male or female subjects with a minimum age of 18 years at Visit 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects with a stable kidney transplant taking TAC and a confirmed diagnosis of&#xD;
             SARS-CoV-2 by nuclear acid testing, with mild-to-moderate symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with mild-to-moderate disease symptoms in which mild disease is defined by&#xD;
             non-hospitalized patients without oxygen need and moderate disease symptoms are&#xD;
             defined by hospitalization to a nursing ward with the need of oxygen therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test at baseline. Two&#xD;
             effective forms of contraception must be used simultaneously unless abstinence is the&#xD;
             chosen method. Subjects must use effective contraception during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects unable or unwilling to give written informed consent and/or to comply with&#xD;
             study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Any known hypersensitivity or contraindication to CNIs, especially CsA, or components&#xD;
             of any cyclosporine drug product.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Current or medical history of:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Congenital immunodeficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Severe, known, active viral infections, excluding SARS-CoV-2, within 3 months of&#xD;
                  baseline (e.g., cytomegalovirus, hepatitis B virus, hepatitis C virus or HIV)&#xD;
                  that are deemed to interfere with study assessments or outcome according to&#xD;
                  Investigator's judgement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Severe symptoms resulting from SARS-CoV-2 infection defined by requiring admittance to&#xD;
             a medium or high care unit with the need for positive pressure ventilation at&#xD;
             baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Other major physical or psychiatric illness or major traumatic injury or any other&#xD;
             medical condition associated with increased risk to the subject or that may affect&#xD;
             study conduct or interfere with study assessments or outcome according to&#xD;
             Investigator's judgement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects who are pregnant, breast feeding or, if of childbearing potential, not using&#xD;
             adequate contraceptive precautions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Participation in another interventional clinical study within 4 weeks prior to&#xD;
             baseline and/or receipt of investigational drugs within 4 weeks or 5 half-lives of the&#xD;
             drug (whichever is longer) prior to baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects less than 3 months post-transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects with documented organ rejection within the past 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects with a documented estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) &lt;15 ml/min&#xD;
             within the previous 3 months prior to screening.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Y.K.O. Teng, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Leiden University Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Y.K.O. Teng, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+31-(0)71-5262148</phone>
    <email>y.k.o.teng@lumc.nl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Leiden University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leiden</city>
        <zip>2333 ZC</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dr. Y.K.O. Teng, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>T +31-(0)71-5262148</phone>
      <email>y.k.o.teng@lumc.nl</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Dr. Y.K.O. Teng, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Leiden University Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Y.K.Onno Teng</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dr. Y.K.O. Teng, MD, PhD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tacrolimus</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

