<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4071">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04573062</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10000089</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>000089-N</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04573062</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Natural History of Post-Coronavirus Disease 19 Convalescence at the National Institutes of Health</brief_title>
  <official_title>Natural History of Post-Coronavirus Disease 19 Convalescence at the National Institutes of Health</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People who get COVID-19 have a wide range of symptoms. They also recover from COVID-19 in&#xD;
      different ways. In this study, researchers will use survey data to describe the different&#xD;
      ways people experience and recover from COVID-19. They will also use the data to help create&#xD;
      future studies to understand why some people do not fully recover.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To learn more about the range and timing of symptoms that people have before, during, and&#xD;
      after COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People ages 18 and older who have recovered from COVID-19 in the last 6 months and can give&#xD;
      documentation of a positive COVID-19 or antibody test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with a telephone interview. It will take 15 minutes. They will&#xD;
      provide their COVID-19 test results and medical records.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will complete a second telephone interview. It will take 30-60 minutes. They&#xD;
      will also take online surveys every 3 months for 3 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The interview and surveys will ask participants about their health before they got COVID-19,&#xD;
      what happened while they had COVID-19, and what their recovery has been like.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will get log-in data to take the online surveys. Completing all of the surveys&#xD;
      the first time may take up to 3 hours. Follow-up surveys will take up to 30 minutes.&#xD;
      Participants do not have to complete the surveys in one sitting. They will be able to save&#xD;
      their progress and finish the surveys later.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may be contacted to take part in other research studies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In late 2019, a novel coronavirus (COVID-19) appeared in Wuhan, China. The various ways that&#xD;
      humans will recover from COVID-19 infections is just starting to be observed and it is clear&#xD;
      there will be a wide range of convalescent experiences. This phased protocol is designed to&#xD;
      observe and study the convalescence and recoveries from acute COVID-19 infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase A Surveying (Phase A) will enable people in the community that are convalescing from&#xD;
      COVID-19 infections to be studied using telephone interviews and internet-based&#xD;
      questionnaires. The objective of Phase A Surveying is to observe and describe the range of&#xD;
      medical syndromes that occur in the wake of an acute COVID-19 infection. Participants are&#xD;
      required to be within the first six months of their recovery and have documentation of a&#xD;
      positive laboratory test for COVID-19. Additional cohorts of persons with neurological&#xD;
      sequelae and persons with a clinical diagnosis of COVID-19 with negative testing will also be&#xD;
      studied. The data collected during Phase A will inform the nature of the patient populations&#xD;
      to be evaluated in more detail.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase B Evaluation (Phase B) will allow surveyed participants of research interest from Phase&#xD;
      A to be invited to the NIH Clinical Center for a medical evaluation and to undergo a panel of&#xD;
      standard research measurements. Each participant would be medically and psychologically&#xD;
      characterized to best understand if their complaints can be attributed to known disorders.&#xD;
      The observations made during Phase B will provide first insights into the range and character&#xD;
      of the post-COVID-19 syndromes. Individuals found to have disorders being studied within the&#xD;
      Division of Intermural Research at NIH will be appropriately referred. The data collected&#xD;
      during Phase B will identify patient populations that may benefit from deep phenotyping&#xD;
      research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Evaluated individuals of research interest may be invited back to the NIH Clinical Center&#xD;
      from broad and deep research measurement during Phase C Deep Phenotyping (Phase C). The deep&#xD;
      phenotyping methods employed will be synchronized with other NIH-approved deep phenotyping&#xD;
      protocols to foster cross-phenotype comparison research with other medical syndromes, such as&#xD;
      Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome and Gulf War Illness. Deep phenotyping&#xD;
      characterizations would be used to generate scientific hypotheses for testing in future&#xD;
      studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Evaluated individuals with Post-COVID-19 syndromes of research interest may be invited to&#xD;
      participate in Phase D Longitudinal Evaluation phase (Phase D). This would enable the&#xD;
      observation of the natural history of Post-COVID convalescence and allow for exploration of&#xD;
      the biological mechanisms underlying successful recovery and how recovery can go awry.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previous epidemics have created unique medical syndromes in the past. It seems possible that&#xD;
      a unique POST-COVID 19 Syndrome or Syndromes may manifest from the global pandemic. If so,&#xD;
      data from this protocol may be used to define the nature of any Post-COVID 19 Syndromes. If&#xD;
      warranted, a Criteria Development phase will develop data-driven research consensus criteria&#xD;
      for any Post-COVID 19 Syndromes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results of this protocol will provide novel insights into COVID-19 convalescence and its&#xD;
      potential outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This current version of the protocol provides the details for Phase A of the study only.&#xD;
      Additional phases will be detailed in planned protocol Amendments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase A: to observe and describe the range of medical syndromes that occur in the wake of an&#xD;
      acute COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase A: To observe and describe recovery trajectories following an acute COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome measures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase A: The number and severity of persistent symptoms associated with COVID-19&#xD;
      convalescence. Collected data will be used to characterize different narratives of COVID-19&#xD;
      convalescence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Populations:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase A:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  1000 adults who are within six months of their convalescence from an acute COVID-19&#xD;
           infection with documentation of a positive COVID-19 test.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  100 adults recovering from neurological sequelae from a COVID-19 infection that may be&#xD;
           eligible for participation in Protocol 00094 An Observational Study of Neurological&#xD;
           Function After COVID 19 Infection .&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  100 adults with medical documentation supporting a clinical diagnosis of a COVID-19&#xD;
           infection with negative or absent PCR testing and negative antibody testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Description of Sites/Facilities&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enrolling Participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase A: All activities will be done using telephone interviews and internet-based&#xD;
      questionnaires that participants will complete offsite.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Duration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant Duration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase A: Participants will be invited to complete questionnaires for a period of three years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 11, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Screening Phase</measure>
    <time_frame>End of Study</time_frame>
    <description>The number and severity of persistent symptoms associated with COVID-19 convalescence. Collected data will be used to characterize different narratives of COVID-19 convalescence.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1200</enrollment>
  <condition>Post-Coronavirus Disease 19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Post COVID patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Individuals whom have previously had COVID-19 infection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        1000 persons who are recovering from an acute COVID-19 infection will participate.&#xD;
        Individuals in the community who are within six months of their convalescence from an acute&#xD;
        COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For Phase A:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1200 persons who are recovering from an acute COVID-19 infection will participate.&#xD;
        Inclusion criteria for Phase A:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Post-COVID-19 Convalescence (n=1000)&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participants 18 and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Ability to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Stated willingness to complete telephone interviews&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Reports having begun recovery from an acute COVID-19 infection within the last six&#xD;
             months&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Provides documentation of a positive COVID-19 PCR or antibody test&#xD;
&#xD;
        OR&#xD;
&#xD;
        Post-COVID-19 Neurological Sequelae (n=100)&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participants 18 and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Ability to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Stated willingness to complete telephone interviews&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Reports having developed neurological symptoms as a consequence of an acute COVID- 19&#xD;
             infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Provides documentation of a positive COVID-19 PCR or antibody test&#xD;
&#xD;
        OR&#xD;
&#xD;
        Test-Negative COVID-19 with Persistent Symptoms (n=100)&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participants 18 and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Ability to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Stated willingness to complete telephone interviews&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Reports having developed persistent symptoms as a consequence of an acute COVID-19&#xD;
             infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Provides documentation of a clinical diagnosis of an acute COVID-19 infection from a&#xD;
             medical practitioner OR meets the Clinical Criteria of the 2020 CDC Interim Case&#xD;
             Definition for Probable COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Has either negative or absent COVID-19 PCR testing for the documented COVID-19&#xD;
             infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Provides documentation of a negative COVID-19 antibody test.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The elements of the 2020 CDC Interim Case Definition for Probable COVID-19 Infection used&#xD;
        for this protocol will be the Clinical Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Clinical Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        At least two of the following symptoms: fever (measured or subjective), chills, rigors,&#xD;
        myalgia, headache, sore throat, new olfactory and taste disorder(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
        OR&#xD;
&#xD;
        At least one of the following symptoms: cough, shortness of breath, or difficulty breathing&#xD;
&#xD;
        OR&#xD;
&#xD;
        Severe respiratory illness with at least one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Clinical or radiographic evidence of pneumonia, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS).&#xD;
&#xD;
        AND&#xD;
&#xD;
        No alternative more likely diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria for Phase A:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not willing to provide personal identifying information to investigative team&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive impairment that is severe enough to limit consent capacity&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Avindra Nath, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Angelique Gavin</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 402-0880</phone>
    <email>angelique.gavin@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_000089-N.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pan L, Mu M, Yang P, Sun Y, Wang R, Yan J, Li P, Hu B, Wang J, Hu C, Jin Y, Niu X, Ping R, Du Y, Li T, Xu G, Hu Q, Tu L. Clinical Characteristics of COVID-19 Patients With Digestive Symptoms in Hubei, China: A Descriptive, Cross-Sectional, Multicenter Study. Am J Gastroenterol. 2020 May;115(5):766-773. doi: 10.14309/ajg.0000000000000620.</citation>
    <PMID>32287140</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu C, Chen X, Cai Y, Xia J, Zhou X, Xu S, Huang H, Zhang L, Zhou X, Du C, Zhang Y, Song J, Wang S, Chao Y, Yang Z, Xu J, Zhou X, Chen D, Xiong W, Xu L, Zhou F, Jiang J, Bai C, Zheng J, Song Y. Risk Factors Associated With Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome and Death in Patients With Coronavirus Disease 2019 Pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA Intern Med. 2020 Jul 1;180(7):934-943. doi: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2020.0994. Erratum in: JAMA Intern Med. 2020 Jul 1;180(7):1031.</citation>
    <PMID>32167524</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chen ATC, Coura-Filho GB, Rehder MHH. Clinical Characteristics of Covid-19 in China. N Engl J Med. 2020 May 7;382(19):1860. doi: 10.1056/NEJMc2005203. Epub 2020 Mar 27.</citation>
    <PMID>32220203</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 28, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 1, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 1, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 5, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Post-COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Convalescence</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Convalescence</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

