<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2932">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04602481</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>COVID-PCD</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04602481</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19 in People With Primary Ciliary Dyskinesia</brief_title>
  <official_title>COVID-19 in People With Primary Ciliary Dyskinesia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Bern</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Selbsthilfegruppe Kartagener Syndrom und Primäre Ciliäre Dyskinesie</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Verein Kartagener Syndrom und PCD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>PCD Family Support Group</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>PCD Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>PCD Australia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>European Lung Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Southampton</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Lucerne</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Bern</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The COVID-PCD is a participatory research project that aims to study how COVID-19 affects&#xD;
      people with primary ciliary dyskinesia (PCD). The study is advertised through patient support&#xD;
      groups and participants register online and answer a baseline questionnaire with details on&#xD;
      PCD diagnosis, habitual symptoms, and COVID-19 episodes occurring before study entry. A short&#xD;
      weekly follow-up questionnaire includes questions on incident SARS-CoV-2 infections, current&#xD;
      symptoms, contact behaviour, and physical activity. The study is hosted at the University of&#xD;
      Bern and recruitment started on May 30th, 2020.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background: The current pandemic of Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) caused by SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      virus is a public health emergency of international concern. The severity of COVID-19 ranges&#xD;
      from asymptomatic to severe. Patients with chronic lung disease such as primary ciliary&#xD;
      dyskinesia (PCD) are thought to be at increased risk, but no data support this. Disease&#xD;
      course and optimal treatment strategies might differ depending on the underlying disease. The&#xD;
      lack of knowledge hampers optimal treatment, and it leads to insecurity and fear among&#xD;
      persons affected by PCD and their family. PCD patient organisations initiated the idea of a&#xD;
      survey that gathers essential knowledge on effects of COVID-19 on people with PCD and makes&#xD;
      it available to patients, physicians, and policy makers in real time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims: To set up an online surveillance system of COVID-19 for people with PCD. For people&#xD;
      with PCD, the study aims to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Describe incidence of COVID-19, symptoms, course of disease, duration of illness,&#xD;
           treatments, and outcomes;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Identify risk factors for prognosis for a severe disease course;&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Assess the experiences of patients, and their wishes and needs such as availability of&#xD;
           preventive measures, medicines, therapies, and official communication and government&#xD;
           policies in relation to the COVID-19 outbreak.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: The study population includes all patients with PCD who can be contacted via patient&#xD;
      organisations. Local organisations invite their contacts using social media and mailing&#xD;
      lists. People with PCD can participate via a link on the study website&#xD;
      (www.covid19pcd.ispm.ch), where they can read the study information and give consent. Once&#xD;
      registered, participants receive a link via e-mail to the baseline questionnaire with&#xD;
      questions on prior COVID-19, PCD diagnosis and treatment, and environment and living&#xD;
      conditions. 7 days after completing the baseline questionnaire, and in regular intervals&#xD;
      thereafter, participants receive a link to a short follow-up questionnaire with questions on&#xD;
      COVID-19, current symptoms, and contact behaviour. Throughout the study, occasional&#xD;
      questionnaires are sent out focusing on emerging questions of interest such as official&#xD;
      information and policy issues, availability of treatments, or anxieties and fears. In case of&#xD;
      hospitalisation, patients or family members are asked to obtain a hospital report. Results&#xD;
      are continuously analysed and summaries are published on the study website. Specific analyses&#xD;
      are possible on request to inform involved persons, physicians, and policymakers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study uses an innovative approach to assess information relevant for risk, disease&#xD;
      course, treatments, and outcomes of COVID-19 directly from persons with a rare lung disease&#xD;
      and make the information available in real time. It will inform and empower patients and be a&#xD;
      resource to relieve anxiety and provide hands-on evidence to physicians and policymakers. It&#xD;
      adds no burden to health care professionals and will provide people with PCD and their&#xD;
      families specialised information, which they can pass on to their physicians.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 31, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SARS-CoV-2</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of people with PCD who report an infection with SARS-CoV-2</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of people with PCD who report an infection with SARS-CoV-2 and report symptoms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 hospitalisation</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of people with PCD who report a hospital stay due to COVID-19</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 intensive care</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of people with PCD who report a hospital stay due to COVID-19 and treatment in intensive care</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 fatal outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of people with PCD who reported an infection with SARS-CoV-2 and died</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>Primary Ciliary Dyskinesia</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study includes all persons with primary ciliary dyskinesia who can be contacted via&#xD;
        patient organisation networks worldwide.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People of any age with reported suspected or confirmed Primary Ciliary Dyskinesia who&#xD;
             gave consent to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People who report not to have suspected or confirmed Primary Ciliary Dyskinesia&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Claudia E Kuehni, Prof.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Bern</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Claudia E Kuehni, Prof.</last_name>
    <phone>+41 31 631 35 07</phone>
    <email>claudia.kuehni@ispm.unibe.ch</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Eva SL Pedersen, Dr.</last_name>
    <phone>+41 31 631 5975</phone>
    <email>eva.pedersen@ispm.unibe.ch</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institute of Social and Preventive Medicine (ISPM), University of Bern</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bern</city>
        <zip>3012</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Claudia E Kuehni, Prof.</last_name>
      <phone>+41 (0)31 631 35 07</phone>
      <email>claudia.kuehni@ispm.unibe.ch</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Eva SL Pedersen, Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+41 (0)31 631 59 75</phone>
      <email>eva.pedersen@ispm.unibe.ch</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://covid19pcd.ispm.ch/</url>
    <description>Study website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ciliary Motility Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dyskinesias</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Researchers who wish to use data should submit a concept sheet describing the planned analysis and send it to Prof. Claudia Kuehni (Claudia.kuehni@ispm.unibe.ch). The concept sheet will be discussed with the patient advisory group and if agreed, a partial dataset will be prepared by the research team.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

