<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3242">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04534478</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-003651-15</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04534478</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Oral Prednisone Regimens to Optimize the Therapeutic Strategy in Patients With Organizing Pneumonia Post-COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>NORCOVID</acronym>
  <official_title>Randomized, Open, Parallel, Single-center, Non-inferiority Clinical Trial, With an Active Control Group, Comparing Two Oral Prednisone Regimens With the Aim of Optimizing the Therapeutic Strategy in Patients With Organizing Pneumonia Post-COVID-19 Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital Universitari Vall d'Hebron Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital Universitari Vall d'Hebron Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Based on data from the 2003 SARS-COVID pandemic, other serious lung infections,&#xD;
      and patients with respiratory distress, it is estimated that 10-30% of patients with severe&#xD;
      SARS-COVID-2 pneumonia may present as a sequel an organized pneumonia. The treatment of this&#xD;
      complication is not well defined. The use of oral corticosteroids is mandatory to avoid a&#xD;
      possible evolution to pulmonary fibrosis, however, the doses to be administered and the&#xD;
      duration of treatment are unknown as there is no study specifically aimed at solving this&#xD;
      doubt. Many authors advocate high-dose treatment regimens for a minimum of six months, as&#xD;
      proposed for cryptogenic organized pneumonia. However, there is a question whether in&#xD;
      non-idiopathic cases of organized pneumonia, less intense treatment could resolve the&#xD;
      disease. Hypothesis: The use of a less intensive prednisone regimen may be sufficient for&#xD;
      therapeutic control in patients with post-COVID-19 organizing pneumonia, in relation to the&#xD;
      established standard regimen Simplicity of the procedures: The objective of the NORCOVID&#xD;
      study is to identify the optimal treatment regimen with corticosteroids in post-COVID19&#xD;
      patients diagnosed with NO. Specifically, the primary objective of this multicenter&#xD;
      randomized trial is to evaluate whether treatment with a less intensive regimen of&#xD;
      corticosteroids produces a non-inferior therapeutic effect than the established control&#xD;
      regimen. Secondary objectives are to evaluate the effect of treatment on secondary efficacy&#xD;
      variables and on safety. DLCO, respiratory function tests, 6MWT test, need for rescue,&#xD;
      radiological tests, complications, mortality and the WHO ordinal scale will be evaluated.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Hypothesis The use of a less intensive prednisone regimen may be sufficient for therapeutic&#xD;
      control in patients with post-COVID-19 organizing pneumonia, in relation to the established&#xD;
      standard regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives The objective of the NORCOVID study is to identify the optimal treatment regimen&#xD;
      with corticosteroids in post-COVID19 patients diagnosed with NO. Specifically, the primary&#xD;
      objective of this multicenter randomized trial is to evaluate whether treatment with a less&#xD;
      intensive regimen of corticosteroids produces a non-inferior therapeutic effect than the&#xD;
      established control regimen. Secondary objectives are to evaluate the effect of treatment on&#xD;
      secondary efficacy variables and on safety. DLCO, respiratory function tests, 6MWT test, need&#xD;
      for rescue, radiological tests, complications, mortality and the WHO ordinal scale will be&#xD;
      evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population: inclusion and exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Inclusion criteria 1) Patients over 18 years of age 2) Diagnosis of COVID-19 pneumonia&#xD;
           that would have required hospital admission 3) Diagnosis of post-COVID-19 organized&#xD;
           pneumonia 4) Without any contraindication to the study drug 5) That, properly informed,&#xD;
           voluntarily agree to participate in the study after knowing its objectives and risks and&#xD;
           give their consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Exclusion criteria Patients will not be randomized if: 1) They do not authorize their&#xD;
           participation 2) Patients with contraindications to receiving corticosteroid treatment&#xD;
           3) Impossibility of understanding the requirements of the study, in the opinion of the&#xD;
           investigator. 4) Expected survival less than the duration of the study in the opinion of&#xD;
           the investigator. 5) Clinical evidence of active infection, including but not limited to&#xD;
           bronchitis, pneumonia, sinusitis, urinary tract infection, and / or cellulitis. 6)&#xD;
           Patient who is subject to receiving a lung transplant during the study period. 7)&#xD;
           Impossibility of conducting lung function studies. 8) Poorly controlled diabetes&#xD;
           mellitus (glycosylated Hb&gt; 10%). 9) Pregnancy or breastfeeding 10) Have any&#xD;
           contraindication to the study drug 11) Are participating in another intervention study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Products evaluated and administration regimens.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The product evaluated will be Prednisone orally in two administration schedules:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Control Group: Prednisone 0.75mg / Kg / d 4week; 0.5mg / Kg / d 4 weeks; 20mg / d 4&#xD;
           weeks; 10mg / d 6 weeks; 5mg / d 6 weeks (6m).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Experimental Group: Prednisone 0.5mg / Kg / d 3 weeks, 20mg / day 3 weeks; 15mg / day 2&#xD;
           weeks; 10mg / day 2 weeks, 5mg / day 2 weeks and discontinue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main variable - The main variable will be the change in pulmonary diffusion, in terms of&#xD;
      predicted DLCO (%), between the baseline value and that obtained at 6 months, comparing the&#xD;
      two treatment groups adjusting for the baseline value using a model of Repeated measures with&#xD;
      random effects (mixed model for repeated measurements: MMRM).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary variables&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  DLCO in original units (DLCO10s mLmin - 1mmHg - 1)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Percentage of patients with values &lt;80% predicted&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Respiratory function tests&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  6-Minute-Walk Test (6MWT) test&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Need for rescue&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Computed Axial Tomography Test&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Complications related to the evolution of the disease (serious and non-serious)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Complications related to corticosteroid treatment (serious and non-serious)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Complication of any kind (serious and non-serious)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Mortality from any cause&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ordinal variable of clinical improvement recommended by the WHO R&amp;D Blueprint expert&#xD;
           group15 for the acute phase. The worst score obtained during the study will be evaluated&#xD;
           at each visit and as a summary measure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 7, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Parallel clinical trial with therapeutic intervention, randomized, open and controlled, of non-inferiority</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in pulmonary diffusion.</measure>
    <time_frame>Six Months</time_frame>
    <description>The main variable will be the change in pulmonary diffusion, in terms of predicted DLCO (%), between the baseline value and that obtained at 6 months, comparing the two treatment groups, adjusting for the baseline value using a repeated measures model with random effects (mixed model for repeated measurements.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19 Pneumonia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Prednisone 0.75mg / Kg / d 4 weeks; 0.5mg / Kg / d 4 weeks; 20mg / d 4 weeks; 10mg / d 6 weeks; 5mg / d 6 weeks (6m)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Prednisone 0.5mg / Kg / d 3 weeks, 20mg / day 3 weeks; 15mg / day 2 weeks; 10mg / day 2 weeks, 5mg / day 2 weeks and discontinue.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prednisone</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will be randomized 1: 1 between the two arms of the study</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients over 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of COVID-19 pneumonia that would have required hospital admission&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Post COVID-19 Organized Pneumonia Diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Without any contraindication to the study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  That, adequately informed, voluntarily agree to participate in the study after knowing&#xD;
             its objectives and risks and grant their written consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  They do not authorize their participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with contraindications to receiving treatment with corticosteroids&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impossibility of understanding the requirements of the study, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             researcher.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expected survival less than the duration of the study in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical evidence of active infection, including but not limited to bronchitis,&#xD;
             pneumonia, sinusitis, urinary tract infection and / or cellulitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who receives a lung transplant during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impossibility of carrying out lung function studies. - Poorly controlled diabetes&#xD;
             mellitus (glycosylated Hb&gt; 10%).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  They are participating in another intervention study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Maria-Jesus Cruz, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0034934894048</phone>
    <email>mj.cruz@vhir.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 31, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 31, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 31, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 31, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

