<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1842">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04425850</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IVERCAR</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04425850</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>USEFULNESS of Topic Ivermectin and Carrageenan to Prevent Contagion of Covid 19</brief_title>
  <acronym>IVERCAR</acronym>
  <official_title>USEFULNESS of Topic Ivermectin and Carrageenan to Prevent Contagion of Covid Among Healthy People and Health Personnel</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Eurnekian Public Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Eurnekian Public Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Estimation of the prevalence and contagiousness of undocumented novel coronavirus infections&#xD;
      is critical for understanding the overall prevalence and pandemic potential of this disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is estimated that 86% of all infections were undocumented [95% credible interval (CI):&#xD;
      82-90%] before the 23 January 2020 travel restrictions. The transmission rate of undocumented&#xD;
      infections per person was 55% the transmission rate of documented infections (95% CI:&#xD;
      46-62%), yet, because of their greater numbers, undocumented infections were the source of&#xD;
      79% of the documented cases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ivermectin + Carrageenan, taking advantage of their virucidal effects, are aimed at reducing&#xD;
      the contagion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      CONTAGION COURSE Estimation of the prevalence and contagiousness of undocumented novel&#xD;
      coronavirus infections is critical for understanding the overall prevalence and pandemic&#xD;
      potential of this disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Observations of reported infection within China, in conjunction with mobility data, a&#xD;
      networked dynamic metapopulation model, and Bayesian inference, to infer critical&#xD;
      epidemiological characteristics associated with SARS-CoV-2, including the fraction of&#xD;
      undocumented infections and their contagiousness, have been attempted. The rapid geographic&#xD;
      spread of SARS-CoV-2 indicate that containment of this virus will be particularly&#xD;
      challenging.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DISSEMINATION BY DROPLETS For COVID-19, the salivary gland could be an important source of&#xD;
      the virus in saliva and would generate infectious saliva on a sustained basis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ACE2 expression in the minor salivary glands was higher than in the lungs, suggesting that&#xD;
      the salivary glands is a potential target for COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The positive rate of COVID-19 in the patients' saliva can reach 91.7%, and the saliva samples&#xD;
      can also culture the live virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to mobility restrictions of people, the World Health Organization and the&#xD;
      Governments have prescribed maintaining an inter-personal distance of 1.5 or 2 m (about 6&#xD;
      feet) from each other in order to minimize the risk of contagion through the droplets that we&#xD;
      usually disseminate around us from nose and mouth. However, recently published studies&#xD;
      support the hypothesis of virus transmission over a distance of 2 m from an infected person.&#xD;
      Researchers have proved the higher aerosol and surface stability of SARS-COV-2 as compared&#xD;
      with SARS-COV-1 (with the virus remaining viable and infectious in aerosol for hours) and&#xD;
      that airborne transmission of SARS-CoV can occur besides close-distance contacts. Indeed,&#xD;
      there is reasonable evidence about the possibility of SARS-COV-2 airborne transmission due to&#xD;
      its persistence into aerosol droplets in a viable and infectious form. Based on the available&#xD;
      knowledge and epidemiological observations, it is plausible that small particles containing&#xD;
      the virus may diffuse in indoor environments covering distances up to 10 m from the emission&#xD;
      sources, thus representing a kind of aerosol transmission. On-field studies carried out&#xD;
      inside Wuhan Hospitals showed the presence of SARS-COV-2 RNA in air samples collected in the&#xD;
      hospitals and also in the surroundings, leading to the conclusion that the airborne route has&#xD;
      to be considered an important pathway for viral diffusion. Similar findings are reported in&#xD;
      analyses concerning air samples collected at the Nebraska University Hospital. On March 16th,&#xD;
      we have released a Position Paper emphasizing the airborne route as a possible additional&#xD;
      factor for interpreting the anomalous COVID-19 outbreaks in northern Italy, ranked as one of&#xD;
      the most polluted areas in Europe and characterized by high particulate matter (PM)&#xD;
      concentrations. The available information on the SARS-COV-2 spreading supports the hypothesis&#xD;
      of airborne diffusion of infected droplets from person to person at a distance greater than&#xD;
      two meters (6 feet). The inter-personal distance of 2 m can be reasonably considered as an&#xD;
      effective protection only if everybody wears face masks in daily life activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IVERMECTIN CONCENTRATION IN SALIVARY GLANDS The concentration of ivermectin was tested in&#xD;
      different tissues, in different studies, both in animals and human beings. The concentration&#xD;
      in salivary glands proved to be adequately acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CARRAGEENAN VIRUCIDAL EFFECTS Iota Carrageenan is widely used in gastronomic, cosmetic and&#xD;
      pharmacologic industry.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, its intrinsic virucidal effectas were proved over a variety of virus (herpes&#xD;
      simplex, Japanese Encephalitis, Rhinovirus, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Its mechanism of action is preventing virus adsorption to host cells. By applying both drugs&#xD;
      topically, 5 times per day, in nasal and oral mucosae, we try to reduce contagion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 10, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 10, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Infected Subjects</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants testing positive for COVID-19 after inclusion in each arm</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events Other Than Those Resulting From Contagion or Disease Progression</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events reported by subjects of each arm are recorded other than those resulting from contagion or disease progression</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">229</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IVER+</arm_group_label>
    <description>Adults, both genders, no age limit. They will be provided with topical medication, to be used 5 times a day. They will follow standard prophylactic measures and use PPE as suggested by OMS.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IVER-</arm_group_label>
    <description>Adults, both genders, no age limit They will follow standard prophylactic measures and use PPE suggestions, only.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Iota carrageenan nasal spray and Ivermectin oral drops (used as buccal drops)</intervention_name>
    <description>Topical application in the nose and oral cavity</description>
    <arm_group_label>IVER+</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Nasitral (iota carrageenan nasal spray), Ivercass (ivermectin oral drops)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Healthy volunteers testing negative for COVID-19 just before inclusion.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Not younger than 18 years of either sex&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Health personnel from the Dr. Alberto Eurnekian Interzonal University Hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. No COVID-19 related symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Able to understand and give written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Known hypersensitivity or allergy to any component of the product under evaluation&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age under 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Use of immunosuppressants (including systemic corticosteroids) in the past 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pregnant or nursing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients with other acute infectious diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with autoimmune disease and / or decompensated chronic diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Unable to fulfill the administrative tasks proposed by the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Infection with SARSCoV-2 confirmed by PCR or rapid test authorized by ANMAT.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Eurnekian</name>
      <address>
        <city>Buenos Aires</city>
        <zip>1802</zip>
        <country>Argentina</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Harden EA, Falshaw R, Carnachan SM, Kern ER, Prichard MN. Virucidal activity of polysaccharide extracts from four algal species against herpes simplex virus. Antiviral Res. 2009 Sep;83(3):282-9. doi: 10.1016/j.antiviral.2009.06.007. Epub 2009 Jul 1.</citation>
    <PMID>19576248</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carlucci MJ, Scolaro LA, Noseda MD, Cerezo AS, Damonte EB. Protective effect of a natural carrageenan on genital herpes simplex virus infection in mice. Antiviral Res. 2004 Nov;64(2):137-41.</citation>
    <PMID>15498610</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ashraf S, Prichard R. Ivermectin exhibits potent anti-mitotic activity. Vet Parasitol. 2016 Aug 15;226:1-4. doi: 10.1016/j.vetpar.2016.06.015. Epub 2016 Jun 11.</citation>
    <PMID>27514873</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 8, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 8, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>August 13, 2020</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>October 15, 2020</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 15, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 15, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Eurnekian Public Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Hector E Carvallo</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>IVERMECTIN CARRAGEENAN COVID 19</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ivermectin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>May 29, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/50/NCT04425850/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <recruitment_details>Health personnel</recruitment_details>
      <pre_assignment_details>Once consent was signed, compliance with all the eligibility criteria verified, and inclusion of the subject decided, the investigator assigns corresponding treatment according to the randomization carried out.&#xD;
It includes volunteers for both cohorts, provided they have test negative for COVID 19 in swabs obtained immediately before inclusion.</pre_assignment_details>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>IVER+</title>
          <description>Standard prophylactic measures and PPEs + iota carrageenan (nasal and buccal) and ivermectin (buccal)</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P2">
          <title>IVER-</title>
          <description>Standard prophylactic measures and PPE only</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Overall Study</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="131">Standard prophylactic measures and PPE + iota carrageenan (nasal and buccal) and ivermectin (buccal)</participants>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="98">Standard prophylactic measures and PPE only</participants>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="131"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="98"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>IVER+</title>
          <description>Adults, both genders, no age limit. They will be provided with topical medication, to be used 5 times a day. PPEs used as suggested by OMS.&#xD;
iota carrageenan: topical use on nasal mucosae&#xD;
Ivermectin: Topical use on oral mucosae</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B2">
          <title>IVER-</title>
          <description>Same as IVER+ They will follow PPEs suggestions, only.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B3">
          <title>Total</title>
          <description>Total of all reporting groups</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="131"/>
            <count group_id="B2" value="98"/>
            <count group_id="B3" value="229"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>years</units>
          <param>Median</param>
          <dispersion>Full Range</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="42" lower_limit="25" upper_limit="60"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="39" lower_limit="28" upper_limit="50"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="40" lower_limit="25" upper_limit="60"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="70"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="72"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="142"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="61"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="26"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="87"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Ethnicity (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Hispanic or Latino</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="131"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="98"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="229"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Not Hispanic or Latino</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Race (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>American Indian or Alaska Native</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Asian</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Black or African American</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>White</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>More than one race</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="131"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="98"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="229"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Region of Enrollment</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>Argentina</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="131"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="98"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="229"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Number of Infected Subjects</title>
        <description>Number of participants testing positive for COVID-19 after inclusion in each arm</description>
        <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
        <population>Hispanic</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>IVER+</title>
            <description>Standard prophylactic measures and PPEs + topical treatment with iota carrageenan (nasal and buccal) and ivermectin (buccal)</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>IVER-</title>
            <description>Standard prophylactic measures and PPEs only</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Number of Infected Subjects</title>
          <description>Number of participants testing positive for COVID-19 after inclusion in each arm</description>
          <population>Hispanic</population>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="131"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="98"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="11"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <analysis_list>
          <analysis>
            <group_id_list>
              <group_id>O1</group_id>
              <group_id>O2</group_id>
            </group_id_list>
            <groups_desc>Chi-squared test on the percentage of subjects who contracted COVID-19 in each arm</groups_desc>
            <non_inferiority_type>Other</non_inferiority_type>
            <p_value>&lt; 0.0001</p_value>
            <method>Chi-squared</method>
          </analysis>
        </analysis_list>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Adverse Events Other Than Those Resulting From Contagion or Disease Progression</title>
        <description>Adverse events reported by subjects of each arm are recorded other than those resulting from contagion or disease progression</description>
        <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
        <population>Hispanic</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>IVER+</title>
            <description>Standard prophylactic measures and PPE + Treatment with iota carragenan (nasal and buccal) and ivermectin (buccal only)</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>IVER-</title>
            <description>Standard prophylactic measures and PPE only</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Adverse Events Other Than Those Resulting From Contagion or Disease Progression</title>
          <description>Adverse events reported by subjects of each arm are recorded other than those resulting from contagion or disease progression</description>
          <population>Hispanic</population>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="131"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="98"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
      <desc>Medical examination Chart of adverse events filled in by subjects</desc>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>IVER+</title>
          <description>Standard prophylactic measures and PPEs + topical treatment with iota carrageenan (nasal and buccal) and ivermectin (buccal).</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E2">
          <title>IVER-</title>
          <description>Standard prophylactic measures and PPEs only</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, all-cause mortality</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="131"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="98"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="131"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="98"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>0</frequency_threshold>
        <default_assessment>Systematic Assessment</default_assessment>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="131"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="11" subjects_at_risk="98"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Infections and infestations</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Contagion</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="131"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="11" subjects_affected="11" subjects_at_risk="98"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>Principal Investigators are NOT employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>There is NOT an agreement between Principal Investigators and the Sponsor (or its agents) that restricts the PI's rights to discuss or publish trial results after the trial is completed. </restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Dr. Héctor Carvallo</name_or_title>
      <organization>Eurnekian Public Hospital</organization>
      <phone>54144800949</phone>
      <email>hymcarvallo@hotmail.com</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

