<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="398">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04673214</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R-2020-785-176</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04673214</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of Prognostic Modification in COVID-19 Patients in Early Intervention Treatment</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prognostic Modification in Patients With COVID-19 Under Early Intervention Treatment at U.M.F 13 and U.M.F 20</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Gilberto Cruz Arteaga</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Coordinación de Investigación en Salud, Mexico</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Coordinación de Investigación en Salud, Mexico</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The present study is designed for patients with mild COVID-19 phase, to demonstrate if there&#xD;
      is a modification in the clinical evolution greater than or equal to 25% in their symptoms,&#xD;
      implemented in two groups of patients under an early intervention treatment, a group ( A)&#xD;
      will receive Azithromycin / Ivermectin / Ribaroxaban / Paracetamol and another group (B) will&#xD;
      receive Azithromycin / Ribaroxaban / Paracetamol followed for 14 days followed by video call&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) is caused by SARS-COV2 and represents the causative agent of a&#xD;
      potential fatal disease generating a global public health problem. Person-to-person&#xD;
      transmission of COVID-19 infection led to the isolation of patients who subsequently received&#xD;
      a variety of treatments. Ivermectin treatment for safety is approved for human use by the FDA&#xD;
      in parasitic and skin infections. Studies report the therapeutic safety of Ivermectin in&#xD;
      humans with COVID-19, describing a 6.1-fold decrease in lethality compared to patients who&#xD;
      did not use Ivermectin (1.4 vs. 8.5%, p &lt;0.0001). In this sense, the WHO and PAHO encourage&#xD;
      the use of unproven therapies in the context of a randomized clinical trial (RCT).&#xD;
      Anticoagulants have reported up to 20% in the reduction of mortality (heparin), Ribaroxaban&#xD;
      is effective with the inhibition of PAR1 / PAR2 / PAR4 receptors through the blocking of&#xD;
      Factor Xa and the formation of thrombin, having anti-inflammatory effects, decreasing&#xD;
      arteriosclerosis and platelet aggregation. There is a Telemedicine working method implemented&#xD;
      by the OOAD of the North Federal District, which detects early signs and symptoms of possible&#xD;
      complications and offers an early intervention treatment policy for first-level care&#xD;
      beneficiaries. Under this method, a quasi-experimental study showed that there is a&#xD;
      modification in the frequency of recovered patients of 80-90% in patients diagnosed with&#xD;
      COVID-19 after an early intervention treatment with paracetamol, Ivermectin, Azithromycin,&#xD;
      Ribaroxaban in patients with COVID -19 from UMF 13 during the period of July-August 2020.&#xD;
      Therefore, it is necessary to carry out a randomized clinical trial to confirm this&#xD;
      assertion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: To evaluate the percentage of patients with a diagnosis of COVID-19 who modify&#xD;
      their clinical evolution under a comparative treatment of early intervention in beneficiaries&#xD;
      of the U.M.F 13 and U.M.F 20 of the I.M.S.S., during the period of December 2020-January&#xD;
      2021.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Material and Methods: A randomized, single-blind, prospective, longitudinal and open&#xD;
      experimental study in 62 patients with COVID-19 from UMF No. 13 and No. 20 from November to&#xD;
      December 2020. Including 31 patients in group A (Azithromycin / Ivermectin / Ribaroxaban /&#xD;
      Paracetamol) and 31 patients in group B (Azithromycin / Ribaroxaban / Paracetamol). With&#xD;
      inclusion criteria over 18 years of age, have type 2 diabetes mellitus, Systemic Arterial&#xD;
      Hypertension, Obesity or overweight, PCR confirmation of COVID-19. For the video call, the&#xD;
      Family Medicine Units have Electronic Equipment Installation for Internet use. Exclusion&#xD;
      criteria are patients with severe COVID-19 (they deserve immediate referral to second level&#xD;
      of care, hospital). Elimination criteria are Prior informed consent, medication is given&#xD;
      randomly to a COVID-19 patient, a follow-up video call will be made at home for 14 days,&#xD;
      recording sex, age, education, date of disease onset, taking laboratories (hematic biometry,&#xD;
      C-reactive protein, D-dimer, Ferritin, prothrombin time, thromboplastin time, lactic&#xD;
      dehydrogenase) taken at the onset of the disease, taking as an outcome variable the&#xD;
      modification of the clinical course (clinical symptoms such as headache, cough, fever,&#xD;
      conjunctivitis , myalgias, arthralgias, rhinorrhea, odynophagia, anosmia, chest pain,&#xD;
      dyspnea) when granting treatment in groups A and B.. Statistical differences will be&#xD;
      evaluated using the Mann-Whitney U test with a power of 90% and a type I error rate of 1% for&#xD;
      the variable of modification of the clinical course in treatment groups A and B. analysis&#xD;
      will be performed in SPSS version 21.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 16, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 12, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Two groups of patients with COVID-19 will be integrated, a Group A taking the following medications: Paracetamol 500 mg orally 1 tablet every 8 hours for 3 days in case of fever equal to or greater than 38.3 ° C, Azithromycin tablets of 500 mg will take 1 single dose tablet the first day and then half a tablet (250 mg) orally every 24 for 4 days, Ivermectin tablets of 200mcg which will be calculated according to your weight and dose, it will be every 24 hours for 2 days and Rivaroxaban 10 mg tablets will take 1 every 24 hours for 10 days and a Group B will take Paracetamol 500 mg orally 1 tablet every 8 hours for 3 days in case of fever equal to or greater than 38.3 ° C, Azithromycin tablets of 500 mg will take 1 single dose tablet on the first day and then half a tablet orally every 24 hours for 4 days and Rivaroxaban 10 mg tablets will take 1 every 24 hours for 10 days.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>For the conformation of the groups, random numbers generated by lottery will be used in which the patient will take a piece of paper as he arrives and will have the number of the group to which he will be assigned. With a type of block randomization, A (Azithromycin, paracetamol, Ivermectin, and Ribaroxaban) and B (paracetamol, Azithromycin, and Ribaroxaban).</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Estimate clinical symptoms by days of follow-up in patients with COVID-19 under treatment with Azithromycin/Ivermectin/Ribaroxaban/Paracetamol vs. Azithromycin/Ribaroxaban/Paracetamol followed by video call for 14 days from U.M.F 13 and U.M.F 20</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Assuming 25% efficacy in modifying the clinical course (Symptoms of fever, cough, headache, myalgia, odynophagia, anosmia, rhinorrhea, arthralgia, chest pain, dyspnea, conjunctivitis) of patients diagnosed with COVID-19 under treatment comparative of early intervention for 14 days followed by video call, with a power of 90%, a type I error rate of 1% and a loss to follow-up of 20%; We calculated a total of 62 patients with COVID-19, that is, 31 cases in group A with Azithromycin / Ivermectin / Ribaroxaban / Paracetamol treatment and 31 in group B with Azithromycin / Ribaroxaban / Paracetamol treatment would be necessary for the analysis. Statistical differences will be evaluated using the Mann-Whitney U test. The analyzes will be performed in SPSS version 21</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess adverse drug reactions by days of follow-up in patients with COVID-19 under treatment with Azithromycin/Ivermectin/Ribaroxaban /Paracetamol vs. Azithromycin /Ribaroxaban/Paracetamol followed by video call for 14 days from U.M.F 13 and U.M.F 20</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Assuming a 25% efficacy in modifying the clinical course (adverse reactions) of patients diagnosed with COVID-19 under a comparative early intervention treatment for 14 days followed by video call, with a power of 90%, an error rate type I of 1% and loss to follow-up of 20%; We calculated a total of 62 patients with COVID-19, that is, 31 cases in group A with Azithromycin / Ivermectin / Ribaroxaban / Paracetamol treatment and 31 in group B with Azithromycin / Ribaroxaban / Paracetamol treatment would be necessary for the analysis. Statistical differences will be evaluated using the Mann-Whitney U test. The analyzes will be performed in SPSS version 21</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">62</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Triple therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Paracetamol 500 mg orally 1 tablet every 8 hours for 3 days in case of fever equal to or greater than 38.3 ° C, Azithromycin 500 mg tablets will take 1 tablet single dose the first day and then half tablet (250 mg) orally every 24 for 4 days, Ivermectin tablets of 200mcg which will be calculated according to your weight and dose, will be every 24 hours for 2 days and Rivaroxaban tablets of 10 mg will take 1 every 24 hours for 10 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Double therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Paracetamol 500 mg orally 1 tablet every 8 hours for 3 days in case of fever equal to or greater than 38.3 ° C, Azithromycin 500 mg tablets will take 1 tablet single dose the first day and then half a tablet orally every 24 for 4 days and Rivaroxaban 10 mg tablets will take 1 every 24 hours for 10 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Azithromycin / Ivermectin / Ribaroxaban / Paracetamol</intervention_name>
    <description>In the patient with the presence of COVID-19 confirmed by the PCR-COVID-19 positive test, the drug is randomly assigned to belong to group A of Azithromycin / Ivermectin / Ribaroxaban / Paracetamol to be followed for 14 days by video call (approximately 15 to 20 min per day) to the patient and the presence or absence of clinical symptoms, adverse reactions being recorded daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>Triple therapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>with Ivermectin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Azithromycin / Ribaroxaban / Paracetamol</intervention_name>
    <description>In the patient with the presence of COVID-19 confirmed by the PCR-COVID-19 positive test, the drug is randomly assigned to belong to group B of Azithromycin / Ribaroxaban / Paracetamol, to be followed for 14 days by video call (approximately 15 to 20 min per day) to the patient and the presence or absence of clinical symptoms, adverse reactions being recorded daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>Double therapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>without Ivermectin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients Eligible for Family Medicine Unit No.20 and Family Medicine Unit No.13&#xD;
             belonging to the North DF of the IMSS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and female patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients over 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with compliance with the operational definition COVID-19 and confirmatory&#xD;
             test of P.C.R. positive within the first days of the illness (that are evaluated in&#xD;
             first level of medical attention).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with comorbidities such as Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus, Systemic Arterial&#xD;
             Hypertension, Overweight or Obesity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  That they agree to sign an informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
             - Related to Video Call:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  That the Family Medicine Unit No.20 and the Family Medicine Unit No.13 belonging to&#xD;
             the North DF of the IMSS have the Installation of Electronic Equipment for Internet&#xD;
             use&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe COVID-19 patients (Ameriten sent immediately to second level of care, hospital)&#xD;
             Patients with any Personal Pathological History of Hematological Diseases. • Patients&#xD;
             allergic to macrolides (Azithromycin) and Ivermectin.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>GILBERTO CR ARTEAGA, specialist</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>MEXICAN SOCIAL SECURITY INSTITUTE</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>GILBERTO CR ARTEAGA, specialist</last_name>
    <phone>55 87 44 22</phone>
    <phone_ext>15320</phone_ext>
    <email>gilberto.cruz@imss.gob.mx</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>ALMA ITALIA GU MARTINEZ, specialist</last_name>
    <phone>55 61 27 00</phone>
    <phone_ext>21315</phone_ext>
    <email>italia.guerrero@imss.gob.mx</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alma Italia Guerrero Martinez</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mexico</city>
        <state>Distrito Federal</state>
        <zip>02000</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>GILBERTO CR ARTEAGA, SPECIALIST</last_name>
      <phone>55 87 44 22</phone>
      <phone_ext>15320</phone_ext>
      <email>gilberto.cruz@imss.gob.mx</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>ALMA ITALIA GU MARTINEZ, SPECIALIST</last_name>
      <phone>55 61 27 00</phone>
      <phone_ext>21315</phone_ext>
      <email>italia.guerrero@imss.gob.mx</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Mexico</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2020.105949</url>
    <description>Hydroxychloroquine and azithromycin as a treatment of COVID-19: results of an open-label non-randomized clinical trial</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/results/NCT04343092?term=NCT04343092&amp;draw=2&amp;rank=1&amp;view=results</url>
    <description>Effectiveness of Ivermectin as add-on Therapy in COVID-19 Management</description>
  </link>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Gautret P, Lagier JC, Parola P, Hoang VT, Meddeb L, Mailhe M, Doudier B, Courjon J, Giordanengo V, Vieira VE, Tissot Dupont H, Honoré S, Colson P, Chabrière E, La Scola B, Rolain JM, Brouqui P, Raoult D. Hydroxychloroquine and azithromycin as a treatment of COVID-19: results of an open-label non-randomized clinical trial. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2020 Jul;56(1):105949. doi: 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2020.105949. Epub 2020 Mar 20.</citation>
    <PMID>32205204</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Becattini C, Pace U, Rondelli F, Delrio P, Ceccarelli G, Boncompagni M, Graziosi L, Visonà A, Chiari D, Avruscio G, Frasson S, Gussoni G, Biancafarina A, Camporese G, Donini A, Bucci AF, Agnelli G. Rivaroxaban for extended antithrombotic prophylaxis after laparoscopic surgery for colorectal cancer. Design of the PRO-LAPS II STUDY. Eur J Intern Med. 2020 Feb;72:53-59. doi: 10.1016/j.ejim.2019.11.015. Epub 2019 Dec 7.</citation>
    <PMID>31818628</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Khorana AA, Soff GA, Kakkar AK, Vadhan-Raj S, Riess H, Wun T, Streiff MB, Garcia DA, Liebman HA, Belani CP, O'Reilly EM, Patel JN, Yimer HA, Wildgoose P, Burton P, Vijapurkar U, Kaul S, Eikelboom J, McBane R, Bauer KA, Kuderer NM, Lyman GH; CASSINI Investigators. Rivaroxaban for Thromboprophylaxis in High-Risk Ambulatory Patients with Cancer. N Engl J Med. 2019 Feb 21;380(8):720-728. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1814630.</citation>
    <PMID>30786186</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Dugina TN, Kiseleva EV, Chistov IV, Umarova BA, Strukova SM. Receptors of the PAR family as a link between blood coagulation and inflammation. Biochemistry (Mosc). 2002 Jan;67(1):65-74. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11841341</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Choudhary R, Sharma AK. Potential use of hydroxychloroquine, ivermectin and azithromycin drugs in fighting COVID-19: trends, scope and relevance. New Microbes New Infect. 2020 Apr 22;35:100684. doi: 10.1016/j.nmni.2020.100684. eCollection 2020 May. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32322397</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Arshad U, Pertinez H, Box H, Tatham L, Rajoli RKR, Curley P, Neary M, Sharp J, Liptrott NJ, Valentijn A, David C, Rannard SP, O'Neill PM, Aljayyoussi G, Pennington SH, Ward SA, Hill A, Back DJ, Khoo SH, Bray PG, Biagini GA, Owen A. Prioritization of Anti-SARS-Cov-2 Drug Repurposing Opportunities Based on Plasma and Target Site Concentrations Derived from their Established Human Pharmacokinetics. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2020 Oct;108(4):775-790. doi: 10.1002/cpt.1909. Epub 2020 Jun 14. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32438446</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 18, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 18, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 22, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Coordinación de Investigación en Salud, Mexico</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Gilberto Cruz Arteaga</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Coordinator of Health Education and Research</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acetaminophen</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Azithromycin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ivermectin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>SHARED VIA EMAIL IF OTHER RESEARCHERS REQUIRE IT</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

