<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4719">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04714164</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>29243</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04714164</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cognitive Behavioral Therapy Group for Older Adults Delivered by Telethealth</brief_title>
  <official_title>Feasibility of Delivering Group Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Older Adults With Depression and Anxiety by Telehealth</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nova Scotia Health Authority</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Nova Scotia Health Authority</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The present aim of the study is to to adapt an established, manualized enhanced Group CBT&#xD;
      (CBT-E) for seniors to a telehealth format, which will allow us to offer the group virtually&#xD;
      during the COVID-19 pandemic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this project is to adapt an established, manualized enhanced Group CBT (CBT-E)&#xD;
      for seniors to a telemedicine format. Currently the Geriatric Psychiatry service associated&#xD;
      with the Nova Scotia Health Authority offer two CBT-E groups every year. They are usually&#xD;
      facilitated by psychiatry residents, under the supervision of a staff psychiatrist. Due to&#xD;
      the risk of COVID-19, we will not be holding in-person groups this year. Instead we will&#xD;
      offer the group in a smaller, telemedicine format. For this project, we will change the group&#xD;
      structure and activities to allow it's delivery in a virtual format. This study will assess&#xD;
      feasibility, tolerability of the telehealth format by using the System Usability Scale and&#xD;
      Group Satisfaction Survey. It will also assess response to online therapy buy using pre- and&#xD;
      post-group questionnaires including the Beck Depression Inventory, Beck Anxiety Inventory and&#xD;
      Perceived Quality of Life Questionnaire. Paired t-tests will be used to analyse the data and&#xD;
      determine whether there has been an improvement in participant's symptoms and quality of&#xD;
      life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Feasibility and acceptability study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of Telehealth CBT group for older adults</measure>
    <time_frame>This will be completed at the end of the 8 week Telehealth CBT group.</time_frame>
    <description>This will be assessed by a questionnaire: System Usability Scale.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of Telehealth CBT group for older adults</measure>
    <time_frame>This will be completed at the end of the 8 week Telehealth CBT group.</time_frame>
    <description>This will be measured by a questionnaire administered to participants titled Satisfaction Survey.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Attrition to the Telehealth CBT group for older adults</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Attendance will be noted by group facilitators at each group session</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect size between pre-group and post-group questionnaires (anxiety)</measure>
    <time_frame>Scales will be administered at baseline and at the end of the 8 weeks of group therapy.</time_frame>
    <description>The following scale will be administered before and after completing the group to determine if there is any change in the result: Beck Anxiety Inventory.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect size between pre-group and post-group questionnaires (depression)</measure>
    <time_frame>Scales will be administered at baseline and at the end of the 8 weeks of group therapy.</time_frame>
    <description>The following scale will be administered before and after completing the group to determine if there is any change in the result: Beck Depression Inventory.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect size between pre-group and post-group questionnaires (perceived quality of life)</measure>
    <time_frame>Scales will be administered at baseline and at the end of the 8 weeks of group therapy.</time_frame>
    <description>The following scale will be administered before and after completing the group to determine if there is any change in the result: Perceived Quality of Life questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Major Depressive Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Generalized Anxiety Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Social Anxiety Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Panic Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Teletherapy Group CBT participants</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients over the age of 65 with either a Major Depressive Disorder or Generalized Anxiety Disorder who will be participating in a Group CBT delivered by Teletherapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Group Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Therapy will be delivered weekly for 8 weeks by Zoom.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Teletherapy Group CBT participants</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People over the age of 65&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of either or both Major Depressive Disorder (MDD) of mild or moderate&#xD;
             severity and an anxiety disorder, including generalized anxiety disorder, social&#xD;
             anxiety disorder or panic disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with psychosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with dementia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with severe Major Depressive Disorder or Anxiety Disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with antisocial or borderline personality disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with acute suicidal ideation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Older adults who do not have access to the technology required for group; computer,&#xD;
             phone or tablet with a webcam and access to Internet&#xD;
&#xD;
        These are also exclusion criteria for the CBT group outside of the study. People younger&#xD;
        than 65 are also excluded from the group because it is offered to older adults only.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christelle Boudreau, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>NSHA</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Christelle Boudreau, MD</last_name>
    <phone>5068752816</phone>
    <email>christelle.boudreau@nshealth.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Meagan MacNeil, MD</last_name>
    <phone>902-464-6032/902-456-3099</phone>
    <email>Meagan.MacNeil@nshealth.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.canada.ca/en/employment-social-development/programs/seniors-action-report.html</url>
    <description>Government of Canada - Action for Seniors report. Published in fall 2014.</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.multiculturalmentalhealth.ca/en/</url>
    <description>Center for Multicultural Mental Health Research 2012</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.basicbooks.com/titles/irvin-d-yalom/the-theory-and-practice-of-group-psychotherapy/9780465012916/</url>
    <description>Yalom, I.D., The Theory and Practice of Group Psychotherapy, 5th edition, Basic Books</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.nice.org.uk/</url>
    <description>National Institute for Clinical Excellence. Depression: management of depression in primary and secondary care. NICE 2004.</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hendriks GJ, Oude Voshaar RC, Keijsers GP, Hoogduin CA, van Balkom AJ. Cognitive-behavioural therapy for late-life anxiety disorders: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2008 Jun;117(6):403-11. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0447.2008.01190.x. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18479316</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tavares LR, Barbosa MR. Efficacy of group psychotherapy for geriatric depression: A systematic review. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2018 Sep - Oct;78:71-80. doi: 10.1016/j.archger.2018.06.001. Epub 2018 Jun 18.</citation>
    <PMID>29933137</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>O'Reilly R, Bishop J, Maddox K, Hutchinson L, Fisman M, Takhar J. Is telepsychiatry equivalent to face-to-face psychiatry? Results from a randomized controlled equivalence trial. Psychiatr Serv. 2007 Jun;58(6):836-43.</citation>
    <PMID>17535945</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gentry MT, Lapid MI, Rummans TA. Geriatric Telepsychiatry: Systematic Review and Policy Considerations. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2019 Feb;27(2):109-127. doi: 10.1016/j.jagp.2018.10.009. Epub 2018 Oct 30.</citation>
    <PMID>30416025</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wilson KC, Mottram PG, Vassilas CA. Psychotherapeutic treatments for older depressed people. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2008 Jan 23;(1):CD004853. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD004853.pub2. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18254062</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hantke N, Lajoy M, Gould CE, Magwene EM, Sordahl J, Hirst R, O'Hara R. Patient Satisfaction With Geriatric Psychiatry Services via Video Teleconference. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2020 Apr;28(4):491-494. doi: 10.1016/j.jagp.2019.08.020. Epub 2019 Aug 24.</citation>
    <PMID>31530457</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hubley S, Lynch SB, Schneck C, Thomas M, Shore J. Review of key telepsychiatry outcomes. World J Psychiatry. 2016 Jun 22;6(2):269-82. doi: 10.5498/wjp.v6.i2.269. eCollection 2016 Jun 22.</citation>
    <PMID>27354970</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Baldwin RC, Anderson D, Black S, Evans S, Jones R, Wilson K, Iliffe S; Faculty of Old Age Psychiatry Working Group, Royal College of Psychiatrists. Guideline for the management of late-life depression in primary care. Int J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2003 Sep;18(9):829-38.</citation>
    <PMID>12949851</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Apóstolo J, Bobrowicz-Campos E, Rodrigues M, Castro I, Cardoso D. The effectiveness of non-pharmacological interventions in older adults with depressive disorders: A systematic review. Int J Nurs Stud. 2016 Jun;58:59-70. doi: 10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2016.02.006. Epub 2016 Feb 17. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27087298</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jonsson U, Bertilsson G, Allard P, Gyllensvärd H, Söderlund A, Tham A, Andersson G. Psychological Treatment of Depression in People Aged 65 Years and Over: A Systematic Review of Efficacy, Safety, and Cost-Effectiveness. PLoS One. 2016 Aug 18;11(8):e0160859. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0160859. eCollection 2016. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27537217</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Choi NG, Marti CN, Bruce ML, Hegel MT, Wilson NL, Kunik ME. Six-month postintervention depression and disability outcomes of in-home telehealth problem-solving therapy for depressed, low-income homebound older adults. Depress Anxiety. 2014 Aug;31(8):653-61. doi: 10.1002/da.22242. Epub 2014 Feb 5.</citation>
    <PMID>24501015</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Egede LE, Acierno R, Knapp RG, Lejuez C, Hernandez-Tejada M, Payne EH, Frueh BC. Psychotherapy for depression in older veterans via telemedicine: a randomised, open-label, non-inferiority trial. Lancet Psychiatry. 2015 Aug;2(8):693-701. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(15)00122-4. Epub 2015 Jul 16.</citation>
    <PMID>26249300</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>MacQueen GM, Frey BN, Ismail Z, Jaworska N, Steiner M, Lieshout RJ, Kennedy SH, Lam RW, Milev RV, Parikh SV, Ravindran AV; CANMAT Depression Work Group. Canadian Network for Mood and Anxiety Treatments (CANMAT) 2016 Clinical Guidelines for the Management of Adults with Major Depressive Disorder: Section 6. Special Populations: Youth, Women, and the Elderly. Can J Psychiatry. 2016 Sep;61(9):588-603. doi: 10.1177/0706743716659276. Epub 2016 Aug 2. Review. Erratum in: Can J Psychiatry. 2017 May;62(5):356.</citation>
    <PMID>27486149</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 15, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Nova Scotia Health Authority</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Christelle Boudreau</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Psychiatry resident</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Panic Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Phobia, Social</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

