<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4150">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04704544</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB-300006553</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04704544</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness of Tele-rheumatology During the COVID-19 Crisis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effectiveness of Tele-rheumatology for Delivering High Quality Rheumatology Care During the COVID-19 Crisis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alabama at Birmingham</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of California, San Francisco</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Tulane University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alabama at Birmingham</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      While tele-rheumatology (TR) visits are a COVID-19 related necessity, there is a lack of&#xD;
      rigorous data on the comparative effectiveness of TR versus (vs) in-person usual care (UC)&#xD;
      especially in medically at-risk populations such as people with rheumatic and musculoskeletal&#xD;
      disease (RMD) using immunosuppressive drugs (IS). This clear research gap was highlighted by&#xD;
      the American College of Rheumatology in its recent Task Force Report on Telehealth in the&#xD;
      COVID era. In this study, the investigators will rigorously evaluate the comparative&#xD;
      effectiveness of TR visits for high risk people living with RMD and among those from socially&#xD;
      vulnerable populations, in the COVID-19 era. This study is of key public health importance&#xD;
      and relevance to rheumatology since it addresses the urgent clinical and policy needs to&#xD;
      provide safe, efficacious, and equitable care to diverse patients with RMD during and beyond&#xD;
      the COVID-19 crisis. Our proposal is very responsive to the RRF's Notice of Special interest&#xD;
      on COVID-19 in improving the care of people with RMD during the COVID-19 pandemic. The&#xD;
      investigators will perform the first randomized experiment of tele-rheumatology, generating&#xD;
      high quality evidence to guide the use of this technology across diverse populations of&#xD;
      people with RMDs. Beyond the high public health impact of this study for people with RMDs,&#xD;
      the investigators expect that our findings will have high generalizability to other at-risk&#xD;
      patient populations with multimorbidity and inform rheumatology practice into the foreseeable&#xD;
      future.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      People with RMDs, especially those with multi-comorbidities and on IS are among the most&#xD;
      at-risk for COVID-19-related fragmented care and poor outcomes. RMD burden is high in terms&#xD;
      of disability-adjusted-life years (DALYs) and has been escalating. Beyond the prevailing&#xD;
      challenges to in-person visits such as scheduling conflicts, transportation, or disability,&#xD;
      the COVID-19 pandemic has further exacerbated RMD patient burden through disruptions in&#xD;
      healthcare delivery (e.g. limited availability of in-person visits). Thus, high quality&#xD;
      adaptations of healthcare services for people living with RMD including through TR in the&#xD;
      context of the COVID-19 crisis are badly needed. The investigators found from a recent survey&#xD;
      of 24,500 people living with RMD that 60% of respondents avoided in-person clinic visits.&#xD;
      However, with the increasing availability of technology (90% Americans have internet access,&#xD;
      81% are online daily most patients and clinicians can engage in some form of TR. Due to&#xD;
      widespread social distancing and major health policy changes necessitated by COVID-19, TR has&#xD;
      been swiftly adopted (but minimally tested) as a means to deliver ongoing care for people&#xD;
      with RMD. Because patients can be evaluated in their own homes, thus avoiding travel that&#xD;
      increases COVID-19 risk, this approach provides means of healthcare for socially and&#xD;
      medically vulnerable groups, such as those residing in rural areas and those with&#xD;
      comorbidities, a group particularly at high risk of COVID-19 complications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>We will conduct an open label, two-period, cross-over, multi-center, non-inferiority, patient-level randomized controlled trial comparing tele-rheumatology (audio +/- video) with usual care (in-person) visits. Patients will be randomized to the sequence of care for their next two visits (V1 and V2): i) tele-rheumatology (V1) + usual care (V2), OR ii) usual care (V1) + tele-rheumatology (V2)</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Care Provider)</masking>
    <masking_description>Providers will be masked to the random assignment of participant visits.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>36-72 hours post visit</time_frame>
    <description>Patient satisfaction with type visit. Assessed with AHRQ's Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems (CAHPS)® survey</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient preference</measure>
    <time_frame>36-72 hours post visit</time_frame>
    <description>Patient preference with type visit. Assessed using &quot;If you had a choice, what type of visit would you prefer?&quot; with options a. telemedicine, b. in-office</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">320</enrollment>
  <condition>Rheumatic Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Tele-rheumatology first visit and Usual Care second visit</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomized to this visit will receive a tele-rheumatology visit first.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Care first visit and Tele-rheumatology second visit</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomized to this visit will receive a usual care visit first.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tele-rheumatology</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive virtual visits via video conferencing and/or phone.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Tele-rheumatology first visit and Usual Care second visit</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Care first visit and Tele-rheumatology second visit</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of rheumatic disease requiring ≥3 rheumatology outpatient visits spaced ≥2&#xD;
             months apart in the past 1 year (e.g. rheumatoid arthritis, SLE&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  very rare or severe rheumatic disease (e.g., vasculitis, scleroderma, inflammatory&#xD;
             myopathy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unstable rheumatic disease that needs in-person visits (e.g. recent diagnosis of&#xD;
             severe lupus nephritis),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  expected in-office procedures (e.g., joint injection)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  lack of access to phone.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>JEFF FOSTER, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>2059966086</phone>
    <email>pjfoster@uabmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Josh Melnick, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>205-975-0583</phone>
    <email>jmelnick@uabmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama at Birmingham</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35294</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Feldman CH, Ramsey-Goldman R. Widening Disparities Among Patients With Rheumatic Diseases in the COVID-19 Era: An Urgent Call to Action. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2020 Sep;72(9):1409-1411. doi: 10.1002/art.41306. Epub 2020 Aug 9.</citation>
    <PMID>32379381</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brooks PM. The burden of musculoskeletal disease--a global perspective. Clin Rheumatol. 2006 Nov;25(6):778-81. Epub 2006 Apr 12. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>16609823</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Donelan K, Barreto EA, Sossong S, Michael C, Estrada JJ, Cohen AB, Wozniak J, Schwamm LH. Patient and clinician experiences with telehealth for patient follow-up care. Am J Manag Care. 2019 Jan;25(1):40-44.</citation>
    <PMID>30667610</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Michaud K, Wipfler K, Shaw Y, Simon TA, Cornish A, England BR, Ogdie A, Katz P. Experiences of Patients With Rheumatic Diseases in the United States During Early Days of the COVID-19 Pandemic. ACR Open Rheumatol. 2020 Jun;2(6):335-343. doi: 10.1002/acr2.11148. Epub 2020 May 9.</citation>
    <PMID>32311836</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Webster P. Virtual health care in the era of COVID-19. Lancet. 2020 Apr 11;395(10231):1180-1181. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30818-7.</citation>
    <PMID>32278374</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bachireddy C, Chen C, Dar M. Securing the Safety Net and Protecting Public Health During a Pandemic: Medicaid's Response to COVID-19. JAMA. 2020 May 26;323(20):2009-2010. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.4272.</citation>
    <PMID>32191260</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Uscher-Pines L, Fischer S, Tong I, Mehrotra A, Malsberger R, Ray K. Virtual First Responders: the Role of Direct-to-Consumer Telemedicine in Caring for People Impacted by Natural Disasters. J Gen Intern Med. 2018 Aug;33(8):1242-1244. doi: 10.1007/s11606-018-4440-8.</citation>
    <PMID>29691713</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hayes BL, Curtis JR, Laster A, Saag K, Tanner SB, Liu C, Womack C, Johnson KC, Khaliq F, Carbone LD. Osteoporosis care in the United States after declines in reimbursements for DXA. J Clin Densitom. 2010 Oct-Dec;13(4):352-60. doi: 10.1016/j.jocd.2010.08.001.</citation>
    <PMID>21029972</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Richardson S, Hirsch JS, Narasimhan M, Crawford JM, McGinn T, Davidson KW; the Northwell COVID-19 Research Consortium, Barnaby DP, Becker LB, Chelico JD, Cohen SL, Cookingham J, Coppa K, Diefenbach MA, Dominello AJ, Duer-Hefele J, Falzon L, Gitlin J, Hajizadeh N, Harvin TG, Hirschwerk DA, Kim EJ, Kozel ZM, Marrast LM, Mogavero JN, Osorio GA, Qiu M, Zanos TP. Presenting Characteristics, Comorbidities, and Outcomes Among 5700 Patients Hospitalized With COVID-19 in the New York City Area. JAMA. 2020 May 26;323(20):2052-2059. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.6775. Erratum in: JAMA. 2020 May 26;323(20):2098.</citation>
    <PMID>32320003</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nesbitt TS, Marcin JP, Daschbach MM, Cole SL. Perceptions of local health care quality in 7 rural communities with telemedicine. J Rural Health. 2005 Winter;21(1):79-85.</citation>
    <PMID>15667014</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yang J, Zheng Y, Gou X, Pu K, Chen Z, Guo Q, Ji R, Wang H, Wang Y, Zhou Y. Prevalence of comorbidities and its effects in patients infected with SARS-CoV-2: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Infect Dis. 2020 May;94:91-95. doi: 10.1016/j.ijid.2020.03.017. Epub 2020 Mar 12.</citation>
    <PMID>32173574</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhou F, Yu T, Du R, Fan G, Liu Y, Liu Z, Xiang J, Wang Y, Song B, Gu X, Guan L, Wei Y, Li H, Wu X, Xu J, Tu S, Zhang Y, Chen H, Cao B. Clinical course and risk factors for mortality of adult inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet. 2020 Mar 28;395(10229):1054-1062. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30566-3. Epub 2020 Mar 11. Erratum in: Lancet. 2020 Mar 28;395(10229):1038. Lancet. 2020 Mar 28;395(10229):1038.</citation>
    <PMID>32171076</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 6, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Maria Danila, MD, MSc, MSPH</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rheumatic Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Collagen Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

