<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="664">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04380896</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20CB17</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04380896</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19 Staff Testing of Antibody Responses Study (Co-Stars)</brief_title>
  <acronym>Co-Stars</acronym>
  <official_title>COVID-19 Staff Testing of Antibody Responses Study (CO-STARS)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will perform prospective repeated serological antibody testing on a cohort of at&#xD;
      least 1000 healthcare workers at Great Ormond Street Hospital. Within this cohort, a subset&#xD;
      of 150-250 staff members with confirmed (PCR positive) SARS-CoV-2 disease will be followed&#xD;
      with intensive monthly testing for 6 months to determine whether antibody levels in the blood&#xD;
      are maintained or decrease during this time. All 1000 recruited healthcare workers will be&#xD;
      followed 6-monthly&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A total of 250 healthcare workers are currently off sick with symptoms of SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      infection (COVID-19) while 99 additional members of staff have been diagnosed with confirmed&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 at Great Ormond Street Hospital. As a consequence, all routine surgery,&#xD;
      out-patient activity and day cases have been postponed or cancelled altogether. It is&#xD;
      therefore critical for us to understand whether or not this disease will continue to threaten&#xD;
      staff health or whether natural infection will give rise to long lasting immunity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a 2-arm prospective cohort study recruiting at least 1000 healthcare workers at GOSH&#xD;
      over 6 years.Staff will be recruited and coordinated from each department to be&#xD;
      representative of the full diversity of healthcare workers at the Trust. The age distribution&#xD;
      of the participants will be monitored on a weekly, basis against the known age distribution&#xD;
      of the hospital to ensure that the sample is representative.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Trust communications team will send an all staff email to inform them about this research&#xD;
      project asking them to get in touch with the study team if they wish to participate and they&#xD;
      meet the basic eligibility criteria. Potential participants will be asked voluntarily to&#xD;
      attend a face to face appointment in person (or if preferred by telephone or 1:1 video&#xD;
      teleconference meeting) to enable trained study staff to seek informed consent before they&#xD;
      enter the study. Informed consent will be undertaken by study staff who are Good Clinical&#xD;
      Practice trained, Human Tissue Act trained, study trained, GOSH consent trained and&#xD;
      registered in the study log.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The consent process will specifically cover the reason for the study, the storage of samples&#xD;
      and agreement for future samples to be tested once improved testing is made available. Once&#xD;
      the member of staff has provided informed consent, they will be asked to undertake an online&#xD;
      questionnaire in which they will record demographic details including age, sex, email address&#xD;
      and telephone contact for results and coordinating follow up. The questionnaire will also&#xD;
      record details of SARS-CoV-2 like symptoms, contact with SARS-CoV-2, pre-existing&#xD;
      co-morbidities and medication or treatments that may interfere with serological testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After providing informed consent, the staff members then be asked attend the study phlebotomy&#xD;
      testing clinic. Appointments will be 20 minutes in length but actual blood sampling for&#xD;
      serological testing will be 5-10 minutes to allow plenty of time and space for staff members&#xD;
      to be tested to maintain social distancing. A total of 8ml of blood will be stored for&#xD;
      testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow up sampling and questionnaires of approximately 200 staff members with PCR confirmed&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 infected staff will take place monthly. While follow up of all ~800 asymptomatic&#xD;
      staff members will take place 6 monthly. All staff will continue to have access to the GOSH&#xD;
      PCR COVID19 testing program (as they do at present). This will enable us to confirm with PCR&#xD;
      testing any new (or reinfected) positive staff member with COVID-19 over the duration of the&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When initially asymptomatic seronegative staff become serologically positive during the&#xD;
      course of the study, they will remain under active surveillance but they will switch arms of&#xD;
      the study and they will contribute to the active follow up of serologically positive&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If staff leave the GOSH NHS trust during the study they will still be eligible to remain in&#xD;
      the study and be followed up and we will update their contact details on the follow-up&#xD;
      questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the initial intensive phase, all approximately 1000 recruits will be followed 6 monthly&#xD;
      for the 6 year duration of the study. Follow-up visits will be arranged following the&#xD;
      baseline assessment. The same blood tests 4ml EDTA and 4ml serum will be taken at each follow&#xD;
      up appointment as well as the same symptom questionnaire.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 27, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 27, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 27, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in serial monthly log-transformed antibody titre levels as measured</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months period post infection</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the kinetics (rate of change) of SARS-CoV-2 nucleo-capsid protein antibody titres in proven cases of SARS-CoV-2 over the 6 month period following infection</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of completely asymptomatic healthcare workers with evidence of SARS-CoV-2 antibodies</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the proportion of completely asymptomatic healthcare workers who have evidence of SARS-CoV-2 antibodies in their serum indicative of past infection</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The attack rate of SARS-CoV-2 in healthcare workers who have antibodies compared to those who do not</measure>
    <time_frame>Betwen 3 to 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the attack rate of SARS-CoV-2 in healthcare workers who have antibodies versus those who do not have antibodies</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The immune correlates of protection against future exposure to SARS-CoV-2</measure>
    <time_frame>Between 3 to 6 years</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the immune correlates of protection (Antibody Titres sufficient for protection) against future exposure to SARS-CoV-2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV-2 Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SARS-CoV-2 Seropositive Cases</arm_group_label>
    <description>It will be formed of approximately N= 200 to 350 staff members&#xD;
Core Group of PCR Confirmed Cases N ~ 150 to 250:&#xD;
A) Symptoms consistent with SARS-CoV-2 infection and SARS-CoV-2 PCR Positive N ~ 150 to 250 OR&#xD;
Other SARS-CoV-2 Sero-positives N ~ 50 to 100:&#xD;
B) Symptoms consistent with SARS-CoV-2 infection and SARS-CoV-2 PCR Negative cases. OR C) No symptoms consistent with SARS-CoV-2 infection and PCR Not Tested cases</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SARS-CoV-2 Seronegative Comparison Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>It will be formed of approximately N= 800 to 900 staff members&#xD;
Core Comparison Group N ~ 800 A) Have not had clinical symptoms consistent with SARS-CoV-2 infection OR&#xD;
Other Seronegatives N ~ 100 B) Have had sympoms of SARS-CoV-2 infection but have been tested and were PCR positive or negative but have not developed antibodies at 21 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Blood test</intervention_name>
    <description>Blood tests (8ml in total) 4ml blood for serological testing (measure the antibody titres to the SARS-CoV-2 nucleo-capsid protein (4ml) and 4ml EDTA to be stored for future research will be taken for each group.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SARS-CoV-2 Seronegative Comparison Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>SARS-CoV-2 Seropositive Cases</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standardised questionnaires</intervention_name>
    <description>It will be an online questionnaire about staff members health, symptoms of SARS-CoV-2 and contact with SARS-CoV-2. All participants will also be asked to complete a detailed symptom and electronic questionnaire prior to each appointment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SARS-CoV-2 Seronegative Comparison Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>SARS-CoV-2 Seropositive Cases</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Each sample will be tested using the EDITM diagnostic assay which detects the optical density&#xD;
      of antibodies in serum samples to the nucleo-capsid protein SARS-CoV-2. Both IgM and IgG&#xD;
      antibodies to the nucleo-capsid protein will be tested and reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the study the samples will be stored at -70oC in the freezers of the Great&#xD;
      Ormond Street Camelia Botnar Laboratories for future research. Future studies may involve&#xD;
      genetic testing on the samples and this has been highlighted on the consent form.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The population will comprise frontline healthcare workers selected to be representative of&#xD;
        all departments at Great Ormond Street Hospital. The researcher will ensure that equal&#xD;
        numbers of men and women are recruited from each department and that age ranges are&#xD;
        representative of the trust population age distribution.We will also check the age&#xD;
        distribution of the participants on a weekly basis during recruitment against the known age&#xD;
        distribution of the hospital to ensure that our sample is representative. If significant&#xD;
        differences among ages between the study population and the hospital population age range&#xD;
        emerge then we will actively recruit from those age ranges that we have inadequately&#xD;
        sampled.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria for ARM 1: SARS-CoV-2 Seropositive Cases:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthcare worker at GOSH&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &gt;18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ALL have confirmed detectable antibodies to SARS-CoV-2 infection on baseline screen&#xD;
&#xD;
        Then can be recruited into either of the following sub-groups&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Core Group of PCR Confirmed Cases : Must have symptoms consistent with SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
             infection and SARS-CoV-2 PCR Positive&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Other SARS-CoV-2 Sero-positives: May have Symptoms consistent with SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
             infection and SARS-CoV-2 PCR Negative cases OR May have no symptoms consistent with&#xD;
             SARS-CoV-2 infection and PCR Not Tested cases&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria for ARM 2: SARS-CoV-2 Seronegative Comparison Group :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthcare worker at GOSH&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &gt;18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ALL have confirmed negative antibodies to SARS-CoV-2 infection on baseline screen&#xD;
&#xD;
        Then can be recruited into either of the following Sub-groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Core Comparison Group: Have not had clinical symptoms consistent with SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
             infection*&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Other Seronegatives: Have had symptoms of SARS-CoV-2 infection but have been tested&#xD;
             and were PCR positive or negative but have not developed antibodies at 21 days&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clinical Symptoms for SARS-CoV-2 infection are defined as one of:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1) New and persistent cough 2) Confirmed temperatures of 37.8 and above 3) Anosmia&#xD;
&#xD;
        General Exclusion Criteria :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &lt;18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  On immunosuppressive or immunomodulatory medication that may impact test reliability&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received any blood product including immunoglobulins after October 2019&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received convalescent sera as treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current diagnosis of a malignancy that may impact test reliability&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those lacking capacity to provide informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Louis Grandjean, Dr</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Great Ormond Street Hospital NHS Foundation Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Louis Grandjean, Dr</last_name>
    <phone>07712336582</phone>
    <email>Louis.Grandjean@gosh.nhs.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Vanshree Patel, Dr</last_name>
    <email>research.governance@gosh.nhs.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Great Ormond Street Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>WC1N 3JH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Louis Grandjean, Dr</last_name>
      <email>louis.grandjean@gosh.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 7, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 8, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 13, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 13, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 15, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

