<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="234">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04468256</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20IC6036</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04468256</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Heart Hive COVID-19 Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Heart Hive COVID-19 Study: A Longitudinal Observational Study of the Impact and Clinical Outcomes of the COVID-19 Pandemic on Individuals With Heart Muscle Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Imperial College London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Imperial College London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      All patients with heart disease should have the opportunity to participate in research into&#xD;
      their condition, to advance knowledge and treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The HeartHive COVID-19 study is an international online pilot observational cohort study&#xD;
      evaluating the impact and clinical outcomes of the COVID-19 pandemic on subjects enrolled in&#xD;
      the HeartHive.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiomyopathies are progressive diseases, and there is a need to better understand what&#xD;
      factors affect the chances of developing cardiomyopathy, and how the condition progresses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on patients with cardiomyopathy has not been explored and&#xD;
      represents a critical unmet need. Insights into exposure, healthcare outcomes, behavioural&#xD;
      changes and the psychosocial ramifications of the pandemic are required to better understand&#xD;
      the health needs of this population during these unprecedented circumstances and to adapt&#xD;
      clinical services to meet these.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will entail completing serial online surveys during the pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study uses The Heart Hive - an international, online registry of patients with&#xD;
      self-reported clinically diagnosed cardiomyopathy, and people without heart disease.&#xD;
      Participants enrol and upload their own data through the website. It is the second research&#xD;
      study that will be offered to registry participants and delivered through The Heart Hive&#xD;
      platform.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on patients with cardiomyopathy has not been explored and&#xD;
      represents a critical unmet need. Insights into exposure, healthcare outcomes, behavioural&#xD;
      changes and the psychosocial ramifications of the pandemic are required to better understand&#xD;
      the health needs of this population during these unprecedented circumstances and to adapt&#xD;
      clinical services to meet these.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The requirements for the population to limit social interaction and stay at home&#xD;
      significantly limits conventional research approaches to studying the effect of the pandemic&#xD;
      on patients. The Heart Hive platform circumnavigates this by offering an online mechanism to&#xD;
      gain insight into the effect of the pandemic in a pre-assembled cohort of patients rapidly&#xD;
      and in real-time as the pandemic evolves without any risk to patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is framed around the following hypotheses:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Patients with cardiomyopathy who contract COVID-19 are at greater risk or death or&#xD;
           hospitalisation than subjects without heart disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Patients with cardiomyopathy perceive themselves to be at enhanced risk and are more&#xD;
           likely to be following national recommendations on social restriction measures than&#xD;
           subjects without heart disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Patients with cardiomyopathy have experienced interruption to the delivery of their&#xD;
           usual cardiology/cardiomyopathy clinical service as a result of the pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Patients with cardiomyopathy are less likely to seek medical help due to fear of&#xD;
           contracting COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. The psychological impact of the pandemic is greater in patients with cardiomyopathy than&#xD;
           in subjects without heart disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To conduct serial surveys in patients with cardiomyopathy and subjects without heart&#xD;
           disease evaluating the health-related, behavioural and psychosocial impact of the&#xD;
           COVID-19 pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To use national registries, including NHS Digital, Office for National Statistics (ONS),&#xD;
           Hospital Episodes Statistics (HES) and medical records to longitudinally assess hospital&#xD;
           admissions and patient mortality from COVID-19 for UK-based participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. To use serial surveys to evaluate the indirect impact of COVID-19 on access to healthcare&#xD;
      amongst patients with cardiomyopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Heart Hive COVID-19 study is an international online pilot observational cohort study&#xD;
      evaluating the impact and clinical outcomes of the COVID-19 pandemic on subjects enrolled in&#xD;
      the Heart Hive. Patients with heart muscle disease and subjects without heart disease who are&#xD;
      Heart Hive registry members are eligible to enrol. Eligible subjects who provide informed&#xD;
      consent will be enrolled. The study will entail completing serial online surveys during the&#xD;
      pandemic. For subjects who live in the UK who provide consent, health information and outcome&#xD;
      data will also be collected from NHS digital, national registries (e.g. ONS, HES, DID) and&#xD;
      medical records.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 26, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Qualitative measures of exposure, perception of risk, behaviour, and experience during the COVID-19 pandemic.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Collected from serial online surveys</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Health Outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Hospital admissions and deaths due to COVID-19, incidents of major adverse cardiovascular events</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <condition>Cardiomyopathies</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cardiomyopathy</arm_group_label>
    <description>Heart Hive registered participants with self-reported cardiomyopathy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Participants without Heart Disease</arm_group_label>
    <description>Heart Hive registered participants without cardiomyopathy or other heart disease.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>COVID-19 experience surveys</intervention_name>
    <description>Serial online surveys recording experiences of the COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cardiomyopathy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Participants without Heart Disease</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Heart Hive registry members with cardiomyopathy and subjects without heart disease will be&#xD;
        invited to enrol in the Heart Hive COVID-19 study. All registry members have previously&#xD;
        given consent to be invited by members of the study team to participate in future studies&#xD;
        and understand that this is voluntary. The Heart Hive COVID-19 study may be advertised on&#xD;
        social media (including Twitter, Facebook and Instagram). The study team may advertise the&#xD;
        study via adverts placed with medical society and patient organisation magazines and&#xD;
        websites (e.g. Cardiomyopathy UK and Pumping Marvelous).&#xD;
&#xD;
        There is no limit on the number of participants in the study. This reflects the pilot&#xD;
        design of the project and the flexibility afforded by the online platform via which the&#xD;
        study is delivered.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult (age 18 and over) Males or Females&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capacity to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with either:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A self-reported confirmed diagnosis of cardiomyopathy (dilated cardiomyopathy,&#xD;
                  hypertrophic cardiomyopathy, arrhythmogenic cardiomyopathy, restrictive&#xD;
                  cardiomyopathy, left ventricular non-compaction cardiomyopathy) Or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No self-reported history of heart disease&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: Pregnant women are eligible. This study is observational and entirely separate from&#xD;
        clinical care.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Patients who lack capacity to consent for themselves Vulnerable groups (e.g. those under&#xD;
        18, prisoners, those in a dependent relationship, the mentally ill)&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Although usually considered a vulnerable group, pregnant women are eligible for this&#xD;
        study which is observational and entirely separate from clinical care.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients with a confirmed history of coronary artery disease:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  who have been informed by their treating physician that their cardiomyopathy is&#xD;
             secondary to their coronary artery disease, or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  who have undergone previous percutaneous coronary intervention or coronary bypass&#xD;
             surgery History of primary valvular heart disease or congenital heart disease Severe,&#xD;
             untreated or untreatable hypertension (systolic blood pressures routinely &gt;180 mm Hg&#xD;
             and/or diastolic blood pressures &gt;120 mm Hg)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>James S Ware</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Imperial College London</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Imperial College London</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>W12 0NN</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>The Heart Hive</last_name>
      <phone>+44 20 7589 5111</phone>
      <email>info@thehearthive.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.thehearthive.org/</url>
    <description>The Heart Hive</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 13, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 1, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 1, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 2, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>cardiomyopathy</keyword>
  <keyword>HCM</keyword>
  <keyword>DCM</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cardiomyopathies</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Only de-identified data may be shared with other researchers</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>July 6, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/56/NCT04468256/ICF_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

