<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1646">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04699578</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>8453</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04699578</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19 Infection and Fetal-neonatal Outcomes</brief_title>
  <official_title>Impact of COVID-19 Infection on the Course of Pregnancy and Fetal-neonatal Outcomes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Campania &quot;Luigi Vanvitelli&quot;</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Campania &quot;Luigi Vanvitelli&quot;</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      COVID-19, the coronavirus responsible for the pandemic that began at the end of 2019 in&#xD;
      China, spreads through respiratory droplets and direct contact. The most common symptoms of&#xD;
      the disease include fever, cough, asthenia or myalgia, wheezing and headache, and the most&#xD;
      serious complication is acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). The new coronavirus has&#xD;
      continued to spread to multiple countries and continents so much so that the epidemic was&#xD;
      declared a Public Health Emergency of International Interest (PHEIC) by the World Health&#xD;
      Organization (WHO) on January 30, 2020. In the first phase of emergency worldwide,&#xD;
      characterized by high morbidity and mortality, scientific interest has been mainly directed&#xD;
      to the study of the transmission mechanisms of the infection, diagnostic tools and therapies&#xD;
      for ARDS, especially in elderly and co-morbid patients. Interest has rapidly spread to other&#xD;
      categories of patients and in particular to pregnancy, on which the virus could impact in&#xD;
      different ways, with consequences for both the mother and the fetus. A recent systematic&#xD;
      review that included all published reports on Coronaviruses (COVID-19, SARS, and MERS) in&#xD;
      pregnancy showed that preterm delivery is the most frequently reported adverse event in these&#xD;
      women, and that COVID-19 is associated with an increased risk of preeclampsia and caesarean&#xD;
      section. Nonetheless, the limited sample size, the main inclusion of cases reported for acute&#xD;
      respiratory symptoms, the lack of information on previous pathologies potentially capable of&#xD;
      complicating pregnancy, do not allow for the extrapolation of strong evidence on the course&#xD;
      of infection in pregnancy. Therefore, the current status of the scientific literature does&#xD;
      not allow for general and wide-ranging implications. THe investigators therefore believe it&#xD;
      is particularly useful to investigate maternal and fetal outcomes in this new broader&#xD;
      scenario, including all pregnancies associated with asymptomatic or symptomatic SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      infection, found in any gestational period, in order to evaluate in a &quot;real world scenario&quot;&#xD;
      &quot;Actual rates of maternal-fetal and neonatal adverse events&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Coronaviruses are a large family of viruses known to cause illnesses ranging from the common&#xD;
      cold to more serious illnesses such as Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS) and Severe&#xD;
      Acute Respiratory Syndrome (SARS). They are positive-stranded RNA viruses, with a corona-like&#xD;
      appearance under the electron microscope, whose primary target cells are the epithelial cells&#xD;
      of the respiratory and gastrointestinal tract. The 2019/20 COVID-19 respiratory disease&#xD;
      pandemic, caused by a coronavirus, began in December 2019 in the city of Wuhan, the capital&#xD;
      of the Chinese province of Hubei, which has subsequently spread to several countries around&#xD;
      the world. In early January 2020, health authorities identified the virus responsible for the&#xD;
      epidemic, designating it, initially as &quot;Coronavirus 2019-nCoV&quot; but later with the official&#xD;
      name of &quot;SARS-CoV-2&quot;. To date, seven Coronaviruses have been shown to be capable of infecting&#xD;
      humans: Common Human Coronaviruses: HCoV-OC43 and HCoV-HKU1 (Betacoronavirus) and HCoV-229E&#xD;
      and HCoV-NL63 (Alphacoronavirus); they can cause common colds but also severe lower&#xD;
      respiratory tract infections; other human coronaviruses (Betacoronaviruses): SARS-CoV,&#xD;
      MERS-CoV and 2019-nCoV (now referred to as SARS-CoV-2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 is therefore the seventh virus of the same family that involves humans, spreads&#xD;
      through respiratory droplets and direct contact. The most common symptoms of the disease&#xD;
      include fever, cough, asthenia or myalgia, wheezing and headache, and the most serious&#xD;
      complication is acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). The new coronavirus has continued&#xD;
      to spread to multiple countries and continents so much so that the outbreak was declared a&#xD;
      public health emergency of international concern (PHEIC) by the World Health Organization&#xD;
      (WHO) on January 30, 2020.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the first phase of world emergency, characterized by high morbidity and mortality,&#xD;
      scientific interest has been mainly focused on the study of the transmission mechanisms of&#xD;
      the infection, diagnostic tools and therapies for ARDS, especially in elderly patients and&#xD;
      with co-morbidities. Interest has rapidly spread to other categories of patients and in&#xD;
      particular to pregnancy, on which the virus could impact in different ways, with consequences&#xD;
      for both the mother and the fetus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During pregnancy, different changes in the immune system and adaptive changes affecting&#xD;
      organs and systems are observed in relation to the gestational period, among which those&#xD;
      affecting the respiratory system are highlighted, particularly evident in the third trimester&#xD;
      including, upper airway mucosal edema induced by elevated levels of estrogen and&#xD;
      progesterone, elevation of the diaphragm and consequent limited lung expansion, and high&#xD;
      oxygen consumption, all conditions that increase the susceptibility of pregnant women to&#xD;
      respiratory insults.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The maternal immune system during pregnancy undergoes specific adaptations aimed at&#xD;
      establishing and maintaining a fetal allogeneic tolerance while preserving the ability to&#xD;
      protect against external infectious agents. It goes from a pro-inflammatory state in the&#xD;
      first trimester (important for implantation and placentation) to an anti-inflammatory state&#xD;
      in the second trimester (necessary for fetal growth), and finally returns to a&#xD;
      pro-inflammatory state again in the third trimester and during childbirth. In addition,&#xD;
      innate immunity cells, that is, NK cells and monocytes respond more actively to viral&#xD;
      insults, while the adaptive immune response is down-regulated (Hong Liu et al). As for CD4 +&#xD;
      (Th) T cells, involved in the regulation of the inflammatory response through the production&#xD;
      of cytokines, there is a shift in the maternal immune response from Th1 (with&#xD;
      pro-inflammatory action) towards Th2 (with anti-inflammatory action ), a crucial modification&#xD;
      for maintaining maternal-fetal tolerance (Wegmannetal et al.).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the first phase of world emergency, characterized by high morbidity and mortality,&#xD;
      scientific interest has been mainly focused on the study of the transmission mechanisms of&#xD;
      the infection, diagnostic tools and therapies for ARDS, especially in elderly patients and&#xD;
      with co-morbidities. Interest has rapidly spread to other categories of patients and in&#xD;
      particular to pregnancy, on which the virus could impact in different ways, with consequences&#xD;
      for both the mother and the fetus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During pregnancy, different changes in the immune system and adaptive changes affecting&#xD;
      organs and systems are observed in relation to the gestational period, among which those&#xD;
      affecting the respiratory system are highlighted, particularly evident in the third trimester&#xD;
      including, upper airway mucosal edema induced by elevated levels of estrogen and&#xD;
      progesterone, elevation of the diaphragm and consequent limited lung expansion, and high&#xD;
      oxygen consumption, all conditions that increase the susceptibility of pregnant women to&#xD;
      respiratory insults.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is widely demonstrated that maternal systemic infections, which cause instability in the&#xD;
      delicate balance of the immune system, may be related to the onset of complications during&#xD;
      pregnancy, such as increased risk of miscarriage, intrauterine growth retardation, death&#xD;
      fetal intrauterine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on these pathophysiological assumptions, it is conceivable that SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
      could clinically modify the course of pregnancy and lead to fetal-neonatal complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recent studies in the literature have shown that severe forms of COVID-19 disease are&#xD;
      associated with a cytokine storm, characterized by increased concentrations of IL-2, IL-7,&#xD;
      IL-10, G-CSF (granulocyte-colony stimulating factor), interferon-γ-inducible protein, MCP&#xD;
      (monocyte chemoattractant protein), MIP- α (macrophage inflammatory protein alpha) and TNF α&#xD;
      (tumor necrosis factor α). It has been hypothesized that during pregnancy this cytokine&#xD;
      cascade could induce an even more severe inflammatory state, particularly in the first and&#xD;
      third trimester of pregnancy (Hong Liu et al).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, Ashary et al. analyzed the possible presence of the virus at the level of the&#xD;
      syncytiotrophoblast, noting that in 12% of patients with active COVID-19 infection, the virus&#xD;
      was identifiable at the placental level. Furthermore, the target receptors of the virus for&#xD;
      entry into the cell, ACE-2 and TMPRSS2, are significantly expressed and used by the virus&#xD;
      also at the placental level, so SARS-CoV-2 could potentially, interacting with these targets,&#xD;
      alter the syncytiotrophoblastic unit and, consequently, the placental function (Seethy et&#xD;
      al.)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although the current evidence does not support a vertical intrauterine transmission of&#xD;
      coronaviruses (Chen et al), it is likely that it is the same maternal infection and the&#xD;
      inflammatory state in the course of the disease that can negatively influence the&#xD;
      maternal-fetal outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given the multiple characteristics common to SARS-CoV1, MERS and SARS-CoV2 infections, of&#xD;
      particular relevance were the studies conducted by Wong et al on SARS-CoV-1 infection in the&#xD;
      first trimester, in which four out of seven women ( 57%), who contracted SARS during the&#xD;
      first trimester, then had a miscarriage, and that of Alfaraj et al on MERS infection, in&#xD;
      which there was a single case of a woman with MERS in the first trimester, who never&#xD;
      developed symptoms of the disease, and carried the pregnancy to term.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A recent systematic review that included all published reports on Coronaviruses (COVID-19,&#xD;
      SARS, and MERS) in pregnancy showed that preterm delivery is the most frequently reported&#xD;
      adverse event in these women, and that COVID-19 is associated with an increased risk of&#xD;
      preeclampsia and caesarean section. Nevertheless, the limited sample size, the main inclusion&#xD;
      of cases reported for acute respiratory symptoms, the absence of information on previous&#xD;
      pathologies potentially capable of complicating pregnancy, do not allow to extrapolate strong&#xD;
      evidence on the course of infection in pregnancy ( Di Mascio et al. 2020).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, Ashary et al. analyzed the possible presence of the virus at the level of the&#xD;
      syncytiotrophoblast, noting that in 12% of patients with active COVID-19 infection, the virus&#xD;
      was identifiable at the placental level. Furthermore, the target receptors of the virus for&#xD;
      entry into the cell, ACE-2 and TMPRSS2, are significantly expressed and used by the virus&#xD;
      also at the placental level, so SARS-CoV-2 could potentially, interacting with these targets,&#xD;
      alter the syncytiotrophoblastic unit and, consequently, the placental function (Seethy et&#xD;
      al.)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although the current evidence does not support a vertical intrauterine transmission of&#xD;
      coronaviruses (Chen et al), it is likely that it is the same maternal infection and the&#xD;
      inflammatory state in the course of the disease that can negatively influence the&#xD;
      maternal-fetal outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given the multiple characteristics common to SARS-CoV1, MERS and SARS-CoV2 infections, of&#xD;
      particular relevance were the studies conducted by Wong et al on SARS-CoV-1 infection in the&#xD;
      first trimester, in which four out of seven women ( 57%), who contracted SARS during the&#xD;
      first trimester, then had a miscarriage, and that of Alfaraj et al on MERS infection, in&#xD;
      which there was a single case of a woman with MERS in the first trimester, who never&#xD;
      developed symptoms of the disease, and carried the pregnancy to term.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the moment there are no data in the literature on the impact of SARS-CoV-2 infection on&#xD;
      early pregnancy as the data currently available in the literature concern women hospitalized&#xD;
      in serious clinical conditions during the first wave of the March 2020 pandemic (Di Mascio et&#xD;
      al.). Conversely, other studies report low seroconversion rates for the virus. Therefore, the&#xD;
      current status of the scientific literature does not allow for general and wide-ranging&#xD;
      implications (La Cour Freiesleben et al.).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Furthermore, easier access to tests for the identification of COVID-19 and the introduction&#xD;
      by hospitals of universal screening for COVID-19 at patient admissions, make it easier to&#xD;
      identify the proportion of positive asymptomatic women. which could be, like what happens in&#xD;
      the general population, particularly relevant, as well as the proportion of women diagnosed&#xD;
      and subsequently resolved of the infection during pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators therefore believe it is particularly useful to investigate maternal and&#xD;
      fetal outcomes in this new broader scenario, including all pregnancies associated with&#xD;
      asymptomatic or symptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection, found in any gestational period, in order&#xD;
      to evaluate in a &quot;real world scenario&quot; &quot;Actual rates of maternal-fetal and neonatal adverse&#xD;
      events.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 28, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Preterm birth rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Less than 37 weeks gestation</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gestational age at delivery</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of delivery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Preterm birth rates</measure>
    <time_frame>Less than 24, 28, 34 weeks gestation</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Birth weight</measure>
    <time_frame>Time of delivery</time_frame>
    <description>Weight of the baby at the time of delivery</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Composite adverse neonatal outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>Between birth and 28 days of age</time_frame>
    <description>Number of neonates who will have at least one of the following:&#xD;
necrotizing enterocolitis (NEC), intraventricular hemorrhage (IVH) (grade 3 or higher), respiratory distress syndrome (RDS), bronchopulmonary dysplasia (BPD), retinopathy (ROP), blood-culture proven sepsis and neonatal death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>Between birth and 28 days after the birth</time_frame>
    <description>Number of mothers who will have at least one of the following:&#xD;
sepsis, histological chorioamnionitis, hysterectomy, intensive care unit admission.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Inflammatory markers: coagulation profile, C-reactive protein, glycaemia, ferritinemia</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">230</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Obstetric Complication</condition>
  <condition>SARS-CoV Infection</condition>
  <condition>Preterm Birth</condition>
  <condition>Miscarriage</condition>
  <condition>Placenta Diseases</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Covid-19 positive</intervention_name>
    <description>All pregnant women at any stage of pregnancy afferent to obstetrics services who tested positive in confirmation tests by nasopharyngeal swab for viral RNA detection through real-time reverse transcriptase - polymerase chain reaction (rRT-PCR) will be included.</description>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Nasopharyngeal swab with rRT-PCR as per ministerial protocol and in any case repeated at any&#xD;
      admission to the hospital ward&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All pregnant women at any stage of pregnancy afferent to obstetrics services who tested&#xD;
        positive in confirmation tests by nasopharyngeal swab for viral RNA detection through&#xD;
        real-time reverse transcriptase - polymerase chain reaction (rRT-PCR) will be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Upon confirmation, women will be placed in a specific pregnancy monitoring program that&#xD;
        will be defined as &quot;at risk for SARS-COVID2&quot;, regardless of participation in this study.&#xD;
        For women recruited in the study, no additional instrumental or laboratory investigations&#xD;
        are required to be performed in addition to those already provided for in the normal&#xD;
        clinical management of COVID-positive patients.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Maternal age&gt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with single or multiple pregnancy at any stage of gestation, with first&#xD;
             ascertained positivity to the nasopharyngeal swab for SARS-CoV-2 during pregnancy,&#xD;
             regardless of the presence of symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age under 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with an altered state of consciousness, seriously ill, with mental handicaps;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with serious systemic diseases that can negatively affect the pregnancy outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women for whom the treating doctor contraindicates participation in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Pregnant women</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nicola Colacurci, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University of Campania &quot;Luigi Vanvitelli&quot;</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Fabiana Savoia</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Campania &quot;Luigi Vanvitelli&quot;</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alessandra Familiari</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Università Cattolica del Sacro Cuore - Dipartimento scienze della salute della donna e del bambino</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Antonio Lanzone, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Università Cattolica del Sacro Cuore - Dipartimento scienze della salute della donna e del bambino</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Antonio Schiattarella, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Campania &quot;Luigi Vanvitelli&quot;</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Maddalena Morlando, Assistant Professor</last_name>
    <phone>+39 333 426 3110</phone>
    <email>madmorlando@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Antonio Schiattarella, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+39 392 16 53 275</phone>
    <email>aschiattarella@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Campania Luigi Vanvitelli</name>
      <address>
        <city>Naples</city>
        <zip>80138</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maddalena Morlando, Assistant Professor</last_name>
      <phone>+39 333 426 3110</phone>
      <email>madmorlando@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Antonio Schiattarella, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+39 1653275</phone>
      <email>aschiattarella@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Campania &quot;Luigi Vanvitelli&quot;</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Maddalena Morlando</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>obstetric</keyword>
  <keyword>Covid19</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV Infection</keyword>
  <keyword>placenta</keyword>
  <keyword>preterm birth</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Abortion, Spontaneous</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Placenta Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

