<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3044">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04577378</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Isotretinoin</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04577378</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Drug Combination Therapy of Isotretinoin and Some Antifungal Drugs as A Potential Aerosol Therapy for COVID-19 : An Innovative Therapeutic Approach COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>Isotretinoin</acronym>
  <official_title>Efficacy and Safety of Drug Combination Therapy of Isotretinoin and Some Antifungal Drugs as A Potential Aerosol Therapy for COVID-19 : An Innovative Therapeutic Approach</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kafrelsheikh University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kafrelsheikh University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Efficacy and safety of Drug combination therapy of Isotretinoin and some Anti fungal Drugs as&#xD;
      A potential Aerosol therapy for COVID-19 : An innovative therapeutic approach&#xD;
&#xD;
      The pandemic of COVID-19 which is caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2&#xD;
      (SARS-COV-2) has infected over 2,000,000 people causing over 150,000 deaths.It hasno&#xD;
      currently approved treatments.. Airborne SARS-CoV-2 infections in humans initiate from the&#xD;
      virus entering nasal and airway epithelial cells through binding to angiotensin-converting&#xD;
      enzyme 2 (ACE2). TMPRSS2, a cellular protease that activates the SARS-CoV-2 spike protein,&#xD;
      colocalizes with ACE2 and can prime SARS-CoV-2 fusion directly at the plasma membrane. In the&#xD;
      lungs, SARS-CoV-2 infects type I and type II alveolar epithelial cells, as well as alveolar&#xD;
      macrophages that are among the first producers of pro-inflammatory cytokines. As key&#xD;
      components of the immediate antiviral response, type I interferons (here after referred to as&#xD;
      IFNs) are crucial for restricting viral replication and spread, through autocrine and&#xD;
      paracrine type I IFN receptor (IFNAR) signalling. However, minimal amounts of IFNs have been&#xD;
      detected in the peripheral blood or lungs of patients with severe COVID-19 In a mouse model&#xD;
      of SARS-CoV infection, local IFN responses in the lungs were delayed relative to peak viral&#xD;
      replication, which impeded virus clearance and was associated with the development of CRS .&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 ORF3b is a potent interferon inhebitor and antagonist Here, we review the&#xD;
      molecular mechanisms by which Retinoic acid (isotretinoin) and antifungal drugs can cooperate&#xD;
      to induce interferon in covid-19 infected patients A study reported that 13 Cis retinoic acid&#xD;
      induced significant upregulation of toll-like receptor 3 resulting in an immune response to&#xD;
      dsRNA intermediate which can be partially generated during CoV-2 replication . TLR3&#xD;
      sensitized by dsRNA and cascades of signaling pathways (Interferon-regulatory factor 1 (IRFs)&#xD;
      and Nuclear factor-κB (NFκB) activation, respectively) are activated to produce type I&#xD;
      interferons. The production of type I IFNs is important to enhance the release of antiviral&#xD;
      proteins for the protection of uninfected cells. RA can be generated in multiple forms as&#xD;
      all-trans, 9-cis,and 13-cis retinoic acid. A study reported that Retinoic acid induces&#xD;
      directly the expression of two transcription factors, Stat1 and IRF-1 which play central&#xD;
      roles in the IFN signal transduction. In addition, RA induces IFN-a synthesis, IFNs can serve&#xD;
      as the first line of immune defense against viral infections. IFNs are very powerful&#xD;
      cytokines, which play a key role in combatting pathogenic infections by controlling&#xD;
      inflammation and immune response by directly inducing antipathogen molecular countermeasures.&#xD;
      There are three classes of IFNs: type I, type II, and type III. Antifungal drug. Fluconazol&#xD;
      or itraconazol can inhibit cytochrome P450 enzymes, especially cype 26 which control retinoic&#xD;
      acid concentration into human cells enhance both isotretinoin effect and Concentrations in&#xD;
      Target Tissues This in turn lead to hyper interferon induction and synthesis in case of&#xD;
      COVID-19. Also a study demonstrated that isotretinoin can be given as aerosolized via&#xD;
      inhalation rout without any damage in lung cells. Repeated high doses of 13 cis retinoic by&#xD;
      inhalation resulted in moderate loss of body weight, but microscopic investigation of ten&#xD;
      tissues including lung and oesophagus did not detect any significant aerosol-induced damage&#xD;
      therefore inhaled isotretinoin might provide sufficient drug to the target cells in lung for&#xD;
      efficacy while avoiding systemic toxicity. In conclusion,isotretinoin therapy has furthermore&#xD;
      a proven anti-inflammatory, anti-platelet and fibrinolytic activities which may protect&#xD;
      patients infected with covid-19 from widespread blood clots. From this point, we suggest that&#xD;
      isotretinoin will be the immunity passport&quot; in the context of COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a small pilot study investigating whether there is any efficacy signal of combination&#xD;
      therapy of Isotretinoin and some Anti fungal Drugs in COVID-19 treatment that warrants a&#xD;
      larger Phase III trial, or any harm that suggests that such a trial should not be done. It is&#xD;
      expected to produce statistically significant results in the major endpoints. The&#xD;
      investigator will examine all of the biologic, physiological, and clinical data to determine&#xD;
      whether a Phase III trial is warranted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary efficacy analysis will be carried only on patients receiving at least 4 doses of&#xD;
      active combination drug. Safety analysis will be carried out on all patients receiving at&#xD;
      least one dose of active drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
      introduction&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Wuhan, Hubei Province, China, cases of acute respiratory infection were reported in&#xD;
      December 2019.1,2 The Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), initially&#xD;
      reported that the cause of this disease is severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2&#xD;
      (SARS-CoV-2), then it is founded to be a novel coronavirus.3Now, This disease, is designated&#xD;
      by the WHO as coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), which rapidly spreads to other cities of&#xD;
      China, and has become a public health emergency of international concern (PHEIC) following&#xD;
      its global spread. The clinical manifestations of COVID-19 are fever, cough, muscle pain,&#xD;
      fatigue, diarrhea and pneumonia, and can cause death in severe cases.4China has reported&#xD;
      72436 cases of confirmed COVID-19 and 1868 fatalities through February 18, 2020.5 The innate&#xD;
      immune system represents the first line of defense and initiates counteractive responses that&#xD;
      protect the host from viral infection through evolutionarily conserved pattern recognition&#xD;
      receptors (PRR) 6. PRRs include the membrane-bound Toll-like receptors (TLRs) and cytosolic&#xD;
      sensors, such as retinoic acidinducible gene-I (RIG-I)-like receptors (RLRs), which sense RNA&#xD;
      viruses 6. RIG-I specifically detects the intracellular double-stranded viral RNA bearing 5'&#xD;
      triphosphate and panhandle structures to activate antiviral signaling7,8. Once a host is&#xD;
      invaded by a virus, PRRs transmit signals to the downstream kinases that activate&#xD;
      transcription factors, including IFN regulatory factor-3 (IRF3), nuclear factor κB (NF-κB),&#xD;
      and ATF-2/c-jun, with the help of different adaptor molecules (MAVS/IPS-1/VISA/Cardif for&#xD;
      RIG-I, TRIF for TLR3, and MyD88 for TLR7/8/9) to activate IFN production9,10,11.Viruses have&#xD;
      evolved elaborate mechanisms to evade or inactivate the innate immune signaling pathway for&#xD;
      their replication 12. Severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) is a highly contagious&#xD;
      respiratory disease that appeared first in China in 2002 and has infected more than 8000&#xD;
      people worldwide and killed about 800 of those infected. SARS coronavirus (SARS-CoV) has a&#xD;
      singlestranded, positive sense RNA genome of approximately 29.7 kb 13,14. Numerous studies&#xD;
      have revealed that SARS-CoV develops an antagonistic mechanism to evade the antiviral&#xD;
      activities of IFN 15 Infection with SARS-CoV-2 can lead to excessive production of&#xD;
      pro-inflammatory cytokines, but the production of type I interferons, which are key antiviral&#xD;
      mediators, is reportedly blunted; Previous studies suggested that SARS-CoV papain-like&#xD;
      protease (PLpro) inhibits activation of the IRF3 pathway, which would normally elicit a&#xD;
      robust IFN response, but the mechanism(s) used by SARS PLpro to inhibit activation of the&#xD;
      IRF3 pathway is not fully known.16 As key components of the immediate antiviral response,&#xD;
      type I interferons are crucial for restricting viral replication and spread, through&#xD;
      autocrine and paracrine type I IFN receptor (IFNAR) signalling. Type 1 interferons have a&#xD;
      broad antiviral activity in vitro and are currently evaluated in a clinical trial to treat&#xD;
      MERS-CoV However, minimal amounts of IFNs have been detected in the peripheral blood or lungs&#xD;
      of patients with severe COVID-19 17,18 In a mouse model of SARS-CoV infection, local IFN&#xD;
      responses in the lungs were delayed relative to peak viral replication, which impeded virus&#xD;
      clearance and was associated with the development of CRS19 . SARS-CoV-2 ORF3b is a potent&#xD;
      interferon inhebitor and antagonist 20 The dysregulated IFN responses are indicative of the&#xD;
      effective immunomodulatory strategies used by betacoronaviruses. During the incubation phase,&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 replicates stealthily in host cells without detectably triggering IFNs, leading to&#xD;
      high viral loads1. Coronaviruses are known to induce the formation of membranous compartments&#xD;
      dedicated to viral RNA synthesis and thereby conceal viral pathogen-associated molecular&#xD;
      patterns (PAMPs; for example, viral RNAs) from detection by host pattern recognition&#xD;
      receptors (PRRs), such as RIG-I and MDA5. Furthermore, several conserved betacoronavirus&#xD;
      proteins, predominantly non-structural proteins (nsps), are known to exert direct&#xD;
      IFN-antagonistic activities. Some modify specific features of the viral RNA (by catalysing&#xD;
      guanosine-N7 and ribose-2'-O methylation) to avoid recognition by specific PRRs (for example,&#xD;
      nsp14 and nsp16), while others, such as nsp3 and nsp1, inhibit the signal transduction&#xD;
      mediated by PRRs and by IFNAR, respectively19&#xD;
&#xD;
      --Impact of TLR3 on type I IFNs&#xD;
&#xD;
      Toll-like receptors (TLRs) are a class of pattern recognition receptors (PRRs) that initiate&#xD;
      innate immune response to invading pathogens by sensing conserved molecular patterns for&#xD;
      early immune recognition of a pathogens like viruses, bacteria, and fungi to initiate innate&#xD;
      immune response to invading pathogens . In addition ,TLRs play an important role in tissues&#xD;
      repair and tissues injury- induced inflammation. The emergence of highly pathogenic severe&#xD;
      acute respiratory syndrome coronaviruses (MERSCoV) is a concern for global public health, as&#xD;
      there is a lack of efficacious vaccine platforms and antiviral therapeutic strategies21. A&#xD;
      study demonstrated that pre-stimulation of TLR3 polyinosini- polycytidylic acid (poly I:C)&#xD;
      hindered MHV infection through induction of INF- β in macrophages 22 A study demonstrated&#xD;
      that TLR3(-/-), TLR4(-/-), and TRAM(-/-) mice are more susceptible to SARS-CoV than wild-type&#xD;
      mice but experience only transient weight loss with no mortality in response to infection. In&#xD;
      contrast, mice deficient in the TLR3/TLR4 adaptor TRIF are highly susceptible to SARS-CoV&#xD;
      infection, showing increased weight loss, mortality, reduced lung function, increased lung&#xD;
      pathology, and higher viral titers In further research, Tsai .and Chen showed the high level&#xD;
      of IFN-α/β produced from the TLR3-IRF3/IRF7 pathway and IFN-β is the reason for inhibiting&#xD;
      DENV replication. In HUH-7 cells, huTLR3 can recognize DENV-1 and induce the expression of&#xD;
      IFN-β, which can enhance the expression of huTLR3 on the contrary . TLR3 also induces type I&#xD;
      IFN during WNV..21&#xD;
&#xD;
      --Impact of isotretinoin 13 cis retinoic acid on TLR3 and TLR-2&#xD;
&#xD;
      Many of the significantly up-regulated genes are known to be retinoid-responsive genes&#xD;
      including: retinoic acid responder 1 [tazarotene induced gene 1 (TIG1)}, cellular retinol&#xD;
      binding protein 1 and cellular retinoic acid binding protein 2. In addition, calcium-binding&#xD;
      proteins (i.e. S100 proteins), serine proteases, serine protease inhibitors (serpins),&#xD;
      lipocalin and solute carriers were significantly affected by 13-cis RA25 In addition, Gene&#xD;
      expression analysis in SEB-1 sebocytes and HaCaT keratinocytes with 72 hour 13-cis RA&#xD;
      treatment. Revealed that there were changes in several genes involved in apoptosis and innate&#xD;
      immunity such as TNFα-induced protein 2, TRAIL, interferon regulatory factor 1 (IRF1),&#xD;
      interferon-induced proteins, NFκB, the death receptor, Fas and TIG3 (a.k.a. retinoic acid&#xD;
      inducible gene 1 (RIG1)). TIG3 encodes an RNA helicase and represents a key intracellular&#xD;
      protein that like the TLR3, can recognize viral double stranded RNA (dsRNA). 26 isotretinoin&#xD;
      can inhebit cytokine storm thorough inhebtion of TLR-2 astudy demonstrated that treatment of&#xD;
      patients with isotretinoin significantly decreased monocyte TLR-2 expression and subsequent&#xD;
      inflammatory cytokine response to P. acnes after 1 week of therapy. This effect was sustained&#xD;
      6 months following cessation of therapy, indicating that TLR-2 modulation may be involved in&#xD;
      the durable therapeutic response to isotretinoin.22 IN contrary, 13Cis retinoic Acid induced&#xD;
      significant upregulation of toll-like receptor 3 (TLR3) , mitochondrial antiviral-signaling&#xD;
      protein (MAVS) and retinoid-induced gene I (RIG-I) and IFN regulatory factor 1 expression in&#xD;
      a time-dependent. 23 this can resulted in an immune response to dsRNA intermediate which can&#xD;
      be partially generated during CoV-2 replicationTLR3 sensitized by dsRNA and cascades of&#xD;
      signaling pathways (IRFs and NFκB activation, respectively) are activated to produce type I&#xD;
      IFNs. The production of type I IFNs is important to enhance the release of antiviral proteins&#xD;
      for the protection of uninfected cells. Sometimes, accessory proteins of CoV can interfere&#xD;
      with TLR3 signaling and bind the dsRNA of CoV during replication to prevent TLR3 activation&#xD;
      and evade the immune response. Interferon regulatory factor 1 (IRF1) was identified as a&#xD;
      critical factor in mediating TRAIL induction by retinoic acid in NB4 APL leukemia cells and&#xD;
      SK-BR-3 breast cancer cells. Interestingly, 13-cis RA significantly up-regulates IRF1 gene&#xD;
      expression (2.42 fold increase) in SEB-1 sebocytes 27&#xD;
&#xD;
      Impact of antifungal drugs on inducing isotretinoin effect and concentration in targeted&#xD;
      tissues&#xD;
&#xD;
      Itraconazole and fluconazole are triazole azole ring antifungal drugs, which are multiringed&#xD;
      synthetic compounds containing three nitrogen atoms On the other hand, azole antifungal drugs&#xD;
      have been demonstrated to inhibit cytochrome P450 28Thecytochrome P450 family (CYP26) enzymes&#xD;
      are responsible for RA clearance, and are potential drug targets to increase concentrations&#xD;
      of retinoid into targeted cells31 CYP26 Inhibitors Increases Retinoid Signaling in Intimal&#xD;
      Smooth Muscle Cells32 Itraconazole has less inhibitive properties than the imidazoles in rat&#xD;
      liver microsomes 29. ICZ interferes with the ergosterol synthesis pathway of the host cell&#xD;
      and inhibits cytochrome P450 enzymes, particularly cyp 34 enzyme that metabolizes retinoic&#xD;
      acid in human cells which increase retinoic acid concentration in to targeted mammalian&#xD;
      cells40 leading to activation of TOLL-like receptors inducing its antiviral mechanism to&#xD;
      induce type I IFN expression levels toward the induction of a preactivated state, thereby&#xD;
      accelerating the virus-induced host cell response41 IFNs can serve as the first line of&#xD;
      immune defense against viral infections.41 IFNs are very powerful cytokines, which play a key&#xD;
      role in combatting pathogenic infections by controlling inflammation and immune response by&#xD;
      directly inducing antipathogen molecular countermeasures.42There are three classes of IFNs:&#xD;
      type I, type II, and type III.. Even though fluconazole has been shown to be a potent&#xD;
      cytochrome P450 inhibitor 30 Here,we suggest that because antifungal drug. Fluconazol or&#xD;
      itraconazol can inhibit cytochrome P450 enzymes, especially cype 26 which control retinoic&#xD;
      acid concentration into human cells antifungal can enhance both isotretinoin effect and&#xD;
      Concentrations in Target Tissues This in turn lead to hyper interferon induction and&#xD;
      synthesis in case of COVID-19 Astudy found that fluconazole has been shown to be a potent&#xD;
      cytochrome P450 inhibitor32 Safety of Aerosolized Isotretinoin Isotretinoin (Accutane, Roche&#xD;
      Laboratories Inc, Nutley, NJ) is an important drug, not only for the treatment of severe&#xD;
      acne, but also for other diagnoses and in chemoprevention settings. Because the use of&#xD;
      isotretinoin is increasing, it is important for physicians to be aware of the adverse events,&#xD;
      toxicities, and management issues related to its use. The most important issue is that of&#xD;
      congenital defects, which has resulted in new pregnancy prevention policies and programs&#xD;
      implemented by the manufacturer. A relatively new concern is that of depression associated&#xD;
      with isotretinoin use, also resulting in new policies placed by the manufacturer and the&#xD;
      FDA., But here, in our review we highly recommend that any researcher who wants to apply&#xD;
      isotritinoin clinically covid-19 his clinical study must be a small pilot study investigating&#xD;
      whether there is any efficacy signal that warrants a larger Phase 2B trial, or any harm that&#xD;
      suggests that such a trial should not be done. The investigator will examine all of the&#xD;
      biologic, physiological, and clinical data to determine whether a Phase 2B trial is&#xD;
      warranted. And he also must abide by these rules :Isotretinoin must be give in the form of&#xD;
      aerosol thorough respiratory route in order for it to has an effect that is focused only on&#xD;
      lung cells so as not to affect any other organs. Aerosol inhalation can deposit drug directly&#xD;
      on the population of cells caught up in the early phase of cancer, potentially achieving much&#xD;
      more efficiency compared with reliance on diffusion from the blood. Direct application of&#xD;
      aerosolized retinoic acid to the lung epithelium may avoid much of the protein binding, and&#xD;
      serious side effects on the other organs especially, congenital organs thus greatly&#xD;
      increasing potency at the target site.35 Because a study on rabbits demonstrated that&#xD;
      isotretinoin can be given in the form of aerosol without serious side effects . Repeated high&#xD;
      doses of 13 cis retinoic by inhalation resulted in moderate loss of body weight, but&#xD;
      microscopic investigation of ten tissues inhalation rout without any damage in lung including&#xD;
      lung and oesophagus did not detect any significant aerosol-induced damage therefore inhaled&#xD;
      isotretinoin might provide sufficient drug to the target cells in lung for efficacy while&#xD;
      avoiding systemic toxicity © 2000 Cancer Research Campaign33 In 2006, a clinical trial&#xD;
      conducted to assess the feasibility of retinoids for the treatment of emphysema, the FORTE&#xD;
      study, was published (NCT00000621)33. In that study, 148 patients from five university&#xD;
      hospitals were recruited and randomized to receive ATRA at either low dose (1 mg/kg/day for 4&#xD;
      days/wk) or high dose (2 mg/kg/day for 4 days/wk), 13-cis retinoic acid (1 mg/kg/day, daily),&#xD;
      or placebo for 6 months, followed by a 3-month crossover phase. Subsequently, they were&#xD;
      observed for an additional 9 months before the final assessment. In the trial, retinoids(13&#xD;
      cis retinoic acid ) were proven to be safe as the drug-related AEs were generally mild.37 In&#xD;
      addition, aerosolized isotretinoin must be given with low dose in accordance to patient&#xD;
      weight and also it must be given gradually concentration thorough a short period not&#xD;
      exceeding 14 days from the date of giving the first dose In contrast to the long course of&#xD;
      treatment, which is considered chronic treatment and Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid must be&#xD;
      be given gradually in one daily dose increases from 0.2 mg/kg/day to 2 mg/kg/day as inhaled&#xD;
      13 cis retinoic acid therapy for 14 days A study demonstrated that the application of&#xD;
      aerosolized retinoic acid system led to a rise of Retinoic Acid levels in lung, but not liver&#xD;
      or plasma. Cellular lung levels of retinol, retinyl palmitate, and retinyl stearate also&#xD;
      appeared to be unaffected (245.6 ± 10.7, 47.4 ± 3.4, and 132.8 ± 7.7 ng•g-1 wet weight,&#xD;
      respectively). And also demonstrated that the application of this aerosolized Retinoic Acid&#xD;
      also induced a dose-dependent protein expression of the cellular retinol-binding protein 1&#xD;
      (CRBP-1) in lung, without apparent harmful side effects.38 Although, more than one clinical&#xD;
      study reported safety and non serious side effects of systemic isotretinon but we highly&#xD;
      recommend that isotretinoin must be given in the form of aerosol with short period of&#xD;
      tratment and with low gradual dose to target lung cells only for avoiding any potential side&#xD;
      effects. A clinical study applied on 1166 patients thorough phase III trial (NCI #I91-0001)&#xD;
      at a National Cancer Institute (NCI) demonstrated that after the median follow-up of 3.5&#xD;
      years, there were no statistically significant differences between the placebo and&#xD;
      isotretinoin arms with respect to the time to SPTs, recurrences, or mortality. In this study&#xD;
      Patients were randomly assigned to receive a placebo or the retinoid isotretinoin (30 mg/day)&#xD;
      for 3 years in a double-blind fashion. Patients were stratified at randomization by tumor&#xD;
      stage, histology, and smoking status. The primary endpoint (time to SPT) and the secondary&#xD;
      endpoints (times to recurrence and death) were analyzed by log-rank test and the Cox&#xD;
      proportional hazards model. All statistical tests were two-sided.34 A study conducted on 720&#xD;
      patients who had received one or more courses of oral isotretinoin treatment, and had a mean&#xD;
      follow up period of 4.9 years (range 2/12 years). Most patients (442) had received a total&#xD;
      cumulative dose of 120/200 mg/kg body weight. One hundred and sixty two patients received a&#xD;
      cumulative dose of &lt;120 mg/kg body weight, and 116 received a cumulative dose &lt;200 mg/kg.&#xD;
      Finally this study proved that oral isotretinoin in the treatment of acne is a safe drug,&#xD;
      with no serious long term side effects.36&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety of Aerosolized fluconazole&#xD;
&#xD;
      A study demonstrated that fluconazole can be given via route of inhalation. Respiratory&#xD;
      fungal diseases therapy is still facing challenges as a result of increasing autoimmune&#xD;
      disorders, cancers, and immunosuppressive medication usage. Fluconazole is a wide spectrum&#xD;
      antifungal agent and is still used successfully in the treatment of opportunistic infections&#xD;
      in combination with other antifungal agents. Since, the treatment of respiratory fungal&#xD;
      diseases requires prolonged hospitalization; it may increase the chances of other&#xD;
      opportunistic infections. Considering the reported drug resistance and adverse effects of&#xD;
      systemic administration, it appears that localized pulmonary antifungal therapy may be a&#xD;
      suitable alternative route. According to the reported suitable inhalation properties of spray&#xD;
      dried powders; spray drying technique was used to prepare fluconazole powders.39&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 20, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 20, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 20, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patients and method :&#xD;
13- This study will performed on 45 patients tested positive for the presence of COVID-19 RNA by RT-PCR kit for RNA detection will randomly divided into 3 equal groups</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>Single (Participant)</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>lung injury score</measure>
    <time_frame>at 7and 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of lung injury score decreased or increased after treatment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute lymphocyte counts</measure>
    <time_frame>at day 7 and 14 after randimization</time_frame>
    <description>Lymphocyte counts</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum levels of CRP, ESR ,IL-1,IL-6,TNF and Type I interferons</measure>
    <time_frame>at day 7 and 14 after randimization</time_frame>
    <description>Serum levels of CRP, ESR ,IL-1,IL-6,TNF and Type I interferons</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All cause mortality rate</measure>
    <time_frame>at day 7 and 14</time_frame>
    <description>Died</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum level of viral RNA</measure>
    <time_frame>at day 7 and 14</time_frame>
    <description>Serum level of viral RNA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ventilation free days</measure>
    <time_frame>at 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Ventilation free days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ICU free days</measure>
    <time_frame>at 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>ICU free days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">45</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>13 cis retinoic acid doses orally</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The infected patients will receive Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid in gradual in one dose per day increases from 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled 13 cis retinoic acid therapy for 14 days plus aerosolized Itraconzaole powder: single dose of 5mg/kg/day for 14 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The infected patients will receive Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid in gradual in one dose per day increases from 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled 13 cis retinoic acid therapy for 14 days plus Aerosolized Itraconzaole powder: single dose of 5mg/kg/day for 14 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>No intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Drug: Isotretinoin(Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid) plus Aerosolized Itraconazole</intervention_name>
    <description>After randomization, erosolized 13 cis retinoic acid in gradual one dose increases froms 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled 13 cis retinoic acid therapy for 14 days plus Aerosolized Itraconazole 5mg per day for 14 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>13 cis retinoic acid doses orally</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Drug: Isotretinoin(Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid)</intervention_name>
    <description>Drug: Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid in gradual one dose increases froms 0.2 mg/kg/day to 4 mg/kg/day as inhaled 13 cis retinoic acid therapy for 14 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Aerosolized 13 cis retinoic acid</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult SARI patients with 2019-ncov infection confirmed by PCR;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute value of lymphocytes &lt; 0. 6x 109/L;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe respiratory failure within 48 hours and requires admission to ICU. (severe&#xD;
             respiratory failure was defined as PaO2/FiO2 &lt; 200 mmHg and was supported by positive&#xD;
             pressure mechanical ventilation (including non-invasive and invasive mechanical&#xD;
             ventilation, PEEP&gt;=5cmH2O))&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt; 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergic to experimental drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The underlying disease is very serious and the expected survival time is less than 6&#xD;
             months (such as advanced malignant tumor);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COPD or end-stage lung disease requires home oxygen therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expected survival time not exceeding 48 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participated in other clinical intervention trials within the last 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Autoimmune diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of organ, bone marrow or hematopoietic stem cell transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received radiotherapy and chemotherapy for malignant tumor within 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV infected patients or diagnosed with acquired immunodeficiency within the past year&#xD;
             (CD4 T cells &lt;=200/mm3)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving anti-hcv treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  90 days of retinal detachment or eye surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Permanent blindness in one eye&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of iritis, endophthalmitis, scleral inflammation or retinitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The competent physician considered it inappropriate to participate in the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>mahmoud Elkazzaz, B.Sc of biochemistry</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Faculty of Science,Damietta university</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>mahmoud Elkazzaz, B.Sc of biochemistry</last_name>
    <phone>00201090302015</phone>
    <email>mahmoudramadan20151@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kafr El-sheikh University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <state>Kafr El-sheikh</state>
        <zip>33561</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 13, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 5, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 6, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 5, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 5, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 6, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Kafrelsheikh University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mahmoud Ramadan mohamed Elkazzaz</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Itraconazole</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tretinoin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Isotretinoin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

