<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1694">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04684550</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FM-CIE-0824-20</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04684550</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Use of Hypochlorous Acid as Prophylaxis in Health Personnel at High Risk of Infection by SARS-CoV 2 (COVID19)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized Controlled Clinical Study (RCT) Phase 3 of the Safety and Efficacy of Hypochlorous Acid in the Prophylaxis of Healthcare Personnel at High Risk of Infection by SARS-CoV2 (COVID19) Versus Placebo</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital Universitario San Ignacio</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Pontificia Universidad Javeriana</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital Universitario San Ignacio</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The pandemic caused by SARS-CoV-2 is a global emergency present in 6 continents including 66&#xD;
      countries, incurring a shortage of effective and safe therapeutic alternatives that can&#xD;
      contribute to reducing the risk of contamination, as well as helping to reduce the viral load&#xD;
      of the positive patient. This requires a coordinated, effective and immediate action on the&#xD;
      part of governments, companies, academic entities and even at the individual level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the search for new therapeutic and prevention alternatives, the application of&#xD;
      hypochlorous acid (HClO) to the nasal mucosa is proposed, a broad-spectrum and fast-acting&#xD;
      antimicrobial solution, whose safety has been proven in preclinical trials. The efficacy of&#xD;
      HClO has been tested against enveloped and non-enveloped viruses, reducing virus particles&#xD;
      without affecting human cells. This solution could contribute to reducing the viral load and&#xD;
      the risk of contamination of patients and professionals. This could have an impact on&#xD;
      controlling the COVID-19 pandemic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Hypochlorous acid (HClO) is a powerful antimicrobial and antiviral used for the control of&#xD;
      various infections, repair and washing of surgical wounds, as well as for disinfection of&#xD;
      surfaces. In vivo, it is synthesized by the cells of the immune system for the control of&#xD;
      pathogens during phagocytosis and has been synthesized and stabilized for use in different&#xD;
      entities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The therapeutic uses of HClO began in the First World War with the studies of Alexis Carrel&#xD;
      and Henry Dakin who obtained a buffered sodium hypochlorite solution (Dakin's solution) which&#xD;
      generated ideal concentrations of HClO, using it successfully in washing and treatment of&#xD;
      wounds without presenting any damage or undesired effect on the patient's tissues. In 1993,&#xD;
      the HClO molecule was stabilized, popularizing its use for the control of predominantly skin&#xD;
      infections, treatment of chronic ulcers, closure and cleaning of wounds, management of burned&#xD;
      patients, and disinfection of surfaces.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biologically, it is part of the reactive oxygen species (ROS) synthesized by cells of the&#xD;
      immune system (Neutrophils and Macrophages) during an immunological process known as&#xD;
      &quot;respiratory burst&quot;, during phagocytosis of antigens in reaction with the enzyme&#xD;
      myeloperoxidase (MPO), hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) and a chlorine ion. Safety profiles in in&#xD;
      vivo models have driven our initiative to use Stabilized Hypochlorous Acid (S-HClO), as an&#xD;
      early therapeutic option in patients with SARS-Cov-2 infection or in close contact with&#xD;
      COVID-193 positive patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Calderon et al and carried out the evaluation of the antimicrobial effect of HClO on&#xD;
      potentially pathogenic microorganisms of the oral cavity. The study reports that hypochlorous&#xD;
      acid achieved bacterial inhibition of 99.9% at a concentration of 0.05% and a pH of 5.2 per&#xD;
      minute of action for different types of bacteria and for infectious microorganisms.&#xD;
      Virological tests have also been performed on feline calcivirus (Ebola-like virus),&#xD;
      rotavirus, AH1N1, adenovirus and SARS, found to be highly effective after 1 minute of&#xD;
      application.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the face of the COVID-19 pandemic, effective and early treatments are being sought to help&#xD;
      prevent the dissipation of the virus (disinfection of surfaces), to neutralize the virus at&#xD;
      an early stage when it is lodged in the upper respiratory tract and nose, since this is the&#xD;
      Probable route of infection of the ethmoid lamina and later causing viral encephalopathy and&#xD;
      treatment of patients with bronchial infection by this virus, decreasing the viral load and&#xD;
      causing destruction of the virus. There are reports of the use of HClO in the nasal mucosa in&#xD;
      studies in humans, reporting safety and effectiveness, both in adults and in children, which&#xD;
      leads us to propose the application of said nasal spray solution, as a prophylaxis in health&#xD;
      personnel with a high risk of infection by SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A RCT with the use S-HClO as a prevention treatment for the infection by SARS-CoV-2 in health&#xD;
      professionals is proposed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A randomized, double-masked, placebo-controlled clinical experiment is proposed.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>The first group of health personnel who work in places of greater risk (hospitals and primary level consultation) with conventional protection elements added to the application of 2 nasal puff every 8 hours of a nasal spray containing 0.9% SSN (placebo) and gargles (SSN 0.9%).&#xD;
A second group of health personnel who work in higher risk places (hospitals and primary level consultation) with conventional protection elements added to the application of 2 puffs and gargles every 8 hours of a solution with low concentrations of S-HCLO (3-5 ppm).</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevention of infection by COVID19</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who get COVID19 infection during the application of S-HClO</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse drug reaction (ADR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the occurrence of ADR by the use of S-HClO</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Seroconversion</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the frequency of seroconversion due to COVID 19</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who fell ill from COVID-19 and was not hospitalized</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ICU</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who fell ill from COVID-19 and was hospitalized in ICU</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">556</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV Infection</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Infection Viral</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Health personnel who work in places of greater risk (hospitals and primary level consultation) with conventional protection elements added to the application of 2 nasal puff every 8 hours of a nasal spray containing 0.9% SSN (placebo) and gargles (SSN 0.9%).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Health personnel who work in higher risk places (hospitals and primary level consultation) with conventional protection elements added to the application of 2 puffs and gargles every 8 hours of a solution with low concentrations of S-HCLO (3-5 ppm).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Stabilized hypochlorous acid</intervention_name>
    <description>Application of 2 puffs and gargles every 8 hours of a solution with low concentrations of S-HCLO (3-5 ppm).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Application of 2 puffs and gargles every 8 hours of a solution with low concentrations of S-HCLO (3-5 ppm).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Specialist physicians, resident physicians, medical students, and nursing personnel&#xD;
             who work at the San Ignacio University Hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects of any sex over 18 years of age who work as health care personnel, in care&#xD;
             services that care for patients with a suspected or confirmed diagnosis of COVID-19&#xD;
             and who are active during the study recruitment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  That they have not presented general symptoms such as malaise, fever, cough, dyspnea&#xD;
             or muscle pain during the last 7 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects negative to the antigen test for COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects considered as a resolved case of COVID-19 infection, according to guidelines&#xD;
             from the Colombian National Institute of Health.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Health personnel with social distancing due to close contact without personal&#xD;
             protective equipment with patients confirmed to be infected or taking any medication&#xD;
             as a possible prophylaxis for COVID-19 (example: chloroquine, hydroxychloroquine,&#xD;
             azithromycin)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Health workers who have permits or temporary withdrawal from their hospital work for&#xD;
             more than one week during the month of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Some type of allergy to chlorinated agents or hypersensitivity to HClO&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known diagnosis of upper airway respiratory disease where COVID-19 such as the common&#xD;
             cold, sinusitis, pharyngitis, laryngotracheitis and epiglottitis or lower such as&#xD;
             bronchiolitis, pneumonia, and mixed conditions have been ruled out.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous COVID19 infection determined by positive PCR or positive serum antibody&#xD;
             titers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that in the principal investigator's discretion renders the subject&#xD;
             ineligible to participate in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Juan Zambrano, MD. M.Sc.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hospital Universitario San Ignacio/Pontificia Universidad Javeriana</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Juan Zambrano, MD. M.Sc.</last_name>
    <phone>+5713208320</phone>
    <phone_ext>2751</phone_ext>
    <email>jczambrano@husi.org.co</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Justo Calderon, BSc. M.Sc</last_name>
    <phone>+5716776684</phone>
    <email>investigaciones@aquilabs.com.co</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hui DS, Chan PK. Severe acute respiratory syndrome and coronavirus. Infect Dis Clin North Am. 2010 Sep;24(3):619-38. doi: 10.1016/j.idc.2010.04.009. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20674795</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Velavan TP, Meyer CG. The COVID-19 epidemic. Trop Med Int Health. 2020 Mar;25(3):278-280. doi: 10.1111/tmi.13383. Epub 2020 Feb 16.</citation>
    <PMID>32052514</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gold MH, Andriessen A, Bhatia AC, Bitter P Jr, Chilukuri S, Cohen JL, Robb CW. Topical stabilized hypochlorous acid: The future gold standard for wound care and scar management in dermatologic and plastic surgery procedures. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2020 Feb;19(2):270-277. doi: 10.1111/jocd.13280. Epub 2020 Jan 6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31904191</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hakim H, Thammakarn C, Suguro A, Ishida Y, Kawamura A, Tamura M, Satoh K, Tsujimura M, Hasegawa T, Takehara K. Evaluation of sprayed hypochlorous acid solutions for their virucidal activity against avian influenza virus through in vitro experiments. J Vet Med Sci. 2015 Feb;77(2):211-5. doi: 10.1292/jvms.14-0413. Epub 2014 Nov 24.</citation>
    <PMID>25421399</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Taharaguchi M, Takimoto K, Zamoto-Niikura A, Yamada YK. Effect of weak acid hypochlorous solution on selected viruses and bacteria of laboratory rodents. Exp Anim. 2014;63(2):141-7.</citation>
    <PMID>24770639</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ishihara M, Murakami K, Fukuda K, Nakamura S, Kuwabara M, Hattori H, Fujita M, Kiyosawa T, Yokoe H. Stability of Weakly Acidic Hypochlorous Acid Solution with Microbicidal Activity. Biocontrol Sci. 2017;22(4):223-227. doi: 10.4265/bio.22.223.</citation>
    <PMID>29279579</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Edward DG, Lidwell OM. Studies on air-borne virus infections: III. The killing of aerial suspensions of influenza virus by hypochlorous acid. J Hyg (Lond). 1943 Sep;43(3):196-200.</citation>
    <PMID>20475674</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yu MS, Kim BH, Kang SH, Lim DJ. Low-concentration hypochlorous acid nasal irrigation for chronic sinonasal symptoms: a prospective randomized placebo-controlled study. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2017 Mar;274(3):1527-1533. doi: 10.1007/s00405-016-4387-5. Epub 2016 Nov 17.</citation>
    <PMID>27853946</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 21, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 24, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 24, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 28, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV Infection</keyword>
  <keyword>Stabilized hypochlorous acid (S-HClO)</keyword>
  <keyword>Prophylaxis</keyword>
  <keyword>Health Professionals</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Virus Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

