<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2867">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04643054</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20201116</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04643054</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Ovotransferrin in COVID-19 Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy and Safety of Ovotransferrin in COVID-19 Patients With Mild-to-Moderate Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Policlinico Paolo Giaccone Palermo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Policlinico Paolo Giaccone Palermo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chicken egg consists of three main components, egg white (56%), yolk (33%) and shell (11%).&#xD;
      The key component of egg white is 88 percent water and 12 percent solids, of which over 90&#xD;
      percent are protein. Ovalbumin, ovotransferrin, and ovomucoid are considered the main&#xD;
      proteins, while ovomucin, lysozyme, ovoglobulin, ovomacroglobulin, ovoglycoprotein,&#xD;
      ovoflavoprotein, thiamin-binding proteins, ficin/papain inhibitors, avidin, and cystatin are&#xD;
      the minor white proteins of the embryo. These proteins and their peptides have been&#xD;
      recognized as antioxidants, antimicrobials, metal-chelators, anti-viral, anti-tumor, and&#xD;
      angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE)-inhibitors for their functional significance SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      virus activates the human cell ACE2 receptor, triggering a series of deleterious events. In&#xD;
      COVID19, renin-angiotensin is upregulated and the pathway is overexpressed and a progressive&#xD;
      cytokine storm is always observed. In all these pathogenic processes, ovotransferrin could&#xD;
      play a modifier function to enhance the condition. Ovotransferrin can be beneficial to the&#xD;
      antioxidant effects of Angiotensin II by inhibiting NF-kB. Ovotransferrin is an&#xD;
      immunomodulator that downregulates pro-inflammatory cytokines including TNF-α, IL-6, and IL-1&#xD;
      that could extinguish the cytokine storm. Ovotransferrin can also serve as a protective agent&#xD;
      against COVID19 cardiotoxicity due to disruption in the ACE2-mediated signaling pathway,&#xD;
      cytokine storm, pulmonary dysfunction, and side effects of medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In patients with coronavirus infection, provided ovotransferrin's possible protective&#xD;
      effects, it is suggested as a supportive and therapeutic alternative.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given this background, in the light of the current COVID-19 emergency, it is the intention of&#xD;
      the investigators to conduct a prospective, randomized, open-label, controlled study in the&#xD;
      cohort of hospitalized patients with covid-19 pneumonia, administering 200 mg of&#xD;
      ovotransferrin orally in addition to the standard of care therapy (SOC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesize that the use of ovotransferrin will be associated with an&#xD;
      earlier improvement of clinical and humoral parameters after 10 days of ovotransferrin&#xD;
      treatment when compared to the group of patients provided with standard care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Chicken egg consists of three main components, egg white (56%), yolk (33%), and shell (11%).&#xD;
      The key component of egg white is 88 percent water and 12 percent solids, of which over 90&#xD;
      percent are protein. Ovalbumin, ovotransferrin, and ovomucoid are considered the main&#xD;
      proteins, while ovomucin, lysozyme, ovoglobulin, ovomacroglobulin, ovoglycoprotein,&#xD;
      ovoflavoprotein, thiamin-binding proteins, ficin/papain inhibitors, avidin, and cystatin are&#xD;
      the minor white proteins of the embryo. These proteins and their peptides have been&#xD;
      recognized as antioxidants, antimicrobials, metal-chelators, anti-viral, anti-tumor, and&#xD;
      angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE)-inhibitors for their functional significance. Among these&#xD;
      functional properties, the antioxidant ability is essential to food processing. Generation of&#xD;
      reactive oxygen species (ROS) and free radicals is an integral part of biological processes&#xD;
      affecting all living organisms in energy production. Ovotransferrin (OTf), which constitutes&#xD;
      12% of the total white egg protein, is known as an iron binder and transporter in animals and&#xD;
      can thus be used as an iron replacement, antimicrobial or antioxidant. Japanese researchers&#xD;
      find ovotransferrin in a redox-dependent method generates observable self-cleaning.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OTf is composed of 686 amino acids and has a molecular mass of 77.90 kDa. It is a superoxide&#xD;
      dismutase (SOD)-mimicking protein with a potent superoxide anion (O2 _-)-scavenging activity&#xD;
      and showed dramatically higher scavenging activity than some known antioxidants, such as&#xD;
      serum albumin or ascorbate. Interestingly, metal-bound OTfs such as Fe2+-OTf, Mn2+-OTf,&#xD;
      Cu2+-OTf exhibited greater O2 _- dismutation capacity than the apoprotein. Conjugation of OTf&#xD;
      with small molecules such as catechin shows improved antioxidant activity. During in vitro&#xD;
      experiments, OTf displayed some antioxidant effects and its hydrolysates showed approximately&#xD;
      3,2 to 13,5 times higher superoxide anion scavenging activity and better copper/calcium&#xD;
      scavenging activity than OTf. Furthermore, autocleaved OTf showed higher antioxidant activity&#xD;
      than the natural OTf, and the hydrolysates of autocleaved OTf showed stronger antioxidant&#xD;
      activity than those of the autocleaved one.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The peptide IRW, resulting from hydrolysis, exhibited a high-oxygen radical-scavenging that&#xD;
      could be related to tryptophan. In addition, two high antioxidant activity tetrapeptides&#xD;
      (WNIP and GWNI) were found in OTf thermolysin digests. WNI's motif seemed to be responsible&#xD;
      for the high antioxidant potential as amino acid residues coupled with both peptides' N or C&#xD;
      terminus decreased their antioxidant capacity. Moreover, when tested in endothelial cells,&#xD;
      the peptide GWNI showed the ability to reduce reactive oxygen species generation. Other&#xD;
      antioxidant peptides previously reported from OTf using the oxygen radical absorbance&#xD;
      ability, on the other hand showed no antioxidant activity in cells, showed deficiencies in&#xD;
      cell-free in vitro methods for antioxidant studies, and highlighted the need to use more&#xD;
      biological systems such as culture cells to test antioxidant peptides. OTf-derived&#xD;
      hydrolyzates obtained with HCl at pH 2.5 or other enzymes such as protamex, alkalase,&#xD;
      trypsin, neutrase, flavorzyme, maxazyme, collupulin, protex, promod 278 and&#xD;
      alpha-chymotrypsin showing higher superoxide anion scavenging activity and radical oxygen&#xD;
      absorption ability than intact protein and showing protective effects against oxidative&#xD;
      stress-induced DNA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to their anti-inflammatory and antioxidant properties, otrf-derived peptides, including&#xD;
      IRW, IQW, and KVREGT, are viable treatment agents for endothelial dysfunction and CVD&#xD;
      prevention. They de-regulate the expression of the cytokine-induced inflammatory protein in&#xD;
      the vascular endothelium by modulating the pathway NF-μB. Recent research also revealed that&#xD;
      KVREGT has a significant role to inhibit ACE and promote vasodilation. IQW impedes ACE,&#xD;
      promoting antioxidation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ovotransferrin and lactoferrin are iron-binding proteins with natural immunity-related&#xD;
      antiviral and antibacterial activities, displaying marked sequence and structural homologies.&#xD;
      Two hen ovotransferrin fragments DQKDEYELL (hOtrf219-227) and KDLLFK (hOtrf269-301 and&#xD;
      hOtrf633-638) have registered antiviral activity against Marek virus infection of chicken&#xD;
      embryo fibroblasts. These fragments have sequence homology with two bovine lactoferrin&#xD;
      fragments with antiviral activity towards herpes simplex virus, indicating that these&#xD;
      fragments may play a role in exploiting intact protein antiviral activity towards herpes&#xD;
      viruses. NMR analysis showed that these chemically synthesized peptides had no favorite&#xD;
      solution conformation, suggesting that both the amino acid sequence and the conformation in&#xD;
      the intact protein are necessary for antiviral action.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 virus activates the human cell ACE2 receptor, triggering a series of deleterious&#xD;
      events. In COVID19, renin-angiotensin is upregulated and the pathway is overexpressed and a&#xD;
      progressive cytokine storm is always observed. In all these pathogenic processes,&#xD;
      ovotransferrin could play a modifier function to enhance the condition. Ovotransferrin can be&#xD;
      beneficial to the antioxidant effects of Angiotensin II by inhibiting NF-kB. Ovotransferrin&#xD;
      is an immunomodulator that downregulates pro-inflammatory cytokines including TNF-α, IL-6,&#xD;
      and IL-1 that could extinguish the cytokine storm. Ovotransferrin can also serve as a&#xD;
      protective agent against COVID19 cardiotoxicity due to disruption in the ACE2-mediated&#xD;
      signaling pathway, cytokine storm, pulmonary dysfunction, and side effects of medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In patients with coronavirus infection, provided ovotransferrin's possible protective&#xD;
      effects, it is suggested as a supportive and therapeutic alternative.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given this background, in the light of the current COVID-19 emergency, it is the intention of&#xD;
      the investigators to conduct a prospective, randomized, open-label, controlled study in the&#xD;
      cohort of hospitalized patients with covid-19 pneumonia, administering 200 mg of&#xD;
      ovotransferrin orally in addition to the standard of care therapy (SOC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesize that the use of ovotransferrin will be associated with an&#xD;
      earlier improvement of clinical and humoral parameters after 10 days of ovotransferrin&#xD;
      treatment when compared to the group of patients provided with standard care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>In-hospital mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>48hours</time_frame>
    <description>Change of hospital mortality</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>C reactive protein (CRP) levels</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Reduction of CRP levels &gt; 50% in comparison with CRP levels at the admission, within 48 hours after the administration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>IL-6 levels</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Reduction of IL-6 levels &gt; 50% in comparison with IL-6 at the admission, within 48 hours after the administration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>D-dimer levels</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Reduction of D-dimer levels &gt; 50% in comparison with D-dimer at the admission, within 48 hours after the administration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital stay</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Length of hospital stay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of positive PCR swab</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>Time length of negativization of PCR molecular swab</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ovotransferrin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dietary Supplement: Ovotransferrin</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard of care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ovotransferrin</intervention_name>
    <description>Administering 200 mg of ovotransferrin orally in addition to the standard of care therapy for 10 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ovotransferrin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive swab test of SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pneumonia related to SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signature of informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of allergies to egg proteins&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unsigned informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative swab test of SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to egg proteins&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy and breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mechanical ventilation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Antonio Cascio, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>AOU Policlinico &quot;P. Giaccone&quot; - University of Palermo, Italy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Antonio Cascio, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+393389912198</phone>
    <email>antonio.cascio03@unipa.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Policlinico Paolo Giaccone</name>
      <address>
        <city>Palermo</city>
        <zip>90127</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Antonio Cascio, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+393389912198</phone>
      <email>antonio.cascio03@unipa.it</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Abeyrathne EDNS, Huang X, Ahn DU. Antioxidant, angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitory activity and other functional properties of egg white proteins and their derived peptides - A review. Poult Sci. 2018 Apr 1;97(4):1462-1468. doi: 10.3382/ps/pex399. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29340654</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Benedé S, Molina E. Chicken Egg Proteins and Derived Peptides with Antioxidant Properties. Foods. 2020 Jun 3;9(6). pii: E735. doi: 10.3390/foods9060735. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32503187</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chen S, Jiang H, Peng H, Wu X, Fang J. The Utility of Ovotransferrin and Ovotransferrin-Derived Peptides as Possible Candidates in the Clinical Treatment of Cardiovascular Diseases. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2017;2017:6504518. doi: 10.1155/2017/6504518. Epub 2017 Mar 13. Review. Erratum in: Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2018 Dec 13;2018:1897257.</citation>
    <PMID>28386310</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Giansanti F, Massucci MT, Giardi MF, Nozza F, Pulsinelli E, Nicolini C, Botti D, Antonini G. Antiviral activity of ovotransferrin derived peptides. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2005 May 27;331(1):69-73.</citation>
    <PMID>15845359</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 22, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 24, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Policlinico Paolo Giaccone Palermo</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Antonio Cascio</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Chief Infectious and Tropical Diseases Departmemt</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Ovotransferrin</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

