<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3473">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04616989</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Integration of mental health</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04616989</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mental Health in Communities Affected by COVID-19 in Uganda</brief_title>
  <official_title>Integration of Mental Health Care in Communities Affected by the COVID-19 Pandemic in Central Uganda</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Makerere University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Makerere University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Introduction: During pandemics like the COVID-19, a significant number of the populace suffer&#xD;
      from psychological distress (PD) that often abates naturally over time in the majority of&#xD;
      people but persists in others to become pervasive and severe enough to trigger the onset of&#xD;
      common mental disorders (CMD) like major depressive disorders (MDD), generalized anxiety&#xD;
      disorders (GAD), post-traumatic stress disorders (PTSD) and substance misuse disorders (SUD).&#xD;
      Once identified, psychological distress as well as CMD can be managed using psychotherapy or&#xD;
      pharmacotherapy. However, low levels of mental health literacy (MHL) manifested by the&#xD;
      individual's unawareness of CMD symptoms, limited human and mental health infrastructure&#xD;
      resources and high levels of mental illness stigma (MIS), are barriers to integration of&#xD;
      mental health care in general health care during pandemics and epidemics such as the&#xD;
      COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study objectives will include: (a) Documenting MHL, PD, MDD, GAD, PTSD and SUD levels in&#xD;
      the study population, (b) Determining the effectiveness of a psycho-education intervention&#xD;
      delivered by village health team (VHT) members on study outcomes&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: We shall employ an open label cluster-randomized trial design, with each village as&#xD;
      a cluster, to conduct the study in 24 villages (12 intervention and 12 control villages) in&#xD;
      Kampala (n= 15), Wakiso (n= 3), Masaka (n= 2) and Mukono (n= 4) districts. To ensure balance&#xD;
      between the two study arms, villages underwent stratified randomization on the basis of rural&#xD;
      vs urban population. The second level of stratification will be achieved by a separate&#xD;
      randomization procedure performed within each stratum to ensure gender balance within each&#xD;
      cluster&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will develop information education and communication materials (IEC) aimed at improving&#xD;
      MHL and reducing MIS. In the intervention arm (n=12 villages), VHTs will distribute the IEC&#xD;
      materials in every 12th household till they accrue 420 individuals (adults ≥ 18 years old)&#xD;
      who express interest in participating in the study. In the control arm (n=12 villages), VHTs&#xD;
      will distribute MOH COVID-19 information leaflets in every 12th household till they accrue&#xD;
      420 individuals who express interest in participating in the study. Within 7days after&#xD;
      distribution of the materials, trained research assistants will schedule and assess&#xD;
      participants (through a phone interview) for MHL, PD, MDD, GAD, PTSD and SUD. Individuals who&#xD;
      don't have phones will be asked to provide a phone number of a friend or relative through&#xD;
      which the interviews can be conducted; interviews could also be conducted using the VHTs'&#xD;
      phone. Cost data will be collected using available implementation data. We will document the&#xD;
      number of individuals from both arms who will contact the investigators&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data analysis plans: We will (a) report frequencies and percentages and their 95% confidence&#xD;
      intervals for the first objective, (b) use an intention to treat analysis to analyze the&#xD;
      second objective,&#xD;
&#xD;
      Conclusion: Findings from this research will guide policy and practice regarding the&#xD;
      integration of mental health services in the community in the context of epidemic&#xD;
      preparedness and response.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study design: The investigators will use a multi-stage open-label cluster-randomized trial of&#xD;
      24 randomly chosen villages (n=12 intervention and n=12 control) in Kampala (n=15), Wakiso&#xD;
      (n=3), Mukono (n=4) and Masaka (n=2) districts. Intervention and control villages are at&#xD;
      least 20km apart to avoid contamination&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study procedure:&#xD;
&#xD;
      (i) Randomization and sampling: The investigators shall employ an open label&#xD;
      cluster-randomized trial design, with each village as a cluster, to conduct the study in 24&#xD;
      villages (12 intervention and 12 control villages) in Kampala (n= 15), Wakiso (n= 3), Masaka&#xD;
      (n= 2) and Mukono (n= 4) districts. To ensure balance between the two study arms, villages&#xD;
      underwent stratified randomization on the basis of rural vs urban population. The second&#xD;
      level of stratification will be achieved by a separate randomization procedure performed&#xD;
      within each stratum to ensure gender balance within each cluster&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators shall employ the multistage open label sampling approach to select 840&#xD;
      participants from 24 randomly selected villages located in the 362 parishes (5250 villages)&#xD;
      that span the study districts. Study villages will be selected using the probability&#xD;
      proportional to size approach (based on number of parishes/villages per district). Thus, the&#xD;
      investigators shall select 15 villages from Kampala district (3297 villages), 4 villages from&#xD;
      Mukono district (813 villages), 2 villages from Masaka district (436 villages) and 3 villages&#xD;
      from Wakiso district (704 villages). The villages are at least 20km apart to avoid&#xD;
      contamination (individuals interacting during the intervention).&#xD;
&#xD;
      (ii) Participant identification: The investigators shall engage the VHT and village Local&#xD;
      Chairpersons to distribute leaflets describing the study to every 12th household in their&#xD;
      catchment area till they accrue 38 participants in their village who express interest in&#xD;
      participating in the study. This figure is based on an average of 4710 households per&#xD;
      village. Thus 4710/38 is approximately every 12th household. Individuals who express interest&#xD;
      in the study will be given 2 consent forms which they will read and sign should they decide&#xD;
      to participate; they will retain one copy. VHTs will read out the consent form to individuals&#xD;
      who can neither read nor write and obtain informed consent (participants will use their thumb&#xD;
      print soaked in an inkpad to consent). Consent forms will be translated into Luganda. The VHT&#xD;
      will then get the participant's telephone contact and provide it to the project administrator&#xD;
      who will pass them to research assistants. Individuals who don't have phones will be asked to&#xD;
      provide a phone number of a friend or relative through which the interviews can be conducted-&#xD;
      interviews could also be conducted using the VHTs' phone if the participants comfortable&#xD;
      receiving calls on the VHT's telephone. The VHT will inform the project administrator of&#xD;
      participants without personal phones and indicate how that participant can be contacted. The&#xD;
      investigators will conduct a times and motions assessment to document the duration of the&#xD;
      interventions as well as the amount of money spent on transport refunds for the VHTs and the&#xD;
      airtime costs&#xD;
&#xD;
      (iii) Baseline data collection: Trained research assistants will call participants and&#xD;
      schedule a phone interview and collect demographic (age, gender, education level and place of&#xD;
      residence) information and administer the Mental health Knowledge Schedule (MAKS) to assess&#xD;
      for MHL, Kesler-10 (K-10) to measure PD, the Generalized Anxiety Disorder scale (GAD-7) to&#xD;
      assess for GAD, Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9) to assess for MDD Post-Traumatic&#xD;
      Stress Disorder- Primary Care Screen (PTSD-PC) for PTSD and the Alcohol Smoking and Substance&#xD;
      Involvement screening Test (ASSIST) to assess for SUD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      (iv) The intervention: Within a week of the baseline surveys, VHTs in the 12 intervention&#xD;
      villages described above- (a) basic information about the symptoms of PD (b) their adverse&#xD;
      effects, (c) the signs and symptoms of CMD, (d) the benefits associated with having them&#xD;
      treated and (e) the contact details of the research team should they need more information.&#xD;
      See a template of the IEC materials attached. Previous studies have administered the&#xD;
      post-test questionnaires a week after the baseline assessment .&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the 12 control villages, VHTs will distribute the MOH IEC materials that contain&#xD;
      information about (a) the signs and symptoms of the COVID-19 and the preventive measures, (b)&#xD;
      the fact that individuals may suffer from PD during the pandemic (c) the sources from where&#xD;
      they can get psychosocial help and (d) the contact details of the research team should they&#xD;
      need more information. The IEC materials will be distributed to individuals who participated&#xD;
      in the baseline surveys&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mitigating the possibility of contamination between the study arms: Being an educational&#xD;
      intervention, there is a chance that participants in the control villages will access IEC&#xD;
      materials distributed to those in the intervention arm, leading to contamination of the study&#xD;
      findings. To avoid contamination, the investigators will do the following: (i) randomize&#xD;
      villages so that they are at least 20km apart (with the limited human movements during the&#xD;
      COVID-19 pandemic, we anticipate that there will be little by way of people sharing the IEC&#xD;
      materials), (ii) conduct the assessments within a week of distributing the materials to limit&#xD;
      the chances that the information will be widely circulated, (iii) ask participants in the&#xD;
      control arms if they accessed the IEC materials meant for the control group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      (v) Follow-up data collection: Within a week after the VHTs have distributed IEC materials,&#xD;
      research assistants will call participants from both arms and (i) confirm whether they&#xD;
      received IEC materials (and read it), then (ii) schedule a phone interview to administer the&#xD;
      instruments administered at baseline (MAKS, K-10, GAD-7, PHQ-9, PTSD-PC and ASSIST).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study measures: Research assistants will administer standardized questionnaires to collect:&#xD;
      i) Demographic variables including age, gender, physical address, contact information,&#xD;
      marital and employment status, education level ii) primary study variable (MHL using MAKS)&#xD;
      and (iii) secondary variables including PD using the K-10, GAD using the GAD-7, MDD using the&#xD;
      PHQ-9, PTSD using the PTSD-PC and SUD using the ASSIST.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant Follow-up: Participants will be assessed for the outcomes of interest at baseline&#xD;
      and within a week (7 days). Participants who have been referred to the psychosocial teams&#xD;
      will be called after 14 days to find out whether they followed up on the referral and if not,&#xD;
      state the reasons for not doing so.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adverse event reporting during the interviews: The investigators anticipate that there will&#xD;
      be minimal adverse events that are directly related to the study, mainly psychological&#xD;
      distress resulting from answering the questions during the survey or loss of private data.&#xD;
      However, in the event that the investigators realize any severe form of distress, or loss of&#xD;
      privacy/confidentiality, then the investigators will report it promptly reported to the&#xD;
      SOMREC/UNCST.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Community tracing: In the event that a participant cannot be accessed for the second&#xD;
      interview after the baseline one, then, the investigators will ask the VHT to visit the&#xD;
      physical location and find out the reason for non-response. The VHT will be provided with a&#xD;
      Log to record this kind of information which could be loss of a phone, change in phone number&#xD;
      of withdrawal from the study among other reasons. If the participant can't be contacted on&#xD;
      phone and physically, (may have moved house), then the investigators will consider this a&#xD;
      loss to follow up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size and statistical considerations Hypothesis: The investigators hypothesize that (a)&#xD;
      the MHL levels are low in the communities in comparison to those observed in high income&#xD;
      countries, (b) a psycho-education intervention delivered by VHTs will lead to a 50% increase&#xD;
      in MHL levels in the intervention arm compared to the control arm (that this difference will&#xD;
      be clinically significant), (c) more participants in the intervention arm will contact the&#xD;
      study team compared to the control arm - and that this difference will be clinically&#xD;
      significant&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Sample size for objective 1. To document the baseline community MHL level, the&#xD;
           investigators will use the Leslie-Kish formular for calculating the sample size for&#xD;
           cross sectional studies. The formula states that: n = Z2 p (1-p)/E2. n- sample size,&#xD;
           E-The standard error (5%), p- Proportion of patients; 50%.The prevalence was estimated&#xD;
           at 50% as the conservative estimates for outcomes or effects sizes with limited&#xD;
           literature to refer to (in this case, prevalence of poor MHL in the Ugandan community).&#xD;
           Z- The standard normal deviation of 1.96 corresponding to 95% confidence interval&#xD;
           Substituting; n=1.962 X 0.5 X (1-0.5)/0.052 n= 384. b) For the population survey, the&#xD;
           investigators will use the sample size calculation, but use a community correction&#xD;
           effect of 2. Thus the sample size for the community sample will be 384X2 = 764. The&#xD;
           investigators will add a 10% sample size to cater for incomplete data mainly due to&#xD;
           failure to complete an interview. Thus, the total sample size will be 840 participants&#xD;
           (420 in the control and 420 in the intervention arms).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Sample size for objective 2: To determine the effectiveness of the psycho-education&#xD;
           intervention, the investigators have calculated the size of effects that the sample will&#xD;
           be able to detect a clinically significant difference in MHL level between the&#xD;
           intervention and control arms. The nature of the educational intervention makes&#xD;
           randomization by clusters (villages) more appropriate in comparison to randomization by&#xD;
           individuals or household.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To estimate the number of villages required per arm for a clinically significant effect size&#xD;
      of 50%: The investigators assume power of 80% at the 95% confidence level, mean MHL score of&#xD;
      14.14 and standard deviation (SD) of 2.19, cluster-size of 35 participants and coefficient of&#xD;
      variation of 0.25, which yields ~8 villages per trial-arm. The investigators shall include a&#xD;
      minimum of 12 villages per arm (50% increment) to cater for the following limitations; i) the&#xD;
      large proportion of participants who do not own mobile phones (~30%) (Incomplete data due to&#xD;
      participants not being able to complete interviews). Therefore, 24 villages (both arms) will&#xD;
      be required; thus, including up to 840 participants (420 per trial-arm).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection and management: Data will be collected on paper and then entered into a&#xD;
      centralized, web-based data management scheme using the open source software REDCap™.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective 1: The investigators will report frequencies and percentages of the study outcomes&#xD;
      and their 95% confidence intervals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective 2: An intention-to-treat analysis will be conducted to compare the groups at&#xD;
      baseline and within 4 weeks to assess the effects of the intervention on MHL. The dependent&#xD;
      variable (MHL) will be calculated as a continuous variable. Independent variables including&#xD;
      presence of PD, MDD, GAD, PTSD or SUD will be presented as continuous and categorical&#xD;
      variables. Baseline characteristics of the intervention and control arms will be compared at&#xD;
      the 5% level to assess if successful randomization was achieved. Data on potential&#xD;
      confounders and effect modifiers, including variables that fail to achieve successful&#xD;
      randomization (e.g. socio-demographic parameters) shall be used to control for confounding&#xD;
      and effect modification. Between-subject analysis at week 4 will be used to assess the direct&#xD;
      effect of the intervention by determining if there is a significant difference between the&#xD;
      mean MHL scores in the intervention and control arms. Within-subject analysis will be&#xD;
      performed among patients in the intervention arm by applying the Generalized Estimating&#xD;
      Equations method on repeated measures data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data safety management board: The data safety management board (DSMB) will be comprised of&#xD;
      Prof Eugene Kinyanda (Psychiatrist and Senior Epidemiologist), Dr Moses Ocan (pharmacologist&#xD;
      and IRB member), and Dr. Paul Bangirana (Clinical psychologist with vast experience in&#xD;
      conducting RCT) from Makerere University. The PI will have periodic meetings with the DSMB&#xD;
      and provide them with reports about the study activities using an agreed template. There will&#xD;
      be at least two meetings during the study period one at the beginning and another midway&#xD;
      through the study. Members of the DSMB will make a visit at the Butabika Hospital where data&#xD;
      will be collected (phone calls) and stored. During this visit, the study procedures (SOPs and&#xD;
      manuals), study responsibilities (delegation log), site facilities (call rooms/data room),&#xD;
      study materials (stationary and administrative materials) and the recruitment and retention&#xD;
      plan will be discussed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants in the intervention arm will receive leaflets about the mental health literacy while those in the control arm will receive COVID-19 leaflets</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in mental health literacy</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will document the change in the mean scores of mental health literacy between the two arms measured using the Mental health Knowledge Schedule (MAKS) instrument</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Burden of anxiety disorders in the community</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will document the prevalence of anxiety using the GAD instrument in the 2 arms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Burden of PTSD in the community</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will document the prevalence of PTSD using the PTSD-PC instrument in the 2 arms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Burden of substance use disorders in the community</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will document the prevalence of substance use disorders using the ASSIST instrument in the 2 arms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Burden of depression disorders in the community</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will document the prevalence of depression use disorders using the PHQ-9 instrument in the 2 arms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">840</enrollment>
  <condition>Community Mental Health</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Psycho-education intervention arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive psycho-education materials</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Comparator arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive COVID-19 leaflets</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Psycho-education</intervention_name>
    <description>Provide psycho-education to members of the community</description>
    <arm_group_label>Psycho-education intervention arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Comparator</intervention_name>
    <description>Distribution of COVID-19 leaflets to members of the community</description>
    <arm_group_label>Comparator arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults aged 18 years and above who live in the community where data will be collected&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with acute illnesses that will prevent them from providing information&#xD;
             during data collection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Dickens Akena, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+256712941009</phone>
    <email>akenadickens@yahoo.co.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 3, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

