<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4618">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03966872</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D19103 31245</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03966872</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparative Effectiveness of IIMR Versus CDSMP</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparative Effectiveness of Integrated Illness Management and Recovery Versus the Chronic Disease Self-Management Program</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Patient-Centered Outcomes Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study will enroll 600 people with serious mental illness who receive services at&#xD;
      Centerstone in KY or TN and will compare two different evidence-based self-management&#xD;
      interventions: Integrated Illness Management and Recovery (I-IMR), a program developed by the&#xD;
      study team at Dartmouth that trains people with serious mental illness on physical and mental&#xD;
      health self-management, and the Stanford Chronic Disease Self-Management Program (CDSMP), a&#xD;
      program largely focused on physical health self-management that has been used widely in the&#xD;
      general population. In addition, PCORI is funding an evaluation of a COVID-related&#xD;
      intervention that will begin in the Fall 2020.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The proposed study will be the first to compare two commonly used but substantially&#xD;
      different, evidence-based self-management interventions. Integrated Illness Management and&#xD;
      Recovery (I-IMR), is an individually-tailored, 16-session, integrated program combining both&#xD;
      physical and mental health self-management specifically developed for people with SMI. In&#xD;
      contrast, the Stanford Chronic Disease Self-Management Program (CDSMP) is a group-based,&#xD;
      6-session, chronic disease self-management program largely focused on physical health&#xD;
      self-management alone. I-IMR is delivered by community mental health providers or by&#xD;
      community outreach workers, while CDSMP is co-delivered by two peers or by a health&#xD;
      professional and a peer. Both programs have been widely recommended, disseminated, and used.&#xD;
      The proposed parent study will randomize people with serious mental illness to I-IMR (n=300)&#xD;
      and CDSMP (n=300).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our COVID-related Enhancement will involve enrolling 150 participants from the parent project&#xD;
      to an evaluation of an additional I-IMR module compared to usual care during the pandemic.&#xD;
      The I-IMR module will be delivered by trained interventionists in 3 calls over 3 weeks to&#xD;
      n=75 I-IMR participants. The I-IMR participants and CDSMP participants will continue to&#xD;
      receive Usual Care, consisting of generic support calls from clinicians at the study sites.&#xD;
      Baseline, and 6, 9, and 12 week assessments will evaluate the effectiveness of the COVID-19&#xD;
      module that will be added to I-IMR.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 2, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Knowledge and skills in illness self-management using the Illness Management and Recovery Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in knowledge and skills for illness self-management. Range of scores from 15-75 with higher scores meaning better illness self-management.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Patient Activation on the Patient Activation Measure (PAM)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Patient Activation (engagement in health care). Maximum score of 100, higher scores meaning greater activation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Acute Hospital Events from Electronic Medical Record Review.</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in the number of acute hospital events. At each assessment a combination of participant report and verified information from mental health clinics will be used to validate the number acute hospital events.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowledge and Behaviors for Preventing Catching and Spreading COVID-19 Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from Baseline to 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in score on this measure, which was developed as part of the study plan because no suitable scale existed to assess knowledge and safety behaviors for COVID-19. Scores range from 0-100%, with higher scores indicating greater knowledge and enactment of safety behaviors.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Mental Illness</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Integrated Illness Management and Recovery (I-IMR):</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants assigned to I-IMR will receive 2 individual sessions to discuss principles of recovery and set personally meaningful goals, with the remainder of the 14 I-IMR sessions delivered in groups of 8-10 (to enable individual tailoring)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Stanford Chronic Disease Self-Management Program (CDSMP):</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomly assigned get a 6-session group-based educational program co-delivered by two peers (lay people who have successfully managed a chronic illness) or a peer and a professional</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Integrated Illness Management and Recovery</intervention_name>
    <description>Education and skills training groups on illness management of chronic medical and psychiatric illness. Subsample of 75 will also receive COVID-specific Integrated Illness Management and Recovery module.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Integrated Illness Management and Recovery (I-IMR):</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Chronic Disease Self-Management Program</intervention_name>
    <description>Education and skills training groups on illness management of chronic conditions</description>
    <arm_group_label>Stanford Chronic Disease Self-Management Program (CDSMP):</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious Mental Illness (diagnosis of schizophrenia, schizoaffective disorder, bipolar&#xD;
             disorder, or chronic depression with moderate impairment in functioning) receiving&#xD;
             services at Centerstone(KY and TN)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of a chronic medical condition increasing risk of early mortality from&#xD;
             cardiovascular or respiratory disease (e.g., diabetes, hyperlipidemia, hypertension,&#xD;
             COPD, heart failure, tobacco dependence, obesity), and at least 1 ER visit or&#xD;
             hospitalization within the past year or judgment by the treatment team of substantial&#xD;
             need for illness self-management training.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consumers who do not speak English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consumers with either no, or a well-controlled medical condition will not be included&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals residing in a nursing home or other institution&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of significant cognitive impairment as indicated by a Mini Mental Status&#xD;
             Examination score &lt;24, will be excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
        Eligibility for the COVID -related substudy is dependent on enrollment and participation in&#xD;
        the parent project.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sarah Pratt</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seven Counties Services</name>
      <address>
        <city>Louisville</city>
        <state>Kentucky</state>
        <zip>40220</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centerstone</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37228</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 1, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 28, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 29, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 19, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 19, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sarah Pratt</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>integrated health</keyword>
  <keyword>mental health</keyword>
  <keyword>illness management</keyword>
  <keyword>cardiovascular disease</keyword>
  <keyword>physical health</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

