<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2039">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04623697</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>S-20200119</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04623697</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Covid-19 Infection and New Onset Type 1 Diabetes</brief_title>
  <official_title>Covid-19 and Type 1 Diabetes - a Multicenter Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital of South West Jutland</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Steno Diabetes Center Odense</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Steno Diabetes Center Nordjylland</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Steno Diabetes Center Aarhus</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Steno Diabetes Center Sjaelland</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Steno Diabetes Center Copenhagen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital of South West Jutland</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Although recognized as an autoimmune disease the etiology of type 1 diabetes remains unknown.&#xD;
      Virus infections has been suggested as a possible agent triggering the autoimmune reaction&#xD;
      finally resulting in beta-cell destruction and fate of insulin secretion. SARS Cov-2 virus&#xD;
      enters the infected cells by binding to the ACE-2 receptor, which is abundant in many tissues&#xD;
      including the pancreas. Accordingly, SARS Covid-19 infection may trigger the development of&#xD;
      type 1 diabetes either by an activation of the immune system or directly via beta-cell&#xD;
      infection and destruction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our aim is to study the impact of the Covid-19 epidemic on the development of type 1&#xD;
      diabetes. This will be done in two ways: a clinical study and an epidemiological follow up.&#xD;
      During the next two years, adult patients with newly diagnosed type 1 diabetes will be asked&#xD;
      to participate. Type 1 diabetes will be diagnosed by usual means and a mixed meal tolerance&#xD;
      test will be performed at time of diagnosis and after one year to evaluate beta-cell&#xD;
      function. People with type 1 diabetes and serologically documented previous SARS Covid-19&#xD;
      will be compared with people with no previous infection regarding beta-cell function and fate&#xD;
      of insulin secretion. In addition, we will estimate the number of new diagnosed type 1&#xD;
      diabetes patients compared to previous years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although recognized as an autoimmune disease, the etiology of type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1D)&#xD;
      remains undetermined. One dominant hypothesis is that a recent virus infection elicits or&#xD;
      enhances an autoimmune reaction, resulting in CD4+ and CD8+ T-cells recognizing pancreatic&#xD;
      antigens and subsequently targeting the beta-cells of the pancreas. This results in a gradual&#xD;
      but irreversible loss of beta-cell function.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Various enterovirus species have been suspected as causative factors of T1D. However, many&#xD;
      different viruses may carry the potential to induce T1D via one of the above-mentioned&#xD;
      mechanisms, including respiratory infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Most people are presently immunologically inert to SARS-Cov-2, but a large proportion of the&#xD;
      world's population is expected to be infected over the next few years, with the global focus&#xD;
      having now shifted to slowing the spread (1). The pandemic of COVID-19 therefore provides an&#xD;
      opportunity to study a possible correlation between a novel type of virus infection and the&#xD;
      development of T1D.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our overall aim is to study the impact of Covid-19 on the incidence and the phenotype&#xD;
      (beta-cell function at time of diagnosis and at follow up) of newly diagnosed adult patients&#xD;
      with T1D in a multicenter study, with enrolments to occur in both Denmark and Portugal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following study populations are established over a two-year period, beginning in October&#xD;
      2020:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Study population 1: Newly diagnosed adult patients with T1D according to usual practice,&#xD;
           stratified for the presence of SARS-Cov-2-antibodies (+/-), in both Denmark and&#xD;
           Portugal.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Study population 2: A control population of the same age (+/- 3 years) and sex from each&#xD;
           participant country, potentially from the national blood banks. This will provide the&#xD;
           SARS-Cov-2 status of the background population. Each newly diagnosed T1D patient is&#xD;
           matched with five control persons.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 1: Clinical study: Study 1:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  T1D patients diagnosed according to standard practice (including Hba1c, C-peptide,&#xD;
           presence of GAD (or islet-cell) antibodies).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patient is attending a hospital unit in Denmark or Portugal, due to T1D.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Age 18 years or above.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Severe psychiatric disorder or other conditions deemed to impair the patient's informed&#xD;
      consent and participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In each country, all subjects from study population 1 will undergo the following assessments&#xD;
      at diagnosis of T1D:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. SARS-Cov-2 antibody measurement.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. GAD-antibodies (and if necessary islet cell antibodies (IA-2)).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. HbA1c, fasting blood glucose and fasting C-peptide.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Mixed-meal tolerance test (MMTT).&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Follow-up one year after the diagnosis with HbA1c, fasting blood glucose, fasting&#xD;
           C-peptide and MMTT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 2: Epidemiological study 1: In each country, the incidence of SARS-Covid-2 antibodies&#xD;
      in study group 1 is compared to the matched control group (Study population 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 3: Epidemiological study 2: Independently of the above mentioned study, the incidence&#xD;
      of newly diagnosed T1D patients in each participant country will be determined by registry&#xD;
      data from January 1st 2020 on a monthly basis and compared with newly diagnosed T1D patients&#xD;
      from the two previous years (2018 and 2019).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcomes&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will have the following outcomes&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 1 (clinical study):&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcome: C-peptide AUC of the MMTT at baseline and one year follow-up, for adult T1D&#xD;
      patients having SARS-Cov-2 positive vs. negative antibody status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary outcomes: Fasting glucose, C-peptide, Hba1c at baseline and one year follow-up, for&#xD;
      adult T1D patients having SARS-Cov-2 positive vs. negative antibody status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 2 (epidemiological study 1):&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome: Proportion of T1D patients having SARS-Cov-2 antibodies, compared to matched&#xD;
      controls from the background population, potentially from the national blood banks (1:5 match&#xD;
      on age, gender and if possible country region).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 3 (epidemiological study 2):&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome: Annual and monthly T1D incidence (cases/100.000) during 2020-2022, compared to 2018&#xD;
      and 2019 in Denmark and Portugal.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>2 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Stimulated insulin secretion</measure>
    <time_frame>One years</time_frame>
    <description>C-peptide AUC of the MMTT at baseline and one year follow-up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>One years</time_frame>
    <description>HbA1c measure at one year</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fasting blood glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>One years</time_frame>
    <description>Fasting blood glucose</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>type1diabetes</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood for research biobank&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All newly diagnosed people with type 1 diabetes&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  T1D patients diagnosed according to standard practice (including Hba1c, C-peptide,&#xD;
             presence of GAD (or islet-cell) antibodies).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is attending a hospital unit in Denmark or Portugal, due to T1D.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 years or above.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe psychiatric disorder or other conditions deemed to impair the patient's&#xD;
             informed consent and participation in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Claus B Juhl</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hospital of South West Jutland</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Claus B Juhl, MD PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+4560867172</phone>
    <email>Claus.Bogh.Juhl@rsyd.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Morten Bjerregaard-Andersen, MD PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+4528112956</phone>
    <email>Morten.Bjerregaard-Andersen2@rsyd.dk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital of South West Jutland</name>
      <address>
        <city>Esbjerg</city>
        <zip>6700</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Claus B Juhl, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+4560867172</phone>
      <email>claus.bogh.juhl@rsyd.dk</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Morten Bjerregaard-Andersen, MSc, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+4528112956</phone>
      <email>Morten.Bjerregaard-Andersen2@rsyd.dk</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Filippi CM, von Herrath MG. Viral trigger for type 1 diabetes: pros and cons. Diabetes. 2008 Nov;57(11):2863-71. doi: 10.2337/db07-1023.</citation>
    <PMID>18971433</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Coleman TJ, Gamble DR, Taylor KW. Diabetes in mice after Coxsackie B 4 virus infection. Br Med J. 1973 Jul 7;3(5870):25-7.</citation>
    <PMID>4577716</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Christoffersson G, Flodström-Tullberg M. Mouse Models of Virus-Induced Type 1 Diabetes. Methods Mol Biol. 2020;2128:93-105. doi: 10.1007/978-1-0716-0385-7_7.</citation>
    <PMID>32180188</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Stone VM, Hankaniemi MM, Svedin E, Sioofy-Khojine A, Oikarinen S, Hyöty H, Laitinen OH, Hytönen VP, Flodström-Tullberg M. A Coxsackievirus B vaccine protects against virus-induced diabetes in an experimental mouse model of type 1 diabetes. Diabetologia. 2018 Feb;61(2):476-481. doi: 10.1007/s00125-017-4492-z. Epub 2017 Nov 18.</citation>
    <PMID>29151123</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hyöty H, Leon F, Knip M. Developing a vaccine for type 1 diabetes by targeting coxsackievirus B. Expert Rev Vaccines. 2018 Dec;17(12):1071-1083. doi: 10.1080/14760584.2018.1548281. Epub 2018 Nov 29. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30449209</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Moltchanova EV, Schreier N, Lammi N, Karvonen M. Seasonal variation of diagnosis of Type 1 diabetes mellitus in children worldwide. Diabet Med. 2009 Jul;26(7):673-8. doi: 10.1111/j.1464-5491.2009.02743.x.</citation>
    <PMID>19573115</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Karaoglan M, Eksi F. The Coincidence of Newly Diagnosed Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus with IgM Antibody Positivity to Enteroviruses and Respiratory Tract Viruses. J Diabetes Res. 2018 Aug 16;2018:8475341. doi: 10.1155/2018/8475341. eCollection 2018.</citation>
    <PMID>30186878</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Patterson CC, Gyürüs E, Rosenbauer J, Cinek O, Neu A, Schober E, Parslow RC, Joner G, Svensson J, Castell C, Bingley PJ, Schoenle E, Jarosz-Chobot P, Urbonaité B, Rothe U, Kržišnik C, Ionescu-Tirgoviste C, Weets I, Kocova M, Stipancic G, Samardzic M, de Beaufort CE, Green A, Soltész G, Dahlquist GG. Seasonal variation in month of diagnosis in children with type 1 diabetes registered in 23 European centers during 1989-2008: little short-term influence of sunshine hours or average temperature. Pediatr Diabetes. 2015 Dec;16(8):573-80. doi: 10.1111/pedi.12227. Epub 2014 Oct 15.</citation>
    <PMID>25316271</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Bindom SM, Lazartigues E. The sweeter side of ACE2: physiological evidence for a role in diabetes. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2009 Apr 29;302(2):193-202. doi: 10.1016/j.mce.2008.09.020. Epub 2008 Oct 1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18948167</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Yang JK, Lin SS, Ji XJ, Guo LM. Binding of SARS coronavirus to its receptor damages islets and causes acute diabetes. Acta Diabetol. 2010 Sep;47(3):193-9. doi: 10.1007/s00592-009-0109-4. Epub 2009 Mar 31.</citation>
    <PMID>19333547</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hospital of South West Jutland</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Claus Bogh Juhl</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD., Ph.D., Clinical Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Covid19</keyword>
  <keyword>Type 1 diabetes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

