<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="317">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04530396</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>04-Gam-COVID-Vac-2020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04530396</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Trial of Efficacy, Safety, and Immunogenicity of Gam-COVID-Vac Vaccine Against COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>RESIST</acronym>
  <official_title>Randomized Double-blind Placebo-controlled Multi-center Clinical Trial in Parallel Assignment of Efficacy, Safety, and Immunogenicity of Gam-COVID-Vac Combined Vector Vaccine in SARS-СoV-2 Infection Prophylactic Treatment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Gamaleya Research Institute of Epidemiology and Microbiology, Health Ministry of the Russian Federation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Government of the city of Moscow</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>CRO: Crocus Medical BV</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Gamaleya Research Institute of Epidemiology and Microbiology, Health Ministry of the Russian Federation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Randomized, double-blind (blinded for the trial subject and the study physician), placebo&#xD;
      controlled, multi-center clinical trial in parallel assignment of efficacy, immunogenicity,&#xD;
      and safety of the Gam-COVID-Vac combined vector vaccine against the SARS-CoV-2-induced&#xD;
      coronavirus infection in adults in the SARS-СoV-2 infection prophylactic treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Randomized, double-blind (blinded for the trial subject and the study physician), placebo&#xD;
      controlled, multi-center clinical trial in parallel assignment of efficacy, immunogenicity,&#xD;
      and safety of the Gam-COVID-Vac combined vector vaccine against the SARS-CoV-2-induced&#xD;
      coronavirus infection in adults in the SARS-СoV-2 infection prophylactic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial will include 40,000 volunteers aged 18+. After screening, they will be randomized&#xD;
      (3:1) into two groups - a reference group of 10,000 volunteers receiving placebo and a study&#xD;
      group of 30,000 volunteers receiving the Gam-COVID-Vac combined vector vaccine against the&#xD;
      SARS-СoV-2-induced coronavirus infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial subjects will be randomized into five age strata: 18-30, 31-40, 41-50, 51-60, and&#xD;
      60+ years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The PCR test for SARS-CoV-2 RNA detection at the visit is performed during screening and&#xD;
      before the second administration of the vaccine/placebo&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each subject will participate in the trial for 180±14 days after the first dose of the study&#xD;
      drug/placebo and will have one screening visit and five on-site visits to the study physician&#xD;
      during the said period. The study drug/placebo will be administered intramuscularly during&#xD;
      vaccination visits 1 and 2 (day 0 and day 21±2). Subsequent observation visits 3, 4, and 5&#xD;
      will be made on days14±2, 28±2, 35±2,42±2, and 180±14 respectively. During the observation&#xD;
      visits, vital signs will be assessed in all trial subjects and changes in the subjects'&#xD;
      condition and wellbeing compared to the previous visit will be recorded. Observation visits&#xD;
      may be remote, through the telemedicine consultation (TMC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additionally, the trial subjects will be able to have remote consultations with the physician&#xD;
      through the TMC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood samples will be taken from certain subjects during the following visits to assess the&#xD;
      immunogenicity parameters listed below:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Virus-neutralizing activity (300 subjects) ×3 Interferon gamma (107 subjects) ×3 CD4 and CD8&#xD;
      cell count and ratio (50 subjects) SARS-CoV-2 glycoprotein-specific antibodies titer (9,520&#xD;
      subjects) ×3 Determination of the titer of SARS-CoV-2 nucleocleocapsid protein-specific&#xD;
      antibodies(9,520 subjects) ×3&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood sampling will be performed on the day of injecting the first dose of the study&#xD;
      drug/placebo immediately prior to the study drug administration Blood sampling for&#xD;
      immunogenicity parameters assessment will be only carried out in specially selected study&#xD;
      centers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood samples will be taken from 9,520 trial subjects. All four immunogenicity parameters may&#xD;
      be assessed in one trial subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Trial subjects data will be collected using electronic case report forms and electronic&#xD;
      questionnaires to be filled by trial subjects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 7, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized double-blind placebo-controlled</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>percentage of trial subjects with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) developed within 6 months after the first dose</measure>
    <time_frame>through the whole study, an average of 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Demonstrate the superiority of Gam-COVID-Vac combined vector vaccine against the SARS-CoV-2-induced coronavirus infection compared to placebo, based on the percentage of trial subjects with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) developed within 6 months after the second dose of the study drug/placebo, as confirmed with the method of polymerase chain reaction (PCR)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>the severity of the clinical course of COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>through the whole study, an average of 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the efficacy of the Gam-COVID-Vac combined vector vaccine against the SARS-CoV-2-induced coronavirus compared to placebo, based on the severity of the clinical course of COVID-19</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changing of antibody levels against the SARS-CoV-2 glycoprotein S</measure>
    <time_frame>day before injecting the first dose of the study drug/placebo and 42±2 and 180±14 days after the first dose</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the immunogenicity of the Gam-COVID-Vac combined vector vaccine against the SARS-CoV-2-induced coronavirus infection compared to placebo, based on the geometric mean titer of SARS-CoV-2 glycoprotein-specific antibodies</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changing of antigen-specific cellular immunity level</measure>
    <time_frame>the drug administration day before injecting the first dose of the study drug/placebo and 28±2 days after the first dose</time_frame>
    <description>Describe the strength of cell-mediated immune response induced by the use of the Gam-COVID-Vac combined vector vaccine against the SARS-CoV-2-induced coronavirus infection compared to placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changing of of virus neutralizing antibody titer</measure>
    <time_frame>the drug administration day before injecting the first dose of the study drug/placebo and 42±2 days after the first dose</time_frame>
    <description>Geometric mean virus-neutralizing antibodies titer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events in trial subjects</measure>
    <time_frame>through the whole study, an average of 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of adverse events in trial subjects compared to placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Severity of adverse events in trial subjects</measure>
    <time_frame>through the whole study, an average of 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Severity of adverse events in trial subjects compared to placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>estimation of the proportion of study subjects with antibodies to the N-protein of the virus SARS-CoV-2</measure>
    <time_frame>day before injecting the first dose of the study drug/placebo and 42±2 and 180±14 days after the first dose</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of study subjects with antibodies&#xD;
to the N-protein of the SARS - CoV-2 virus that appeared after&#xD;
vaccination</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">33758</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19 Prevention</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Primary Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Gam-COVID-Vac combined vector vaccine, 0,5ml/dose+0,5 ml/dose prime-boost immunization in days 1 (component I rAd26-S) and 21(component II rAd5-S)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>placebo, 0,5ml/dose+0,5 ml/dose immunization in days 1 and 21</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Gam-COVID-Vac</intervention_name>
    <description>vaccine for intramuscular injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Primary Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>placebo comparator</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Written informed consent of a subject to participate in the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Males and females aged ≥18 y.o.;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Negative HIV, hepatitis, and syphilis test results&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Negative anti-SARS CoV2 IgM and IgG antibodies test carried out with the enzyme&#xD;
             immunoassay method&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Negative COVID-2019 PCR test result at the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. No COVID-2019 in the past medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. No contact with COVID-2019 diseased persons within at least 14 days before the&#xD;
             enrollment (according to trial subjects)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Consent to use effective contraception methods during the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Negative urine pregnancy test at the screening visit (for child-bearing age women)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Negative drugs or psychostimulants urine test at the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Negative alcohol test at the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. No evident vaccine-induced reactions or complications after receiving immunobiological&#xD;
             products in the past medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. No acute infectious and/or respiratory diseases within at least 14 days before the&#xD;
             enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Any vaccination/immunization within 30 days before the enrollment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Steroids (except hormonal contraceptives) and/or immunoglobulins or other blood&#xD;
             products therapy not finished 30 days before the enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Immunosuppressors therapy finished within 3 months before the enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pregnancy or breast-feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Acute coronary syndrome or stroke suffered less than one year before the enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Tuberculosis, chronic systemic infections&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Drug allergy (anaphylactic shock, Quincke's edema, polymorphic exudative eczema,&#xD;
             atopy, serum disease), hypersensitivity or allergic reaction to immunobiological&#xD;
             products, known allergic reactions to study drug components, acute exacerbation of&#xD;
             allergic diseases on the enrollment day&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Neoplasms in the past medical history (ICD codes C00-D09)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Donated blood or plasma (450+ ml) within 2 months before the enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of splenectomy;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Neutropenia (absolute neutrophil count &lt;1,000/mm3), agranulocytosis, significant blood&#xD;
             loss, severe anemia (hemoglobin &lt;80 g/L), immunodeficiency in the past medical history&#xD;
             within 6 months before the enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Active form of a disease caused by the human immunodeficiency virus, syphilis,&#xD;
             hepatitis B or C&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Anorexia, protein deficiency of any origin&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Big-size tattoos at the injection site (deltoid muscle area), which does not allow&#xD;
             assessing the local response to the study drug/placebo administration&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Alcohol or drug addiction in the past medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Participation in any other interventional clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Any other condition that the study physician considers as a barrier to the trial&#xD;
             completion as per the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Study center staff or other employees directly involved in the trial, or their&#xD;
             families.&#xD;
&#xD;
        If a subject has any contraindications to vaccination based on the Guidelines on Detection,&#xD;
        Investigation and Prevention, of Vaccination-induced Side Reactions (approved by the&#xD;
        Ministry of Healthcare of Russia on Apr. 12, 2019, the vaccination may be postponed for a&#xD;
        period of time specified in the document.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>111 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Elena Smolyarchuk, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Study Coordinator</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sergey Zyryanov, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Study Coordinator</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>ARCHIMED V Clinic of new medical technologies limited liability company</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hadassah LTD</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medsi Group of companies joint-stock company&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Niarmedic Plus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State budgetary healthcare institution of the city of Moscow &quot;City clinical hospital No. 52 of the Moscow city health Department&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State Budgetary Healthcare Institution, Moscow, Consultation and Diagnosis Polyclinic No. 121, Moscow Healthcare Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State Budgetary Healthcare Institution, Moscow, M. Konchalovsky Municipal Clinical Hospital, Moscow Healthcare Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State Budgetary Healthcare Institution, Moscow, M. Zhadkevich Municipal Clinical Hospital, Moscow Healthcare Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State Budgetary Healthcare Institution, Moscow, Municipal Polyclinic No. 115, Moscow Healthcare Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State Budgetary Healthcare Institution, Moscow, Municipal Polyclinic No. 2, Moscow Healthcare Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State Budgetary Healthcare Institution, Moscow, Municipal Polyclinic No. 210, Moscow Healthcare Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State Budgetary Healthcare Institution, Moscow, Municipal Polyclinic No. 212, Moscow Healthcare Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State Budgetary Healthcare Institution, Moscow, Municipal Polyclinic No. 219, Moscow Healthcare Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State Budgetary Healthcare Institution, Moscow, Municipal Polyclinic No. 220, Moscow Healthcare Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State Budgetary Healthcare Institution, Municipal Polyclinic No. 62, Moscow Healthcare Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State budgetary institution of health care of the city of Moscow &quot; city polyclinic No. 109 Of the Department of health of the city of Moscow&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State budgetary institution of health care of the city of Moscow &quot; city polyclinic No. 170 Of the Department of health of the city of Moscow&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State budgetary institution of health care of the city of Moscow &quot; city polyclinic No. 36 Of the Department of health of the city of Moscow&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State budgetary institution of health care of the city of Moscow &quot; city polyclinic No. 46 Of the Department of health of the city of Moscow&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State budgetary institution of health care of the city of Moscow &quot; city polyclinic No. 6 Of the Department of health of the city of Moscow&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State budgetary institution of health care of the city of Moscow &quot; city polyclinic No. 68 Of the Department of health of the city of Moscow&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State budgetary institution of health care of the city of Moscow &quot;Diagnostic center No. 5 with polyclinic Department Of the Department of health of the city of Moscow&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>State budgetary institution of health care of the city of Moscow &quot;Diagnostic clinical center No. 1 Of the Department of health of the city of Moscow&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 27, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 28, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>vector vaccine</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>adenoviral vector</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

