<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1788">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04700462</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB00250644</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>3R01AG056587-03S1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04700462</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19 Preventive Behavior in African Americans</brief_title>
  <official_title>Optimizing Tailored-feedback Message to Promote Adherence Behavior to Prevent COVID-19 in African Americans</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Johns Hopkins University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute on Aging (NIA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Johns Hopkins University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The Center Disease Control has published a set of guidelines to contain the spread of the&#xD;
      virus, since it is known to spread from person-to-person. Given the vaccine and specific&#xD;
      antiviral treatment for Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) remain under development and will take&#xD;
      months or years to develop, intermittent and sustained preventive behaviors may be needed&#xD;
      into 2022 unless effective treatments or vaccines are developed. Thus, effectively&#xD;
      implementing preventive behaviors remains a critical step in bringing the pandemic under&#xD;
      long-term control. Leveraging the ecological momentary assessment (EMA) method developed in&#xD;
      the parent R01 for smartphones, which allows for real-time data collection on individual's&#xD;
      behaviors, the investigators propose a prospective single arm and longitudinal study to&#xD;
      examine the effectiveness of self-monitoring EMA (SM-EMA) in promoting adherence to COVID-19&#xD;
      preventative behaviors. SM-EMA users will download the smartphone app which includes: (1)&#xD;
      instructional videos to provide knowledge of preventative behaviors; (2) self-monitoring of&#xD;
      preventative behaviors during intervention and follow-up phases; (3) tailored-feedback&#xD;
      messages to encourage preventative behaviors; and (4) mobile-enabled website to provide an&#xD;
      interactive learning platform. If proven efficacious, this intervention could be efficiently&#xD;
      disseminated to reach the larger public and foster preventive behaviors into self-management&#xD;
      as effective strategies for long-term control of the COVID-19 pandemic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Given the vaccine and specific antiviral treatment for COVID-19 will take months or years to&#xD;
      develop and finalize, preventive behaviors remain the most effective strategy thus far and&#xD;
      may be needed until 2022 to control the pandemic. African Americans, who have 3-fold higher&#xD;
      infection rate and 6-fold higher death rate compared to the white counterparts, are an&#xD;
      especially vulnerable population to COVID-19. Immediately initiating a project that promotes&#xD;
      and maximizes adherence to preventative behaviors is vital to addressing the ongoing COVID-19&#xD;
      pandemic. The investigators propose a prospective single arm and longitudinal study to&#xD;
      examine the effectiveness of SM-EMA in promoting adherence to COVID-19 preventative&#xD;
      behaviors. The intervention will include two daily pop-up messages during Week 1 (one in the&#xD;
      morning and one in the afternoon), one daily pop-message in Week 2, and two pop-up messages a&#xD;
      week in Weeks 3 and 4. The duration for the intervention will be four weeks. The study&#xD;
      outcomes will be collected at baseline (pre-intervention, T1), post-(completion of the&#xD;
      intervention, T2, primary endpoint), and monthly follow-up for three months (T3-T5). The&#xD;
      total study duration will be four months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 5, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Knowledge Test score as assessed by a questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-intervention, Immediately Post-intervention, 1, 2, and 3 months Post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>It is a measure of one's knowledge of COVID-19 preventative behaviors, with a score range of 0-18, higher scores indicating better knowledge.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Self-efficacy as assessed by self-efficacy questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-intervention, Immediately Post-intervention, 1, 2, and 3 months Post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>It is a measure of one's belief that they will be successful in reaching a behavior goal, with 6-items of questionnaire, with a score of 0-60, higher score indicating higher level of self-efficacy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in preventive Behavior Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-intervention, Daily during intervention week 1 and bi-weekly during intervention weeks 3-4, Immediately Post-intervention, 1, 2, and 3 months Post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>It is a measure of one's adherence to COVID-19 preventative behaviors, with a score range 0-18, higher score indicating worsening preventive behaviors.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in System Usability Scale (SUS) score</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately Post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>It is used to assess the global view of the participant's assessment about usability of SM-EMA, with a score of 1-7, higher score indicting more useable for the app.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Global Impression of Change as assessed by a questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately Post-intervention, 1, 2, and 3 months Post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>It is a single item used to assess the participant's perceived behavior change, with a score of 1-7, higher score indicating better global impression of change.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">250</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Health Behavior</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sm-EMA</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive the Self-monitoring ecological momentary assessment behavior change tool.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sm-EMA</intervention_name>
    <description>Self-monitoring ecological momentary assessment behavior change tool to promote adherence to a desired behavior (i.e. COVID-19 preventative behaviors).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sm-EMA</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  African American aged 60 or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to read and write English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to commit to use the smartphone app with the pop-up messages and then four&#xD;
             follow-up surveys (total four months).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No children or others aged 59 years or younger&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Chao Hsing Yeh, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Johns Hopkins School of Nursing</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Chao Hsing Yeh, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>667-208-7637</phone>
    <email>cyeh13@jhu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Catherine Ling, PhD</last_name>
    <email>cling11@jhu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 6, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Smartphone App</keyword>
  <keyword>Preventative Behavior</keyword>
  <keyword>Self-Management</keyword>
  <keyword>Health Disparities</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

