<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2117">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04597775</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>APCC-19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04597775</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Chemoprevention Clinical Trial of COVID-19: Hydroxychloroquine Post Exposure Prophylaxis</brief_title>
  <acronym>APCC-19</acronym>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Randomized, Adaptive Phase II/III Clinical Trial, Controlled, Open-label, 3-arms, Parallel, Multi-centred, Chemoprevention of COVID-19: Hydroxychloroquine Post Exposure Prophylaxis For COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Regional Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Jordan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Farhat Hached Hospital, Tunisia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Fattouma Bourguiba, Tunisia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Regional Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Jordan</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Protocol summary&#xD;
&#xD;
      Title&#xD;
&#xD;
      A Prospective, randomized, adaptive phase II/III clinical trial, controlled, open-label,&#xD;
      chemoprevention, 3-arms, parallel, multi-centred, to A Prospective, randomized, clinical&#xD;
      trial, controlled, open-label, 3-arms, parallel, multi-centred, chemoprevention of COVID-19:&#xD;
      Hydroxychloroquine Post Exposure Prophylaxis For COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Periods &amp; Duration of Treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Duration: 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approval (IRB and regulatory bodies) 1 month&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment and follow-up: 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analysis, report writing and submission of publications 1 month This study is a parallel&#xD;
      study of one period with an expected duration of treatment (for each subject) of 28 days,&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate if hydroxychloroquine with the proposed dose can provide potent&#xD;
           chemoprophylaxis against the development of COVID-19 positive patients in subjects who&#xD;
           had primary exposure to COVID-19 positive patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To measure the incidence of potential adverse drug reaction rates for giving&#xD;
           hydroxychloroquine for prevention of COVID-19 amongst close contacts&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To provide early analysis of results and redefine sample size accordingly.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  identifying subjects most likely to benefit during the phase II and focusing recruitment&#xD;
           efforts on them during phase III&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  stopping one arm or the whole trial at an early stage for success or lack of efficacy&#xD;
           based on phase II study results&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prospective, Randomized, open-label, three-arm, parallel, adaptive phase II/III controlled&#xD;
      study in which subjects will be randomly assigned in a 1:1:1 ratio as per the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Arm-1: hydroxychloroquine 800mg (400mg twice daily) given orally on day 1, (loading dose)&#xD;
      hydroxychloroquine. Then 400mg (200mg 2 tablets) on day 2,3, 4 and 5.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Arm-2: hydroxychloroquine 400mg (200mg twice daily) Given orally first day (loading dose),&#xD;
      then 200mg once daily on day 2,3, 4 and 5.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Arm-3: No Intervention- SARS-CoV-2 surveillance Standard control measures in the country of&#xD;
      interest such as self isolation, good personal hygiene and good nutrition.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Type of study and design&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prospective, Randomized, open-label, three-arm, parallel, controlled adaptive phase II/III&#xD;
      clinical trial in which subjects will be randomly assigned in a 1:1:1 ratio as per the&#xD;
      following:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Arm 1 Arm 2 Arm 3 Day 1 HCQ 400 mg (twice daily) HCQ 200 mg (twice daily) Standard&#xD;
      measurements of the country until the end of the participation in the study Day 2 HCQ 400 mg&#xD;
      (once daily) HCQ 200 mg (once daily) Day 3 HCQ 400 mg (once daily) HCQ 200 mg (once daily)&#xD;
      Day 4 HCQ 400 mg (once daily) HCQ 200 mg (once daily) Day 5 HCQ 400 mg (once daily) HCQ 200&#xD;
      mg (once daily)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Amount needed: Plaquenil 200mg: 558 tables per protocol. 42 tablets are needed as preserved&#xD;
      supply: total 600 tables.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomisation Subjects who meet the eligibility criteria at the study locations will be&#xD;
      invited to take part in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be randomly assigned to the treatment arms. Index cases will be used for&#xD;
      the assignment of contacts. For example, number 1,4,7, 9. will be on arm 1, number 3, 5,&#xD;
      10.etc. will be in arm 2, number 2,6, 8, etc. will be in arm 3.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All close contacts of the same index case will be allocated to the same arm. This would allow&#xD;
      more valid results through prevention of potential further exposure to the virus mainly for&#xD;
      the control arms, who are expected to have higher incidence of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blinding This clinical trial is open-label. The study does not compare multiple medicinal&#xD;
      products; it also does not include the use of a placebo product, as it is a Proamtic clinical&#xD;
      trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study procedures and evaluations Baseline assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Inquiry about previous history of G6PD&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Check for contraindications&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Vital signs&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Physical examination&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  RT-PCR&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  IgM, IgG AB for SARS-Cov-2&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hematology&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Biochemistry&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Urinalysis&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Retinopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ECG&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Retinopathy screening&#xD;
&#xD;
      During follow-up visits subjects will assessed for:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Random glucose level&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Vital signs&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Assessment of study intervention adherence&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Assessment of adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ECG&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Retinopathy screening Study schedule&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sampling technique:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This adaptive phase II/III clinical trial will be conducted in two sites in Tunisia. The main&#xD;
      study is planned in 2 sites in Tunisia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As soon as a new subject in identified, he/she will be consented for reaching his contacts&#xD;
      according to Eligibility criteria. The research team within 48 hours of index case&#xD;
      identification will call his/her contacts who fulfil below criteria for participation in the&#xD;
      trial. All potential participants will be tested using RT-PCR and IgM and IgG antibodies to&#xD;
      rule out current or previous disease status. Results will be obtained on the same day and&#xD;
      before consenting for taking part in the study. Subjects positive for COVID-19 will be&#xD;
      referred to local authorities for treatment according to their protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will follow multistage sampling technique in involved countries. Samples will be&#xD;
      stratified by gender and then follow simple random sampling process.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before carrying out any procedure in this study, subjects will be provided &quot;subject&#xD;
      information and consent form&quot;. The study will be thoroughly explained and all questions will&#xD;
      be answered to the satisfaction of the subject. Subjects will be given enough time to think&#xD;
      about their participation through and inquire about any detail that may influence the&#xD;
      decision. Consent procedure will be carried out by the clinical investigator &amp; delegated&#xD;
      clinical staff. Neither the investigator nor the study staff will coerce or unduly influence&#xD;
      subjects to participate or to continue to participate against their will. Prior to the&#xD;
      subject's participation, the subject will personally sign &amp; date the consent form, along with&#xD;
      one witness at least &amp; the principal investigator (the principal investigator may delegate&#xD;
      the clinical investigator to sign the ICF whenever needed).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enrollment (Baseline) All potential participants will be tested using RT-PCR and IgM and IgG&#xD;
      antibodies to rule out current or previous disease status. Results will be obtained on the&#xD;
      same day and before consenting for taking part in the study. Subjects positive for COVID-19&#xD;
      will be referred to local authorities for treatment according to their protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Only subjects eligible for this study will be enrolled. Refer to section 5 for eligibility&#xD;
      criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Informed consent, , demographics, vital signs, Medical History and contraindications,&#xD;
      physical examination,hematology, KFT, LFT, urinalysis,IgM and IgG antibodies for SARS-CoV-2,&#xD;
      RT-PCR, Pregnancy test, ECG, Retinopathy screening, Blood Glucose, dosing, Adverse event&#xD;
      review&#xD;
&#xD;
      During screening and follow-up visits, subjects will be examined and vital signs will be&#xD;
      taken with relevant medical history taken to determine the lack of contraindication of the&#xD;
      use the IMP and the achievement of the inclusion criteria Laboratory evaluations Laboratory&#xD;
      evaluations will be conducted as per Table 6.1 of visits and procedures elaborated on table&#xD;
      6.1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety considerations Methods and timing for assessing, recording, and analysing safety&#xD;
      parameters Adverse events The study period during which adverse events must be reported is&#xD;
      normally defined as the period from the initiation of any study procedures to the end of the&#xD;
      study treatment follow-up. At each contact with the subject, the Clinical Investigator will&#xD;
      seek information on adverse events by specific questioning and, as appropriate, by&#xD;
      examination. Information on all adverse events will be recorded immediately in the source&#xD;
      document, and also in the appropriate adverse event module of the case report form (CRF).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All adverse events occurring during the study period will be recorded. The clinical course of&#xD;
      each event will be followed until resolution, stabilization, or until it has been determined&#xD;
      that the study treatment or participation is not the cause. Serious adverse events that are&#xD;
      still ongoing at the end of the study period will be followed up to determine the final&#xD;
      outcome. Any serious adverse event that occurs after the study period and is considered to be&#xD;
      possibly related to the study treatment or study participation should be recorded and&#xD;
      reported immediately.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The AE report will include the intensity, severity, duration of the event. It will also&#xD;
      explain how the case was managed. At the end of the study, all records and follow up forms of&#xD;
      AEs/ADRs/SAEs/SADRs will be enlisted in the final report.&#xD;
&#xD;
      4 Discontinuation criteria 4.1 Participant's premature termination&#xD;
&#xD;
      The reason for participant's premature termination will be documented on the appropriate page&#xD;
      of the CRF and specified which of the following possible reasons were responsible for the&#xD;
      study premature termination:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Serious Adverse Event / SUSAR&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant's consent withdrawal&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Inappropriate enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Development of exclusion criterion&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Protocol deviation: as described below:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Such as not taking study treatment on time or the prescribed dose more than one time.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Decline PCR test at baseline or during the follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Decline ECG or ophthalmoscopy exams.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Migrated/moved from the study area&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Lost to follow-up. A 'lost to follow-up' is any participant who completed all protocol&#xD;
           specific procedures up to the administration of the investigational product or&#xD;
           intervention, but was then lost during the study period to any further follow-up, with&#xD;
           no safety information and no efficacy endpoint data ever became available.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is vital to collect safety data on any participant discontinued because of an AE or SAE.&#xD;
      In any case, every effort must be made to undertake protocol-specified safety follow-up&#xD;
      procedures. If voluntary withdrawal occurs, the participant should be asked to continue&#xD;
      scheduled evaluations, complete an end-of-study evaluation, and be given appropriate care&#xD;
      under medical supervision until the symptoms of any AE resolve or the participant's condition&#xD;
      becomes stable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      5 Statistical considerations Following an adaptive seamless phase II/III design assuming 60%&#xD;
      efficacy (an odds ratio of about 0.3) of hydroxychloroquine in reducing COVID-19 infections&#xD;
      for primary contacts, and reported secondary attack rate of 35% (incidence amongst close&#xD;
      contacts), Liu Y., et.al. 90% power, a confidence level of 95% and 10% loss to follow-up, 31&#xD;
      COVID-19 contacts are needed in each arm for phase II totaling 93 contacts for the three&#xD;
      arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoints of this study are observed COVID-19 infection and observed ADRs.&#xD;
      Descriptive statistics including means, frequencies and proportions will be used to summarize&#xD;
      collected contacts data. Incidence of the primary endpoints will be reported as well. All&#xD;
      summaries will be provided for the three study arms. Chi-squared test will be used to compare&#xD;
      incidence levels of the primary endpointsacross the three study arms. To examine for&#xD;
      associations among categorical contacts attributes, Chi-squared and Fishers exact tests&#xD;
      whenever appropriate will be used.When needed, ANOVA will be used to test for significant&#xD;
      differences among numerical attributes.Logistic Regression techniques with stepwise selection&#xD;
      method will be used to identify significant predictors of the primary endpoints Intention to&#xD;
      treat analysis will be followed in this clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data handling and record keeping Source documents and access to source data The Principal&#xD;
      Investigators will maintain appropriate medical and research records for this study in&#xD;
      compliance with the principles of good clinical practice and regulatory and institutional&#xD;
      requirements for the protection of confidentiality of participants. The study team members&#xD;
      will have access to records.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Authorised representatives of the sponsor, the ethics committee(s) or regulatory bodies may&#xD;
      inspect all documents and records required to be maintained by the investigator for the&#xD;
      purposes of quality assurance reviews, audits, inspections, and evaluation of the study&#xD;
      safety and progress. This will include, but not limited to, medical records (office, clinic,&#xD;
      or hospital) for the participants in this study. The clinical study site will permit access&#xD;
      to such records.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Missing data will be reported as missing indicating the reasons where applicable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Protocol deviations A protocol deviation is any noncompliance with the clinical trial&#xD;
      protocol, good clinical practice (GCP), or other protocol-specific requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If a deviation from, or a change of, the protocol is implemented to eliminate an immediate&#xD;
      hazard(s) to trial participant without prior ethics approval, the PI or designee will submit&#xD;
      the implemented deviation or change, the reasons for it, and, if appropriate, the proposed&#xD;
      protocol amendment(s) as soon as possible to the relevant ethics committee(s) for review and&#xD;
      approval and to the sponsor for agreement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The PI or designee will document and explain any deviation from the approved protocol on the&#xD;
      CRF, where appropriate, and record and explain any deviation in a file note or deviation form&#xD;
      that will be maintained as an essential document.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Deviations from the protocol, GCP or trial specific requirements that might have an impact on&#xD;
      the conduct of the trial or the safety of participants will be reported within 5 working days&#xD;
      to the sponsor and relevant EC, as appropriate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethical considerations The investigator will ensure that this study is conducted in full&#xD;
      conformity with the principles set forth in the ICH Harmonised Tripartite Guideline for Good&#xD;
      Clinical Practice and the Declaration of Helsinki in its current version, whichever affords&#xD;
      the greater protection to the participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rationale for participants election Study population will be males and females aged 18-65&#xD;
      years (non-pregnant and non-lactating) with primary exposure to COVID-19 patients. The study&#xD;
      is proposed to be conducted in Tunisia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Financing and insurance All subjects will be covered by insurance throughout the study and in&#xD;
      case of an injury to health caused by the trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 27, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective, Randomized, open-label, three-arm, parallel, adaptive phase II/III controlled study in which subjects will be randomly assigned in a 1:1:1 ratio as per the following:&#xD;
Arm-1: hydroxychloroquine 800mg (400mg twice daily) given orally on day 1, (loading dose) hydroxychloroquine. Then 400mg (200mg 2 tablets) on day 2,3, 4 and 5.&#xD;
Arm-2: hydroxychloroquine 400mg (200mg twice daily) Given orally first day (loading dose), then 200mg once daily on day 2,3, 4 and 5.&#xD;
Arm-3: No Intervention- SARS-CoV-2 surveillance Standard control measures in the country of interest such as self isolation, good personal hygiene and good nutrition.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence rate of COVID-19 on day 14 according to positive results of RT-PCR rate at day 14</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Study will seek to find direct correlation between the administration of Hydroxychloroquine and incidence of COVID-19: A reduced positive RT-PCR samples in subjects who were exposed to COVID-19patients. Positive RT-PCR samples in close contacts on day 14 of randomization.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and adverse events (AEs) incidence rate at day 14</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Safety and adverse events (AEs) incidence rate at day 14</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>IgM antibodies positive rate for COVID-19 at day 28</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Positive IgM antibodies</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence rate of COVID-19 on day 28 according to positive results of RT-PCR rate at day 28</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Positive at 28 days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and adverse events (AEs) incidence rate on day 28</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Safety and adverse events (AEs) incidence rate on day 28</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">93</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1 hydroxychloroquine 800mg day 1 and hydroxychloroquine 400mg day 2-5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>hydroxychloroquine 800mg (400mg twice daily) given orally on day 1, (loading dose) hydroxychloroquine. Then 400mg (200mg 2 tablets) on day 2,3, 4 and 5.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 2 hydroxychloroquine 400mg day 1 and hydroxychloroquine 200mg day 2-5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>hydroxychloroquine 400mg (200mg twice daily) Given orally first day (loading dose), then 200mg once daily on day 2,3, 4 and 5.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>No Intervention- SARS-CoV-2 surveillance Standard control measures in the country of interest such as self isolation, good personal hygiene and good nutrition.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>hydroxychloroquine</intervention_name>
    <description>hydroxychloroquine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1 hydroxychloroquine 800mg day 1 and hydroxychloroquine 400mg day 2-5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 2 hydroxychloroquine 400mg day 1 and hydroxychloroquine 200mg day 2-5</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>plaquenil</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary contacts, described below, aged 18 to 65 years and having provide Written&#xD;
             informed consent by the patient, by the patient's legal /authorized representative as&#xD;
             applicable.&#xD;
&#xD;
        According to below criteria, as soon as a new subject in identified, he/she will be&#xD;
        consented for reaching his contacts according to below criteria. The research team within&#xD;
        48 hours of index case identification will call his/her contacts who fulfill below criteria&#xD;
        for participation in the trial. All potential participants will be tested using RT-PCR and&#xD;
        IgM and IgG antibodies to rule out current or previous disease status.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Contact is a person free from COVID-19 who experienced any one of the following exposures&#xD;
        during the 2 days before and the 14 days after the onset of symptoms of a probable or&#xD;
        confirmed case:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A person living in the same household as a COVID-19 case&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A person having had direct physical contact with a COVID-19 case (e.g. shaking hands)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A person having unprotected direct contact with infectious secretions of a COVID-19&#xD;
             case (e.g. being coughed on, touching used paper tissues with a bare hand)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A person having had face-to-face contact with a COVID-19 case within 2 meters [2] and&#xD;
             &gt; 15 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A person who was in a closed environment (e.g. classroom, meeting room, hospital&#xD;
             waiting room, etc.) with a COVID-19 case for 15 minutes or more and at a distance of&#xD;
             less than 2 meters&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A healthcare worker (HCW) or other person providing direct care for a COVID-19 case,&#xD;
             or laboratory workers handling specimens from a COVID-19 case without recommended&#xD;
             personal protective equipment or with a possible breach of personal protective&#xD;
             equipment use policies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A contact in an aircraft sitting within two seats (in any direction) of the COVID-19&#xD;
             case, travel companions or persons providing care, and crew members serving in the&#xD;
             section of the aircraft where the index case was seated (if severity of symptoms or&#xD;
             movement of the case indicate more extensive exposure, passengers seated in the entire&#xD;
             section or all passengers on the aircraft may be considered close contacts)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant (at the time of screening) or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  known hypersensitivity or allergy to hydroxychloroquine or other aminoquinoline&#xD;
             compounds&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe skin reactions such as Stevens-Johnson syndrome and toxic epidermal&#xD;
             necrolysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of pre-existing retinopathy or maculopathy,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  concomitant use of tamoxifen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of congenital or acquired long QT-interval, current use of drugs that prolong&#xD;
             the QT interval,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  family history of long QT arrythmia, cardiac disease such as heart failure, myocardial&#xD;
             infarction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  concurrent use of anti-arrhythmic drugs, or family history of sudden cardiac death, or&#xD;
             sudden cardiac death, bradycardia &lt; 50 beats/min, uncorrected hypokalemia or&#xD;
             hypomagnesemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe renal disease or patients receiving dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients less than 35 kg bodyweight&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently taking Hydroxychloroquine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suspected or confirmed current COVID-19, defined as: (1) temperature &gt; 38 Celsius; (2)&#xD;
             cough; (3) shortness of breath; (4) sore throat; or, if available (not required), (5)&#xD;
             positive confirmatory testing for COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to take medications orally&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to provide written consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With significantly abnormal liver function&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with psoriasis, myasthenia, hematopoietic and retinal diseases,&#xD;
             CNS-related hearing loss;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RT-PCR positive for SARS-CoV-2, IgM and IgG antibodies for SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently using another treatment regimen or medication that is being investigated for&#xD;
             efficacy in the management of COVID-19.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Munir Abu-Helalah, PHD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Regional Center for Disease Control</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Wissem Hachfi, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Farhat Hached Hospital, Tunisia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Munir A Abu-Helalah, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>00962795912413</phone>
    <phone_ext>0</phone_ext>
    <email>mabuhelalah@yahoo.co.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Amer A Amous, MD</last_name>
    <phone>00962797950001</phone>
    <phone_ext>0</phone_ext>
    <email>amer.amous@rcdcp.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 21, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 21, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Regional Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Jordan</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr Munir Abu-Helalah</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Chief Executive Officer</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>Chemoprevention</keyword>
  <keyword>Primary contact</keyword>
  <keyword>Hydroxychloroquine</keyword>
  <keyword>prophylaxis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hydroxychloroquine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Through publications in Peer Review Journal</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

