<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4933">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04475718</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R43MD014923</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R43MD014923</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04475718</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Fourth Trimester - A Web-based Tool for Postpartum Care to Address the Needs of Underserved Women</brief_title>
  <official_title>Fourth Trimester - A Web-based Tool for Postpartum Care to Address the Needs of Underserved Women</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>HealthCore-NERI</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Orange Square Design, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute on Minority Health and Health Disparities (NIMHD)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>HealthCore-NERI</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The postpartum period is a critical time for both maternal and child health, and more than&#xD;
      half of all maternal deaths occur postpartum, from one day to one year after birth. This poor&#xD;
      outcome is linked to the racial and ethnic disparities that disproportionately effects low&#xD;
      income and black women. To reduce the burden of the postpartum period for this population,&#xD;
      the goal of this project is to develop an accessible, targeted online tool designed to&#xD;
      address the needs of underserved women who are at greater risk for adverse postpartum&#xD;
      outcomes by providing the appropriate tools, knowledge and skills to improve postpartum&#xD;
      health.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In the United States, the postpartum period is a critical time for both maternal and child&#xD;
      health, the mortality rate is the highest among other developed, high income countries and&#xD;
      more than half of all maternal deaths occur postpartum, from one day to one year after birth.&#xD;
      This poor outcome is linked to the racial and ethnic disparities that disproportionately&#xD;
      effect black women who are 3-4 times more likely to experience maternal mortality than white&#xD;
      women. Recently, the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists recognized the&#xD;
      deficiencies in postpartum care and coined the term the 'fourth trimester' to mark the time&#xD;
      following the birth of the infant through the first 3-months postpartum, and updated its&#xD;
      recommendations to address these challenges. With impacts to health outcomes and healthcare&#xD;
      costs, there is a need to holistically bridge the gap for low-income and/or ethnically&#xD;
      diverse groups of women to address the physical, cultural, and knowledge barriers to&#xD;
      accessing quality postpartum care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To improve the rate at which underserved women are disproportionately affected by maternal&#xD;
      mortality and morbidity, the investigators need to engage women leading into and specifically&#xD;
      during the postpartum period to identity areas of need, and to provide tools which reduce&#xD;
      barriers for women to get appropriate postpartum care. Technology offers innovative solutions&#xD;
      to challenges around equal information access. Pregnant women often turn to the internet to&#xD;
      find out more information about their health and their developing babies health. Yet, studies&#xD;
      find that mothers are not finding sufficient resources to match their postpartum needs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To address this gap in care, this project aims to develop a mobile tool designed to increase&#xD;
      accessibility to information and practical approaches for addressing the complex needs of&#xD;
      women in this 'fourth trimester'. This tool will specifically focus on underserved women who&#xD;
      are at greatest risk of adverse postpartum outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 6, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 22, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 22, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Interviews will be conducted with 30 pregnant and postpartum women. From this research and other activities, the investigators will build a prototype program. Once the prototype is completed, the investigators will conduct a pre-test with 85 participants. The pre-test will capture key outcome measures (resilience, stress, anxiety, depression, fear, knowledge, and variables related to COVID-19) and other descriptive variables. All participants who complete the pre-test will be given access to the prototype mobile postpartum tool. Participants will be asked to actively engage with the tool for 4 weeks, during which time they will be able to provide real-time user experience feedback. At the end of the 4-week period, the investigators will conduct a post-test to measure change in outcomes. The investigators will also conduct follow up interviews with the original 30 participants.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline Resilience at 4 Weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale, a 25-item scale covering 17 domains related to resiliency, used with a variety of populations, across a wide range of languages, racial/ethnic, and cultural groups. It has strong psychometric properties and validated short forms. Scoring of the scale is based on summing the total of all items, each of which is scored from 0-4. For the CD-RISC-25, the full range is from 0 to 100, with higher scores reflecting greater resilience.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline Depressive Symptoms at 4 Weeks Using the Edinburgh Postnatal Depression Scale (EPDS)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The Edinburgh Postnatal Depression Scale (EPDS) will be used to assess depressive symptoms. The 10-question Edinburgh Postnatal Depression Scale (EPDS) is a valuable and efficient way of identifying patients at risk for perinatal depression. Scores range from 0-30. Higher scores indicate more depressive symptoms. Mothers who score above 13 are likely to be suffering from a depressive illness of varying severity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline Depressive Symptoms at 4 Weeks Using the Center for Epi Studies of Depression (CES-D)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The Center for Epi Studies of Depression (CES-D) will be used to assess depressive symptoms. The CES-D has been used extensively in culturally diverse populations. The CES-D is a 20-item measure that asks caregivers to rate how often over the past week they experienced symptoms associated with depression, such as restless sleep, poor appetite, and feeling lonely. Scores range from 0 to 60, with high scores indicating greater depressive symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline Depressive Symptoms at 4 Weeks Using the Patient Health Question (PHQ-9)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The Patient Health Question (PHQ-9) will be used to identify major depression. Scores range from 1-27, with higher scores indicating greater severity of depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline Parent Anxiety at 4 Weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The State-Trait Anxiety Inventory (STAI) is a measure of trait and state anxiety with 20 items for assessing trait anxiety and 20 for state anxiety. It has been validated for use with pregnant women. All items are rated on a 4-point scale (e.g., from &quot;Almost Never&quot; to &quot;Almost Always&quot;). The range of possible scores for form Y of the STAI varies from a minimum score of 20 to a maximum score of 80 on both the STAI-T and STAI-S subscales. Higher scores indicate greater anxiety.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline Health Care Access and Utilization at 4 Weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System (BRFSS) Historical Questions will be used to address topics including health insurance coverage, continuity, cost barriers, health care visits, and satisfaction with care. Specific questions of interest relevant to this population will be selected by the investigators. Change in individual question responses will be assessed from baseline to 4 weeks.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from COVID-19 Specific Fear and Anxiety at 4 Weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Emerging scales on COVID-19 include The Fear of COVID-19 Scale and the Coronavirus Anxiety Scale. Where no validated scales exist, questions will be developed specific to the COVID-19 crisis for this population. Existing scales will be used to inform the development of a study-specific instrument to assess COVID-19 specific fear and anxiety in postpartum women. Specific questions of interest relevant to this population will be selected by the investigators. Change in individual question responses will be assessed from baseline to 4 weeks.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">85</enrollment>
  <condition>Pregnancy Related</condition>
  <condition>Postpartum Sadness</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Fourth Trimester Mobile Tool</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Fourth Trimester Mobile Tool</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fourth Trimester Mobile Tool</intervention_name>
    <description>A mobile web-based tool for underserved women in the fourth trimester. The mobile platform teaches self-efficacy, care management, and coping skills to help reduce major health risks and provide tools and resources to maintain mental health.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Fourth Trimester Mobile Tool</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 21+;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-reported annual household income less than $39,500 (at least 75% of participants&#xD;
             - defined as &quot;low income&quot; household by the PEW Research Center);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Racial/ethnic minority (at least 75% of participants must be non-white, with at least&#xD;
             50% identifying as Black/African American);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be a new or expectant mother - participants must be at least 28 weeks/6 months&#xD;
             pregnant (3rd trimester), and up to 6 months post-birth (no more than 10% of&#xD;
             participants will be currently pregnant, at least 90% will be postpartum).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to comply with the terms of the study (available time commitment, have internet&#xD;
             access; willing to comply with the specified focus groups and survey); and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to read, write and speak English (all research and product development activities&#xD;
             will be conducted in English due to budgetary constraints).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to comply with the Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Did not have a live birth (for those who are post-birth)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-reported major medical/health issue which would impact participants' health or&#xD;
             ability to participate.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kristine Merz</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Orange Square Design, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lisa Marceau, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>HealthCore-NERI</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lisa Marceau, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>617-972-3011</phone>
    <email>lmarceau@healthcore.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Julia Coleman</last_name>
    <phone>617-972-3299</phone>
    <email>jcoleman@healthcore.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>HealthCore</name>
      <address>
        <city>Watertown</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02472</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lisa Marceau, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>617-972-3011</phone>
      <email>lmarceau@healthcore.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Julia Coleman</last_name>
      <phone>617-972-3299</phone>
      <email>jcoleman@healthcore.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lisa Marceau, MPH</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Orange Square Design Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pawtucket</city>
        <state>Rhode Island</state>
        <zip>02860</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kristine Merz</last_name>
      <phone>401-305-6611</phone>
      <email>kristine@orangesquare.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Juli Leonard</last_name>
      <phone>401-305-6611</phone>
      <email>jleonard@orangesquare.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kristine Merz</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 14, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>HealthCore-NERI</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lisa Marceau</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Staff Vice President, Digital Research Solutions</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Postpartum health</keyword>
  <keyword>Fourth trimester</keyword>
  <keyword>Resiliency</keyword>
  <keyword>Health disparities</keyword>
  <keyword>Maternal health</keyword>
  <keyword>Mobile tools</keyword>
  <keyword>Human-centered design</keyword>
  <keyword>Digital health</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

