<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1900">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04678830</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CD15_COVID-19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04678830</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19 Long-Haulers Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2, Randomized, Double Blind, Placebo Controlled Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Leronlimab in Patients Experiencing Prolonged Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Symptoms [Long-Haulers]</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>CytoDyn, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Amarex Clinical Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>CytoDyn, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to assess the safety and efficacy of leronlimab (PRO 140)&#xD;
      administered as weekly subcutaneous injection in subjects experiencing prolonged symptoms (&gt;&#xD;
      6 weeks) of COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 2, two-arm, randomized, double blind, placebo controlled multicenter study to&#xD;
      evaluate the safety and efficacy of leronlimab (PRO 140) in patients with prolonged symptoms&#xD;
      caused by COVID-19. Patients will be randomized to receive weekly doses of 700 mg leronlimab&#xD;
      (PRO 140), or placebo. Leronlimab (PRO 140) and placebo will be administered via subcutaneous&#xD;
      injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will have three phases: Screening Period, Treatment Period, and Follow-Up Period.&#xD;
      Total study duration is 91 weeks. The study will be conducted at up to 10 centers in the&#xD;
      United States and planned number of subjects are 102 subjects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 21, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 23, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 23, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Fatigue Severity Score at Day 28</measure>
    <time_frame>Day28</time_frame>
    <description>This score is based on a 9-item scale which measures the severity of fatigue and its effects on a person's activities and lifestyle. Scores range from 9 - 63; Higher the score = greater fatigue severity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in daily COVID-19-related symptom severity score during the treatment phase (56 Days).</measure>
    <time_frame>56 days</time_frame>
    <description>Note: A set of common COVID-19-related symptoms (see patient diary template) will be evaluated daily by the patient regardless of which symptoms a subject had at baseline, as new symptoms may appear following the baseline assessment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of targeted COVID-19 associated symptoms from start of study treatment (Day 0) based on self-assessment using daily symptom diary.</measure>
    <time_frame>56 days</time_frame>
    <description>Duration defined as the last day on or before study Day 56 when any symptoms scored as&#xD;
moderate or severe at study entry (pre-treatment) are still scored as moderate or severe (i.e., not mild or absent), or&#xD;
mild or absent at study entry are scored as mild or worse (i.e., not absent).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression through Day 56 of one or more COVID-19-associated symptoms to a worse status than recorded in the study diary at study entry, prior to start of study treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>56 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Fatigue Severity Score at Days 42 and 56.</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 42 and 56</time_frame>
    <description>This score is based on a 9-item scale which measures the severity of fatigue and its effects on a person's activities and lifestyle. Scores range from 9 - 63; Higher the score = greater fatigue severity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Mental Fatigue Questionnaire score at Days 28, 42 and 56.</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 28, 42 and 56</time_frame>
    <description>Scores range from 0 - 36. Higher the score = greater fatigue severity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in pulse oxygen saturation (SpO2) at Day 7, 14, 21, 28, 35, 42, 49, and 56.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7, 14, 21, 28, 35, 42, 49, and 56.</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Heart Rate Variability at Days 28, 42 and 56 (sub-study at selected sites)</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 28, 42 and 56</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of hospitalization during the treatment phase</measure>
    <time_frame>56 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration (days) of hospitalization during the treatment phase</measure>
    <time_frame>56 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Transgrowth factor beta 1 (TGF beta1) on Days 14, 28, 42, and 56</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 14, 28, 42, and 56</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in CRP on Days 14, 28, 42, and 56</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 14, 28, 42, and 56</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">102</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronavirus Disease 2019</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>700mg Leronlimab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebos</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebos</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Leronlimab (700mg)</intervention_name>
    <description>Leronlimab (PRO) 140 is a humanized IgG4, monoclonal antibody (mAb) to the C-C chemokine receptor type 5 (CCR5)</description>
    <arm_group_label>700mg Leronlimab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female adult ≥ 18 years of age at time of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient with prior confirmed COVID-19 diagnosis by standard RT-PCR assay or equivalent&#xD;
             testing and currently experiencing two or more of the following symptoms consistent&#xD;
             with COVID-19 infection for a prolonged period of time (&gt;6 weeks).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Respiratory symptoms such as cough, sore throat, stuffy or runny nose, shortness&#xD;
                  of breath (difficulty breathing), tightness of chest etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Neurological symptoms such as difficulty in concentration (brain fog), sleep&#xD;
                  disturbance/insomnia, headache, dizziness, anxiety, tingling or numbness, loss of&#xD;
                  sense of smell or taste etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cardiovascular and Gastrointestinal symptoms such as feeling of fast heartbeat,&#xD;
                  nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  General immune response symptoms such as fatigue (low energy or tiredness),&#xD;
                  muscle cramps, joint pain, chills or shivering, feeling hot or feverish or other&#xD;
                  flu-like symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Clinical Symptom Score of ≥6 with at least two symptoms of moderate or higher severity&#xD;
             at the time of Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Chalder Fatigue Scale bimodal score ≥ 4 at the time of Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Electrocardiogram (ECG) with no clinically significant findings as assessed by the&#xD;
             Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Note: Below are the examples of clinically significant and non-clinically significant&#xD;
             ECG abnormalities:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ECG findings indicative of acute myocardial infarction or acute ischemic changes&#xD;
                  would be considered clinically significant abnormalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ECG finding such as atrial fibrillation, atrial flutter, paced rhythms in&#xD;
                  individuals who have undergone permanent pacemaker placement, evidence of prior&#xD;
                  infarction, unchanged stable conduction abnormalities e.g. right bundle branch&#xD;
                  block, or any other finding which does not significantly impact mortality would&#xD;
                  be considered non-clinically significant findings and subjects with these&#xD;
                  abnormal findings would be allowed to enroll in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject (or legally authorized representative) provides written informed consent prior&#xD;
             to initiation of any study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Understands and agrees to comply with planned study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Women of childbearing potential and their partner must agree to use at least one&#xD;
             highly effective method of contraception (e.g., hormonal contraceptives [implants,&#xD;
             injectables, combination oral contraceptives, transdermal patches, or contraceptive&#xD;
             rings], intrauterine devices, bilateral tubal occlusion, or sexual abstinence) for the&#xD;
             duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects showing signs of severe pneumonia, acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS)&#xD;
             or respiratory failure necessitating mechanical ventilation during the course of their&#xD;
             COVID-19 illness;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of moderate or severe chronic respiratory disease (such as COPD or asthma) and&#xD;
             requirement for long-term oxygen therapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient with pulse oxygen saturation (SpO2) of &lt;94% on room air at the time of&#xD;
             screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of pulmonary embolus or deep venous thrombosis within the past year&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of splenectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of chronic liver disease or patient showing signs of clinical jaundice at the&#xD;
             time of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of severe chronic kidney disease or requiring dialysis at the time of&#xD;
             screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patient with NYHA Class III or IV congestive heart failure (CHF)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patient with uncontrolled rheumatologic disorders at the time of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients with a history of organ transplantation or are candidates for organ&#xD;
             transplantation at the time of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients with underlying chronic viral or bacterium illnesses including hepatitis of&#xD;
             any kind, HIV, Epstein-Barr virus (EBV), chronic Lyme disease&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. No history of Chronic Fatigue Syndrome prior to COVID-19 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. No history of fibromyalgia prior to COVID-19 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patients with malignant tumor, or other serious systemic diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Treatment with any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Hydroxychloroquine, oral or parenteral corticosteroids, immunosuppressants, or&#xD;
                  immunomodulating agents within 7 days prior to the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Albuterol as nebulizer for the off-label treatment of COVID-19 within 7 days&#xD;
                  prior to the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Subjects who have a history of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar&#xD;
             chemical or biologic composition to leronlimab (PRO 140) are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Inability to provide informed consent or to comply with test requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Consideration by the investigator, for safety reasons, that the subject is an&#xD;
             unsuitable candidate to receive study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Pregnancy or breast feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Subject participating in another study with for an investigational treatment for&#xD;
             COVID-19&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>kush Dhody, MBBS, MS, CCRA</last_name>
    <phone>301-956-2536</phone>
    <email>kushd@amarexcro.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

