<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4261">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04402970</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2022206</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04402970</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dornase Alfa for ARDS in Patients With SARS-CoV-2</brief_title>
  <acronym>DORNASESARS2</acronym>
  <official_title>Inhaled Dornase Alfa for Treatment of ARDS in Patients With SARS-CoV-2</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Missouri-Columbia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Missouri-Columbia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is designed to evaluate a potential mechanism by which a hyperactive immune&#xD;
      response may contribute to death from SARS-CoV-2; by an excessive neutrophil-mediated&#xD;
      deposition of cell-free DNA in neutrophil extracellular traps (NET). Excessive amounts of&#xD;
      NETs can increase rigidity of mucus, clog airways, and be agents for the development of acute&#xD;
      respiratory distress (Narasaraju et al., Am J Pathol. 2011). Many aspects of this pathway&#xD;
      have been observed in severe SARS-CoV-2 (Zhang et al., Respiratory research. 2020). Dornase&#xD;
      alfa (DNAse I; Pulmozyme (Genentech) is a nebulized drug that works by degrading cell-free&#xD;
      DNA and thus promoting airway clearance and recovery. The investigators hypothesize that by&#xD;
      thinning mucus and degrading these NETs further lung damage may be prevented and a reduction&#xD;
      in time to recovery may occur. The two aims of the study are to see if inhaled/nebulized&#xD;
      dornase alfa will improve clinical outcome measures in SARS-CoV-2 related acute respiratory&#xD;
      distress syndrome (ARDS) and to see if dornase alfa reduces the amount of bronchoalveolar&#xD;
      lavage and blood markers of NET activity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will recruit patients who are on mechanical ventilation for respiratory failure&#xD;
      related to SARS-CoV-2 positive infection and have ARDS based upon Berlin criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators aim to recruit 20 patients for this study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Severe cases of SARS-CoV-2 infection have shown an inflammatory neutrophil and mucus-mediated&#xD;
      airway exclusion pathway similar to previously described acute respiratory distress syndrome&#xD;
      (ARDS) in other viral syndromes (Narasaraju et al., Am J Pathol. 2011). Lung neutrophilia in&#xD;
      ARDS is related to significant neutrophil extracellular trap (NET) production and formation.&#xD;
      Thus, NET production is likely contributing to the severe lung pathology in SARS-CoV-2 (Yu&#xD;
      Zuo et al. JCI Insight. 2020). Recent connections have been made between NET formation in&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 patients and excessive thrombosis and the development of cytokine storm further&#xD;
      warranting evaluation as a potential site for consideration of treatment (Barnes, Betsy et&#xD;
      al. J exp Med. 2020). Dornase alfa (Pulmozyme) is a recombinant human deoxyribonuclease I,&#xD;
      that acts as a mucolytic by cleaving extracellular chromosomal DNA from NETs and other&#xD;
      cell-free DNA. Unknown are the effects of dornase alfa therapy on SARS-CoV-2 related ARDS and&#xD;
      if therapy with dornase alfa truly reduces the amount of NETs in the severely damaged lungs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is a non-randomized, single-center, open-label clinical trial to evaluate the&#xD;
      potential benefit and cellular mechanism of nebulized dornase alfa administration in&#xD;
      mechanically ventilated patients with SARS-CoV-2 related ARDS. Evaluation of dornase alfa&#xD;
      effects at a cellular level will be measured by analysis of blood samples before and after&#xD;
      the 3 days of therapy for cell-free DNA, quantification of citrullinated histone H3,&#xD;
      quantification of MPO-DNA complexes and analysis of bronchoalveolar lavage samples for&#xD;
      quantification of NETs and cell count and differential.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 19, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Nebulized dornase alfa will be administered through the ventilator circuit at a dose of 2.5 mg, 12 hours apart, for 3 consecutive days. Patients will also receive lung protective ventilation (VC 6-8 ml/kg predicted body weight), plateau pressure &lt; 30 cmH2O, targeted driving pressure &lt; 15, neuromuscular blockade if indicated, and prone positioning based upon PaO2/FiO2 ratio &lt; 150 or upon treating physician decision; along with all other ICU care based upon best practice standards and evidence based medicine.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Improvement in PaO2/FiO2</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Daily evaluation of PaO2/FiO2 ratio on the day prior to starting therapy and then repeat daily for 14 days after starting therapy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in static lung compliance</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Daily evaluation of static lung compliance, measured by change in driving pressure over volume delivered, on the day prior to starting therapy and then repeated daily for 14 days after the first dose of therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of mechanical ventilation</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until extubation or date of death from any cause, whichever came first, assessed up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days on mechanical ventilation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of ICU stay</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until discharge/transfer out of the ICU or date of death from any cause, whichever came first, assessed up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days in the medical intensive care unti</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of hospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until discharge from acute care hospital or date of death from any cause, whichever came first, assessed up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days as an inpatient at the University of Missouri</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary bacterial infections</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until first positive culture or clinical diagnosis of infection if occurs, assessed up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Determination of secondary bacterial infections based upon positive culture results and clinical diagnosis by treating physician.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>Evaluation at 30 and 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>All cause mortality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">10</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV 2</condition>
  <condition>ARDS</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Inhaled/nebulized dornase alfa</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patient to receive inhaled/nebulized dornase alfa (Pulmozyme) 2.5 mg twice daily in the ventilator circuit for 3 days, along with standard of care for ARDS.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard of care provided for ARDS.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dornase Alfa Inhalation Solution</intervention_name>
    <description>Nebulized dornase alfa</description>
    <arm_group_label>Inhaled/nebulized dornase alfa</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Pulmozyme</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hospitalized and mechanically ventilated for illness related to SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed positive SARS-CoV-2 infection by PCR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  individual or surrogate ability to sign informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  negative, urine-based pregnancy test in females&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  contraindication or intolerance to dornase alfa&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mechanical ventilation expected to be less than 48 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  life expectancy less than 24 hours based upon judgement of treating physician&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  inability to obtain informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Zachary M Holliday, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Missouri-Columbia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adam Schrum, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University of Missouri-Columbia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Missouri Hospital and Clinics</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbia</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>65212</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Barnes BJ, Adrover JM, Baxter-Stoltzfus A, Borczuk A, Cools-Lartigue J, Crawford JM, Daßler-Plenker J, Guerci P, Huynh C, Knight JS, Loda M, Looney MR, McAllister F, Rayes R, Renaud S, Rousseau S, Salvatore S, Schwartz RE, Spicer JD, Yost CC, Weber A, Zuo Y, Egeblad M. Targeting potential drivers of COVID-19: Neutrophil extracellular traps. J Exp Med. 2020 Jun 1;217(6). pii: e20200652. doi: 10.1084/jem.20200652.</citation>
    <PMID>32302401</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Narasaraju T, Yang E, Samy RP, Ng HH, Poh WP, Liew AA, Phoon MC, van Rooijen N, Chow VT. Excessive neutrophils and neutrophil extracellular traps contribute to acute lung injury of influenza pneumonitis. Am J Pathol. 2011 Jul;179(1):199-210. doi: 10.1016/j.ajpath.2011.03.013. Epub 2011 May 7.</citation>
    <PMID>21703402</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhang G, Zhang J, Wang B, Zhu X, Wang Q, Qiu S. Analysis of clinical characteristics and laboratory findings of 95 cases of 2019 novel coronavirus pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a retrospective analysis. Respir Res. 2020 Mar 26;21(1):74. doi: 10.1186/s12931-020-01338-8.</citation>
    <PMID>32216803</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Earhart AP, Holliday ZM, Hofmann HV, Schrum AG. Consideration of dornase alfa for the treatment of severe COVID-19 acute respiratory distress syndrome. New Microbes New Infect. 2020 Apr 30;35:100689. doi: 10.1016/j.nmni.2020.100689. eCollection 2020 May.</citation>
    <PMID>32355564</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zuo Y, Yalavarthi S, Shi H, Gockman K, Zuo M, Madison JA, Blair C, Weber A, Barnes BJ, Egeblad M, Woods RJ, Kanthi Y, Knight JS. Neutrophil extracellular traps in COVID-19. JCI Insight. 2020 Jun 4;5(11). pii: 138999. doi: 10.1172/jci.insight.138999.</citation>
    <PMID>32329756</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 22, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Missouri-Columbia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Zach Holliday</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor of Clinical Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

