<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4018">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04333368</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>APHP200395</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-001287-28</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04333368</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cell Therapy Using Umbilical Cord-derived Mesenchymal Stromal Cells in SARS-CoV-2-related ARDS</brief_title>
  <acronym>STROMA-CoV2</acronym>
  <official_title>Cell Therapy Using Umbilical Cord-derived Mesenchymal Stromal Cells in SARS-CoV-2-related ARDS</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Whereas the pandemic due do Covid-19 continues to spread, the severe acute respiratory&#xD;
      syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) causes Severe Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome in 30%&#xD;
      of patients with a 30%-60% mortality rate for those requiring hospitalization in an intensive&#xD;
      care unit. The main physio-pathological hallmark is an acute pulmonary inflammation.&#xD;
      Currently, there is no treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mesenchymal stem cells (MSC) feature several attractive characteristics: ease of procurement,&#xD;
      high proliferation potential, capacity to home to inflammatory sites, anti-inflammatory,&#xD;
      anti-fibrotic and immunomodulatory properties. If all MSC share several characteristics&#xD;
      regardless of the tissue source, the highest productions of bioactive molecules and the&#xD;
      strongest immunomodulatory properties are yielded by those from the Wharton's jelly of the&#xD;
      umbilical cord. An additional advantage is that they can be scaled-up to generate banks of&#xD;
      cryofrozen and thus readily available products. These cells have already been tested in&#xD;
      several clinical trials with an excellent safety record.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this project is to treat intubated-ventilated patients presenting with a&#xD;
      SARS-CoV2-related Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome (ARDS) of less than 96 hours by three&#xD;
      intravenous infusions of umbilical cord Wharton's jelly-derived mesenchymal stromal cells&#xD;
      (UC-MSC) one every other day (duration of the treatment: one week). The primary endpoint is&#xD;
      the PaO2/FiO2 ratio at day 7. The evolution of several inflammatory markers, T regulatory&#xD;
      lymphocytes and donor-specific antibodies will also be monitored. The trial will include 40&#xD;
      patients, of whom 20 will be cell-treated while the remaining 20 patients will be injected&#xD;
      with a placebo solution in addition to the standard of care. Given the pathophysiology of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV2, it is thus sound to hypothesize that the intravenous administration of UC-MSC&#xD;
      during the initial phase of ARDS could control inflammation, accelerate its recovery with&#xD;
      improved oxygenation, reduced mechanical ventilation and ventilation weaning time and&#xD;
      therefore reduced length of stay in intensive care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The feasibility of the project is supported by the expertise of the Meary Cell and Gene&#xD;
      Therapy Center, which is approved for the production of Advanced Therapy Medicinal Products&#xD;
      and has already successfully prepared the first batches of cells, as well as by the&#xD;
      involvement of a cardiac surgery team which will leverage its experience with stem cells for&#xD;
      the treatment of heart failure to make it relevant to the Stroma-Cov-2 project.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      General context:&#xD;
&#xD;
      As of March 13, 2020, more than 145,000 cases of 2019-nCoV infection have been confirmed with&#xD;
      5,500 deaths worldwide. As of March 21, 14,469 cases have been confirmed in France, of which&#xD;
      562 have been fatal while 1,525 patients are currently hospitalized in intensive care units.&#xD;
      Whereas the pandemic continues to spread, the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2&#xD;
      (SARS-CoV-2) causes Severe Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome in 30% of patients (Murthy et&#xD;
      al., 2020) with a 30%-60% mortality rate. The main physio-pathological hallmark is an acute&#xD;
      pulmonary inflammation. Currently, there is no treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this project is to treat intubated-ventilated patients presenting with a&#xD;
      SARS-CoV2-related Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome (ARDS) of less than 96 hours by three&#xD;
      intravenous infusions of umbilical cord Wharton's jelly-derived mesenchymal stromal cells&#xD;
      (UC-MSC) one every other day (duration of the treatment: one week). The primary endpoint is&#xD;
      the PaO2/FiO2 variation from baseline at day 7. The evolution of several inflammatory&#xD;
      markers, T regulatory lymphocytes and donor-specific antibodies will also be monitored. The&#xD;
      trial will include 40 patients, of whom 20 will be randomized to cell-treatment administered&#xD;
      via intravenous route while the remaining 20 patients will be randomized to receive a placebo&#xD;
      solution in addition to the standard of care. Patients will be followed up to 12 months after&#xD;
      treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      State of the art:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mesenchymal stem cells feature several attractive characteristics: ease of procurement, high&#xD;
      proliferation potential, capacity to home to inflammatory sites, anti-inflammatory,&#xD;
      anti-fibrotic and immunomodulatory properties. Their therapeutic benefits have been&#xD;
      demonstrated in &gt; 100 animal models, including sheep. Specifically, the therapeutic effects&#xD;
      of MSC have been demonstrated in ARDS models induced by H1N1, H5N1, H9N2 influenza&#xD;
      virus-associated pneumoniae and were also shown to reduce bacterial-induced acute lung injury&#xD;
      in a human model of ex vivo perfused lung (Lee et al., 2013). In the clinics, MSC have&#xD;
      demonstrated an excellent tolerance in over 3,000 patients (Thompson et al., 2020),&#xD;
      regardless of the dosing and delivery route. Three phase I/II trials have included patients&#xD;
      with an ARDS and in one (START II), MSC significantly reduced pulmonary endothelial injury&#xD;
      (Matthay et al., 2019). If all MSC share several characteristics regardless of the tissue&#xD;
      source, the highest productions of bioactive molecules and the strongest immunomodulatory&#xD;
      properties are yielded by those from the Wharton's jelly of the umbilical cord (Romanov et&#xD;
      al., 2019) which can be scaled-up to generate banks of cryofrozen and thus readily available&#xD;
      products.&#xD;
&#xD;
      So far, UC-MSC have been used in a wide variety of diseases (reviewed in Scarfe et al., 2018)&#xD;
      and, in most cases, they have been delivered via the intravenous route which is clinically&#xD;
      attractive because of its non invasive nature and the subsequent possibility of repeated&#xD;
      administrations. Labeling techniques have shown that &gt;80% of intravenously injected MSCs are&#xD;
      rapidly trapped in the lungs, followed by a rapid distribution of some of the injected MSCs&#xD;
      to other tissues including liver, spleen, and inflammatory or injured sites (Brooks et al.,&#xD;
      2018). Over all, these biodistribution patterns have been confirmed by human studies using&#xD;
      magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), positron emission tomography (PET) and/or single-photon&#xD;
      emission computed tomography (SPECT).2 A four-parameter model (injection rate, clearance&#xD;
      rate, rate of extravasation and rate of intravasation) predicts that transplanted MSCs are&#xD;
      only therapeutically active for a short period of time (probably less than 24 h) (Parekkadan&#xD;
      and Milwid, 2010), a timescale consistent with that of the biological responses that they&#xD;
      trigger. These assumptions are an incentive to repeated MSC administrations within a short&#xD;
      period of time to induce a sustained therapeutic effect and has rationalized our protocol of&#xD;
      injecting MSC one every other day over a one week-period, a design consistent with the&#xD;
      earlier report of the benefits of delivering MSC at relatively small doses but in a repeated&#xD;
      fashion in patients with graft-versus-host disease (Zhou et al., 2010).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once they have homed in the lungs, MSC have been reported to first induce an inflammatory&#xD;
      response which is detectable at the tissue level and systemically (Hoogduijn et al., 2013)&#xD;
      and is likely due to their interaction with resident lung cells once they have accumulated in&#xD;
      the microvasculature. This initial response is then followed by a downstream phase of reduced&#xD;
      immune reactivity (Hoogduijn et al., 2013), the mechanisms of which have been extensively&#xD;
      investigated. Thus, 24 hours after their intravenous infusion, most of the UC-MSC that have&#xD;
      accumulated in the lungs are dead after their phagocytosis by monocytes and neutrophils which&#xD;
      then migrate through the blood stream, particularly in the liver (Leibacher et al., 2017; de&#xD;
      Witte et al., 2018). Co-culture experiments have shown that the internalization of MSC&#xD;
      fragments by monocytes triggers a phenotypic shift which translates into the upregulation of&#xD;
      PD-L1 and CD90 along with an increased expression of mRNA levels for IL-1β, IL-6, IL-8 and&#xD;
      IL-10 and a decreased expression of TNF-α. Of note, monocytes polarized towards an&#xD;
      immune-regulatory phenotype increase the expression of Foxp3+ T regulatory lymphocytes while&#xD;
      decreasing that of activated CD4+ cells (de Witte et al., 2018). That apoptosis of&#xD;
      intravenously infused MSC is a requirement for their immunosuppressive function is further&#xD;
      supported by the observation that the cytotoxic activity against MSC is predictive of&#xD;
      clinical responses in patients treated by MSC for graft-versus-host disease, i.e., the best&#xD;
      responders are those with high cytotoxicity; in this study, the postulated mechanistic link&#xD;
      is that phagocytes that have engulfed apoptotic MSC then produce indoleamine 2,3-dioxygenase&#xD;
      (IDO) and thus ultimately deliver MSC immunosuppressive activity (Galleu et al., 2017).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given the pathophysiology of SARS-CoV2, it is thus sound to hypothesize that the intravenous&#xD;
      administration of UC-MSC during the initial phase of ARDS could control inflammation,&#xD;
      accelerate its recovery with improved oxygenation, reduced mechanical ventilation and&#xD;
      ventilation weaning time and therefore reduced length of stay in intensive care. This&#xD;
      assumption is indeed supported by the recent results of a preliminary Chinese trial in which&#xD;
      MSC (the source of which has not be specified) have been reported to improve pulmonary&#xD;
      function and symptoms in 7 patients with COVID-19 pneumonia along with a rapid clearance of&#xD;
      overactivated cytokine-secreting immune cells (CXCR3+CD4+ T cells, CXCR3+CD8+ T cells, and&#xD;
      CXCR3+ NK cells), a decrease in TNF-α circulating levels and an increase in&#xD;
      CD14+CD11c+CD11bmid regulatory DC cells and IL-10 levels, compared with a placebo group (Leng&#xD;
      et al., 2020).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 6, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 6, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Respiratory efficacy evaluated by the increase in PaO2/FiO2 ratio from baseline to day 7 in the experimental group compared with the placebo group</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to day 7</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lung injury score</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to day 28</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oxygenation index</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to day 28</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>In-hospital mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to day 28</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>At day 28</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ventilator-free days</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to day 28</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of days between randomization and the first day the patient meets weaning criteria o Number of days between randomization and the first day the patient meets PaO2/FiO2 &gt; 200 (out of a prone positioning session)</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to day 28</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative use of sedatives</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to day 28</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative duration of use of sedatives</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to day 28</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative duration of use of neuromuscular blocking agents (other than used for intubation)</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to day 28</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative use of neuromuscular blocking agents (other than used for intubation)</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to day 28</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ICU-acquired weakness and delirium</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to day 28</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment-induced toxicity rate and adverse events up to day 28</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to day 28</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life at one year (EQ5D-3L quality of life questionnaire)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 6 months and 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measurements of plasmatic cytokines (IL1, IL6, IL8, TNF-alpha, IL10, TGF-beta, sRAGE, Ang2) level</measure>
    <time_frame>At day 1, 3, 5, 7 and 14</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-HLA antibodies plasmatic dosage</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to day 14, and at 6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">47</enrollment>
  <condition>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2</condition>
  <condition>Severe Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MSC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NaCl</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Umbilical cord Wharton's jelly-derived human</intervention_name>
    <description>Umbilical cord Wharton's jelly-derived human MSC (at the dose of 1 Million / kg) will be administered via a peripheral or central venous line over 60 minutes, using tubing with a 200-μm filter. Cells, in a 150 mL volume, will be delivered at D1 - D3 - D5.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MSC</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>NaCl 0.9%</intervention_name>
    <description>NaCl 0.9% (150 mL) given via an intravenous route at D1 - D3 - D5</description>
    <arm_group_label>NaCl</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female patient, age &gt; 18 years,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Laboratory (RT-PCR)-confirmed infection with SARS-CoV2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of ARDS according to the Berlin definition of ARDS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Under invasive, non-invasive ventilation or high-flow nasal oxygen therapy (PEEP ≥ 5&#xD;
             cmH2O)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Onset of ARDS &lt;96 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with French Social Security System&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provision of a written informed consent by the designated substitute decision maker,&#xD;
             if present. In the event of absence, the patient can be included by investigator's&#xD;
             decision alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous history of ARDS in the last month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic respiratory diseases requiring long-term oxygen therapy and/or long-term&#xD;
             respiratory assistance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allogeneic bone marrow transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Liver cirrhosis with basal Child and Pugh of C&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pulmonary fibrosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with end-of-life decision&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient not expected to survive for 24 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who received an organ transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Woman known to be pregnant or lactating&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient already enrolled in another interventional pharmacotherapy protocol on&#xD;
             COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has burns to ≥15% of their total body surface area&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is receiving extra-corporeal membrane oxygenation, high-frequency oscillatory&#xD;
             ventilation or any form of extra-corporeal lung support&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient under tutelage&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Antoine MONSEL, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hôpital Pitié-Salpêtrière - Assitance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Pitié-Salpêtrière - APHP</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75013</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Européen Georges Pompidou - APHP</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75015</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 1, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 3, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 3, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 3, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 4, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV2</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome</keyword>
  <keyword>Cell therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Mesenchymal stromal cells</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Adult</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acute Lung Injury</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

