<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1381">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04594356</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NET_COV</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04594356</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Assessment of Netosis During COVID-19, Under Treatment With Anakinra, an Interleukin-1 Receptor Antagonist</brief_title>
  <acronym>NET_COV</acronym>
  <official_title>Assessment of Netosis During COVID-19, Under Treatment With Anakinra, an Interleukin-1 Receptor Antagonist</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      During their activation in response to an infectious stimulus or during chronic inflammatory&#xD;
      processes, blood and tissue neutrophils modify their functional phenotype and produce&#xD;
      numerous toxic mediators. In particular, they rapidly release chromatin filaments covered&#xD;
      with numerous granular and cytoplasmic components called &quot;Neutrophil Extracellular Traps&quot;&#xD;
      (NETs). This phenomenon, called netosis, has been implicated in many diseases, in particular&#xD;
      in viral infections during which this response can be useful for the anti-infectious response&#xD;
      at the initial phase, then deleterious when it becomes toxic. for the tissue environment.&#xD;
      This has been shown in particular during post-pneumonia acute respiratory distress syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intensity of netosis is therefore an early factor in activating neutrophils and&#xD;
      inflammation. Given the major biological signs of inflammation observed in patients with&#xD;
      COVID-19 as soon as they enter the hospital [C-Reactive protein (CRP), Interleukin-6 (IL-6),&#xD;
      D-dimers, etc.), it seems particularly interesting to better document this inflammation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 19, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the netosis process</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>This outcome corresponds to the of the determination of DNA-myeloperoxidase complexes (DNA-MPO).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the netosis process at day 3</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 3</time_frame>
    <description>This outcome corresponds to the of the determination of DNA-myeloperoxidase complexes (DNA-MPO).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Link between this marker (DNA-MPO) and the clinical course of patients</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 3</time_frame>
    <description>This outcome is to evaluate the clinical course of patients according to the DNA-MPO marker.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">126</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with COVID-19 infection</arm_group_label>
    <description>As part of this research, existing clinical data of patients infected with COVID-19 is collected from the patients' computerized medical records.&#xD;
During the hospitalization of the patients, in addition to the clinical and laboratory data collected, the dosage of IL-6, apparently playing a central role in the worsening of the symptoms of COVID-19, was performed. The remainder of the contents of the tube used to perform this assay will allow further research by assaying the DNA-myeloperoxidase (DNA-MPO) complexes. These complexes reflect a phenomenon called &quot;netosis,&quot; most likely involved in the widespread inflammation that patients have suffered from.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients hospitalized within the Paris Saint-Joseph Hospital Group for whom the diagnosis&#xD;
        of COVID-19 has been established on the basis of a PCR positive for SARS-CoV 19 using a&#xD;
        nasal swab and or a typical chest CT scan, with a severe or aggravating form of COVID-19,&#xD;
        based on an oxygen saturation ≤93% under 6 l / min of nasal oxygen or a saturation ≤93%&#xD;
        under 4 l/min oxygen with a decrease in saturation of at least 3% during the last 24 hours,&#xD;
        in ambient air&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients aged ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients hospitalized within the Paris Saint-Joseph Hospital Group for whom the&#xD;
             diagnosis of COVID-19 has been established on the basis of a PCR positive for SARS-CoV&#xD;
             19 using a nasal swab and/or a typical chest CT scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a severe or aggravating form of COVID-19, based on an oxygen saturation&#xD;
             ≤93% under 6 l/min of nasal oxygen or a saturation ≤93% under 4 l/min oxygen with a&#xD;
             decrease in saturation of at least 3% during the last 24 hours, in ambient air&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients treated with Anakinra&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients for whom IL-6 assays have been performed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  French speaking patients&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gilles HAYEM, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Gilles HAYEM, MD</last_name>
    <phone>144127806</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>ghayem@ghpsj.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Helene BEAUSSIER, PharmD, pHD</last_name>
    <phone>144127038</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>crc@ghpsj.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Bichat Claude Bernard</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75018</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sylvie CHOLLET MARTIN, MD</last_name>
      <email>sylvie.martin2@aphp.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Twaddell SH, Baines KJ, Grainge C, Gibson PG. The Emerging Role of Neutrophil Extracellular Traps in Respiratory Disease. Chest. 2019 Oct;156(4):774-782. doi: 10.1016/j.chest.2019.06.012. Epub 2019 Jun 29. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31265835</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Granger V, Peyneau M, Chollet-Martin S, de Chaisemartin L. Neutrophil Extracellular Traps in Autoimmunity and Allergy: Immune Complexes at Work. Front Immunol. 2019 Dec 3;10:2824. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2019.02824. eCollection 2019. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31849989</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Bendib I, de Chaisemartin L, Granger V, Schlemmer F, Maitre B, Hüe S, Surenaud M, Beldi-Ferchiou A, Carteaux G, Razazi K, Chollet-Martin S, Mekontso Dessap A, de Prost N. Neutrophil Extracellular Traps Are Elevated in Patients with Pneumonia-related Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome. Anesthesiology. 2019 Apr;130(4):581-591. doi: 10.1097/ALN.0000000000002619.</citation>
    <PMID>30676417</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Chen G, Wu D, Guo W, Cao Y, Huang D, Wang H, Wang T, Zhang X, Chen H, Yu H, Zhang X, Zhang M, Wu S, Song J, Chen T, Han M, Li S, Luo X, Zhao J, Ning Q. Clinical and immunological features of severe and moderate coronavirus disease 2019. J Clin Invest. 2020 May 1;130(5):2620-2629. doi: 10.1172/JCI137244.</citation>
    <PMID>32217835</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ruan Q, Yang K, Wang W, Jiang L, Song J. Correction to: Clinical predictors of mortality due to COVID-19 based on an analysis of data of 150 patients from Wuhan, China. Intensive Care Med. 2020 Jun;46(6):1294-1297. doi: 10.1007/s00134-020-06028-z.</citation>
    <PMID>32253449</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sarzi-Puttini P, Giorgi V, Sirotti S, Marotto D, Ardizzone S, Rizzardini G, Antinori S, Galli M. COVID-19, cytokines and immunosuppression: what can we learn from severe acute respiratory syndrome? Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2020 Mar-Apr;38(2):337-342. Epub 2020 Mar 22. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32202240</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mehta P, McAuley DF, Brown M, Sanchez E, Tattersall RS, Manson JJ; HLH Across Speciality Collaboration, UK. COVID-19: consider cytokine storm syndromes and immunosuppression. Lancet. 2020 Mar 28;395(10229):1033-1034. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30628-0. Epub 2020 Mar 16.</citation>
    <PMID>32192578</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kupferschmidt K, Cohen J. Race to find COVID-19 treatments accelerates. Science. 2020 Mar 27;367(6485):1412-1413. doi: 10.1126/science.367.6485.1412.</citation>
    <PMID>32217705</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mahase E. Covid-19: what treatments are being investigated? BMJ. 2020 Mar 26;368:m1252. doi: 10.1136/bmj.m1252.</citation>
    <PMID>32217607</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Li G, De Clercq E. Therapeutic options for the 2019 novel coronavirus (2019-nCoV). Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2020 Mar;19(3):149-150. doi: 10.1038/d41573-020-00016-0.</citation>
    <PMID>32127666</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 19, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 19, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 30, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 30, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 31, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

