<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4807">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04719039</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PSY014</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04719039</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Yoga Self-Practice on Sleep Disturbance</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Restorative Yoga Self-Practice on Sleep Disturbance: A Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Chinese University of Hong Kong</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Chinese University of Hong Kong</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study will examine the effect of Restorative Yoga self-practice on sleep disturbance in&#xD;
      the Chinese adult population. Restorative Yoga is a relaxation-focused yoga style which&#xD;
      includes a series of static stretching poses and mindful breathing. Existing literature has&#xD;
      demonstrated that face-to-face yoga sessions of different types are effective in improving&#xD;
      sleep disturbance and reducing the severity of insomnia. There were pilot studies conducted&#xD;
      on the effect of yoga on cancer patients' sleep quality, but research that focuses on&#xD;
      insomnia population is rare (Wang et al., 2020). In addition, there is very limited research&#xD;
      on the effectiveness of self-practice without the presence of a yoga instructor. Given the&#xD;
      social distancing policy under COVID-19 and the need to stay home, this study can shed light&#xD;
      on whether self-practice at home can be an effective alternative to face-to-face yoga&#xD;
      sessions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will be a pilot randomized controlled trial on the effectiveness of restorative&#xD;
      yoga self-practice for sleep disturbance. Prior to all study procedures, online informed&#xD;
      consent (with phone support) will be obtained from potential participants. Around 30 eligible&#xD;
      participants will be randomly assigned to either the yoga group (intervention group) or the&#xD;
      waitlist control group in a ratio of 1:1. The randomization will be performed by an&#xD;
      independent assessor using a computer-generated list of numbers. No deception is necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in the intervention group will receive links to two 60-min videos per week for 8&#xD;
      consecutive weeks. Each video will include a yoga practice guided by a certified yoga&#xD;
      instructor. The intervention group is required to perform the yoga practice at least two&#xD;
      times per week. If preferred, they can do additional sessions with the videos and record&#xD;
      their total hours of self-practice. The waitlist control group will receive the video links&#xD;
      subsequent to the 8-week study. The intervention group will complete a set of online&#xD;
      questionnaires before the intervention commences, weekly during the intervention period,&#xD;
      immediately after the intervention, and 4 weeks after the intervention. The waitlist control&#xD;
      group will complete the same set of online questionnaires before the intervention commences&#xD;
      and immediately after 8-week intervention period has ended.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, intervention period (8 weeks), immediate and 4-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The PSQI-19 is a 19-item questionnaire used for measuring and identifying quality of sleep.&#xD;
It provides a measure of global sleep quality, including sleep latency, sleep duration, habitual sleep efficiency and sleep disturbances.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Insomnia Severity Index (ISI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, intervention period (8 weeks), immediately and 4-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>ISI is a 7-item scale designed to evaluate perceived insomnia severity. Ratings on the 5-point Likert scale are obtained on the perceived severity of sleep-onset, sleep-maintenance, early morning awakening problems, satisfaction with current sleep pattern, interference with daily functioning, noticeably of impairment attributed to the sleep problem, and level of distress caused by the sleep problem.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep Diary - Change in sleep-Onset latency (SOL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, intervention period (8 weeks), immediately and 4-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The standardized sleep diary records the length of time that it takes to accomplish the transition from full wakefulness to sleep on a daily basis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep Diary - Change in wake after sleep onset (WASO)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, intervention period (8 weeks), immediately and 4-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The standardized sleep diary records the periods of wakefulness occurring after defined sleep onset on a daily basis, reflecting sleep fragmentation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep Diary - Change in total wake time (TWT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, intervention period (8 weeks), immediately and 4-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The standardized sleep diary records wake time to measure sleep disturbance.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep Diary - Change in total sleep time (TST)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, intervention period (8 weeks), immediately and 4-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The standardized sleep diary records wake time to measure sleep disturbance.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep Diary - Change in sleep efficiency (SE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, intervention period (8 weeks), immediately and 4-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The Sleep efficiency is measured in percentage by dividing TST by total time in bed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS-14)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, immediately after the 8-week intervention, and 4-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>HADS is a 14-item self-rated questionnaire which consists of two 7-item subscales that measure the presence of anxiety and depression symptoms respectively. Each item is rated on a 4-point-scale (0-3) by the participant. The greater the score, the more psychologically distressed the respondent is.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Multidimensional Fatigue Inventory (MFI-20)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, immediately after the 8-week intervention, and 4-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The MFI-20 assesses the severity of fatigue covering the following dimensions: general fatigue, physical fatigue, mental fatigue, reduced motivation and reduced activity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Short Form (Six-Dimension) Health Survey (SF-6D)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, immediately after the 8-week intervention, and 4-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>SF-6D is a preference-based single index measure of health. A six-digit number represents each SF-6D health state, each digit denotes the level of one of six SF-6D dimensions: physical functioning, role limitation, social functioning, bodily pain, mental health, and vitality.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Credibility-Expectancy Questionnaire (CEQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, immediately after the 8-week intervention, and 4-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The 6-item CEQ yielded ratings of treatment credibility, acceptability/satisfaction, and expectations for success.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Yoga</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Yoga Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Restorative Yoga intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Waitlist Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the waitlist control group will receive the intervention after the immediate post-treatment assessment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Restorative Yoga Internvention</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants in the intervention group will receive links to two 60-min videos per week for 8 consecutive weeks. Each video will include a yoga practice guided by a certified yoga instructor. The intervention group is required to perform the yoga practice at least two times per week. If preferred, they can do additional sessions with the videos and record their total hours of self-practice.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Yoga Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Hong Kong residents aged 18-59 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Cantonese language fluency;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. A global Insomnia Severity Index (ISI) score of 10 or higher;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. No yoga experience within the 6 months before the study; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. A willingness to provide informed consent and comply with the trial protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants were excluded if they&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. are pregnant;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. are having unsafe conditions and are not recommended for restorative yoga by&#xD;
             physicians;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. have major psychiatric, medical or neurocognitive disorders that make participation&#xD;
             infeasible or interfere with the adherence to the yoga practice;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. have insomnia due to specific medical conditions, side effects of medication intake or&#xD;
             other sleep disorders; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. are shift workers.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>59 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tina Chan</last_name>
    <phone>+852 3943 6575</phone>
    <email>1009613291@link.cuhk.edu.hk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Chinese University of Hong Kong</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sha Tin</city>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Chinese University of Hong Kong</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Fiona YY Ho</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Insomnia</keyword>
  <keyword>Yoga</keyword>
  <keyword>Mindful breathing</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dyssomnias</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Parasomnias</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

