<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4701">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04441164</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>35RC20_8897_VERARE</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-A01722-37</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04441164</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>VERARE : Effectiveness of Virtual Motor Actions for Improving Walking in Patients With Post-resuscitation Muscle Weakness</brief_title>
  <acronym>VERARE</acronym>
  <official_title>VERARE : Effectiveness of Virtual Motor Actions for Improving Walking in Patients With Post-resuscitation Muscle Weakness</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rennes University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut National de Recherche en Informatique et en Automatique</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rennes University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      After a hospitalization in Intensive Care Unit (ICU), approximately 50% of patients usually&#xD;
      have a ICU-Weakness, i.e. nerves and muscles injury secondary to immobilization and to&#xD;
      treatments which had to be used. This disease is expected to be similar or even higher in&#xD;
      patients suffering from COVID-19 and hospitalized in ICU due to the average length of&#xD;
      hospitalization of several weeks in this population. This condition will delay the&#xD;
      return-to-walk of these patients, their discharge from hospitalization and may deteriorate&#xD;
      their autonomy in daily life activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Virtual Reality (VR) environments are already used and have proven their worth for the&#xD;
      assessment and rehabilitation of patients with neurological diseases. It therefore seems&#xD;
      appropriate to offer the use of virtual environments for this type of population. VR&#xD;
      represents a unique opportunity for the rehabilitation care of these patients, and in&#xD;
      particular those who have been reached by COVID-19, due to the possible mismatch between the&#xD;
      amount of motor rehabilitation to be provided and the fatigability and breathlessness at the&#xD;
      slightest effort which seem particularly intense in this population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective of our project is to improve and to accelerate gait recovery in patients&#xD;
      hospitalized in Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine after discharge from Resuscitation or&#xD;
      Continuous Care Unit and in patients hospitalized in ICU and presenting ICU-weakness&#xD;
      secondary to resuscitation, notably due to COVID-19 infection, thanks to the use of Virtual&#xD;
      Reality tools. The VR tool will consist of virtual environments presented using a Virtual&#xD;
      Reality headset where an avatar (double) of the patient hospitalized in Physical and&#xD;
      Rehabilitation Medicine or in ICU will be represented, who will perform different motor tasks&#xD;
      involving their lower limbs (ex: walking, or kicking a ball) in several different virtual&#xD;
      environments (settings). The patient will be asked to observe actions, then to imagine&#xD;
      carrying out their actions which will be performed by the avatar in the virtual environment,&#xD;
      then they will be able to control the actions of the avatar using their legs thanks to&#xD;
      sensors, then feel walking sensations through the use of haptic devices.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Step 1: The objective is to evaluate the effectiveness of the Observation of Virtual Actions&#xD;
      on gait recovery in patients hospitalized in Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine (MPR) and&#xD;
      presenting ICU-weakness, in particular following a COVID-19 infection. If the patient is&#xD;
      included in the Virtual Reality group, they will be asked to observe once a day for 9 days&#xD;
      for 5 minutes Virtual Motor Actions (avatar moving in a virtual environment) using a headset.&#xD;
      Virtual Reality, followed by 5 minutes of relaxation performed using soothing music played&#xD;
      through headphones. If the patient is included in the Relaxation group, they will be offered&#xD;
      10 minutes of relaxation performed using soothing music played in headphones once a day for 9&#xD;
      days. We will assess gait, motive power, balance, confidence in the future and patient&#xD;
      autonomy before the start of the first session, the day after the last session and one month&#xD;
      after inclusion. At the end of each session, we will ask the patient questions about fatigue&#xD;
      (VAS) and the occurrence of side effects (open question) after wearing the Virtual Reality&#xD;
      headset or headset. At the end of the 9 sessions, we will ask to patients in the Virtual&#xD;
      Reality group to complete a questionnaire concerning the acceptance of the proposed device.&#xD;
      We want to include 20 patients in the Virtual Reality group and 20 patients in the Relaxation&#xD;
      group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Step 2: The objective is to assess the acceptability (a priori) of the Virtual Reality tool&#xD;
      created in ICU by the nursing staff and by the patients who are hospitalized there. It will&#xD;
      be offered to caregivers of the ICU of the Rennes University Hospital and to patients&#xD;
      hospitalized in these 2 services and presenting ICU- weakness, especially in the aftermath of&#xD;
      COVID infection. We will be asked to complete an acceptability questionnaire (a priori)&#xD;
      concerning the use of a Virtual Reality tool intended to improve walking in the ICU. The&#xD;
      duration of filling in this questionnaire is estimated at 30 minutes. Caregivers will be&#xD;
      invited to participate in an information meeting (4 will be carried out) at least 1 week&#xD;
      before their possible participation (which they will be informed by internal mail, and which&#xD;
      will be led by investigators). We believe that approximately 300 caregivers and 50 patients&#xD;
      will participate in this acceptability survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Step 3: The objective is to evaluate the effectiveness of the Observation of Virtual Actions&#xD;
      on gait recovery in patients hospitalized in ICU and with ICU-weakness. If the acceptability&#xD;
      questionnaire is in favor of a good future acceptance of the tool designed and after possible&#xD;
      adaptations of the Virtual Reality device based on the responses of caregivers and patients&#xD;
      to the acceptability questionnaire proposed during the step 2, we will suggest to patients&#xD;
      hospitalized in ICU with ICU-weakness to carry out a protocol similar to that carried out&#xD;
      with Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine patients in step 1. If the patient is included in&#xD;
      the Virtual Reality group, they will be asked to observe once a day for 9 days for 5 minutes&#xD;
      Virtual Motor Actions (avatar moving in a virtual environment) using a Virtual Reality&#xD;
      headset, followed by 5 minutes of relaxation performed using soothing music played through&#xD;
      headphones. If the patient is included in the Relaxation group, they will be offered 10&#xD;
      minutes of relaxation performed using soothing music played in headphones once a day for 9&#xD;
      days. We will assess gait, motive power, balance, confidence in the future and patient&#xD;
      autonomy before the start of the first session, the day after the last session and 1 month&#xD;
      after inclusion. At the end of each session, we will ask the patient questions about fatigue&#xD;
      (VAS) and the occurrence of side effects (open question) after wearing the Virtual Reality&#xD;
      headset. At the end of the 9 sessions, we will suggest to patients in the Virtual Reality&#xD;
      group that they complete a questionnaire concerning the acceptance of the proposed device. We&#xD;
      want to include 20 patients in the Virtual Reality group and 20 patients in the Relaxation&#xD;
      group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Step 4: The objective is to assess the effectiveness of the realization of virtual actions&#xD;
      compared to the observation of virtual actions on gait recovery in patients hospitalized in&#xD;
      ICU or in Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine and presenting ICU-weakness. If the patient is&#xD;
      included in the group Performing Virtual Actions, they will be asked to perform Virtual&#xD;
      Actions of the lower limbs by controlling the legs of his avatar (virtual double) in order to&#xD;
      move around in a virtual environment for 10 minutes per day, once a day for 9 days. If the&#xD;
      patient is included in the Observation of Virtual Actions group, they will be asked to&#xD;
      observe for 10 minutes once a day for 9 days Virtual Motor Actions (avatar moving in a&#xD;
      virtual environment) using a Virtual Reality headset. We will assess gait, motive power,&#xD;
      balance, confidence in the future and patient autonomy before the start of the first session,&#xD;
      the day after the last session and 1 month after inclusion. At the end of each session, we&#xD;
      will ask the patient questions about fatigue (VAS) and the occurrence of side effects (open&#xD;
      question) after wearing the Virtual Reality headset. At the end of the 9 sessions, we will&#xD;
      offer patients to fill out a questionnaire concerning the acceptance of the proposed device.&#xD;
      We want to include 20 patients in the Virtual Actions group and 20 patients in the Virtual&#xD;
      Actions Observation group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Step 5: The objective is to evaluate the effectiveness of adding a sensation of walking using&#xD;
      haptic stimuli during the Observation or Realization of Virtual Actions on the recovery of&#xD;
      walking in patients hospitalized in ICU or in Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine and with&#xD;
      ICU-weakness. Depending on the superiority or not of the Realization of Virtual Actions or&#xD;
      the Observation of Virtual Actions, we will test the most effective condition of step 4 in&#xD;
      combination with: either haptic stimulation (sensory feedback through vibrators positioned on&#xD;
      the lower limbs to give a feeling of walking), either without haptic stimulation, once a day&#xD;
      for 10 minutes for 9 days. We will assess gait, motive power, balance, confidence in the&#xD;
      future and patient autonomy before the start of the first session, the day after the last&#xD;
      session and 1 month after inclusion. At the end of each session, we will ask the patient&#xD;
      questions about fatigue (VAS) and the occurrence of side effects (open question) in the&#xD;
      aftermath of wearing a Virtual Reality headset. At the end of the 9 sessions, we will offer&#xD;
      patients to fill out a questionnaire concerning the acceptance of the proposed device. We&#xD;
      want to include 20 patients in the group with haptic stimulation and 20 patients in the group&#xD;
      without haptic stimulation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Submitted, denied (too much steps; project to be cut in several projects)&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Step 1: 40 patients (20 in the Virtual Reality group and 20 in the Relaxation group)&#xD;
Step 2: Estimated response rate of approximately 300 caregivers and 50 patients&#xD;
Step 3: 40 patients (20 in the Virtual Reality group and 20 in the Relaxation group)&#xD;
Step 4: 40 patients (20 in the group Performing Virtual Actions and 20 in the group Observing Virtual Actions)&#xD;
Step 5: 40 patients (20 in the group with Haptic stimulation, 20 in the group without Haptic stimulation</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>6-minute test</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 10</time_frame>
    <description>Number of meters taken during the 6-minute test the day after the last session.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time for 10-meter test</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the start of the first session (day 1), the day after the last session (day 9) and 1 month after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Gait assessment before the start of the first session, the day after the last session and 1 month from inclusion: 10-meter test (time in seconds)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>6-minute walk test</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the start of the first session (day 1), the day after the last session (day 9) and 1 month after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Gait assessment before the start of the first session, the day after the last session and 1 month from inclusion: 6-minute walk test (need for breaks, scale de Borg, existence of desaturation)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Recovery time</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the start of the first session (day 1), the day after the last session (day 9) and 1 month after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Gait assessment before the start of the first session, the day after the last session and 1 month from inclusion: recovery time for walking over 10 meters without human or technical assistance</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Normal or deficient posture balance in sitting and standing</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the start of the first session (day 1), the day after the last session (day 9) and 1 month after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of balance before the start of the first session, the day after the last session and 1 month from inclusion: normal or deficient posture balance in sitting and standing</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Berg Balance Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the start of the first session (day 1), the day after the last session (day 9) and 1 month after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of balance before the start of the first session, the day after the last session and 1 month from inclusion: Berg Balance Scale. Berg's balance scale includes 14 tests that assess static balance and dynamic balance. Each test is rated from 0 (needs help) to 4 (can do on him/her own). Total score is on 56 points.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Timed Up and Go test</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the start of the first session (day 1), the day after the last session (day 9) and 1 month after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of balance before the start of the first session, the day after the last session and 1 month from inclusion: Timed Up and Go test (time in seconds)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration for the test of the 10 chair lifts</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the start of the first session (day 1), the day after the last session (day 9) and 1 month after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of balance before the start of the first session, the day after the last session and 1 month from inclusion: test of the 10 chair lifts (duration in seconds, existence of a desaturation, Borg scale)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>MRC scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the start of the first session (day 1), the day after the last session (day 9) and 1 month after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Strength assessment before the start of the first session, the day after the last session and within 1 month of inclusion: MRC testing of the lower limbs.&#xD;
The Medical Research Council's scale (MRC scale) is an assessment of muscle power, rated form 0 (no contraction) to 5 (normal power).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional Independence Measure</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the start of the first session (day 1), the day after the last session (day 9) and 1 month after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of autonomy before the start of the first session, the day after the last session and within 1 month of inclusion: Functional Independence Measure.&#xD;
The Functional Independence Measure (FIM) is an 18-item instrument measuring a person's level of disability in terms of burden of care. Each item is rated from 1 (requiring total assistance) to 7 (completely independent). Three independent FIM scores can be generated by summing item scores: a total score (FIM total: 18 items), a motor score (FIM motor: eating, grooming, bathing, dressing - upper body, dressing - lower body, toileting, bladder management, bowel management, and transfers bed/chair/wheelchair, toilet, tub/shower, walk, stairs), and a cognitive score (FIM cognitive: auditory comprehension, verbal expression, social interaction, problem solving, and memory). Multiple studies support the reliability and validity of FIM scales in the older population.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 (step 2)</time_frame>
    <description>Acceptability (a priori, patients and caregivers for stage 2) questionnaires</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptance</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 (step 2)</time_frame>
    <description>Acceptance (patients for stages 1, 3, 4 and 5) questionnaires</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fatigue</measure>
    <time_frame>End of each session, at days 1 to 9</time_frame>
    <description>Fatigue assessment (visual analog scale) (steps 1, 3, 4, 5)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Undesirable effects</measure>
    <time_frame>End of each session, at days 1 to 9</time_frame>
    <description>Collections of possible undesirable effects by open question at the end of each session with the Virtual Reality tool (steps 1, 3, 4, 5)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Confidence in the future</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the start of the first session (day 1), the day after the last session (day 9) and 1 month after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of confidence in the future using a questionnaire (steps 1, 3, 4, 5) before the start of the first session, the day after the last session and 1 month from inclusion</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>9</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Weakness of the Lower Limbs</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Observation of Virtual Actions (steps 1 and 3)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>If the patient is included in the Virtual Reality group, he/she will be asked to observe Virtual Motor Actions (their own avatar moving in a virtual environment) using a headset once a day for 9 days during 5 minutes, followed by 5 minutes of relaxation performed using soothing music played through headphones.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Relaxation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>If the patient is included in the Relaxation group, he/she will be offered 10 minutes of relaxation performed using soothing music played in headphones once a day for 9 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>It will be offered to patients hospitalized in these 2 services and presenting post-resuscitation ICU-weakness, especially in the aftermath of COVID infection, to complete an acceptability questionnaire (a priori) concerning the use of a Virtual Reality tool intended to improve walking in the ICU. The duration of filling in this questionnaire is estimated at 30 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Caregivers</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>It will be offered to caregivers of the ICU of the Rennes University Hospital, to complete an acceptability questionnaire (a priori) concerning the use of a Virtual Reality tool intended to improve walking in the ICU. The duration of filling in this questionnaire is estimated at 30 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Relaxation (step 3)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>If the patient is included in the Relaxation group, he/she will be offered 10 minutes of relaxation performed using soothing music played in headphones once a day for 9 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Performing Virtual Actions</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>If the patient is included in the group Performing Virtual Actions, he/she will be asked to perform Virtual Actions of the lower limbs by controlling the legs of his avatar (virtual double) in order to move around in a virtual environment for 10 minutes per day, once a day for 9 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Observation of Virtual Actions</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>If the patient is included in the Observation of Virtual Actions group, he/she will be asked to observe for 10 minutes once a day for 9 days Virtual Motor Actions (avatar moving in a virtual environment) using a Virtual Reality headset.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Haptic stimulation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Depending on the superiority or not of the Realization of Virtual Actions or the Observation of Virtual Actions, we will test the most effective condition of step 4 in combination with haptic stimulation (sensory feedback through vibrators positioned in the lower limbs to give a feeling of walking), once a day for 10 minutes for 9 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Without haptic stimulation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Without haptic stimulation Depending on the superiority or not of the Realization of Virtual Actions or the Observation of Virtual Actions, we will test the most effective condition of Step 4 in combination without haptic stimulation (without sensory feedback through vibrators positioned in the lower limbs to give a feeling of walking), once a day for 10 minutes for 9 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Observation of Virtual Actions</intervention_name>
    <description>If the patient is included in the Virtual Reality group, he/she will be asked to observe Virtual Motor Actions (their own avatar moving in a virtual environment) using a headset once a day for 9 days during 5 minutes, followed by 5 minutes of relaxation performed using soothing music played through headphones.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Observation of Virtual Actions (steps 1 and 3)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Relaxation</intervention_name>
    <description>If the patient is included in the Relaxation group, he/she will be offered 10 minutes of relaxation performed using soothing music played in headphones once a day for 9 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Relaxation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Relaxation (step 3)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acceptability questionnaire</intervention_name>
    <description>It will be asked to complete an acceptability questionnaire (a priori) concerning the use of a Virtual Reality tool intended to improve walking in the ICU. The duration of filling in this questionnaire is estimated at 30 minutes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Caregivers</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Observation of Virtual Actions (step 4)</intervention_name>
    <description>If the patient is included in the Observation of Virtual Actions group, he/she will be asked to observe for 10 minutes once a day for 9 days Virtual Motor Actions (avatar moving in a virtual environment) using a Virtual Reality headset.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Observation of Virtual Actions</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Performing Virtual Actions</intervention_name>
    <description>If the patient is included in the group Performing Virtual Actions, he/she will be asked to perform Virtual Actions of the lower limbs by controlling the legs of his avatar (virtual double) in order to move around in a virtual environment for 10 minutes per day, once a day for 9 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Performing Virtual Actions</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Haptic stimulation</intervention_name>
    <description>According to the superiority or not of the Realization of Virtual Actions or the Observation of Virtual Actions, we will test the most effective condition of step 4 in combination with haptic stimulation (sensory feedback through vibrators positioned in the lower limbs to give a feeling of walking), once a day for 10 minutes for 9 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Haptic stimulation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Without haptic stimulation</intervention_name>
    <description>Without haptic stimulation Depending on the superiority or not of the Realization of Virtual Actions or the Observation of Virtual Actions, we will test the most effective condition of Step 4 in combination without haptic stimulation (without sensory feedback through vibrators positioned in the lower limbs to give a feeling of walking), once a day for 10 minutes for 9 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Without haptic stimulation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Step 1: Patient hospitalized in the Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation department of&#xD;
             the Rennes University Hospital following a stay in intensive care or in a Continuing&#xD;
             Care Unit, in particular following a COVID-19 infection, and with muscle weakness of&#xD;
             the lower limbs with an MRC motor testing on the main muscle segments giving a score&#xD;
             less than or equal to 48/60 (diagnostic criterion of ICU Weakness)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Steps 2 and 3: Patient hospitalized in one of the ICU of the Rennes University&#xD;
             Hospital and presenting post-resuscitation muscle weakness in the lower limbs with MRC&#xD;
             motor testing on the main muscle segments giving a score less than or equal to 48/60&#xD;
             (diagnostic criterion of ICU Weakness)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Steps 4 and 5: Patient hospitalized in one of the ICU or in the Physical Medicine and&#xD;
             Rehabilitation service of the Rennes University Hospital and presenting&#xD;
             post-resuscitation muscle weakness in the lower limbs with an MRC motor testing on the&#xD;
             main muscle segments giving a score less than or equal to 48/60 (diagnostic criterion&#xD;
             of ICU-Weakness)&#xD;
&#xD;
        For nursing staff:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Step 2: Person with one of the following professions: nursing assistant, nurse, doctor,&#xD;
        physiotherapist, and practicing for more than a month in one of the ICU of the Rennes&#xD;
        University Hospital .&#xD;
&#xD;
        For everyone :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person of full age;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Affiliation to a social security insurance;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Free, informed and written consent signed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of central neurological event with clinical repercussions;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gait disturbances preexisting in ICU hospitalization and limiting the gait perimeter&#xD;
             (declaration by the patient) or requiring the use of technical assistance;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled epilepsy (last crisis occurring less than 6 months old);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons of full age subject to legal protection (safeguard of justice, curators,&#xD;
             guardians), persons deprived of their liberty;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating woman.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For caregivers:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-French fluent people;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults over the age of legal protection (safeguard of justice, curators, guardians),&#xD;
             persons deprived of their liberty.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rennes University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rennes</city>
        <state>Bretagne</state>
        <zip>35033</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Muscle Weakness</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Paresis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

