<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2203">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04609085</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10000210</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>000210-I</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04609085</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SARS-COV2 Pandemic Serosurvey in a Rare Disease Population</brief_title>
  <official_title>SARS-COV2 Pandemic Serosurvey in a Rare Disease Population</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The SARS-COV2 outbreak has had a major impact on the economy and society. Researchers want to&#xD;
      learn how widespread the infection is in the rare disease community. To do this, they will&#xD;
      get blood samples from people with rare diseases. They will use at-home sampling. This will&#xD;
      allow them to get samples from people across a wide area.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To estimate the proportion of people with rare diseases who have SARS-COV2 antibodies in the&#xD;
      National Center for the Advancement of Translational Sciences Rare Disease Clinical Research&#xD;
      Network (RDCRN) Rare Diseases Survey over time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People under age 90 who have a rare disease and have taken part in the Cincinnati Children s&#xD;
      Hospital Medical Center (CCHMC) protocol# 2020-0299.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      RDCRN will tell CCHMC participants about this NIH study. RDCRN will only reach out to those&#xD;
      who agreed to be contacted for future studies. They will be contacted by phone and email.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have a virtual visit to collect data. It will take place over the phone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be sent a home kit to collect a blood sample. The kit contains gauze, a&#xD;
      lancet, bandages, a collection device, and instructions. They will also be given shipping&#xD;
      materials. They will give up to 80ul of blood. They will ship the sample back to NIH.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will complete a survey. It can be done online or over the phone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation will last for 1 week.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      It has been demonstrated that respiratory virus outbreaks and pandemics, such as influenza,&#xD;
      SARS, MERS, and now the newly emerged SARS-COV2 virus, have a major impact on morbidity and&#xD;
      mortality worldwide, as well as having devastating global economic and societal impact.&#xD;
      During these outbreaks it is critical to gain a rapid understanding of the exposures and&#xD;
      immunity in the general population. Current ongoing serosurvey efforts to estimate the&#xD;
      prevalence of infection/exposure are focused on the general population, but these estimates&#xD;
      may not be applicable to individuals living with rare diseases. An effort to identify the&#xD;
      impact of this pandemic on this community is underway in the Rare Disease Clinical Research&#xD;
      Network (RDCRN) led by the Data Management and Coordinating Center (DMCC) at Cincinnati&#xD;
      Children s Hospital Medical Center (CCHMC) supported by NCATS. Through a survey they are&#xD;
      attempting to evaluate infection rates and impact on those with rare diseases. In this study&#xD;
      we propose to enroll a subset of the individuals participating in the RDCRN study to collect&#xD;
      blood for SARS-Cov-2 antibody testing. This will allow us to add a biological marker to&#xD;
      confirm infection/exposure and further our understanding of how widespread this infection is&#xD;
      in the rare diseae community.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 11, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To estimate the proportion of people with rare diseases who have detectable antibodies to SARS-COV2 in the NCATS RDCRN Rare Diseases Survey over time.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Anti-SARS-COV2 IgG, IgA, and IgM measured by ELISA</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To estimate the proportion of detectable antibodies across specific categories of rare diseases (e.g., people who live with rare diseases characterized by immune compromise vs. people with hyper-reactivity of the immune system).</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Variation in the Observed-to-expected ratio of people with detectable Anti-SARS-COV2 IgG, IgA, and IgM measured by ELISA (seroprevalent cases), across subgroups of people with different categories of rare diseases.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">5000</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-COV2 Virus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Participants with Rare Diseases</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants with history of rare disease</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Participants who are enrolled in CCHMC protocol# 2020-0299 'Impact of COVID-19 on People&#xD;
        Living with Rare Diseases and their Families.'&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. &lt;90 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Participant in CCHMC Protocol# 2020-0299.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Will have expressed interest in discussing this study with us when contacted by&#xD;
                  CCHMC Protocol# 2020-0299 study team.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Willing and able to complete a verbal telephone consent or if a minor, has a&#xD;
                  parent/guardian able to complete the consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Willing to undergo 3 home blood sampling procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Willing to have blood samples stored for future research.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Unable to provide consent and/or does not have a parent or guardian to provide consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Any condition or event that, in the PI s opinion, may substantially increase the risk&#xD;
             associated with study participation or compromise the study s scientific objectives.&#xD;
             Conditions that exclude a subject are considered to be unlikely, but an example would&#xD;
             include having an acute respiratory infection that would make it unsafe to obtain&#xD;
             blood samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Not willing to have blood samples stored for future research.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Matthew J Memoli, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pittsburgh</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15261</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 1, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Rare Diseases</keyword>
  <keyword>Antibodies</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rare Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

