<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="635">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04591015</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>3R01DK112322-05S1</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>3R01DK112322-05S1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04591015</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dulce Digital-COVID Aware (DD-CA) Discharge Texting Platform for US/Mexico Border Hispanics With Diabetes + COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Dulce Digital-COVID Aware (DD-CA) Discharge Texting Platform for US/Mexico Border Hispanics With Diabetes + COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Scripps Whittier Diabetes Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Scripps Whittier Diabetes Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The COVID-19 pandemic has triggered extremely high hospitalization rates where mitigation&#xD;
      strategies are urgently necessary to aid vulnerable Hispanic and Latino populations who are&#xD;
      experiencing health disparities as well as high type 2 diabetes (T2D) prevalence with poor&#xD;
      clinical outcomes when compared to non-Hispanic populations. The supplemental Dulce&#xD;
      Digital-COVID Aware (DD-CA) intervention addresses specific barriers in diverse underserved&#xD;
      Hispanic and Latino communities to improve glucose control and lower transmission of COVID-19&#xD;
      during a highly vulnerable period post hospitalization discharge, to reduce hospital&#xD;
      readmission rates. This supplement will integrate COVID educational messaging with glucose&#xD;
      management messaging within a low-cost, easily adoptable digital texting platform and offer&#xD;
      critical information in a culturally and linguistically relevant manner to address specific&#xD;
      barriers in diverse underserved communities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Hispanics, a group that shows higher type 2 diabetes (T2D) prevalence, and poor&#xD;
      self-management and clinical outcomes, have been disproportionally adversely impacted by&#xD;
      COVID-19. The California Department of Public Health reports that Hispanics make up 39% of&#xD;
      California's population but an unprecedented 57% of the confirmed COVID-19 cases. This&#xD;
      devastating finding is especially notable on the US/Mexico border. Diabetes has emerged as a&#xD;
      leading risk factor for severe COVID-19 illness leading to hospitalization, is associated&#xD;
      with greater disease severity and mortality and is an independent predictor of intensive care&#xD;
      placement and invasive ventilation. It is becoming increasingly clear that maintaining good&#xD;
      glucose control improves prognosis of COVID-19 among people with pre-existing T2D. However,&#xD;
      social distancing, quarantine, and stay-at-home/lockdown guidelines may impact one's ability&#xD;
      to maintain adequate glycemic control. Research is needed to evaluate the effect and clinical&#xD;
      outcomes of a flexible, easily adopted low cost digital intervention that improves glucose&#xD;
      excursions and provides urgently needed COVID-19 mitigation strategies, among rapidly rising&#xD;
      groups of high-risk Hispanics with poorly controlled T2D in US/Mexico border communities.&#xD;
      Strong evidence from our parent grant Dulce Digital-Me (DD-ME), supports the use of&#xD;
      technology (such as text messaging) alone or in combination with coaching interventions as a&#xD;
      viable and desired method of delivering tailored diabetes self-management education and COVID&#xD;
      awareness messaging to high-risk, underserved populations in a manner that is more convenient&#xD;
      for both patients and staff while having the added benefit of being cost-effective for health&#xD;
      systems, especially within low resource settings. However, effective interventions may&#xD;
      encounter barriers which preclude guaranteed success upon implementation in the real world.&#xD;
      This project, taking place along the San Diego/Tijuana border, historically the busiest land&#xD;
      port of entry in the Western Hemisphere, will assess the effect of providing an enhanced&#xD;
      digital texting intervention-Dulce Digital-COVID Aware (DD-CA) to N = 172 Hispanic patients&#xD;
      with T2D upon discharge from a recent hospitalization. Key outcomes will assess the impact of&#xD;
      DD-CA on hospital readmissions at 30, 90 and 180 days post-discharge, glucose control and&#xD;
      patient reported outcomes at 90 and 180 days post-discharge while also assessing COVID status&#xD;
      and the implementation process. Given that DD-CA offers the potential to address many of the&#xD;
      practical barriers to access and extend the reach of diabetes services, while additionally&#xD;
      providing COVID awareness support, it offers an ideal low-cost and flexible solution to&#xD;
      reduce hospital admissions and re-admissions in US/Mexico border communities significantly&#xD;
      and simultaneously affected by COVID-19 and T2D. Implemented in a typical hospital and&#xD;
      post-discharge setting, it augments existing care team processes, thus providing a valuable&#xD;
      test of real-world effectiveness. More importantly, by helping to reduce existing inequities&#xD;
      in access to diabetes and COVID-19 care, this program aims to improve health outcomes on a&#xD;
      larger scale.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Readmission rate (30-days)</measure>
    <time_frame>30-days</time_frame>
    <description>The Electronic Medical Record (EMR) will be used to identify readmissions during each patient's unique follow up period. Unadjusted between group differences will first be analyzed by comparing proportion of patients with any hospital readmissions within the 30-day period by a Fisher's exact test. Followup analyses will be conducted using multiple logistic regression models to account for gender, ethnicity, race, comorbid conditions including COVID-19, medication use, and baseline glycemic control, in addition to study arm, as fixed effects in predicting the primary outcome, rate of readmissions within 30-days. We do not anticipate missing data for covariates included in regression models since demographic data will be captured directly from the EMR, and baseline glycemic control (i.e. HbA1c at hospital admission) and COVID-19 diagnosis will be determined during the admission of study enrollment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Glycosylated Hemoglobin (HbA1c)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 90-days, 180-days</time_frame>
    <description>Additional metrics of glycemic control will be captured for each study participant from the EMR including HbA1c at 90 and 180-days post-discharge. Unadjusted group mean differences in HbA1c will be assessed with a students t-test, followed by multiple linear regression analysis controlling for baseline HbA1c (at time of initial admission), as well as covariates including gender, ethnicity, race, comorbid conditions including COVID-19, and medication/steriod use, in addition to study arm, as fixed effects in predicting HbA1c at 90 and 180 days.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Diabetes Distress Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 90-days, 180-days</time_frame>
    <description>Diabetes distress will be measured using the Diabetes Distress Scale (DDS); range 1-6, with higher scores indicating worse outcomes/greater diabetes-related emotional stress. The survey will be administered immediately post enrollment, prior to randomizing, and during the 90 and 180-day follow-up visit. Measures will be compared between groups by t-tests at each time point.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 Patient Survey</measure>
    <time_frame>90-days, 180-days</time_frame>
    <description>Research assistants will deliver the COVID-19 Patient Survey (PhenixToolkit) to each participant at their 90 and 180-day follow up to obtain their COVID-19 diagnosis status to determine whether any new infections occurred in the 90 and 180-day post-discharge time frame. Additional questions in the survey will be used for descriptive analyses to characterize infections. Differences in proportions of patients experiencing new infections per group (i.e. patients who were negative at discharge but had a self-reported positive test within 90 and 180 days) will be compared by Fisher's exact tests.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Summary of Diabetes Self-Care Activities Survey</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 90-days, 180-days</time_frame>
    <description>Summary of Diabetes Self-Care Activities (SDSCA; range 0-7, with higher scores indicating better outcomes/greater adherence to diabetes self-management behaviors) will be administered immediately post enrollment, prior to randomizing, and during the 90 and 180-day follow-up visit. Measures will be compared between groups by t-tests at each time point.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS Quality of Life Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 90-days, 180-days</time_frame>
    <description>Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS) Global-10 (range 0-100, with higher scores reflecting better outcomes/higher quality of life) will be administered immediately post enrollment, prior to randomizing, and during the 90 and 180-day follow-up visit. Measures will be compared between groups by t-tests at each time point.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowledge, Attitudes and Practice Toward COVID-19 Survey</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 90-days, 180-days</time_frame>
    <description>Knowledge, Attitudes and Practices Toward COVID-19 Survey (range 0-12, with higher scores reflecting better knowledge of COVID-19) will be administered immediately post enrollment, prior to randomizing, and during the 90 and 180-day follow-up visit. Measures will be compared between groups by t-tests at each time point.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Demographics Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Socio-Economic Status (SES), nativity, duration of US residence, Marital status, depressive symptoms and healthcare utilization will be measured immediately post enrollment, prior to randomizing.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Readmission Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>90-days, 180-days</time_frame>
    <description>Exploratory analyses will be conducted similarly to our Primary Outcome. The EMR will be used to identify readmissions during each patient's unique follow up period. Unadjusted between group differences will first be analyzed by comparing proportion of patients with any hospital readmissions within the 90-day period by a Fisher's exact t-test. Followup analyses will be conducted using multiple logistic regression models to account for gender, ethnicity, race, comorbid conditions including COVID-19, medication use, and baseline glycemic control, in addition to study arm, as fixed effects in predicting the exploratory outcome, rate of readmissions within 90 and 180-days.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">172</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>DD-CA</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the DD-CA arm, participants will be offered a proven digital texting platform in their language of preference (Spanish/English) as part of the diabetes transitions discharge program with added COVID support messages.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Care (UC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>UC participants will not receive the added COVID support messages, both arms will have a referral placed to the Diabetes Transitions Service (DTS) as part of usual care at the time of discharge.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hospital: DD-CA</intervention_name>
    <description>In the DD-CA group, participants will be offered a proven digital texting platform in their language of preference (Spanish/English) as part of the diabetes transitions discharge program with educational, motivational and medication adherence messaging that is currently an arm of our parent DD-ME grant with added COVID support messages that provide information addressing identified barriers in Hispanic underserved communities (e.g. obtaining testing supplies and medications, accessing routine medical care, and completing other important diabetes self-management behaviors such as healthful eating, exercise, social distancing, quarantine, and stay-at-home/lockdown guidelines).</description>
    <arm_group_label>DD-CA</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hospital: Usual Care (UC)</intervention_name>
    <description>In the UC group, participants will not receive the added COVID support messages, both groups will have a referral placed to the Diabetes Transitions Service (DTS) at the time of discharge as part of usual care. Participants will be contacted by a peer health coach following protocol to coordinate care with outpatient health and other community resources.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Care (UC)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are a patient admitted to a Scripps Mercy Hospital,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consider yourself Hispanic/Latino, of any race&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are 18 years of age or older,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Speak English or Spanish,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have type 2 diabetes and A1c ≥ 7% in the last 90 days, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a cellphone that can receive/send text messages.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are pregnant,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are currently participating in another diabetes or COVD-19 related study, or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not meet all eligibility inclusion criteria.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Athena Philis-Tsimikas, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Scripps Whittier Diabetes Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Athena Philis-Tsimikas, MD</last_name>
    <phone>858-678-7045</phone>
    <email>philis-tsimikas.athena@scrippshealth.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Type 2 Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

