<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="5006">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04429061</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB-300002251</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04429061</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Reaching 90 90 90 in Adolescents in Zambia: Using All Our SKILLZ</brief_title>
  <acronym>SKILLZ</acronym>
  <official_title>Reaching 90 90 90 in Adolescents in Zambia: Using All Our SKILLZ</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alabama at Birmingham</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of California, San Francisco</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centre for Infectious Disease Research in Zambia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Grassroot Soccer (GRS)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Washington University School of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alabama at Birmingham</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      &quot;SKILLZ,&quot; is a mixed methods evaluation of the Grassroots Soccer (GRS) SKILLZ Package based&#xD;
      in Lusaka, Zambia. The package is made up of three football-based programs: (1) SKILLZ-Girl -&#xD;
      implemented in schools as part of a 10-week program culminating in a tournament event; (2)&#xD;
      SKILLZ-Club - implemented as an ongoing extra-curricular activity after the completion of&#xD;
      SKILLZ-Girl; (3) SKILLZ-Plus - a clinic based football group targeted at girls that are&#xD;
      HIV-positive.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The programs work together to build a continued support system which encourages uptake of&#xD;
      Sexual Reproductive Health (SRH) and HIV services, while facilitating ART adherence (for&#xD;
      HV-positive participants) and continued engagement with health services over the long-term&#xD;
      (whether to contraceptive methods, HIV prevention services, HIV repeat testing, and/or HIV&#xD;
      treatment and care).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study team has developed an enhanced SKILLZ-Girl offering, which will include a&#xD;
      comprehensive module on HIVST, contraceptives and PrEP, access to a nurse during the&#xD;
      implementation of sessions and the additional offering of HIVST and contraceptive services at&#xD;
      the event along with ongoing engagement through the SKILLZ-Club program (Enhanced Arm) , The&#xD;
      central hypothesis is that this enhanced curriculum will increase HIV testing and&#xD;
      contraceptive uptake compared to the standard SKILLZ curriculum &amp; standard event (SOC Arm).&#xD;
      The investigators further hypothesize that the intervention in the enhanced arm will&#xD;
      positively and directly affect a number of mediating factors including attendance at soccer&#xD;
      events where community-based SRH services are offered, SRH knowledge, empowerment,&#xD;
      self-confidence, and perceptions of gender balance, and (reduced) stigma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For girls found to be HIV-positive, the follow-on SKILLZ intervention (SKILLZ-Plus) has been&#xD;
      designed to facilitate linkage to HIV care and treatment, reduce HIV-related stigma, increase&#xD;
      disclosure to family and partners, increase feelings of social support, empowerment,&#xD;
      self-efficacy, and ultimately adherence to ARVs, viral load suppression (VLS) and retention&#xD;
      in HIV care and treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will be conducted in up to 32 secondary schools that GRS currently serves in the&#xD;
      Lusaka Urban District.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Research Aims &amp; Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 1: Assess the impact of SKILLZ over two years on:&#xD;
&#xD;
      (i) (a) HIV testing and (b) SRH-related prevention services uptake among adolescent girls&#xD;
      aged 16-19 in up to 9 intervention schools in Lusaka, Zambia (with enhanced HIVST, PrEP, and&#xD;
      contraceptive method offerings) compared to up to 9 control schools using a&#xD;
      quasi-experimental difference-in-difference approach; and (ii) linkage to care and treatment,&#xD;
      and viral load suppression and retention at 6, 12, and 24 months through a cohort model using&#xD;
      pre-existing SmartCare data on HIV+ individuals in care to match to adolescent girls aged 16&#xD;
      and over from the same district (Lusaka) who are identified to be HIV+ at any time during&#xD;
      SKILLZ Girl or SKILLZ Club participation and enrolled in SKILLZ-Plus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This will be achieved by i) using a quasi-experimental difference-in-difference approach that&#xD;
      compares girls aged 16 and over in 9 SKILLZ control schools compared to 9 schools where&#xD;
      enhanced SKILLZ will be delivered with the enhanced HIVST and a variety of contraceptive&#xD;
      method offerings; and ii) through a cohort model using pre-existing SmartCare data on HIV+&#xD;
      individuals in care to match to adolescent girls aged 16 and over from the same district&#xD;
      (Lusaka) who are identified to be HIV+ at any time during SKILLZ-Girl or SKILLZ-Club&#xD;
      participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2: Examine how the intervention works including lessons learned for future implementation&#xD;
      by:&#xD;
&#xD;
      (i) conducting a process evaluation to identify mediators, predictors, and barriers to uptake&#xD;
      of the SKILLZ-Girl, Club, and Plus curricula both quantitatively through mediation and&#xD;
      moderation analyses and qualitatively through a sequential explanatory approach using focus&#xD;
      groups discussions, interviews and observation with coaches and girls; and by (ii) monitoring&#xD;
      fidelity Aim 3: Estimate the short- and long-term cost-effectiveness and return on investment&#xD;
      of the SKILLZ Girl, Club, and Plus curricula for improving health outcomes for adolescent&#xD;
      girls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design This is a mixed-methods evaluation of the SKILLZ intervention in Lusaka, Zambia&#xD;
      using the following approaches: (1)A quasi-experimental cohort of school-aged 16-year old and&#xD;
      over females to be followed for a two-year period will be evaluated with a&#xD;
      difference-in-difference (DID) approach to estimate HIV testing uptake and&#xD;
      sexual/reproductive health services use. (2) A process evaluation to better understand the&#xD;
      casual pathways and effect mediators and moderators using mixed methods approaches, including&#xD;
      supplemental qualitative data collection; (3) Fidelity monitoring of the intervention&#xD;
      implementation, including receptivity to and understanding of, the intervention amongst&#xD;
      participants, the perceived appropriateness and relevancy of the intervention for adolescent&#xD;
      girls in school, and the extent to which the intervention was delivered per protocol in&#xD;
      different communities and schools; and (4) Economic evaluation to estimate the short- and&#xD;
      long-term cost-effectiveness and return on investment of SKILLZ for improving health outcomes&#xD;
      for adolescent girls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Selection of participants, sampling methods and sample size The study will take place across&#xD;
      all the highly densely populated areas of Lusaka where CIDRZ supports government MoH clinics&#xD;
      with ARV services, electronic data management, and youth-friendly trained clinical personnel,&#xD;
      and where GRS has been implementing their basic curriculum and events. All schools selected&#xD;
      will be secular government schools.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will recruit all girls in Grade 10 who are at least 16 years old at the start of&#xD;
      the intervention period (i.e., the commencement of SKLLZ-Girl). Of the 30,000 youth in Lusaka&#xD;
      that have benefitted from GRS services to date, GRS has seen HIV testing uptake of 62% as&#xD;
      compared to a baseline of 13% (internal program data). The study sample size is powered for&#xD;
      the primary endpoints in Aim 1ii to account for attrition anticipated along the cascade (see&#xD;
      below). For HIV testing, all eligible girls (estimated to be an average of 100 girls per&#xD;
      school in up to 18 schools) is large enough to detect a significant difference in testing&#xD;
      uptake if defining statistical significance at p-value=0.05, power=0.2, ICC=0.1, and an&#xD;
      expected testing uptake of 60% (control) and 80% (intervention).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study sites The study will be conducted in up to 18 (2 pilot + 16 for full implementation)&#xD;
      schools from the Urban District of Lusaka to receive the SKILLZ-Girl curriculum. Of the total&#xD;
      (up to 18), half will be randomly allocated to host the standard SKILLZ-Girl curriculum, and&#xD;
      the remaining half (e.g., up to eight) will be randomized to the enhanced SKILLZ-Club. Those&#xD;
      schools randomized to standard SKILLZ Girl curriculum will only have access to SOC clubs.&#xD;
      Those schools selected for enhanced SKILLS Girl curriculum will offer SKILLZ Club.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the small minority of girls found to be HIV-infected across all study schools, linkage to&#xD;
      care and on treatment, VLS, and retention in care will be evaluated for a period of two&#xD;
      years. These girls will be encouraged to continue in to the HIV positive-specific SKILLZ-Plus&#xD;
      facility-based curriculum. The impact of SKILLZ-Plus on linkage to care and treatment,&#xD;
      retention and viral load at 6, 12, and 24 months after diagnosis (or since participant is&#xD;
      identified by GRS as HIV+) will be quantitatively measured using SmartCare data and compared&#xD;
      to an existing matched cohort.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection plan and tools&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. SmartCare electronic data:&#xD;
&#xD;
           All antiretroviral therapy services offered to participants who are in the study are&#xD;
           captured in SmartCare, which permits measuring of utilization and clinical outcomes&#xD;
           (i.e., Linkage to Care, VLS) at soccer events, mobile clinics, and public clinics in&#xD;
           Lusaka. Consent will be requested from all participants as part of the consent process&#xD;
           to access their SmartCare records.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Youth-Friendly services electronic data:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Depending on the location of the school, the girl's residential address and/or personal&#xD;
           preferences, participants will be referred to either the PEPFAR Funded DREAMS houses or&#xD;
           the M.A.C. funded youth-friendly spaces based in local MOH clinics in order to access&#xD;
           ongoing SRH services after the events (this will include accessing PrEP, STI testing and&#xD;
           contraceptive methods). Consent will be requested from all participants as part of the&#xD;
           consent process to allow researchers to access either DREAMS or M.A.C data should they&#xD;
           chose to access either of these services.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Survey at baseline:&#xD;
&#xD;
           A baseline survey will be administered to all to collect information on school&#xD;
           characteristics, sexual behavior, age, HIV knowledge, maternal education, baseline HIV&#xD;
           status, and sexual/reproductive health uptake and retention. These variables will be&#xD;
           used as covariates and moderators for service uptake and retention. The target sample of&#xD;
           3,200 girls will respond to a self-administered survey using REDCap software upon&#xD;
           informed consent. The survey will be available in English, Nyanja and Bemba&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Survey post-SKILLZ-Girl event, 3-, 12-, and 24 months:&#xD;
&#xD;
           All girls (regardless of HIV status) will complete a REDCap survey to collect&#xD;
           information on sexual behavior, HIV knowledge, maternal education, sexual/reproductive&#xD;
           health uptake and retention. Post-SKILLZ-Girl survey data will be used to assess the&#xD;
           effect of SKILLS Girl and SKILLZ-Club on the outcomes of interest. In schools selected&#xD;
           to offer SKILLZ-Club, surveys will be conducted during club attendance approximately 3&#xD;
           months after the SKILLZ-Girl community soccer event; coaches will help them navigate the&#xD;
           survey. If a participant has opted to not attend the clubs or has since left or changed&#xD;
           schools, the coaches and study staff will attempt to trace participants in the community&#xD;
           in order to complete the follow-up survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Qualitative methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Through a phenomenological and narrative study approach, the study aims to understand&#xD;
           factors involved in decision-making for uptake by learning from girls about how&#xD;
           psychological, social and structural factors affected their health decisions also&#xD;
           including personal beliefs, perceptions and motives. Additionally, the study will&#xD;
           document individual stories (narrative approach) regarding how HIV infected girls&#xD;
           experience the mediating factors (such as stigma, disclosure, social support and trust&#xD;
           in the health facility) and how they affect their adherence to care&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Extraction of GRS programmatic data:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Quantitative measurements coming from programmatic GRS data (e.g., frequency and attendance&#xD;
      at SKILLZ-Plus meetings, frequency of home visits) will be collated from reports,&#xD;
      supplemented with interviews of implementing staff (e.g., program managers and coordinators,&#xD;
      coaches) to track key process indicators.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data management and storage&#xD;
&#xD;
      Quantitative:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Individual-level data will be collected on clinical, laboratory, and demographic&#xD;
      characteristics, including retention in care and VLS at 6, 12 and 24 months. Using case&#xD;
      reporting forms (CRFs), the team will collect study-specific data, including information&#xD;
      obtained directly from participants, routine programmatic data from GRS and abstract routine&#xD;
      clinical data from paper-based medical records, the SmartCare Electronic Management Records&#xD;
      (EMR), CIDRZ Laboratory Information Management System (LIMS) and DREAMS electronic management&#xD;
      system. Routinely collected individual-level clinical data are first written onto forms in&#xD;
      the paper medical record and then entered into the SmartCare EMR. SmartCare serves as a&#xD;
      repository of clinical data for HIV-infected individuals and includes such data fields as:&#xD;
      ART initiation date, ART regimen, visit dates, and laboratory data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      GRS will collect programmatic data through a combination of paper and electronic data entry&#xD;
      via tablets, with all data stored securely in RedCap. Where paper files are used for&#xD;
      programmatic management, data will be manually entered by study staff directly into the&#xD;
      RedCap database. De-identified data will made available to GRS co-investigators to enable&#xD;
      review of key fidelity and quality indicators in order to monitor implementation in real&#xD;
      time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All paper study files will be stored in secured, locked cabinets located in locked rooms&#xD;
      available to study staff only. A secure server will be used to store encrypted study data,&#xD;
      including the study database. All personal identifiers will be removed prior to generating&#xD;
      the analytical dataset.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Qualitative:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All data will be obtained using digital audio recorders. Recorded data will be transferred on&#xD;
      to a lockable computer kept by the co-principal investigator leading the qualitative&#xD;
      research. Transcripts will go through a QA/QC process where researchers will cross check&#xD;
      randomly selected transcribed verbatim with the recordings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data analysis plan The primary outcome is the probability of testing for HIV at any time&#xD;
      during the period when SKILLZ is delivered through to 24 months after the final soccer event.&#xD;
      The primary analysis for Aim 1 will follow a difference-in-difference (DID) effect between&#xD;
      study arms. The outcome of interest will be regressed on an indicator of study arm assignment&#xD;
      interacted with a dichotomous variable POST which indicates the outcome after the&#xD;
      intervention is implemented; this differentiates baseline and end-line for each study arm,&#xD;
      controls for any time dependent variables that might confound the effect, as well as any&#xD;
      time-invariant observed or unobserved confounders that might differ between study arm&#xD;
      schools. Clustering by school will be accounted for by a generalized estimating equation&#xD;
      approach. Intention-to-treat (ITT) will be evaluated by including all girls in the evaluation&#xD;
      cohort assigned to each arm rather than all girls who actually participated in SKILLZ.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Stepped (dynamic interval given school schedule) implementation design at the school level. Randomization at the school level defines a school as receiving arm one or arm two.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants undergoing HIV testing within 24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants, enrolled in the study, undergoing HIV testing (HIVST our Determine tests) over 2 years. Collected from facility testing registers and community testing registers.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants accessing SRH related prevention services within 24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants, enrolled in the study, accessing contraception, PreP or PEP over 2 years. Determined through the electronic medical record and clinic registers.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of HIV infected participants being virally suppressed at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants, testing HIV positive, who have an undetectable viral load (as defined by the laboratory doing the test) after one year on treatment. Collected from routine laboratory data.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of HIV infected participants retained in care at 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants, testing HIV positive, who are actively retained in care at 3 months ie are not more than 7 days late for a scheduled appointment. Determined using the electronic medical record.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of HIV infected participants retained in care at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants, testing HIV positive, that have made their scheduled visit to the clinic within the first at 6 months of enrolment. (less than 7 days late), using the electronic medical record.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of HIV infected participants retained in care at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants, testing HIV positive, who attend their scheduled visits within the first 12 months of enrolment (less than seven days late). determined through the electronic medical record.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Conduct a process evaluation to describe how the intervention worked</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>FGD's, IDI's and routine program data ( attendance registers, process data and documented observations) will be used to identify mediators, predictors, and barriers to uptake of the SKILLZ package after implementation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Average short-term costs for the program implementation based on net-costs for the intervention.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Costs will include the personnel to manage the intervention, financial incentives and other related miscellaneous costs. These will be collected by the program manager and study team and will be based on actual costs.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fidelity monitoring or adherence to the program as measured by the number of coaching sessions conducted per plan.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Each session that is conducted will be documented including number of participants in attendance (assessed voia attendance registers and routine program data).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Identify barriers that prevent intervention participation</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Record and track key barriers through review of routine program data that prevent participants from engaging with the intervention. ie through review of the data collected by coaches from feedback from participants, FGD's and IDI's. During this COVID-19 period, we may be limited or may need to revise our anticipated collection of study results. The study record will reflect these changes as we navigate through the course of the study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">3200</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <condition>Pregnancy Related</condition>
  <condition>STI</condition>
  <condition>Mental Health Wellness 1</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SOC Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard of care (SOC) SKILLZ-Girl Curriculum implemented with subsequent encouragement to be involved with pre-existing clubs at their school</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Enhanced Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Enhanced SKILLZ-Girl Curriculum, including an enhanced event (including HIVST + access to family planning) with subsequent encouragement to be involved with SKILLZ-Clubs at their school</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SKILLZ-Girl Enhanced football curriculum</intervention_name>
    <description>Participation in the enhanced SKILLZ-Girl curriculum and SKILLZ-Club</description>
    <arm_group_label>Enhanced Arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The student is &gt;16 years of age prior to the first session of SKILLZ-Girl or the&#xD;
             student will turn 16 years of age before the last session of SKILLZ-Girl (ie prior to&#xD;
             the event)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is enrolled in one of the SKILLZ STUDY schools&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is able to converse in and comprehend either Nyanja, English and/or Bemba&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The Parent/Guardian of the participant has consented for the participant to take part&#xD;
             in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The student has a mental disability that would interfere with their ability to give&#xD;
             informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carolyn Bolton, MPH, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UAB/ CIDRZ</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Carolyn Dr Bolton, MPH, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+26096841034</phone>
    <email>carolyn.bolton@cidrz.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Nancy Dr Padian, MPH, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+15109261387</phone>
    <email>nancy.padian@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre of Infectious Disease Research Zambia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lusaka</city>
        <zip>10101</zip>
        <country>Zambia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carolyn Bolton</last_name>
      <phone>+260966841034</phone>
      <email>carolyn.bolton@cidrz.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Zambia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 9, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 9, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 11, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Carolyn Bolton</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Adolescents</keyword>
  <keyword>Zambia</keyword>
  <keyword>Football</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>De-identified IPD will be shared via secure server to co-investigators</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data will be shared with requisite co-investigators on a rolling basis in order to conduct interim analysis</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Must be a co-investigator</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>August 20, 2019</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/61/NCT04429061/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

