<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3424">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04692779</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ProneARDS</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04692779</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Prospective Clinical Study to Explore Response to Prone Positioning in ARDS Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective Clinical Study to Explore the Mechanism of Patients' Response to Prone Positioning in ARDS Patients, Including COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rush University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rush University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The proposed study will be conducted to investigate the mechanism of patients' responses to&#xD;
      prone positioning with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) acute respiratory distress&#xD;
      syndrome (ARDS) and non-COVID-19 ARDS utilizing lung ultrasound.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective observational study of adult patients with coronavirus disease 2019&#xD;
      (COVID-19) acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) and non-COVID-19 ARDS who are&#xD;
      intubated, in the prone position and receiving mechanical ventilation in the intensive care&#xD;
      units at Rush University Medical Center. In this study design, we will prospectively enroll&#xD;
      subjects, who fulfill eligibility criteria, to investigate the mechanism of their responses&#xD;
      to the first three prone positioning sessions, utilizing lung ultrasound (LUS). Inclusion&#xD;
      criteria include: adult subjects 18 years and older with a diagnosis of ARDS, endotracheally&#xD;
      intubated and receiving assisted mechanical ventilation, meet criteria for prone positioning&#xD;
      (ratio of arterial oxygen tension to the fraction of inspired oxygen (PaO2/FiO2) of ≤ 150 mm&#xD;
      Hg with ventilator parameters of positive end-expiratory pressure (PEEP) ≥ 10 cm H2O and FiO2&#xD;
      of .60, and order for prone positioning. Patients will be excluded from the study if they&#xD;
      meet the following criteria: pregnant, tracheostomy, receiving extracorporeal membrane&#xD;
      oxygenation (ECMO), palliative care, received prone positioning more than once during&#xD;
      intubation in an outside hospital, or receive invasive ventilation in an outside hospital for&#xD;
      more than 72 hours. Enrolled subjects will undergo LUS 1 hour before and 1 hour after prone&#xD;
      positioning by a trained clinician and will be assessed using a LUS score based on LUS&#xD;
      pattern. LUS will then be performed again 1 hour before supination (16 hours) and assessed by&#xD;
      a LUS score. This process will be repeated on the first 3 prone sessions. Patients will be&#xD;
      enrolled in the study for 4 weeks in order to observe patient outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Oxygenation and Lung Ultrasound Score (LUS)</measure>
    <time_frame>10 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patients' responses of oxygenation and lung ultrasound score (0 - 36 where 0 = normal lung aeration and 36 = most severe lung consolidation) to prone positioning in the first three prone positioning sessions for ARDS patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 ARDS vs non-COVID-19 ARDS</measure>
    <time_frame>10 months</time_frame>
    <description>observed lung ultrasound score (0 - 36 where 0 = normal lung aeration and 36 = most severe lung consolidation) differences between patients who respond to prone positioning and those who do not respond among patients with COVID-19 ARDS and non-COVID-19 ARDS.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>ARDS</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intubated ARDS patients undergoing prone positioning</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lung Ultrasound (LUS)</intervention_name>
    <description>Enrolled subjects will undergo LUS 1 hour before and 1 hour after prone positioning by a trained clinician and will be assessed using a LUS score based on LUS pattern. LUS will then be performed again 1 hour before supination (16 hours) and assessed by a LUS score. This process will be repeated on the first 3 prone sessions. Patients will be enrolled in the study for 4 weeks in order to observe patient outcomes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intubated ARDS patients undergoing prone positioning</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Intubated adults (18 years or older) with a diagnosis of ARDS receiving mechanical&#xD;
        ventilation and meet criteria for prone positioning.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adult subjects 18 years and older, diagnosis of ARDS&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. endotracheally intubated and receiving assisted mechanical ventilation&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. meet criteria for prone positioning: PaO2/FIO2 (P/F ratio) of ≤ 150 mm Hg with&#xD;
             ventilator parameters of PEEP ≥ 10 cm H2O and FiO2 of .60&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. receive an order for prone positioning.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Tracheostomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Receiving ECMO&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Palliative care&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Receive prone positioning more than once during intubation in an outside hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Receive invasive ventilation in an outside hospital for more than 72 hours&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tyler Weiss</last_name>
    <phone>312-947-3027</phone>
    <email>Tyler_Weiss@rush.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Arbelot C, Ferrari F, Bouhemad B, Rouby JJ. Lung ultrasound in acute respiratory distress syndrome and acute lung injury. Curr Opin Crit Care. 2008 Feb;14(1):70-4. doi: 10.1097/MCC.0b013e3282f43d05. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18195629</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Bouhemad B, Brisson H, Le-Guen M, Arbelot C, Lu Q, Rouby JJ. Bedside ultrasound assessment of positive end-expiratory pressure-induced lung recruitment. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2011 Feb 1;183(3):341-7. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201003-0369OC. Epub 2010 Sep 17.</citation>
    <PMID>20851923</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Bouhemad B, Zhang M, Lu Q, Rouby JJ. Clinical review: Bedside lung ultrasound in critical care practice. Crit Care. 2007;11(1):205. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17316468</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Doerschug KC, Schmidt GA. Intensive care ultrasound: III. Lung and pleural ultrasound for the intensivist. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2013 Dec;10(6):708-12. doi: 10.1513/AnnalsATS.201308-288OT.</citation>
    <PMID>24364779</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Haddam M, Zieleskiewicz L, Perbet S, Baldovini A, Guervilly C, Arbelot C, Noel A, Vigne C, Hammad E, Antonini F, Lehingue S, Peytel E, Lu Q, Bouhemad B, Golmard JL, Langeron O, Martin C, Muller L, Rouby JJ, Constantin JM, Papazian L, Leone M; CAR'Echo Collaborative Network; AzuRea Collaborative Network. Lung ultrasonography for assessment of oxygenation response to prone position ventilation in ARDS. Intensive Care Med. 2016 Oct;42(10):1546-1556. doi: 10.1007/s00134-016-4411-7. Epub 2016 Jun 20.</citation>
    <PMID>27324241</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Prat G, Guinard S, Bizien N, Nowak E, Tonnelier JM, Alavi Z, Renault A, Boles JM, L'Her E. Can lung ultrasonography predict prone positioning response in acute respiratory distress syndrome patients? J Crit Care. 2016 Apr;32:36-41. doi: 10.1016/j.jcrc.2015.12.015. Epub 2015 Dec 30.</citation>
    <PMID>26806842</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Wang XT, Ding X, Zhang HM, Chen H, Su LX, Liu DW; Chinese Critical Ultrasound Study Group (CCUSG). Lung ultrasound can be used to predict the potential of prone positioning and assess prognosis in patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome. Crit Care. 2016 Nov 30;20(1):385.</citation>
    <PMID>27899151</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Arentz M, Yim E, Klaff L, Lokhandwala S, Riedo FX, Chong M, Lee M. Characteristics and Outcomes of 21 Critically Ill Patients With COVID-19 in Washington State. JAMA. 2020 Apr 28;323(16):1612-1614. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.4326.</citation>
    <PMID>32191259</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Chen N, Zhou M, Dong X, Qu J, Gong F, Han Y, Qiu Y, Wang J, Liu Y, Wei Y, Xia J, Yu T, Zhang X, Zhang L. Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of 99 cases of 2019 novel coronavirus pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a descriptive study. Lancet. 2020 Feb 15;395(10223):507-513. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30211-7. Epub 2020 Jan 30.</citation>
    <PMID>32007143</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Zhao J, Hu Y, Zhang L, Fan G, Xu J, Gu X, Cheng Z, Yu T, Xia J, Wei Y, Wu W, Xie X, Yin W, Li H, Liu M, Xiao Y, Gao H, Guo L, Xie J, Wang G, Jiang R, Gao Z, Jin Q, Wang J, Cao B. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020 Feb 15;395(10223):497-506. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5. Epub 2020 Jan 24. Erratum in: Lancet. 2020 Jan 30;:.</citation>
    <PMID>31986264</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Wang D, Hu B, Hu C, Zhu F, Liu X, Zhang J, Wang B, Xiang H, Cheng Z, Xiong Y, Zhao Y, Li Y, Wang X, Peng Z. Clinical Characteristics of 138 Hospitalized Patients With 2019 Novel Coronavirus-Infected Pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA. 2020 Mar 17;323(11):1061-1069. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.1585.</citation>
    <PMID>32031570</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Wu C, Chen X, Cai Y, Xia J, Zhou X, Xu S, Huang H, Zhang L, Zhou X, Du C, Zhang Y, Song J, Wang S, Chao Y, Yang Z, Xu J, Zhou X, Chen D, Xiong W, Xu L, Zhou F, Jiang J, Bai C, Zheng J, Song Y. Risk Factors Associated With Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome and Death in Patients With Coronavirus Disease 2019 Pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA Intern Med. 2020 Jul 1;180(7):934-943. doi: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2020.0994. Erratum in: JAMA Intern Med. 2020 Jul 1;180(7):1031.</citation>
    <PMID>32167524</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Yang X, Yu Y, Xu J, Shu H, Xia J, Liu H, Wu Y, Zhang L, Yu Z, Fang M, Yu T, Wang Y, Pan S, Zou X, Yuan S, Shang Y. Clinical course and outcomes of critically ill patients with SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia in Wuhan, China: a single-centered, retrospective, observational study. Lancet Respir Med. 2020 May;8(5):475-481. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30079-5. Epub 2020 Feb 24. Erratum in: Lancet Respir Med. 2020 Apr;8(4):e26.</citation>
    <PMID>32105632</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Guérin C, Reignier J, Richard JC, Beuret P, Gacouin A, Boulain T, Mercier E, Badet M, Mercat A, Baudin O, Clavel M, Chatellier D, Jaber S, Rosselli S, Mancebo J, Sirodot M, Hilbert G, Bengler C, Richecoeur J, Gainnier M, Bayle F, Bourdin G, Leray V, Girard R, Baboi L, Ayzac L; PROSEVA Study Group. Prone positioning in severe acute respiratory distress syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2013 Jun 6;368(23):2159-68. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1214103. Epub 2013 May 20.</citation>
    <PMID>23688302</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Munshi L, Del Sorbo L, Adhikari NKJ, Hodgson CL, Wunsch H, Meade MO, Uleryk E, Mancebo J, Pesenti A, Ranieri VM, Fan E. Prone Position for Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome. A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2017 Oct;14(Supplement_4):S280-S288. doi: 10.1513/AnnalsATS.201704-343OT. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29068269</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Marini JJ, Hurford WE. Should Early Prone Positioning Be a Standard of Care in ARDS With Refractory Hypoxemia? Wrong Question-Reply. Respir Care. 2016 Nov;61(11):1564-1565.</citation>
    <PMID>27794087</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Scholten EL, Beitler JR, Prisk GK, Malhotra A. Treatment of ARDS With Prone Positioning. Chest. 2017 Jan;151(1):215-224. doi: 10.1016/j.chest.2016.06.032. Epub 2016 Jul 8. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27400909</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kallet RH. A Comprehensive Review of Prone Position in ARDS. Respir Care. 2015 Nov;60(11):1660-87. doi: 10.4187/respcare.04271. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26493592</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Reilly JP, Calfee CS, Christie JD. Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome Phenotypes. Semin Respir Crit Care Med. 2019 Feb;40(1):19-30. doi: 10.1055/s-0039-1684049. Epub 2019 May 6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31060085</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Gattinoni L, Chiumello D, Caironi P, Busana M, Romitti F, Brazzi L, Camporota L. COVID-19 pneumonia: different respiratory treatments for different phenotypes? Intensive Care Med. 2020 Jun;46(6):1099-1102. doi: 10.1007/s00134-020-06033-2. Epub 2020 Apr 14.</citation>
    <PMID>32291463</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Robba C, Battaglini D, Ball L, Patroniti N, Loconte M, Brunetti I, Vena A, Giacobbe DR, Bassetti M, Rocco PRM, Pelosi P. Distinct phenotypes require distinct respiratory management strategies in severe COVID-19. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2020 Aug;279:103455. doi: 10.1016/j.resp.2020.103455. Epub 2020 May 11. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32437877</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Weiss TT, Cerda F, Scott JB, Kaur R, Sungurlu S, Mirza SH, Alolaiwat AA, Kaur R, Augustynovich AE, Li J. Prone positioning for patients intubated for severe acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) secondary to COVID-19: a retrospective observational cohort study. Br J Anaesth. 2021 Jan;126(1):48-55. doi: 10.1016/j.bja.2020.09.042. Epub 2020 Oct 10.</citation>
    <PMID>33158500</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rush University Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Tyler Weiss</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Education Coordinator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Prone positioning</keyword>
  <keyword>Lung ultrasound</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

