<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4721">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04618926</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PROTECTOR</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04618926</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Comparison of Fiberoptic Endotracheal Intubation Between the Intubating Laryngeal Tube Suction and the LMA Protector</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective Randomized Study Comparing Fiberoptic Bronchoscope Endotracheal Intubation Between the Intubating Laryngeal Tube Suction and the LMA Protector</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bnai Zion Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bnai Zion Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Securing the airway is a pivotal skill for anesthesiologists and emergency care providers.&#xD;
      Endotracheal intubation (ETI) is considered the gold standard for securing the airway.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When ETI via laryngoscopy has failed, the use of a supraglottic airway device (SGAD) has been&#xD;
      recommended. The intubating Laryngeal Tube Suction-Disposable and the LMA Protector are a new&#xD;
      step in the evolution of supraglottic airways. Both SGADs are enable to ventilation and&#xD;
      oxygenation, but the ventilation channel allow the insertion of an endotracheal tube and the&#xD;
      use of fiberoptic bronchoscope. The aim of this study is to compare the time of fiberoptic&#xD;
      intubation through the intubating Laryngeal Tube Suction Disposable and the LMA Protector in&#xD;
      adult patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Detailed Description: Securing the airway is a pivotal skill for anesthesiologist and&#xD;
      emergency providers. Endotracheal intubation (ETI) is considered the gold standard for&#xD;
      securing the airway. Induction time during anesthesia may sometimes present unexpected&#xD;
      difficulties during ETI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When ETI via laryngoscopy has failed, the use of a supraglottic airway device (SGAD) has been&#xD;
      recommended. Previous studies suggested that compare intubation with laryngoscope, SGADs&#xD;
      enables rapid and effective airway control. Improved second generation SGADs enable&#xD;
      ventilation and oxygenation, but also include a second channel that separates the trachea&#xD;
      from the esophagus preventing aspiration. According with the results of the Fourth National&#xD;
      Audit Project of the Royal College of Anesthetist will bets and the Difficult Airway Society,&#xD;
      the second generation SGADs should be uses instead the first generation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some of the second generations of SGADs have a ventilation channel that allow the insertion&#xD;
      of an endotracheal tube.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two of these devices recently introduced in the market are the intubating Laryngeal Tube&#xD;
      Suction Disposable (iLTS-D) and the Laryngeal Mask Airway Protector [5, 6] The intubating&#xD;
      Laryngeal Tube Suction- Disposable (iLTS-D) (VBM, Germany) is a new updated version of the&#xD;
      Laryngeal Tube-Suction Disposable (LTS-D). [5] It has a ventilator channel with a 13.5mm&#xD;
      internal diameter, which enables the passage of an Endotracheal Tube (ETT) No 7.5 mm. for&#xD;
      fiberoptic guidance. Similarly to the LTS-D, the iLTS-D also has a separate channel for&#xD;
      gastric tubes placement up to a size of 18 Fr. The device is latex free, made of PVC, and&#xD;
      like the original laryngeal tube (LT), can be inserted blindly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The iLTS-D comes in one size. According to the depth of insertion, the device will be&#xD;
      equivalent to size 4 for patients 175 to 190 cm tall, or size 5 for patients taller than 190&#xD;
      cm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The LMA Protector™ Airway (Teleflex Ireland) will be a new step in the evolution of&#xD;
      supraglottic airways. This is a single use device made mainly of silicone. The LMA Protector&#xD;
      is designed to provide an opportunity to insert a tracheal tube of proper size through the&#xD;
      device without the need of any special technique. [6] It is a PVC, double- lumen tube. One&#xD;
      lumen will be used for ventilation and the others for gastric tube placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The ventilation channel has the ability to pass an ETT 7.5 mm with a fiberscope. The LMA&#xD;
      Protector will be provide in sizes from 3, 4 and 5. The size 3 will be for patient of weight&#xD;
      30 to 50 Kg, the size 4 to patients of weight from 50 to 70 Kg and the size 5 to patients of&#xD;
      weight 70 to 100 Kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Unlike the most of the second generation SGAD the LMA Protector possesses a shortand&#xD;
      wide-bore preformed airway tube. Thwill be allows passage of wide internal diameter ETTs. It&#xD;
      will be currently one of the few second-generation .SADs together with the iLTS-D that can&#xD;
      also act as a conduit for endotracheal intubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The two SGDs will be inserted blindly with its distal tip positioned in the upper esophagus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this be study will be to compare the time of fiberoptic intubation through the&#xD;
      intubating Laryngeal Tube Suction Disposable and the LMA Protector in adult patients. The&#xD;
      procedures will be performed by anesthesiologist with no previous experience with these two&#xD;
      devices.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We hypothesized that the time needed for first-attempt successful fiberoptic-guided&#xD;
      intubation with the two novel SADs would not differ by more than 10 s.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MATERIALS AND METHODS The study will obtain the approval of the Bnai Zion Medical Center&#xD;
      Clinical Research Ethics Committee and will be obtain the registration from the&#xD;
      ClinicalTrials.gov We will recruit patients if they have ≥18 years of age and of American&#xD;
      Society of Anesthesiologic (ASA) physical status 1-2. Exclusion criteria included patients&#xD;
      who have predicted to a difficult airway, who has any contraindication to the use of an SAD,&#xD;
      weight &gt; 90 Kg, aspiration risk and pregnancy woman.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After written informed consent , patients will be assigned, using a computer-generated&#xD;
      randomized list, to having their airway intubated fibreopticaly through either an LMA&#xD;
      Protector or iLTS-D. Patients will be blinded as to their allocation group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intubation will be performed by two experienced anesthesiologist, defined as having more&#xD;
      than 10 years of clinical experience since the commencement of specialty and expert with&#xD;
      Supraglottic Devices and fiberscope intubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All anesthesiologist involved in this study will participate in a standardized educational&#xD;
      program and practice on an airway manikin and patients. Anesthesiologist will completed &gt;10&#xD;
      uses on each device prior to the study either in simulators and patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The size of the LMA Protector was chosen by the intubating anesthesiologist based on the&#xD;
      patient's weight and airway assessment. Size 3 to patient weighs of 30 to 50 Kg and size 4 to&#xD;
      patient weight of 50 to 70 Kg. and 5 to patient weight of 70 to 100 Kg. The iLTS-D has only&#xD;
      one size with marks in the proximal end of the device with the number 4 or 5 in order to&#xD;
      guide the insertion more deep or more superficial according with the height of the patients.&#xD;
      Number 4, color red, to adult height of 155-180 cm and number 5, color purple, to adult&#xD;
      height of &gt; 180 cm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For each participant the following data will be recorded preoperatively: age, sex, height,&#xD;
      weight, ASA physical status, predictors for difficult airway (Mallampati score, thyromental&#xD;
      distance), and type of surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After 3 minutes of pre-oxygenation with 100% oxygen to reach an end-tidal O2 ≥70 %, patients&#xD;
      will be given induction agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anesthesia will be induced with up to 2-3 mg/kg propofol, 3mcg/kg fentanyl and maintained&#xD;
      with 70% nitrous oxide/30% oxygen and sevofluorane. Neuromuscular blockade will be obtained&#xD;
      with rocuronium bromide 0.6 mg/kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After complete muscle paralysis (train of four = 0), the allocated SAD will be inserted by&#xD;
      the study anesthesiologist according to the manufacturer's instructions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The time to effective SGAD insertion will be define by the time between the devices was in&#xD;
      the level of the lip patients until the CO2 waveform will be observed on the monitor display.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When more than one insertion attempt will be require, the patient will be receive&#xD;
      bag-and-mask ventilation between attempts. A fail insertion attempt will be defined as&#xD;
      complete withdrawal of the device from the mouth following an unsuccessful placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After two attempts the device will be deemed to have fail and the study protocol will be&#xD;
      stop.The treating anesthetesiologist will then proceeded with the airway management of their&#xD;
      choosing according to the needs of the patient and the surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After achieving satisfactory ventilation via the allocated SAD, fibreoptic-guided tracheal&#xD;
      intubation will be start.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A fiberscope (Karl Storz, Tuttlingen, Germany) with an outer diameter of 4.8 mm was used in&#xD;
      all fiberoptic-guided procedures. All intubations will be perform with a disposable&#xD;
      Endotracheal Tube with a low pressure, high volume cuff (VBM Medizintechnik GmbH, Sulz,&#xD;
      Germany) with an internal diameter of 7.5 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The flexible fiberscope will be loaded with the tracheal tube (TT), and advanced 2 cm beyond&#xD;
      the TT for guidance. The participant will advance the fiberscope to the end of the SAD and&#xD;
      the glottis will be view and assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The scope will be insert into the trachea, the ETT will be railroad into the trachea, and the&#xD;
      fibrescope will be then remove. Proper placement of the ETT will be confirm clinically and by&#xD;
      the presence of the end tidal CO2 trace. The SAD will be then removed according to the&#xD;
      manufacturer's instructions. After this maneuver the position of the ETT relative to the&#xD;
      carina will be assessed bronchoscopicaly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A maximum of two attempts will be s allowed with fibreoptic guided intubation. An alternative&#xD;
      airway management plan could be instituted at the criterion by the anesthesiologist if a&#xD;
      failed intubation is encountered after two attempts with the allocated device. The time of&#xD;
      fiberscope intubation will be defined how the time when the fiberoscope is inserted in the&#xD;
      ventilation channel of the SGAD until the presence of the CO2 waveform trace in the display&#xD;
      of the monitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome variable will be the total time to achieve successful fibreoptic&#xD;
      intubation through the SADs (time to insertion of the SAD plus time to fibreoptic TI).&#xD;
      Secondary variables included the following: SAD insertion time; TT insertion time; intubation&#xD;
      success rate, and glottic view according to the Fiber-Optic Scoring System proposed by&#xD;
      Brimacombe et al. In order to standardize the assessment of the SGD position (4 = only vocal&#xD;
      cords seen; 3 = vocal cords plus posterior epiglottwill be seen; 2 = vocal cords plus&#xD;
      anterior epiglottis seen; 1= vocal cords not seen), maneuvers performed to achieve TI&#xD;
      (up-down mobilization or side to side mobilization) and Likert scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The anesthesiologist will be asked to rate the ease of use of the fiberscope-guided technique&#xD;
      on a Likert scale for each technique, using the statement: ''The TT was easily inserted into&#xD;
      the trachea'' (1 = strongly agree, 2 = disagree, 3 = neither agree nor disagree, 4 = agree, 5&#xD;
      = strongly agree) (8).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis will be performed. The primary outcome will be time to fiberoptic-guided&#xD;
      TI. Based on the pilot study, the investigator expected to obtain a large Cohen's d effect&#xD;
      size corresponding to a time difference of at least 10 s, relative to the observed standard&#xD;
      deviations (SDs) (9). In order to achieve a statistical significance for such mean time&#xD;
      differences when using a repeated-measures procedure with an overall significance level of&#xD;
      0.05 (a = 0.05/3 for each pair with the Bonferroni adjustment) and a power of 0.8, a sample&#xD;
      size of 24 would be necessary. The statistical power was calculated using G*Power free,&#xD;
      version 3.0.10 (Franz Faul, University of Kiel, Kiel, Germany). A repeated-measures model was&#xD;
      used to compare the mean time measurements (SAD insertion time, time to TI, and total time to&#xD;
      secure the airway using fiberscope intubation technique among the two devices.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Categorical data were analyzed with nonparametric Friedman's two-way analysis of variance&#xD;
      test. If the results were statistically significant at a 5% significance level, the tests&#xD;
      were followed by post-hoc multiple compare between each pair of study devices. The paired&#xD;
      t-test was used to analyze continuous data, and the Sign test was used to compare two&#xD;
      dependent samples of categorical data sets.&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to Bonferroni multiple comparison adjustments, when comparing each pair of devices,&#xD;
      p values &lt;0.017 were considered statistical significant. SPSS, version 20 (SPSS Inc., IBM&#xD;
      Corp.) was used for statistical analysis be. Continuous data will be presented as mean (SD).&#xD;
      Categorical data will be presented as n (%)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>time of success fiberoptic endotracheal intubation</measure>
    <time_frame>60 seconds</time_frame>
    <description>seconds</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Difficult Airway</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>intubating Laryngeal Tube Suction Disposable</arm_group_label>
    <description>intubating Laryngeal Tube Suction Disposable Airway control</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>intubating laryngeal Tube suction Disposable</arm_group_label>
    <description>intubating laryngeal Tube Suction Disposable</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Device intubating Laryngeal Tube Suction Disposable</intervention_name>
    <description>Resuscitation in covid 19 patients</description>
    <arm_group_label>intubating Laryngeal Tube Suction Disposable</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>intubating laryngeal Tube suction Disposable</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Device LMA Protector</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        We will recruit patients if they are ≥18 years of age and of American Society of&#xD;
        Anesthesiologists (ASA) physical status 1-2&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with normal airway&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. weight 50-90kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. AGE 18-75&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. ASA I-II&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. predicted difficult airway&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. weight &gt; 90 Kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. aspiration risk&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. pregnancy woman.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mostafa Somri, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Bnai Zion Medical Center Haifa Israel</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Luis Gaitini, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>#972506223999</phone>
    <email>luis.gaitini@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Mostafa Somri, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>#972506267289</phone>
    <email>somri_m@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 6, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 10, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 10, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Bnai Zion Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>LUIS.GAITINI</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Clinical Professor of Anesthesiology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>iLTS-D, LMA Protector, Fiberoptic intubation</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

