<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2789">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04328480</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>COLCOVID version 2.0</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04328480</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The ECLA PHRI COLCOVID Trial. Effects of Colchicine on Moderate/High-risk Hospitalized COVID-19 Patients.</brief_title>
  <acronym>COLCOVID</acronym>
  <official_title>The ECLA PHRI COLCOVID Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Estudios Clínicos Latino América</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Population Health Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Estudios Clínicos Latino América</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The ECLA PHRI COLCOVID Trial is a simple, pragmatic randomized open controlled trial to test&#xD;
      the effects of colchicine on moderate/high-risk hospitalized COVID-19 patients with the aim&#xD;
      of reducing mortality and/or new requirement for mechanical ventilation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Various anti-viral treatments are being tested in clinical trials worldwide. The World Health&#xD;
      Organization (WHO) launched a simple,pragmatic worldwide open-label trial to test Remdesivir,&#xD;
      Lopinavir/Ritonavir, Interferon and Hydroxychloroquine or Chloroquine.The most important&#xD;
      complication of COVID-19 severe cases is respiratory failure from severe acute respiratory&#xD;
      syndrome (SARS), the leading cause of mortality. Accumulating evidence suggests that patients&#xD;
      with severe COVID-19 might have a cytokine storm syndrome, a hyperinflammatory syndrome&#xD;
      characterized by a fulminant and fatal hypercytokinemia and multiorgan failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The proposed pathophysiological mechanism of cytokine storm and inflammatory cascade&#xD;
      activation is based on evidence collected primarily during the SARS-CoV and MERS-CoV&#xD;
      epidemics (with a significant increase in IL1B, IL6, IL12, IFNγ, IP10, TNFα, IL15, and IL17&#xD;
      among others). The data collected during the pandemic with COVID-19 also shows a significant&#xD;
      increase in inflammatory cytokines (GCSF, IP10, MCP1, MIP1A, and TNFα, among others) in&#xD;
      sicker patients admitted to intensive care. In the absence of effective treatments for the&#xD;
      management of patients with COVID-19 and respiratory failure, the immunomodulatory and&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory effect of colchicine on cytokines involved in the hyper-inflammatory state&#xD;
      is postulated. Several lines of research worldwide are testing powerful anti-inflammatory&#xD;
      drugs for the pandemic, with different options including steroids, cytokine blockers, and&#xD;
      other potent anti-inflammatory agents. Steroids are partially contraindicated in viral&#xD;
      infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Colchicine is a powerful anti-inflammatory drug approved for the treatment or prevention of&#xD;
      gout and Familial Mediterranean Fever at doses ranging between 0.3 mg and 2.4 mg/day. Its&#xD;
      mechanism of action is through the inhibition of tubulin polymerization, as well as through&#xD;
      potential effects on cellular adhesion molecules and inflammatory chemokines. It might also&#xD;
      have direct anti-inflammatory effects by inhibiting key inflammatory signalling networks&#xD;
      known as inflammasome and pro-inflammatory cytokines. Additionally, evidence suggests that&#xD;
      colchicine exerts a direct anti-inflammatory effect by inhibiting the synthesis of tumor&#xD;
      necrosis factor alpha and IL-6, monocyte migration, and the secretion of matrix&#xD;
      metalloproteinase-9. Through the disruption of the cytoskeleton, colchicine is believed to&#xD;
      suppress secretion of cytokines and chemokines as well as in vitro platelet aggregation. All&#xD;
      these are potentially beneficial effects that might diminish or ameliorate the COVID-19&#xD;
      inflammatory storm associated with severe forms of the disease. Importantly, in one&#xD;
      contemporary trial low-dose colchicine administered to patients who survived from acute&#xD;
      coronary syndrome shows a statistically significantly reduction of cardiovascular&#xD;
      complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We have therefore designed in a simple, pragmatic randomized controlled trial to test the&#xD;
      effects of colchicine on severe hospitalized COVID-19 cases with the aim of reducing&#xD;
      mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size calculation:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A minimum sample size of 1200 patients will provide 80% power to detect a relative risk&#xD;
      reduction of approximately 30% in the treated group if the assumed composite rate (new&#xD;
      requirement of intubation and / or death) in the control group is about 24%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The ECLA PHRI COLCOVID Trial allows randomization to another trial, specifically patients&#xD;
      included in the trial might be (or not) randomized to an antithrombotic strategy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 17, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Simple pragmatic randomized open controlled trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Composite outcome: New requirement for mechanical ventilation or death</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who require new intubation for mechanical ventilation or die</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who die</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>In hospital - Composite outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>During hospitalization or until death, whichever comes first, assessed up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who require intubation for mechanical ventilation or die</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>In hospital - Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>During hospitalization or until death, whichever comes first, assessed up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who die</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Highest WHO descriptive score of COVID-19 during hospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>During hospitalization or until death, whichever comes first, assessed up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Mean highest WHO descriptive score of COVID-19 in the active treatment group compared to the placebo group</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean WHO descriptive score of COVID-19 during hospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>During hospitalization or until death, whichever comes first, assessed up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Mean WHO descriptive score of COVID-19 in the active treatment group compared to the placebo group</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Composite outcome (New requirement for mechanical ventilation or death) evaluated in Non-intubated population</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who were not intubated at randomization and require new intubation for mechanical ventilation or die</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality evaluated in Non-intubated population</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who were not intubated at randomization and die</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1200</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Local standard of care plus colchicine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Local standard of care plus colchicine (specific dosage schedule)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Local standard of care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Local standard of care for COVID-19 SARS moderate / high-risk patients</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Colchicine</intervention_name>
    <description>The colchicine dosage schedule will vary according to the following scenarios:&#xD;
In patients not receiving Lopinavir/Ritonavir&#xD;
Loading dose of 1.5 mg followed by 0.5 mg after two hours (day 1)&#xD;
The next day 0.5 mg bid for 14 days or until discharge.&#xD;
In patients receiving Lopinavir/Ritonavir&#xD;
Loading dose of 0.5 mg (day 1)&#xD;
After 72 hours from the loading dose, 0.5 mg every 72 hours for 14 days or until discharge.&#xD;
Patients under treatment with Colchicine that are starting with Lopinavir/Ritonavir&#xD;
Dose of 0.5 mg 72 hours after starting Lopinavir/Ritonavir.&#xD;
Continue with 0.5 mg every 72 hours for 14 days or until discharge.&#xD;
Only the oral route will be used except in the case of patients associated with mechanical ventilation or with contraindications to the oral route, in whom it will be administered by nasogastric tube.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Local standard of care plus colchicine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Colchicina</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Local standard of care</intervention_name>
    <description>Local standard of care for COVID-19 SARS moderate /high-risk patients</description>
    <arm_group_label>Local standard of care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Local standard of care plus colchicine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria (case definition)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consented adults (age ≥18 years) and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 suspicious and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Admitted to hospital or already in hospital and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 suggestive symptoms (fever or febrile equivalent, loss of smell and taste,&#xD;
             fatigue, etc.) that may be present or absent at randomization time and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SARS (severe acute respiratory syndrome)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  shortness of breath (dyspnea) or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  image of typical or atypical pneumonia or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  oxygen desaturation (SpO2 ≤ 93)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clear indication or contraindication for the use of colchicine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding female.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic renal disease with creatinine clearance &lt;15 ml/min/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative PCR test for SARS-COV2&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rafael Diaz, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>ECLA- ICR</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andres Orlandini, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+ 54 341 4450210</phone>
    <email>aorlandinimd@eclainternational.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Rafael Diaz, MD</last_name>
    <email>rdiazmd@eclainternational.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sanatorio Parque</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rosario</city>
        <state>Santa Fe</state>
        <zip>2000</zip>
        <country>Argentina</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Luciano Lovesio</last_name>
      <email>lucianolovesio@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Carolina Bozikovich</last_name>
      <email>bozikovichcarolina@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Carolina Bozikovich</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Luciano Lovesio</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.who.int/dg/speeches/detail/who-director-general-s-opening-remarks-at-the-media-briefing-on-covid-19---18-march-2020</url>
    <description>WHO opening remarks</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Slobodnick A, Shah B, Krasnokutsky S, Pillinger MH. Update on colchicine, 2017. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2018 Jan 1;57(suppl_1):i4-i11. doi: 10.1093/rheumatology/kex453. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29272515</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tardif JC, Kouz S, Waters DD, Bertrand OF, Diaz R, Maggioni AP, Pinto FJ, Ibrahim R, Gamra H, Kiwan GS, Berry C, López-Sendón J, Ostadal P, Koenig W, Angoulvant D, Grégoire JC, Lavoie MA, Dubé MP, Rhainds D, Provencher M, Blondeau L, Orfanos A, L'Allier PL, Guertin MC, Roubille F. Efficacy and Safety of Low-Dose Colchicine after Myocardial Infarction. N Engl J Med. 2019 Dec 26;381(26):2497-2505. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1912388. Epub 2019 Nov 16.</citation>
    <PMID>31733140</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yusuf S, Collins R, Peto R. Why do we need some large, simple randomized trials? Stat Med. 1984 Oct-Dec;3(4):409-22.</citation>
    <PMID>6528136</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>McDermott MM, Newman AB. Preserving Clinical Trial Integrity During the Coronavirus Pandemic. JAMA. 2020 Jun 2;323(21):2135-2136. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.4689.</citation>
    <PMID>32211830</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mehta P, McAuley DF, Brown M, Sanchez E, Tattersall RS, Manson JJ; HLH Across Speciality Collaboration, UK. COVID-19: consider cytokine storm syndromes and immunosuppression. Lancet. 2020 Mar 28;395(10229):1033-1034. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30628-0. Epub 2020 Mar 16.</citation>
    <PMID>32192578</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 30, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 31, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Colchicine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

