<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1767">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04395768</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Alliance-COVID19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04395768</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>International ALLIANCE Study of Therapies to Prevent Progression of COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Therapies to Prevent Progression of COVID-19, Including Hydroxychloroquine, Azithromycin, Zinc, Vitamin D, Vitamin B12 With or Without Vitamin C, a Multi-centre, International, Randomized Trial: The International ALLIANCE Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Integrative Medicine, Australia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institute of Integrative Medicine, Australia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      COVID-19 is a global pandemic. So far encouraging results have been shown in different parts&#xD;
      of the world with the utilisation of hydroxycloroquine, zinc, and azithromycin, and early&#xD;
      studies into some of these, plus some with Vitamin C, have also proven beneficial. Vitamin D&#xD;
      levels have also been shown to be an important indicator to the severity of symptoms in&#xD;
      COVID-19 patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Design&#xD;
&#xD;
      Type of study A multi-centre, open-label, randomized controlled trial evaluating the efficacy&#xD;
      and safety of therapy with azithromycin, hydroxychloroquine, zinc, vitamin D3/B12 and IV&#xD;
      vitamin C compared with azithromycin, hydroxychloroquine, zinc, vitamin D3/B12 in&#xD;
      participants with COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Expected number of participants The sample size for the study is a minimum of 100&#xD;
      participants in each arm. However, this sample size may change as this trial has an adaptive&#xD;
      design.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Allocation procedure Randomization: Eligible patients that have provided informed written&#xD;
      consent will be randomized by independent researcher. Randomization will be in randomly&#xD;
      permuted blocks (undisclosed sizes to maintain concealment of allocation). The allocation&#xD;
      will be communicated to site personnel and participants will be made aware of their&#xD;
      assignment. It is not practical to use placebo in this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stratification: randomization will be stratified by site and age (65 years or younger, over&#xD;
      65 years of age).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Duration of the study period for each subject Participants will be followed for 45 days from&#xD;
      the time of randomization. Data of events occurring during hospital will be obtained from&#xD;
      hospital records supplemented by a telephone call or follow up at 7-10 days and at 45 days&#xD;
      after randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adaptive design features&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adaptive intervention arms: The Steering Committee will keep abreast of other ongoing trials&#xD;
      and if other promising interventions emerge, may recommend adding (or replacing) one arm with&#xD;
      the new promising intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adaptive sample size: Sample size calculations are based on disease progression rates that&#xD;
      are not well known. The investigators remain flexible, and the Data Safety Committee (DSMC)&#xD;
      will be monitoring the possibility that the assumptions for sample size calculations may be&#xD;
      modified with emerging information from this trial or other ongoing trials. If recruitment is&#xD;
      going well, the steering committee may decide to extend recruitment as long as the&#xD;
      independent DSMC does not terminate the trial for clear evidence of efficacy, futility (low&#xD;
      probability) to detect a clinically meaningful difference (e.g. a 20% RRR in events) or&#xD;
      concerns about safety.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Procedures Direct electronic data entry will be utilized in this trial. The&#xD;
      investigators will use Redcap platform and software (www.project-redcap.org).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consenting process Due to the stringent measures in infection control in hospitals,&#xD;
      digitalised consent will be obtained instead of written consent on paper. Be this preferably&#xD;
      from the patient or his legal representative. All patients will be in strict contact and&#xD;
      droplet precautions and there may be an imperative to minimise use of personal protective&#xD;
      equipment (PPE) by staff due to resource limitations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The consenting process will be as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The clinical team will inform a potential participant in the trial that an investigator&#xD;
           will contact them&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To minimise PPE use, the investigator will make telephone contact with the patient. If&#xD;
           an interpreter is required for the consent discussion, this will be by the telephone&#xD;
           interpreter service. An informed consent discussion will be held with each participant&#xD;
           by a site investigator or their delegate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The Patient Information Sheet and Consent form (PICF) will be emailed to the patient or&#xD;
           the clinical team will take it into the room for viewing by the patient. These documents&#xD;
           will be left in the patient's room&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The participant will be given time to ask questions and consider whether to participate&#xD;
           in the research.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Verbal consent will be recorded in both the participant's medical record and study&#xD;
           consent form. This will state that the terms and conditions were all read and agreed to&#xD;
           and all questions asked were answered. The full PICF, including the signed consent page&#xD;
           (by the investigator), will be uploaded into the electronic database.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the patient is too unwell or is unable to use a digital device, to personally give&#xD;
           consent, written consent can be obtained from their next of kin, or other adult family&#xD;
           members, or partner or legal representative.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The following day, the investigator or clinical team will verbally confirm with the&#xD;
           participant that they have consented to participate. A copy of the signed consent form&#xD;
           will then either be emailed to the participant or sent via post. The participant, their&#xD;
           next of kin or legal representative will send a return email confirming their consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Interventions&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blinding: Participants and healthcare providers will not be blinded to treatment. To account&#xD;
      for this, the investigators have objective outcome definitions to minimize the opportunity&#xD;
      for bias to influence event assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consenting participants will be randomized to receive therapy with azithromycin,&#xD;
      hydroxychloroquine, zinc, Vitamin D3/B12 and IV vitamin C or azithromycin, zinc and&#xD;
      hydroxychloroquine, Vitamin D3/B12.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For further details see: Arms &amp; Interventions&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will place no constraints for treating physicians on the therapies with&#xD;
      respect to usual care. The investigators will document information on all key&#xD;
      co-interventions, including information on drugs at the time of randomization and post&#xD;
      randomization /during hospitalization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection The investigators will collect participant sex, age, disease severity,&#xD;
      comorbidities (smoking, diabetes, heart disease, lung disease, immunosuppression, etc.),&#xD;
      other medications, and trial outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in this trial will be swabbed (nasal and/or oral) on approximately days 0, 3 and&#xD;
      7 for quantitative polymerase chain reaction (PCR) assessment of viral titre.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Outcomes For details see primary &amp; secondary outcome section.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, the investigators will collect data on:&#xD;
&#xD;
      WHO Master Protocol ordinal score at day 15:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Not hospitalized, no limitations on activities&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Not hospitalized, limitation on activities;&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Hospitalized, not requiring supplemental oxygen;&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Hospitalized, requiring supplemental oxygen;&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Hospitalized, on non-invasive ventilation or high flow oxygen devices;&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Hospitalized, on invasive mechanical ventilation or ECMO;&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Death.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary safety outcomes&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  QTc prolongation (&gt;500ms) 24 hours following initial dose of study drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Serious ventricular arrhythmia (including ventricular fibrillation) or sudden unexpected&#xD;
           death in hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Any of the following adverse events in first 10 days from enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Diarrhoea - grade 2 or greater&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Nausea - grade 2 or greater&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Vomiting - grade 2 or greater&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Considerations&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size calculation The minimum sample size required is N=100 in each intervention arm in&#xD;
      order to have 80% statistical power to detect a 30% relative risk reduction (RRR) in the&#xD;
      proportion progressing to mechanical ventilation or death, assuming a standard-of-care risk&#xD;
      of progression of 30%. Since participants will be hospitalized, a minimal (&lt;1%) loss to&#xD;
      follow-up is assumed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis methods The primary analysis of efficacy will be conducted under the&#xD;
      intention-to-treat principle; all randomized participants will be included in the analyses.&#xD;
      All results will be analyzed with 2-sided level of significance of 0.05.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 9, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>randomized investigator-blinded controlled</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participants not blinded as they will know whether they are receiving the comparator vitamin c (either IVC) or oral in addition to treatments in the control group; outcomes assessor / investigators conducting statistical analysis will be blinded</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>once daily for 15 days since enrollment/baseline at admission to hospital</time_frame>
    <description>Composite measure: Change in severity and duration of symptoms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of hospital stay</measure>
    <time_frame>at 15 and 45 days since admission/ enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>total number of days in hospital since admission</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>invasive mechanical ventilation or mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>any time within 15 days from enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>need for invasive mechanical ventilation or mortality within 15 days from enrolment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>15 and 45 days since enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>Death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>mechanical ventilation</measure>
    <time_frame>at 15 and 45 days since enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>need for and number of days of invasive mechanical ventilation, in case of no need for mechanical ventilation: days=0</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>oxygen</measure>
    <time_frame>15 and 45 days since enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>need for and number of days for humidified high-flow oxygen</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ICU</measure>
    <time_frame>15 and 45 days since enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>admission to ICU (intensive care unit)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>days in hospital</measure>
    <time_frame>15 and 45 days since enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>days in hospital</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>days in ICU</measure>
    <time_frame>15 and 45 days since enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>days in ICU</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>renal replacement therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>15 and 45 days since enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>need for and days of renal replacement therapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Extracorporeal support</measure>
    <time_frame>15 and 45 days since enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>need for and days of Extracorporeal support</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vitamin C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive vitamin C in addition to active comparator treatment:&#xD;
Inpatients: IV Vitamin C (Sodium Ascorbate) 50mg/kg every 6hrs on day 1 followed by 100mg/kg every 6hrs (4x per day; 400mg/kg/day) for 7 days (average 28g/day; maximum dose of 50g/24hrs for those weighing more than 125kg). Can be converted to 1 gram three times per day PO on hospital discharge) Outpatients: Vitamin C Outpatient trial: 200mg/kg x1 IV, then 1 gram PO three times per day for 7 days;&#xD;
Plus Active Comparator treatment:&#xD;
Hydroxychloroquine Hydroxychloroquine 400mg (2x200mg) PO for 1 day, followed by 200mg PO per day for 6 days Azithromycin 500 mg PO on day 1 followed by 250 mg PO once daily for 4 days Zinc Citrate 30mg elemental zinc PO daily Vitamin D3 5,000iu PO daily for 14 days Vitamin B12 (Methylcobalamin) 500mcg PO daily for 14 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Hydroxychloroquine Hydroxychloroquine 400mg (2x200mg) PO for 1 day, followed by 200mg PO per day for 6 days Azithromycin 500 mg PO on day 1 followed by 250 mg PO once daily for 4 days Zinc Citrate 30mg elemental zinc PO daily Vitamin D3 5,000iu PO daily for 14 days Vitamin B12 (Methylcobalamin) 500mcg PO daily for 14 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vitamin C</intervention_name>
    <description>In addition to the active comparator, which is a combination of 2 drugs and 3 dietary supplements, the experimental treatment arm will also receive Vitamin C (intravenous or oral)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vitamin C</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Sodium ascorbate</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hydroxychloroquine</intervention_name>
    <description>Active comparator group will receive: a combination of 2 drugs and 3 dietary supplements</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Vitamin C</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Plaquenil</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Azithromycin</intervention_name>
    <description>Active comparator group will receive: a combination of 2 drugs and 3 dietary supplements</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Vitamin C</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Z-Pak</other_name>
    <other_name>Zithromax</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Zinc Citrate</intervention_name>
    <description>Active comparator group will receive: a combination of 2 drugs and 3 dietary supplements</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Vitamin C</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vitamin D3</intervention_name>
    <description>Active comparator group will receive: a combination of 2 drugs and 3 dietary supplements</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Vitamin C</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cholecalciferol</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vitamin B12</intervention_name>
    <description>Active comparator group will receive: a combination of 2 drugs and 3 dietary supplements</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Vitamin C</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Methylcobalmin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Provision of informed consent in writing, can be electronic&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Diagnosis of active COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Known G6PD deficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Contra-indication to hydroxychloroquine, azithromycin or Vitamin C: allergy to study&#xD;
             interventions, epilepsy, serious hearing or visual problems, history of severe&#xD;
             depression, calcium oxalate stones, advanced liver disease, pregnancy or lactating&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Already receiving chloroquine, azithromycin, &gt;3 grams Vitamin C daily or an&#xD;
             experimental antiviral&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of fever (e.g. night sweats, chills) and/or acute respiratory infection (e.g.&#xD;
             cough, shortness of breath, sore throat) of more than 7 days' duration. Note, if study&#xD;
             numbers not quickly reached, the investigators may decide to include those with&#xD;
             symptoms of longer than 7 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Calculated creatinine clearance of &lt; 30 mL/minute&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Baseline ECG showing: QTc ≥470 for males, QTc ≥480 for females&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Receipt of a drug known to increase QTc: quetiapine, amiodarone, sotalol&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Karin Ried, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Integrative Medicine, Australia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Karin Ried, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0061399129545</phone>
    <email>karinried@niim.com.au</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Taufiq Binjemain, MD</last_name>
    <phone>0061498049362</phone>
    <email>tbinjemain@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institute of Integrative Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Melbourne</city>
        <state>Victoria</state>
        <zip>3122</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Karin Ried, PhD</last_name>
      <email>karinried@niim.com.au</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 19, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 20, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 9, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 9, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 11, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID19</keyword>
  <keyword>hydroxychloroquine</keyword>
  <keyword>azithromycin</keyword>
  <keyword>zinc</keyword>
  <keyword>Vit-D3</keyword>
  <keyword>B12</keyword>
  <keyword>C</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Disease Progression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cholecalciferol</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ascorbic Acid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vitamin B 12</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hydroxocobalamin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Azithromycin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hydroxychloroquine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

