<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3822">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04407208</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>3471041S322342020040800002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04407208</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Convalescent Plasma Therapy in Patients With COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Convalescent Plasma Therapy in Patients With COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Biofarma</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Rumah Sakit Pusat Angkatan Darat Gatot Soebroto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eijkman Institute for Molecular Biology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Biofarma</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Scientists and medical workers all around the world were running out of time to manage&#xD;
      COVID-19. Several studies have been done to understand the disease and ultimately to find&#xD;
      possible treatment. Based on those studies, one of the potential treatment was antibody&#xD;
      transfer from recovered COVID-19 patients. Passive antibody transfer was a fast and easy&#xD;
      choice. The rational use of antibody from the patient's plasma is a natural neutralizing&#xD;
      protein to the cell-infected virus and could possibly slow the active infection down.&#xD;
      Investigators initiate an intervention study with purposes to produce quality convalescent&#xD;
      plasma from the recovered patients, define the safety of plasma for human use and as an&#xD;
      alternative treatment to improve the clinical outcomes of severe COVID-19 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study hypothesis is convalescent plasma is safe and could possibly improve outcome of&#xD;
      severe (non-critical) COVID-19 patients. This research will conduct the plaque reduction&#xD;
      neutralizing test (PRNT) of recipient blood in vitro. The plasma will be collected in the&#xD;
      blood transfusion unit (BTU) in Gatot Soebroto hospital. The storage, testing, transfer, and&#xD;
      transfusion of eligible convalescent plasma are the authority of Gatot Soebroto BTU. PRNT and&#xD;
      plasma antibody titer measurement from donor plasma will be conducted at Eijkman Institute of&#xD;
      Molecular Biology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investigators enroll approximately 10 patients consecutively, who will be admitted at Gatot&#xD;
      Soebroto hospital. Baseline demographic characteristics of samples are recorded. Clinical dan&#xD;
      laboratory data will be measured before and after plasma transfusion periodically. The&#xD;
      measured variables are pharmacological therapy (antivirus, antibiotics, steroids), invasive&#xD;
      oxygen therapy, oxygen index, sequential organ failure assessment (SOFA) score, and&#xD;
      laboratory parameters such as leukocyte count, blood chemical panel include liver and renal&#xD;
      function, C-reactive protein, procalcitonin, IL-6 and immunoglobulin titer of the recipient&#xD;
      and also chest X-ray evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The potential expected risk of plasma transfusions is transfusion reaction (immunological or&#xD;
      non-immune related) and transferred foreign pathogen. Investigator will report and treat all&#xD;
      adverse events after plasma transfusion has been done. A severe adverse event (SAE) will also&#xD;
      report in a special form to sponsor and data safety monitoring board (DSMB). There is&#xD;
      theoretically antibody-dependent enhancement (ADE) mechanism from COVID-19 whom will receive&#xD;
      plasma transfusion to progress to severe immune response.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This preliminary study is supposed to provide supporting data and experience of plasma&#xD;
      processing to a larger study in the near future.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The rational use of antibodies from the recovered patient's plasma as a natural neutralizing&#xD;
      antibody to the cell-infected virus (plaques). Several expanded use of convalescent plasma&#xD;
      therapy to severe and/or critically ill COVID-19 patients had been done in the US and China.&#xD;
      Investigator reported that 5 patients received convalescent plasma, three patients were&#xD;
      successfully discharged and 2 patients improved.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on the previous study, investigators initiate an intervention study with purposes to&#xD;
      produce quality convalescent plasma from the recovered patients and to find an alternative&#xD;
      treatment to improve the clinical outcomes of severe COVID-19 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investigators research questions are&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Are the convalescent plasma could neutralize cell-infected virus in vitro?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Are those COVID-19 patients who received convalescent plasma will have a better&#xD;
           prognosis and possibly be cured? The Investigator study hypothesis is convalescent&#xD;
           plasma could possibly cure severe (non-critical) COVID-19 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective of this study is to produce a good quality convalescent plasma from&#xD;
      recovered COVID-19 patient which could neutralize the plaque in vitro and in Vivo. In Vivo&#xD;
      neutralization will be monitored based on the patient's clinical improvement of symptoms,&#xD;
      laboratory, and radiology assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Invitro tests will be done to the recipient plasma before and after convalescent plasma&#xD;
      transfusion. The objective evaluation will be a plaque reduction neutralizing test (PRNT) of&#xD;
      recipient plasma. Donor plasma will be collected by apheresis methods at the Gatot Soebroto&#xD;
      Blood transfusion unit (BTU).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All donors must meet the eligibility criteria and sign an informed consent form. Donor's&#xD;
      plasma will be screened for blood-borne infection pathogens in BTU. Each donor will produce&#xD;
      210 ml of plasma, which 200 ml will be stored in 2 separate bags (each 100 ml) and 3 ml of&#xD;
      plasma will be tested for antibody anti-COVID-19 titer in Biofarma and 3 ml of plasma will be&#xD;
      tested for PRNT in Eijkman Institute. Plasma transfusion will be given to COVID-19 patients&#xD;
      with severe (IIb) and critical conditions. The storage, testing, transfer, and transfusion of&#xD;
      eligible convalescent plasma are the authority of Gatot Soebroto BTU. Investigators enroll&#xD;
      approximately 10 patients consecutively, who will be admitted at Gatot Soebroto hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All recipients will be enrolled consecutively if they met the eligibility criteria. Baseline&#xD;
      demographic characteristics of the included patient are recorded in case report forms.&#xD;
      Clinical and laboratory data will be measured before the plasma transfusion. Pre-transfusion&#xD;
      patients will be put in group 1. Whereas group 2 is the same patient but received the&#xD;
      convalescent plasma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Transfusions will be given twice in 100 ml bag, during the 1st 4 hours, the acute adverse&#xD;
      event will be monitored. There will be three serial transfusions, on the 1st day, 3rd day,&#xD;
      and 6th day. The clinical, laboratory and radiology parameters will be re-measured after&#xD;
      the14th day and they will be analyzed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data analysis will be done after all the measurement is finished and recorded in clinical&#xD;
      report form. Investigators will find the mean difference of ordinal variables between group 1&#xD;
      and group two with the Wilcoxon signed-rank test (alternative to the paired T-test). The&#xD;
      relative risk (risk reduction) of nominal variables will be measured between group 1 and&#xD;
      group 2. Unfortunately, it is impossible to determine the number needed to harm (NNH) in this&#xD;
      research since both groups are depending on each other.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All documents regarding the study will be kept in data form and will be protected with a&#xD;
      password. We will concern about the safety of convalescent plasma by recording all adverse&#xD;
      events after transfusion. To anticipate the risk of AE progression to a severe adverse event&#xD;
      (SAE), all of the AE will be treated as soon as it is found according to the clinical&#xD;
      competence of treating physicians. SAE will be reported in a certain form to sponsor and data&#xD;
      safety monitoring board as soon as possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investigators are all aware of the potential ethical issue regarding this study. The plasma&#xD;
      convalescent is an alternative therapy for COVID-19, and urgently needed because of the&#xD;
      pandemic situation currently happen. Investigators are weighing all potential expected and&#xD;
      theoretical risks and benefits of convalescent plasma transfusion. The potential expected&#xD;
      risk of plasma transfusions is transfusion reaction (immunological or non-immune related) and&#xD;
      transferred unwanted pathogen. The theoretical risk from plasma transfusion of COVID-19&#xD;
      patient is an antibody-dependent enhancement (ADE) mechanism as seen in dengue patients. A&#xD;
      Potential benefit of plasma for the patient is the neutralizing potential of a polyclonal&#xD;
      antibody to cell infected SARS-Cov2. Resulting in faster recovery and improvement of the&#xD;
      disease stages.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All donors will read the informed consent form thoroughly and willingly given their plasma&#xD;
      draw at Gatot Soebroto BTU. The donor could revoke his/her consent at any time before being&#xD;
      transfused, even after the plasma has been processed and stored in BTU. Donor's decision will&#xD;
      not affect his/her future treatment at Gatot Soebroto hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This preliminary study is supposed to provide supporting data and experience of plasma&#xD;
      processing to a larger study in the near future.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 22, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 22, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>single-arm, pre, and post-test dependent group</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Plaque reduction neutralization test (PNRT)</measure>
    <time_frame>day 7 after first transfusion</time_frame>
    <description>PNRT50</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>D-dimer</measure>
    <time_frame>day 1,4,7,14 after first transfusion</time_frame>
    <description>Change of D-dimer compared between pre and post transfusion</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>C-Reactive Protein (CRP)</measure>
    <time_frame>day 1,4,7,14 after first transfusion</time_frame>
    <description>Change of CRP compared between pre and post transfusion</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>International Normalized Ratio (INR)</measure>
    <time_frame>day 1,4,7,14 after first transfusion</time_frame>
    <description>Change of INR compared between pre and post transfusion</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Oxygenation Index</measure>
    <time_frame>day 1,4,7,14 after first transfusion</time_frame>
    <description>Change of OI compared between pre and post transfusion</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Chest X-ray</measure>
    <time_frame>day 1,4,7,28 after first transfusion</time_frame>
    <description>Change of CXR with CXR covid score compared between pre and post transfusion</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>severe adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>from day 0 to 14 days after plasma transfusion</time_frame>
    <description>every adverse event that cause patient to die, prolonged hospitalization or worsening clinical stage of illness</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Convalescence</condition>
  <condition>Corona Virus Infection</condition>
  <condition>Plaque</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Convalescent plasma recipient</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Recipients receive 3 times of each 100 ml convalescent plasma on day 0, 3, and 6</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Convalescent plasma</intervention_name>
    <description>The minimum titer of specific antibody is 1/80</description>
    <arm_group_label>Convalescent plasma recipient</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed COVID-19 case with RT-PCR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stage IIb of COVID-19 or higher&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consent was given by the patient or legal guardian&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of anaphylactic reaction in previous blood product transfusion&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nana Sarnadi, Sp.OG</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>director of research and develpment</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gatot Soebroto central army presidential hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jakarta Pusat</city>
        <zip>10410</zip>
        <country>Indonesia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Indonesia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.thelancet.com/action/showPdf?pii=S0140-6736%2820%2930566-3</url>
    <description>Clinical course and risk factors for mortality of adult inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: a retrospective cohort study</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2762130</url>
    <description>Characteristics of and Important Lessons From the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Outbreak in China</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(20)30183-5/fulltext</url>
    <description>Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>June 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 27, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 27, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 30, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Biofarma</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>dr. Marliana Sri Rejeki, Sp.FK</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Medical doctor, clinical pharmacologist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>convalescent plasma</keyword>
  <keyword>treatment</keyword>
  <keyword>severe ill</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Convalescence</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>May 27, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/08/NCT04407208/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

