<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1115">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04703790</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AAAT5154</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04703790</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Acceptability of a COVID-19 Vaccine Among US Adults Over Two Time Periods</brief_title>
  <official_title>Acceptability Across Two Time Periods of a SARS-CoV-2 Vaccine Among a Representative Sample of Adults Within the United States</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Columbia University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Columbia University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The overall purpose of this study is to address the factors associated with an individual's&#xD;
      personal willingness to get the vaccine and attitudes about potential public policy&#xD;
      approaches to implementation of a Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) vaccine. Additionally,&#xD;
      to evaluate how these attitudes change over time. The 1200 participants will be recruited by&#xD;
      Ipsos (Ipsos KnowledgePanel®) from their nationally representative panel to participate in a&#xD;
      survey at Time 1 and 1 year later. The information collected will include demographics,&#xD;
      health status, household composition, experiences with COVID-19, attitudes about vaccines in&#xD;
      general, COVID-19 vaccine specific attitudes, willingness to get a COVID-19 vaccine&#xD;
      acceptability, and attitudes regarding COVID-19 vaccine mandates. The investigators&#xD;
      anticipate that those who live in urban areas and who are older, have greater knowledge of&#xD;
      COVID-19, who have known someone who was hospitalized for COVID-19, and have generally&#xD;
      positive attitudes about vaccines will be more willing to get a vaccine. The primary reasons&#xD;
      for willingness will be personal safety and desire to return to normal activities. The&#xD;
      investigators also anticipate that those who vary on socio-demographics (e.g., live in urban&#xD;
      areas, have more liberal political views), have greater knowledge of COVID-19, who have known&#xD;
      someone who was hospitalized for COVID- 19, and have generally positive attitudes about&#xD;
      vaccines will be more supportive of mandatory vaccination strategies. The investigators&#xD;
      anticipate that attitudes will change over time in response to the current status of the&#xD;
      pandemic and of available data about the vaccine's efficacy and safety.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The overall objective is to address attitudes about potential public policy approaches to&#xD;
      implementation of a Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) vaccine and&#xD;
      the factors associated with an individual's personal willingness to get the vaccine once&#xD;
      available, and to assess how these attitudes change over time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      First specific aim:&#xD;
&#xD;
      1a. To describe participants' perceptions of public health strategies including mandatory&#xD;
      vaccination requirements (e.g., travel, school attendance, work place requirements (e.g.,&#xD;
      schools, health care facilities, offices), working in a health care facility, health care&#xD;
      providers, living in residential facilities) and targeted age groups (e.g., children,&#xD;
      adolescents, adults, elderly).&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. b. To determine how attitudes about strategies are related to socio-demographic&#xD;
           characteristics (e.g., age, education, race/ethnicity, political views and political&#xD;
           party affiliation, household structure), knowledge of SARS-CoV-2, personal experience&#xD;
           with the infection, and other vaccine attitudes.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Example hypothesis: Those who vary on socio-demographics (e.g., live in urban areas,&#xD;
           have more liberal political views), have greater knowledge of SARS-CoV-2, who have known&#xD;
           someone who was hospitalized for SARS-CoV-2, and have generally positive attitudes about&#xD;
           vaccines will be more supportive of mandatory vaccination strategies.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Second specific aim:&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. a. To determine the relationship of socio-demographic characteristics (e.g., age,&#xD;
           education, race/ethnicity, political views and political party affiliation, household&#xD;
           structure), knowledge of SARS-CoV-2, personal experience with the infection, and other&#xD;
           vaccine attitudes with willingness to get the vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2b. To evaluate the primary reasons driving vaccine acceptance including safety issues&#xD;
      (personal, family, or global), desire to return to normal activities (e.g., school, work, or&#xD;
      social events), and desire to no longer need to wear a mask.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Example hypotheses: Those who vary on socio-demographic characteristics (e.g., live in urban&#xD;
      areas, who are older), have greater knowledge of SARS-CoV-2, who have known someone who was&#xD;
      hospitalized for SARS-CoV-2, and have generally positive attitudes about vaccines will be&#xD;
      more willing to get a vaccine. The primary reasons for willingness will be personal safety&#xD;
      and desire to return to normal activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Third specific aim: This specific aim focuses on how the findings from aim 1 and aim 2 change&#xD;
      over time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3a. To evaluate how national level perceptions of public health strategies (aim 1) and an&#xD;
      individual's personal willingness to get the vaccine (aim 2) change over time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given the unknown trajectory, there are several possible scenarios. For example, if&#xD;
      nationally there is a decrease in new infections with lifting of the restrictions then the&#xD;
      investigators hypothesize that there will be an overall decrease in support for mandatory&#xD;
      strategies and in willingness to accept the vaccine. Alternatively, if new infections are&#xD;
      rising and restrictions are in place, then there will be an overall increase in&#xD;
      acceptability. The investigators are also prepared to adapt our surveys should one or more&#xD;
      vaccines become licensed and available prior to the time 1 or time 2 survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3b. The investigators will explore whether changes in perceptions of public health strategies&#xD;
      (aim 1) and an individual's personal willingness to get the vaccine (aim 2) vary based on&#xD;
      relevant socio-demographic characteristics (e.g., region of the country, political views and&#xD;
      political party affiliation, household structure, race/ethnicity) and, when appropriate,&#xD;
      changes within those characteristics (e.g., when rates of infections are changing&#xD;
      differentially across regions). The investigators also will explore whether changes in&#xD;
      perceptions of public health strategies (aim 1) and an individual's personal willingness to&#xD;
      get the vaccine (aim 2) vary based on perceptions of societal events. For example, the&#xD;
      investigators will evaluate if changes in vaccine attitudes are associated with regional&#xD;
      differences in whether cases are increasing or decreasing; changes in household structure&#xD;
      (e.g., the presence of elders in the home); or perceptions of media reports.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intention to get vaccinated for COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Participants intention to get vaccinated for COVID-19 will be measured via survey items.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 vaccination received</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Participants self report of vaccine receipt on survey.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1200</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Vaccine Acceptability</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Adults from the United States</arm_group_label>
    <description>Adult participants 18 years of age or older who are panelists recruited and maintained by Ipsos (KnoweledgePanel). All participants live within the United States.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adults 18 years of age and older, who live in the US and who have been recruited to be&#xD;
        members of Ipsos (KnowledgePanel) survey research panel.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years of age and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to read English and Spanish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Panelists with Ipsos (KnowledgePanel)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  17 years of age and younger&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not able to read English or Spanish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not a member of Ipsos (KnowledgePanel)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Susan L Rosenthal, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Columbia University Irving Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jane A Andresen, BS</last_name>
    <phone>212-305-0272</phone>
    <email>ja3337@cumc.columbia.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Susan L Rosenthal, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>212-305-7175</phone>
    <email>slr2154@cumc.columbia.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Columbia University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Susan Rosenthal, PhD, ABPP</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

