<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2251">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04686747</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MH - COVID - AGICT</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04686747</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID - 19 and Advanced Gastro-intestinal Cancer Treatment</brief_title>
  <acronym>COVID - AGICT</acronym>
  <official_title>COVID - 19 and Advanced Gastro-intestinal Cancer Treatment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>S.M. Misericordia Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>S.M. Misericordia Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A multicenter Italian retrospective study on COVID-19 pandemic condition and advanced Gastro&#xD;
      - Intestinal Cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Are in Italy increased the new diagnosis of GI cancer in advanced stage in the 2020 compared&#xD;
      with 2019, as a consequence of COVID-19?&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. Background The ongoing COVID-19 pandemic condition had a catastrophic consequence on the&#xD;
           healthcare system. In order to contain the death from other diseases, such as cancer,&#xD;
           the healthcare system still fights a challenging battle focusing the attention on&#xD;
           COVD-19 without losing sight of other patient care. Routine screening and non urgent&#xD;
           surgeries reduced to increase capacity for COVID-19 patients complications. Moreover, it&#xD;
           must take into account the fear for COVID-19 exposure of patients during the routine&#xD;
           assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Nevertheless, death related to other causes is not decreased. Standard cancer screening&#xD;
           is decreased, such as colorectal cancer protocol which dropped by 84.5% through May&#xD;
           20201. As a consequence, according to London JW et al, the incidence of new cancer&#xD;
           diagnoses decreased of 65.2%. As matter of fact, the new diagnosis of melanoma dropped&#xD;
           by 67.1%, as well as the new diagnosis of lung cancer which dropped of 46.8%1 in April&#xD;
           2020 compared to one year earlier. Furthermore, the number of advanced gastrointestinal&#xD;
           cancers are supposed to be increased in the surgical community. As conventional wisdom,&#xD;
           the number of patients with locally advanced or metastatic gastrointestinal, as well as&#xD;
           patients needing an emergency or a palliative procedure (i.e., stoma, feeding&#xD;
           jejunostomy, gastroentero anastomosis) seems increased this year compared to 2019. These&#xD;
           therapeutic delays may influence the long-term survival of these patients. An increased&#xD;
           rate of related death is expected, rising from 15.5% to 16.6% and 4.8% to 5.3 % for&#xD;
           colorectal and lung cancer, respectively. This study aims to investigate whether the&#xD;
           main gastrointestinal cancers was diagnosed in a more advanced stage in 2020 compared to&#xD;
           2019 as a consequence of Covid-19 pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Methods This is a multicenter retrospective study that will include patients treated for&#xD;
           esophageal, gastric, pancreatic and colorectal cancer, from January 2019 to December&#xD;
           2020 in more than 50 Italian centers. All patients will be included in a&#xD;
           disease-specific database, which will be sent to each Italian reference center. A&#xD;
           minimum of 1.000 patient/year is expected to show a significative difference between the&#xD;
           considered years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of advanced Esophageal, Gastric, Pancreatic and Colorectal cancer in 2020 compared to 2019.</measure>
    <time_frame>From January 2019 to December 2020</time_frame>
    <description>The primary endpoint is to show if in Italy the number of cancer mentioned above, was diagnosed in a more advanced stage (i.e. &gt; I stage, Metastatic disease) in 2020 compared to 2019 as a consequence of COVID-19 pandemic condition.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of neo-adjuvant therapy in 2020 compared to 2019</measure>
    <time_frame>From January 2019 to December 2020</time_frame>
    <description>To show any difference in the rate of cancer related neo-adjuvant therapy in 2020 compared to 2019;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of palliative procedure in 2020 compared to 2019</measure>
    <time_frame>From January 2019 to December 2020</time_frame>
    <description>To show any difference in the rate of cancer related palliative procedures/ bridge therapy in 2020 compared to 2019, before starting with standard treatment;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of preoperative chemo or radiotherapy in 2020 compared to 2019 for metastatic disease.</measure>
    <time_frame>From January 2019 to December 2020</time_frame>
    <description>To show any difference of patients unable to performer cancer related preoperative chemo or radiotherapy in 2020 compared to 2019 due to scarce performance status or for symptomatic disease;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of patient unable to performer adjuvant treatment in 2020 compared to 2019</measure>
    <time_frame>From January 2019 to December 2020</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of patients unable to performer cancer related adjuvant therapy in 2020 compared to 2019 due to scarce performance status</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2000</enrollment>
  <condition>Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Gastric Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Esophagus Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Colorectal Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Esophageal Cancer</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Gastric Cancer</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pancreatic Cancer</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Colorectal Cancer</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This is a multicenter retrospective study that will include patients treated for&#xD;
        esophageal, gastric, pancreatic and colorectal cancer, from January 2019 to December 2020&#xD;
        in more than 50 Italian centers. In the study are included both patients treated with a&#xD;
        curative or palliative intent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients submitted to elective surgery for esophageal, gastric, pancreatic and&#xD;
             colorectal cancer in the year 2019-2020;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients submitted to emergency surgery/procedure (Interventional radiology,&#xD;
             endoscopic procedure) for complication (i.e. perforation, bleeding, occlusion)&#xD;
             secondary to esophageal, gastric, pancreatic and colorectal cancer in the year&#xD;
             2019-2020;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients submitted to palliative surgery/procedure (i.e. stoma, GEA, external biliary&#xD;
             drainage, feeding jejunostomy) for esophageal, gastric, pancreatic and colorectal&#xD;
             cancer in the year 2019-2020;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing preoperative chemo or radiation therapy for locally advanced or&#xD;
             metastatic esophageal, gastric, pancreatic and colorectal cancer in the year&#xD;
             2019-2020;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing to adjuvant therapy after esophageal, gastric, pancreatic and&#xD;
             colorectal cancer I surgery in the year 2019-2020&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under 18 years old and over 85 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with multiple tumors.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of General and Emergency Surgery. Misericordia Hospital. Director: Coratti Andrea, MD</name>
      <address>
        <city>Grosseto</city>
        <state>Tuscany</state>
        <zip>58100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 26, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 26, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 26, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 26, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 29, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ospedale della Misericordia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Giuliani Giuseppe</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Intestinal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

