<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1753">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04526977</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EC 273/20</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04526977</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Differences in Immune Response Among HIV-1-infected Individuals With Previous or Current COVID-19 (CoVIHDis).</brief_title>
  <acronym>CoVIHDis</acronym>
  <official_title>Differences in Susceptibility and Cytokine Profile, Specific CD4/CD8 T Cell Response, Toll Like Receptors (TLRs) and Killer Immunoglobulin-like Receptors (KIRs) Among HIV-1-infected Individuals With Previous or Current COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Asociacion para el Estudio de las Enfermedades Infecciosas</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Asociacion para el Estudio de las Enfermedades Infecciosas</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      People living with HIV could have different susceptibility and outcome to the SARS CoV-2&#xD;
      infection. The risk of SARS CoV-2 infection in this population could be no related to HIV&#xD;
      infection, immunodepression or antiretroviral therapy, but to the different susceptibility as&#xD;
      measured by ACE2 or CD26 receptors. Also, patients with HIV-1 infection could have different&#xD;
      cytokine profile and cellular immune response after SARS-CoV-2 infection, leading to a&#xD;
      differential outcome,&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Since March 2020, the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) pandemic&#xD;
      has affected almost five million people in 168 countries on five continents, with more than&#xD;
      300.000 deaths (1-4). The scientific evidence so far does not suggest that people with HIV-1&#xD;
      have an increased risk of serious complications if they develop COVID-19 disease (5-7). In&#xD;
      our recent work, we have shown in a few patients that people with HIV-1 under antiretroviral&#xD;
      treatment, with undetectable viral load and a CD4 count greater than 200 cells/mm3, do not&#xD;
      have a higher risk of developing serious complications than people without HIV-1, but also&#xD;
      HIV-1 infected patients does not seem to be protected of the so-called cytokine storm (8-11).&#xD;
      Like in the general population, they would be more likely to develop serious complications if&#xD;
      they are older and with previous pathologies (comorbidity), such as high blood pressure,&#xD;
      diabetes, cardiovascular disease, chronic lung disease, cancer or immunosuppression&#xD;
      (congenital, acquired or due to treatment with immunosuppressive drugs). Thus, people with&#xD;
      HIV-1 who are immunocompromised with a CD4 count less than 200 cells/mm3, regardless of&#xD;
      whether or not they take antiretroviral treatment should be considered among the vulnerable&#xD;
      groups and therefore at an increased risk of developing serious clinical complications&#xD;
      associated to COVID-19 (12-14). It should be noted, however, that, so far, there is no enough&#xD;
      scientific evidence that can confirm this possibility (10,15-17).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since March 2020, the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) pandemic&#xD;
      has affected almost five million people in 168 countries on five continents, with more than&#xD;
      300.000 deaths (1-4). The scientific evidence so far does not suggest that people with HIV-1&#xD;
      have an increased risk of serious complications if they develop COVID-19 disease (5-7). In&#xD;
      our recent work, we have shown in a few patients that people with HIV-1 under antiretroviral&#xD;
      treatment, with undetectable viral load and a CD4 count greater than 200 cells/mm3, do not&#xD;
      have a higher risk of developing serious complications than people without HIV-1, but also&#xD;
      HIV-1 infected patients does not seem to be protected of the so-called cytokine storm (8-11).&#xD;
      Like in the general population, they would be more likely to develop serious complications if&#xD;
      they are older and with previous pathologies (comorbidity), such as high blood pressure,&#xD;
      diabetes, cardiovascular disease, chronic lung disease, cancer or immunosuppression&#xD;
      (congenital, acquired or due to treatment with immunosuppressive drugs). Thus, people with&#xD;
      HIV-1 who are immunocompromised with a CD4 count less than 200 cells/mm3, regardless of&#xD;
      whether or not they take antiretroviral treatment should be considered among the vulnerable&#xD;
      groups and therefore at an increased risk of developing serious clinical complications&#xD;
      associated to COVID-19 (12-14). It should be noted, however, that, so far, there is no enough&#xD;
      scientific evidence that can confirm this possibility (10,15-17).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Indeed, there are two main questions for the management of this disease in this population,&#xD;
      the real incidence of COVID 19 (susceptibility) and if the immune response could be different&#xD;
      in those who were already coinfected.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. The differences in susceptibility to infection could be related to host factors. Thus,&#xD;
           it is important to characterize and genotyping the main receptor for SARS-CoV-2, ACE2,&#xD;
           and other related receptor, such as CD26, to explore the genetic background affecting&#xD;
           the real incidence of this disease, along CD4 count and antiretroviral therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. People with HIV-1 have an impaired immune system, especially in those with less than 200&#xD;
           CD4 cells/mm3. Hence, the immune response in these individuals could be weaker than in&#xD;
           general population, including the cytokine response reported after SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
           (18-20). In addition, the specific CD4/CD8 T cell response could be altered due to the&#xD;
           HIV-1 infection and the level of immunosuppression. This specific T cell response could&#xD;
           be a good marker for the presence or persistence of immunity against SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
           infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, the first line of immune defense is the interaction of the virus with innate&#xD;
      immunity cell members. The toll like receptors (TLRs) family is a group of pattern&#xD;
      recognition receptors that include many different molecules (21-23). These bindings can&#xD;
      activate dendritic cells, monocytes, macrophages. There is an important RNA and DNA&#xD;
      connection, activation of TLRs, the production of type I interferons, and the development of&#xD;
      some autoimmune diseases. TLR7 and TLR8 specifically recognize simple-chain RNA of viruses&#xD;
      and are expressed in endosomal membranes. TLR8 is expressed in regulatory cells (Treg) and&#xD;
      its activation results in inhibition of its regulatory functions. Natural killer cells (NK)&#xD;
      respond to alterations of class I HLA molecules present in infected cells (24-26). An&#xD;
      increase in class I HLA expression could lead to an increase in NK activation by increasing&#xD;
      its ability to produce IFN-gamma. Therefore, the reasons for KIR binding are often variable&#xD;
      between individuals and between populations. However, there are no data about TLRs activation&#xD;
      and KIRs binding in HIV infected patients with SARS CoV-2 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This project is designed to improve scientific knowledge and give answers to the actual&#xD;
      clinical questions regarding SARS-CoV-2 infection in people living with HIV-1. It could be of&#xD;
      importance to determine the risk of infection not related to HIV-related factors, and to&#xD;
      ascertain the adequation of the immune response of HIV infected patients after a SARS-CoV-2,&#xD;
      identifying therefore those at risk of severe disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 10, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in immune cellular response</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Differences in cellular response to SARS-COV-2 peptides</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Immune Suppression</condition>
  <condition>HIV-1-infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cases</arm_group_label>
    <description>HIV-1 infected individuals with previous or current diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2 infection, defined as the presence of suggestive symptoms and a positive PCR from the nasopharyngeal swab.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Controls</arm_group_label>
    <description>HIV-1-infected individuals of the same age (range, 5 years) and sex, who not have been diagnosed of clinical (asymptomatic) or confirmed SARS CoV-2 infection, but were positive for IgG antibodies (controls group 1) or with no evidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection (no previous neither current symptoms, negative for IgM/IgG antibodies, controls group 2)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Immune response study</intervention_name>
    <description>ACE2 and CD26 receptor study&#xD;
Cytokine profile: Quantification of plasma cytokine levels&#xD;
SARS-CoV-2 CD4/CD8 T cell response&#xD;
TLR7/8 activation&#xD;
KIR characterization</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cases</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Controls</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        HIV infected patients in regular follow up&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  adult (&gt;18 year-old), confirmed HIV-1-infection, and provide written informed consent,&#xD;
             with previous SARS CoV-2 infection as demonstrated by clinical and a positive PCR&#xD;
             (cases) or no previous compatible symptoms and no diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
             (controls, classified according to serological determination)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unable to provide a written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  immunological alterations (chronic intake of corticoid or immunosuppresants)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jose L Casado, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hospital Ramon y Cajal</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jose L Casado, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0034913368672</phone>
    <email>jcasado.hrc@salud.madrid.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Alejandro Vallejo, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0034913368710</phone>
    <email>avallejot@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Ramon y Cajal</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28034</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jose L Casado, Md, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>34913368790</phone>
      <email>jcasado.hrc@salud.madrid.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alejandro Vallejo, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Pilar Vizcarra, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Carmen Quereda, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ana Moreno, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jose M Del Rey, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 22, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 26, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

