<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4950">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04604821</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00019997</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04604821</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Delivering EMT Via Telehealth to Children and Families</brief_title>
  <official_title>Delivering Enhanced Milieu Teaching (EM-Teach) Via Telehealth to Children and Families in Rural Communities</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Oregon Health and Science University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ)</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Oregon Health and Science University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In the U.S., approximately 12% of children under 36 months have language impairments, yet&#xD;
      less than 2% receive early language intervention. Early language intervention is&#xD;
      underutilized nationally, with pronounced service gaps in rural communities. This gap is a&#xD;
      significant issue because children with language impairments are at increased risk for&#xD;
      learning and reading disabilities that can persist into adulthood. Telehealth has the&#xD;
      potential to mitigate service gaps by improving access to treatments, increasing the&#xD;
      availability of clinicians with expertise in language intervention, and reducing healthcare&#xD;
      costs. Telehealth can alleviate logistic and geographic barriers to treatment facing children&#xD;
      with disabilities and their families in rural communities. However, there is insufficient&#xD;
      evidence on the effects of telehealth interventions for children with language impairments&#xD;
      under 36 months. Consequently, there is an urgent need to explore innovative telehealth&#xD;
      interventions with potential to improve the quality and efficiency of language treatments.&#xD;
      The investigators will conduct a feasibility trial (small randomized control trial) to&#xD;
      evaluate a telehealth intervention for children with language impairments and their&#xD;
      caregivers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aim 1: Explore stakeholders' preferences, experiences, and information needs regarding the&#xD;
      delivery of language interventions via telehealth. Ethnographic interviews will be conducted&#xD;
      with 16 stakeholders (n= 8 caregivers, 8 clinicians) to explore their preferences,&#xD;
      experiences, and needs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2: Determine the effect of telehealth Enhanced Milieu Teaching on caregiver language&#xD;
      strategy use. Caregiver language strategy use will be compared between the intervention and&#xD;
      control groups (n = 28 families, 14 intervention,14 control) during semi-structured&#xD;
      caregiver-child interactions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 20, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Feasibility Study (Small Randomized Control Trial)</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The assessor of the primary outcome will be blind to treatment condition.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in number of Different Words on Structured Language Sample</measure>
    <time_frame>1 pre-intervention assessment (start of study) and 1 post intervention assessment through study completion (3-4 months later).</time_frame>
    <description>A language sample is a naturalistic adult-child interaction with a specific set of toys to evaluate a child's spontaneous expressive language ability.&#xD;
Metric/ Measurement Unit: Change in frequency count of the number of different words spoken during a 20 minute language sample.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Productive Vocabulary on the Mac-Arthur Bates Communication Development Inventory (MCDI) score after 3-4 months of intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>1 pre-intervention assessment (start of study) and 1 post intervention assessment through study completion (3-4 months later).</time_frame>
    <description>The MacArthur-Bates Communicative Development Inventory (MCDI) is a parent report instrument which captures important information about children's developing abilities in early language, including vocabulary comprehension, production, gestures, and grammar.&#xD;
An increase in the productive vocabulary represents a positive outcome.&#xD;
Metric/ Measurement Unit: Number of words expressed on the MCDI. The range of this instrument is 0 - 396.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Individual Growth and Development Indicators for Infants and Toddlers- Early Communication Indicator (IGDI-ECI) score through 3-4 months of intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Once per month of intervention through study completion (3-4 months of intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>The ECI is a brief, repeatable, play-based, observational measure of a child's communicative performance during a 6-minute play period with a familiar adult. It measures the number of gestures, vocalizations, single words, and multiple word combinations during this play period.&#xD;
An increase in the ECI presents a positive outcome.&#xD;
Metric/ Measurement Unit: Frequency count of communication utterances expressed during the 6 minute play interaction. ECI scores are weighted such that each single-word utterance is given a weight of two (each tally is multiplied by two), and each multiple word utterance is given a weight of three (each tally is multiplied by three)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Preschool-Language Scales - 5th edition (PLS-5)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 pre-intervention assessment (start of study) and 1 post intervention assessment through study completion (3-4 months later).</time_frame>
    <description>PLS™-5 Preschool Language Scales Fifth Edition offers a comprehensive developmental language assessment with items that range from pre-verbal, interaction-based skills to emerging language to early literacy.&#xD;
Increases on the PLS-5 represent a positive outcome.&#xD;
Metric/ Measurement Unit: Total Standard Score Range = 50 - 150 (Mean = 100, SD = 15).&#xD;
If we are unable to administer assessments to all participants in person due to public health impacts of COVID-19, we will report the raw scores because the PLS-5 is not standardized for telepractice administration. Raw scores range 0 - 132.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">28</enrollment>
  <condition>Language Impairment</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Enhanced Milieu Teaching</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Child-caregiver dyads receive up to 24 speech-language therapy sessions (50minutes, 2x per week for 3 months) where parents are taught by the interventionist to use Enhanced Milieu Teaching Strategies. Children and their families may continue to participate community-based educational programs.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Community Treatment as Usual</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Child-caregiver dyads may continue to participate in community-based educational programs. Researchers provide up to 4 educational sessions to caregivers (50 minutes, every 3 weeks). During educational sessions parents are taught developmental milestones from the CDC Learn the Signs Act Early Public Health Campaign.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Enhanced Milieu Teaching</intervention_name>
    <description>A behavioral language intervention that uses naturally occurring interactions to facilitate young children's language skills.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Enhanced Milieu Teaching</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Parent Education</intervention_name>
    <description>Parents receive information on child developmental milestones.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Community Treatment as Usual</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (a) Child age between 18 and 36 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (b) developmental age of 9 months as measured on the Visual Reception Scale of the&#xD;
             Mullen Scales of Early Learning (MSEL; 1995)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (c) language delay as measured by a score of at least 1.33 SD below the mean on the&#xD;
             Preschool Language Sclaes-5th Edition (PLS-5; Zimmerman, Steiner, &amp; Evatt-Pond, 2011),&#xD;
             and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (d) hearing (with or without amplification) reported at 25dB HL or better confirmed by&#xD;
             audiological testing, or medical record.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (a) primary diagnosis of any specific disability other than a language impairment&#xD;
             including severe motor impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (b) concomitant sensory impairments (e.g., hearing impairment, blindness), and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (c) symptoms of autism spectrum disorder as measured by a result indicating &quot;high&#xD;
             risk&quot; for autism (e.g., scores of 8 or higher) on the Modified Checklist for Autism In&#xD;
             Toddlers-Revised with Follow-up (MCHAT-R/F Robins, Fein &amp; Barton, 2009).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>36 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Emily D Quinn, Ph.D</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Oregon Health and Science University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Emily D Quinn, Ph.D</last_name>
    <phone>503-494-2263</phone>
    <email>quinnem@ohsu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Alexandria R Cook, B.A.</last_name>
    <email>cooal@ohsu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 26, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Oregon Health and Science University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Emily Quinn</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Language Impairment</keyword>
  <keyword>Telehealth</keyword>
  <keyword>Rural</keyword>
  <keyword>Enhanced Milieu Teaching</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Language Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

