<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="174">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04740658</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RC31/20/0300</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04740658</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Organizational Measures to Prevent and Control COVID-19 Infection in Nursing Homes on the Risk of Death of Residents</brief_title>
  <acronym>PIANO-COVID-19</acronym>
  <official_title>Effect of Organizational Measures to Prevent and Control COVID-19 Infection in Nursing Homes on the Risk of Death of Residents During and After the Epidemic Period</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Toulouse</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Toulouse</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The COVID epidemic has shown very high mortality among older people, especially among&#xD;
      polymorbid and dependent subjects. In addition to the classic risk factors of age, dependence&#xD;
      and associated co-morbidities, community life exposes to specific increased risks in the&#xD;
      event of this easily inter human transmissible viral epidemic. In France, according to the&#xD;
      Drees data (Ehpa study, 2015) more than 600,000 elderly people currently live in nursing&#xD;
      homes (NH). Since March 28, a national guidance for monitoring the COVID epidemic in NH has&#xD;
      just been set up. In France, 14 178 of the 29 319 COVID deaths (48.35%) by June 10th 2020&#xD;
      occurred among NHs residents. Work to consolidate these data is underway, suggesting a much&#xD;
      heavier balance sheet. Faced to this threat, in addition to practical recommendations&#xD;
      (barrier protection gestures), strict instructions were also announced to all NH to keep&#xD;
      their residents safe from COVID : restricting all visitors, all volunteers and nonessential&#xD;
      personnel, and more recently, confining residents in their room in case of incident case of&#xD;
      COVID in the NH. Organizational factors of NH such as the prevention strategies deployed&#xD;
      before and during the epidemic (pneumococcal vaccination, restricting group activities), as&#xD;
      well as NH internal resources (equipment, nursing staff) and health resources in the NH&#xD;
      environment (hospital partnerships, support devices, telemedicine) lead to heterogeneous&#xD;
      situations and could influence the death rates of residents. On the other hand, social&#xD;
      isolation can also precipitate the decline of fragile residents. Beyond the immediate and&#xD;
      directly risks linked to COVID-19, the present hypothesize that the organizational measures&#xD;
      (guidance and recommendations) put in place can have, during and at a distance from the&#xD;
      outbreak, beneficial effects but also deleterious effects depending on the severity of the&#xD;
      outbreak of a geographic area. More precisely, the hypothesis is that strong and&#xD;
      well-followed recommendations at the time of the epidemic were associated with a reduction in&#xD;
      the risk of total death in particular of deaths related to COVID in the zones most affected&#xD;
      by the epidemic but also that strong and well-followed recommendations were associated with&#xD;
      an increased risk of total death, in particular of deaths unrelated to COVID in the areas&#xD;
      least affected by the epidemic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The PIANO COVID-19 study is an observational, ambidirectional multicenter cohort study. The&#xD;
      study will compare the death rates (COVID and non-COVID) in NHs according to the application&#xD;
      of the general and specific recommendations of the region by the NH teams, taking into&#xD;
      account the COVID infection rate in the NH department, the transfer capacities to hospitals,&#xD;
      the medicalization of NH and the general characteristics of residents of NH. These parameters&#xD;
      having been fluctuating over time, the analysis will also take into account the period&#xD;
      considered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3 sources of data will be used :&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Questionnaire: The NH team leaders will be asked to report variable related to the&#xD;
      implementation of the recommendation/guidance by the nursing home staff, the general&#xD;
      characteristics of the residents (GMP, PMP, GIR, rate of death during the previous three&#xD;
      years 2017, 2018 and 2019), and characteristics of the NH (private, publics, address, level&#xD;
      of medicalization with nurses, coordinating physician), and the monthly rate of death (COVID&#xD;
      and not COVID) from January to December 2020.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A score will be built in regard to the implementation of the recommendation/guidance from the&#xD;
      nursing home staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Data related to the recommendations/guidance of the 13 regions of France (general guidance&#xD;
      such as barriers measures and specificity guidance such as rt-PCR COVID diagnostic and&#xD;
      management strategy), the COVID infection rate in each NH department, the transfer capacities&#xD;
      to hospitals and emergency department, will be collected by the PIANO COVID-19 research team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For this purpose, referent teams for the COVID-19 outbreak of the each Regional Health Agency&#xD;
      (RHA) of the 13 regions of France are contacted in order to recover the recommendation&#xD;
      documents having been sent to the NHs.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Official national data related to the COVID infection rate in the NH administrative&#xD;
           region, and transfer capacities to hospitals, will be collected from open access website&#xD;
           of the Santé Publique France website or other official websites currently providing&#xD;
           these data. These data are updated on a daily basis for all administrative region of&#xD;
           France and have been registered from the beginning of the outbreak.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Qualitative study: To improve the understanding of the effects of the&#xD;
           recommendations/guidance on resident's health, we will carry out a qualitative study&#xD;
           with the NH staff of 20 public and private NH (half clusters NH for COVID-19 and half NH&#xD;
           saved from COVID-19). Onsite semi-structured interviews will be conducted with the NH&#xD;
           staff to better understand the subjective assessment of healthcare professional on the&#xD;
           impact of the recommendations/guidance on the residents' health status. The main&#xD;
           questions to which the interviews with the nurses and the nursing assistants will&#xD;
           answer, will relate to the functional decline, the appetite and the nutritional status,&#xD;
           the mood, the evolution of the cognitive capacities,their psycho-behavioral disturbances&#xD;
           and their quality of life during the epidemic period. This qualitative survey will be&#xD;
           carried out among NHs having been strongly impacted by the epidemic (NHs cluster with&#xD;
           more than 20 deaths) and NHs having not at all been affected by the epidemic (no case of&#xD;
           COVID-19 among residents or health care professional). The qualitative study will&#xD;
           involve NHs located in very variable geographical regions in regards to the outbreak.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Death occurrence within one year of follow up</measure>
    <time_frame>from January 2020 to December 2020</time_frame>
    <description>Primary criteria is death occurrence within one year of follow up: death rates will be recorded.&#xD;
Level of implementation of the recommendation/guidance to prevent and control COVID-19 NH residents' infection will be score 14 days before the peak wave of the outbreak in the geographic area of each NH.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>deaths related to COVID during the one-year follow-up</measure>
    <time_frame>from January 2020 to December 2020</time_frame>
    <description>The secondary objective N°1 is to compare the rate of death related to confirmed or suspected COVID cases in NH with a high level of implementation of the recommendation/guidance to prevent and control COVID-19 NH residents' infection and NH with a low level of implementation of the recommendation/guidance to prevent and control COVID-19 NH.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>deaths not related to COVID during the one-year follow-up</measure>
    <time_frame>from January 2020 to December 2020</time_frame>
    <description>The secondary objective N°2 is to compare the rate of death not related to COVID cases in NH with a high level of implementation of the recommendation/guidance to prevent and control COVID-19 NH residents' infection and NH with a low level of implementation of the recommendation/guidance to prevent and control COVID-19 NH.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>evaluate the economic impact of the implementation of prevention measures</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months before and after the implementation of the preventive measures</time_frame>
    <description>This secondary objective N°3 is to evaluate the economic impact of the implementation of prevention measures applied by nursing homes staff, from healthcare system and the NH perspectives.&#xD;
- Direct medical and non-medical costs 6 and 12 months before and after the high or low level implementation of recommendations to prevent and control COVID-19, using the Mandatory National Health Insurance database.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Health economic study: evaluate Direct medical and non-medical costs</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months before and after the implementation of the preventive measures</time_frame>
    <description>This secondary objective N°3 is to evaluate the economic impact of the implementation of prevention measures applied by nursing homes staff, from healthcare system and the NH perspectives.&#xD;
- Direct medical and non-medical costs rate to assess the cost-effectiveness of high-level implementation of recommendation to prevent and control COVID-19.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Health economic study: evaluate the mortality rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months before and after the implementation of the preventive measures</time_frame>
    <description>This secondary objective N°3 is to evaluate the economic impact of the implementation of prevention measures applied by nursing homes staff, from healthcare system and the NH perspectives.&#xD;
- Mortality rate to assess the cost-effectiveness of high-level implementation of recommendation to prevent and control COVID-19.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">9600</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>There is no intervention</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        NH volunteers located in different regions more or less affected by the epidemic and NH&#xD;
        coordinating physician/directors of NHs via the SFGG website, directors of large private&#xD;
        groups (Korian, Orpea, Edenis, DOMUS-vi ..) or public groups (APHP), regional (FMC&#xD;
        Gériatres 31) and national (FFAMCO) NH coordinating physician associations (FFAMCO, MCOOR),&#xD;
        the referents geriatricians of large cities that have been particularly exposed to the&#xD;
        epidemic (Mulhouse, Strasbourg, Paris) or particularly least exposed (Bordeaux, Brest).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Within each NH, all NH residents living in the NH the 1st of January 2020 will be&#xD;
             included.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  NHs or LTCFs that refuse to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  NHs that are not voluntary or not located in the Occitanie, Nouvelle-Aquitaine or&#xD;
             Auvergne-Rhône-Alpes regions and NHs that do not have a coordinating doctor .&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Within each NH, all NH residents not living in the NH or LTCFs the 1st of January 2020&#xD;
             will be not be included.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yves ROLLAND, MD, PHD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Toulouse</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>YVES ROLLAND, MD, PHD</last_name>
    <phone>33 (0)5 61 77 21 00</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>rolland.y@chu-tououse.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Delphine PENNETIER</last_name>
    <email>pennetier.d@chu-toulouse.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Toulouse - Gérontopôle</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toulouse</city>
        <zip>31059</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yves ROLLAND, MD, PHD</last_name>
      <phone>33 (0)5 61 77 21 00</phone>
      <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
      <email>rolland.y@chu-toulouse.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>epidemic period</keyword>
  <keyword>nursing homes</keyword>
  <keyword>mortality</keyword>
  <keyword>restriction measures impact</keyword>
  <keyword>beneficial effects</keyword>
  <keyword>deleterious effects</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

