<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4329">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04623346</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Treatment in the time of Covid</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04623346</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Orthopaedic Conservative Treatment in the Time of Covid-19 Pandemic</brief_title>
  <official_title>Orthopaedic Conservative Treatment in the Time of Covid-19 Pandemic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Prof. Dr. Cemil Tascıoglu Education and Research Hospital Organization</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Prof. Dr. Cemil Tascıoglu Education and Research Hospital Organization</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a one centered retrospective study. Tendency for surgical interventions in the&#xD;
      pre-pandemic period was reduced to protect surgical team and patients. The investigators&#xD;
      aimed to find out the answer to the following question: will conservative treatment be the&#xD;
      shining star in the post pandemic period?&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The researchers compared the treatments performed for fractures during the Covid 19 pandemic&#xD;
      period with the treatments performed in the prepandemic period. For this purpose, they tried&#xD;
      to measure the effectiveness of the treatments according to clinical scoring by forming 2&#xD;
      groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 11, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 1, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the two groups in terms of bony union</measure>
    <time_frame>12 week</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators aimed to investigate the duration of bone union time between two groups</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>6</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">262</enrollment>
  <condition>Ankle Fractures</condition>
  <condition>Proximal Humeral Fracture</condition>
  <condition>Wrist Fracture</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Weber B-type Ankle fractures in prepandemic period</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with AO Weber B-type ankle fracture in prepandemic period</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Weber B-type Ankle fractures in pandemic period</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with AO Weber B-type ankle fracture in pandemic period</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Wrist fractures in prepandemic period</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with extraarticular distal radius fracture in prepandemic period</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Wrist fractures in pandemic period</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with extraarticular distal radius fracture in pandemic period</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Proximal humerus fractures in prepandemic period</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with 2-part,3-part and 4-part fractures in prepandemic period</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Proximal humerus fractures in pandemic period</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with 2-part,3-part and 4-part fractures in pandemic period</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Observation for study group</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients with Weber B-type Ankle fractures, extraarticular wrist fractures and proximal humerus fractures were followed with conservative manner( cast or sling)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Proximal humerus fractures in pandemic period</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Weber B-type Ankle fractures in pandemic period</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Wrist fractures in pandemic period</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Surgery for control group</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients who admitted to emergency orthopedics department between March 11, 2020 and August&#xD;
        11, 2020&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with extraarticular distal radius fracture, proximal humerus fracture and&#xD;
             Weber type B ankle fracture were treated conservatively during March 11, 2020 and 11&#xD;
             August, 2020&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Surgically treated patients during March 11, 2020 and 11 August, 2020&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>85 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>SBU Prof. Cemil Tascioglu City Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <zip>34040</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Zhao J, Hu Y, Zhang L, Fan G, Xu J, Gu X, Cheng Z, Yu T, Xia J, Wei Y, Wu W, Xie X, Yin W, Li H, Liu M, Xiao Y, Gao H, Guo L, Xie J, Wang G, Jiang R, Gao Z, Jin Q, Wang J, Cao B. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020 Feb 15;395(10223):497-506. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5. Epub 2020 Jan 24. Erratum in: Lancet. 2020 Jan 30;:.</citation>
    <PMID>31986264</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhu N, Zhang D, Wang W, Li X, Yang B, Song J, Zhao X, Huang B, Shi W, Lu R, Niu P, Zhan F, Ma X, Wang D, Xu W, Wu G, Gao GF, Tan W; China Novel Coronavirus Investigating and Research Team. A Novel Coronavirus from Patients with Pneumonia in China, 2019. N Engl J Med. 2020 Feb 20;382(8):727-733. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2001017. Epub 2020 Jan 24.</citation>
    <PMID>31978945</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Holshue ML, DeBolt C, Lindquist S, Lofy KH, Wiesman J, Bruce H, Spitters C, Ericson K, Wilkerson S, Tural A, Diaz G, Cohn A, Fox L, Patel A, Gerber SI, Kim L, Tong S, Lu X, Lindstrom S, Pallansch MA, Weldon WC, Biggs HM, Uyeki TM, Pillai SK; Washington State 2019-nCoV Case Investigation Team. First Case of 2019 Novel Coronavirus in the United States. N Engl J Med. 2020 Mar 5;382(10):929-936. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2001191. Epub 2020 Jan 31.</citation>
    <PMID>32004427</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chen YC, Lin WC. Risk of long-term infection-related death in clinical osteoporotic vertebral fractures: A hospital-based analysis. PLoS One. 2017 Aug 9;12(8):e0182614. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0182614. eCollection 2017.</citation>
    <PMID>28793342</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mi B, Xiong Y, Lin Z, Panayi AC, Chen L, Liu G. COVID-19 Orthopaedic Safe Care Toolset: Guidelines for the Diagnosis and Management of Patients with Fracture and COVID-19. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2020 Jul 1;102(13):1116-1122. doi: 10.2106/JBJS.20.00532.</citation>
    <PMID>32618909</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Guo X, Wang J, Hu D, Wu L, Gu L, Wang Y, Zhao J, Zeng L, Zhang J, Wu Y. Survey of COVID-19 Disease Among Orthopaedic Surgeons in Wuhan, People's Republic of China. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2020 May 20;102(10):847-854. doi: 10.2106/JBJS.20.00417.</citation>
    <PMID>32271208</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Saxena A, Bullock M, Danoff JR, Rodd DS, Fischer SJ, Stronach BM, Levine BR. Educating Surgeons to Educate Patients About the COVID-19 Pandemic. J Arthroplasty. 2020 Jul;35(7S):S65-S67. doi: 10.1016/j.arth.2020.04.037. Epub 2020 Apr 18.</citation>
    <PMID>32340829</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lei S, Jiang F, Su W, Chen C, Chen J, Mei W, Zhan LY, Jia Y, Zhang L, Liu D, Xia ZY, Xia Z. Clinical characteristics and outcomes of patients undergoing surgeries during the incubation period of COVID-19 infection. EClinicalMedicine. 2020 Apr 5;21:100331. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2020.100331. eCollection 2020 Apr.</citation>
    <PMID>32292899</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Handoll HH, Keding A, Corbacho B, Brealey SD, Hewitt C, Rangan A. Five-year follow-up results of the PROFHER trial comparing operative and non-operative treatment of adults with a displaced fracture of the proximal humerus. Bone Joint J. 2017 Mar;99-B(3):383-392. doi: 10.1302/0301-620X.99B3.BJJ-2016-1028.</citation>
    <PMID>28249980</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Orman S, Mohamadi A, Serino J, Murphy J, Hanna P, Weaver MJ, Dyer G, Nazarian A, von Keudell A. Comparison of surgical and non-surgical treatments for 3- and 4-part proximal humerus fractures: A network meta-analysis. Shoulder Elbow. 2020 Apr;12(2):99-108. doi: 10.1177/1758573219831506. Epub 2019 Feb 28.</citation>
    <PMID>32313559</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Maier D, Jaeger M, Izadpanah K, Strohm PC, Suedkamp NP. Proximal humeral fracture treatment in adults. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2014 Feb 5;96(3):251-61. doi: 10.2106/JBJS.L.01293. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24500588</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hertel R, Hempfing A, Stiehler M, Leunig M. Predictors of humeral head ischemia after intracapsular fracture of the proximal humerus. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2004 Jul-Aug;13(4):427-33.</citation>
    <PMID>15220884</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Murray IR, Amin AK, White TO, Robinson CM. Proximal humeral fractures: current concepts in classification, treatment and outcomes. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2011 Jan;93(1):1-11. doi: 10.1302/0301-620X.93B1.25702. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21196536</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Martin AG. Weber B ankle fracture: an unnecessary fracture clinic burden. Injury. 2004 Aug;35(8):805-8.</citation>
    <PMID>15246805</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mittal R, Harris IA, Adie S, Naylor JM; CROSSBAT Study Group. Surgery for Type B Ankle Fracture Treatment: a Combined Randomised and Observational Study (CROSSBAT). BMJ Open. 2017 Mar 27;7(3):e013298. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2016-013298.</citation>
    <PMID>28348185</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Van Schie-Van der Weert EM, Van Lieshout EM, De Vries MR, Van der Elst M, Schepers T. Determinants of outcome in operatively and non-operatively treated Weber-B ankle fractures. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2012 Feb;132(2):257-63. doi: 10.1007/s00402-011-1397-z. Epub 2011 Sep 30.</citation>
    <PMID>21959696</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Young BT, Rayan GM. Outcome following nonoperative treatment of displaced distal radius fractures in low-demand patients older than 60 years. J Hand Surg Am. 2000 Jan;25(1):19-28.</citation>
    <PMID>10642469</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chang HC, Tay SC, Chan BK, Low CO. Conservative treatment of redisplaced Colles' fractures in elderly patients older than 60 years old - anatomical and functional outcome. Hand Surg. 2001 Dec;6(2):137-44.</citation>
    <PMID>11901459</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fujii K, Henmi T, Kanematsu Y, Mishiro T, Sakai T, Terai T. Fractures of the distal end of radius in elderly patients: a comparative study of anatomical and functional results. J Orthop Surg (Hong Kong). 2002 Jun;10(1):9-15.</citation>
    <PMID>12401915</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Anzarut A, Johnson JA, Rowe BH, Lambert RG, Blitz S, Majumdar SR. Radiologic and patient-reported functional outcomes in an elderly cohort with conservatively treated distal radius fractures. J Hand Surg Am. 2004 Nov;29(6):1121-7.</citation>
    <PMID>15576226</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 12, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 12, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Prof. Dr. Cemil Tascıoglu Education and Research Hospital Organization</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Bulent KARSLIOGLU</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Orthopedics and Traumatology specialist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ankle Fractures</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Humeral Fractures</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Shoulder Fractures</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

