<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="647">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04383444</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>200117</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>20-I-0117</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04383444</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Surveillance of Individuals Following SARS-CoV-2 Infection</brief_title>
  <official_title>Surveillance of Individuals Following SARS-CoV-2 Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People who have had contact with a person with a known SARS-CoV-2 infection are being told to&#xD;
      self-quarantine for 14 days. This is done to avoid potential virus spread. But the actual&#xD;
      time it takes for a person to develop an infection after being exposed to the virus is not&#xD;
      well known. The proper quarantine time could be less or more than 2 weeks. Researchers hope&#xD;
      this study can be used to help improve public health guidelines for quarantines, social&#xD;
      distancing, and returning to work after a possible SARS-CoV-2 exposure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To better understand how long it takes a person to develop (or not develop) an infection with&#xD;
      the SARS-CoV-2 virus after they have had contact with a person who has a confirmed infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      NIH staff members age 18 and older who had recent contact with a person who has a SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      infection&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have 3 study visits at the NIH Clinical Center. They may be asked to have&#xD;
      an extra visit depending on the test results at the third visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At each visit, participants will give a blood and saliva sample. It will be used to test for&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 antibodies. Their temperature will be taken. They will complete a short survey to&#xD;
      collect data about possible COVID-19 symptoms. At the first visit only, they will also&#xD;
      complete a survey that asks about their recent social contacts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two types of nasal samples will be collected at each visit. These samples will be tested for&#xD;
      the SARS-CoV-2 virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. a swab will be inserted deep into the back of the nose and&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. a swab will be inserted to the middle of your nose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation lasts 3 to 4 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Description:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a prospective longitudinal cohort study of individuals who have recently tested&#xD;
      positive or are highly suspected to be positive for severe acute respiratory&#xD;
      syndrome-coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV- 2) infection. The aim is to correlate results of reverse&#xD;
      transcription-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) using various sample types, assays, and&#xD;
      culture. We will enroll individuals with at least one recent positive RT-PCR test result&#xD;
      (confirmed cases) and individuals whose referring physician highly suspects current or recent&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 infection but the individual has not had access to testing (probable cases). At&#xD;
      baseline, participants will undergo collection of nasopharyngeal (NP) swabs, saliva samples,&#xD;
      and midturbinate swabs for SARS-CoV-2 RT-PCR and culture, and blood draw for antibody assay.&#xD;
      Subjects enrolled as probable cases who have a positive baseline RT-PCR result and all&#xD;
      subjects enrolled as confirmed cases (regardless of baseline result) will be followed with&#xD;
      serial screenings until they have 2 consecutive negative RT-PCR test results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Correlate results of SARS-CoV-2 RT-PCR using various sample types, antibody assays and&#xD;
      culture.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Determine rate of culture positivity in individuals who persistently shed virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Correlate symptoms with culture positivity and RT-PCR cycle threshold.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endpoints: Primary Endpoint: Results of SARS-CoV-2 RT-PCR using NP swab, saliva, and&#xD;
      midturbinate swab, antibody assay and culture.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Endpoint:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. SARS-CoV-2 culture and RT-PCR results.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Symptom checklist and RT-PCR cycle threshold value.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will enroll up to 1,000 (accrual ceiling: 1,050) adults who have had one or more positive&#xD;
      RT-PCR test result(s) within the last two weeks (confirmed cases) and those who have not been&#xD;
      tested within the last two weeks but meet a high index of clinical suspicion for current or&#xD;
      recent SARS-CoV-2 infection (probable cases).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Facilities Enrolling Participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
      NIH CC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Duration: 3 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant Duration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Probable cases who have negative RT-PCR results at baseline will have a single (baseline)&#xD;
      visit. Probable cases with positive baseline RT-PCR and all confirmed cases will continue in&#xD;
      the&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 7, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Results of SARS-CoV-2 RT- PCR testing, antibody assay, and culture</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1, 14, then every 2-4 weeks as needed</time_frame>
    <description>Correlate results of SARS-CoV-2 RT-PCR using various sample types, antibody assays, and culture.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SARS-CoV-2 culture and RT-PCR results</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1, 14, then ever 2-4 weeks as needed</time_frame>
    <description>Determine rate of culture positivity in individuals who persistently shed virus.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom checklist and RT-PCR cycle threshold</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1, 14, then every 2-4 weeks as applicable</time_frame>
    <description>Correlate symptoms with culture positivity and RT-PCR cycle threshold.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1050</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SARS-CoV-2 exposure</arm_group_label>
    <description>NIH staff exposed to SARS-CoV-2 or current or previous SARS-CoV-2 infection, but currently asymptomatic</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        NIH staff or contractors working at an NIH facility and able to come to the NIH campus for&#xD;
        study visits.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        To be eligible to participate in this study, an individual must meet all of the following&#xD;
        criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Able to attent study visits at the NIH.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age greater than or equal to 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Meets one of the following case definitions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Confirmed case: At lease one current or recent (within past 14 days positive&#xD;
                  RT-PCR test for SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Probable case: Suspected current or recent (within the past 14 days) SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
                  infection by referring physician but no availability of confirmatory test&#xD;
                  results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Able to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Willing to allow storage of samples for future research..&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        An individual who meets any of the following criteria will be excluded from participation&#xD;
        in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The most recent RT-PCR tests have yielded two negatives.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Inability or unwillingness to have NP sampling, mid-turbinate, or saliva sampling&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Inability or unwillingness to have blood sampling.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Steven M Holland, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lisa A Barnhart, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 496-5270</phone>
    <email>lbarnhart@niaid.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2020-I-0117.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>January 15, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 12, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Coronavirus</keyword>
  <keyword>Antibody Testing</keyword>
  <keyword>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome-Coronavirus-2 infection</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

