<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2865">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04470531</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BSMMU/2020/6969</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04470531</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Role of Co-trimoxazole in Severe COVID-19 Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Role of Co-trimoxazole in Severe COVID-19 Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujib Medical University, Dhaka, Bangladesh</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Anwar Khan Mordern Medical College and Hospital, Dhaka</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Mugda Medical College and Hospital, Dhaka</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujib Medical University, Dhaka, Bangladesh</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus Disease 19 (COVID-19) is a global pandemic caused by Severe Acute Respiratory&#xD;
      Syndrome Coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2). Severe disease occurs in 15% of the cases with COVID-19&#xD;
      and may progress to critical disease in only 5% of the cases with a high risk of mortality.&#xD;
      Critical disease may present as acute respiratory failure secondary to Acute Respiratory&#xD;
      Distress Syndrome (ARDS) and is caused by the body's hyper-immune response to the virus in&#xD;
      the form of a cytokine storm syndrome (CSS). There is currently no effective anti-viral&#xD;
      treatment against SARS-CoV-2 and the mainstay of treatment is supportive. Co-trimoxazole&#xD;
      (combination of trimethoprim and sulphamethoxazole in a 1:5) ratio is a Sulphur containing&#xD;
      anti-folate bactericidal antibiotic indicated for the treatment of respiratory tract&#xD;
      infections. It has been around for over 60 years and is inexpensive and readily available&#xD;
      with a good safety profile. It has a rapid onset of action with excellent bioavailability and&#xD;
      lung penetration. In addition to having antimicrobial properties co-trimoxazole have&#xD;
      immunomodulatory and anti-inflammatory properties and may be a potential treatment option for&#xD;
      cytokine storm syndrome mediated severe COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This open-label randomized controlled trial will be conducted in the department of medicine&#xD;
      at Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujib Medical University (BSMMU), Anwar Khan Modern Medical college and&#xD;
      Mughda Medical College Hospital (DMCH), Dhaka for a duration of 6 months following approval&#xD;
      of this protocol. It will recruit at least 94 consecutive adults (18 years or older) patients&#xD;
      with clinically suspected COVID-19 and severe illness as per WHO criteria. After taking&#xD;
      informed written consent patients will be randomly assigned in a 1:1 ratio to either oral&#xD;
      co-trimoxazole in addition to standard therapy or standard therapy alone. Baseline&#xD;
      characteristics, changes in the physiological and biochemical parameters like (SpO2/FiO2&#xD;
      ratio, respiratory rate, body temperature and C - reactive protein), length of hospital stay,&#xD;
      side effects of drugs, requirement for ventilatory support (non-invasive and invasive&#xD;
      ventilation) and in-patient mortality between the two groups will be compared.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Conclusion If the results from this clinical trial demonstrate the beneficial effects of&#xD;
      co-trimoxazole in severe COVID-19 patients it could be used widely, thereby reducing the need&#xD;
      for respiratory support and potentially saving thousands of lives in developing nations with&#xD;
      limited resources where healthcare may be easily overwhelmed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) caused by SARS-COV2, represents a highly transmissible and&#xD;
      potentially fatal disease that is of great global public health concern at this moment. The&#xD;
      pandemic situation in Bangladesh is also evolving rapidly with positive cases and deaths&#xD;
      increasing each day. Epidemiological changes in COVID-19 infection should be monitored taking&#xD;
      into account potential routes of transmission and subclinical infections, in addition to the&#xD;
      adaptation, evolution, and virus spread among humans and possible intermediate animals and&#xD;
      reservoirs. But till today there is no specific management to deal with this highly deadly&#xD;
      viral infection. Howeverthere are few drugs which might cause some beneficial effects in the&#xD;
      recovery of the patient. Cotrimoxazole is a time tested antibiotic which has been in clinical&#xD;
      use for 60 years with anti-bacterial action against a wide range of organism. In addition to&#xD;
      the antimicrobial effects, co-trimoxazole has anti-inflammatory and immunomodulatory effects.&#xD;
      Co-trimoxazole has previously been shown to exert anti-cytokine effect by inhibiting&#xD;
      interleukin 1, 6 (IL-1, IL-6) and Tumour Necrosis Factor α (TNF α) which are the major&#xD;
      cytokines identified in patients with severe COVID-19. As in some case reports this has shown&#xD;
      significant clinical improvement in ARDS, so there is a possibility, that cotrimoxazole might&#xD;
      have also role in improving the clinical outcome in COVID-19 patients especially in moderate&#xD;
      to severe cases. As till today there is no specific treatment for COVID-19 infections, if&#xD;
      cotrimoxazole ifs found to be effective this will bring a great benefit to the target&#xD;
      populations. Beside this, cotrimoxazole is a very cheap drug in comparison to other ones this&#xD;
      will also be of great economical benefit in taking cares of the general population. As there&#xD;
      is no such study published about the role of cotrimoxazole in COVID-19 patients, this study&#xD;
      will generate a new information which bring a great benefit in battling with the COVID-19&#xD;
      infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Question:&#xD;
&#xD;
      What is the outcome of co-trimoxazole in severe COVID-19 patients?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      General Objectives To assess the clinical outcome of co-trimoxazolein patients with severe&#xD;
      COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess length of stay who are treated with co-trimoxazole in addition to standard&#xD;
      treatment versus standard treatment alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To find out side effects (rash.itching. dizziness, headache, nausea,vomiting, diarrhea, sore&#xD;
      throat, unusual bruising or bleeding, yellowing of the skin or eye discolorations, joint or&#xD;
      muscle pain,red or purple skin.etc) of drugs who are treated with co-trimoxazole in addition&#xD;
      to standard treatment versus standard treatment alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To find out requirement for ventilator support (non-invasive and invasive ventilation) who&#xD;
      are treated with co-trimoxazole in addition to standard treatment versus standard treatment&#xD;
      alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess the mortality in patients with severe COVID-19 who are treated with co-trimoxazole&#xD;
      in addition to standard treatment versus standard treatment alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design:Open-label randomized controlled trial Study duration: Six months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients presenting to participating hospitals in Bangladesh with symptoms ofCOVID-19 will be&#xD;
      assessed for eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Diagnosed COVID-19 patients ( RT-PCR positive for COVID-19)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Age &gt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Hypoxic respiratory failure (saturation &lt;90% on air at rest or increasing oxygen&#xD;
           requirement)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Chest examination findings of bilateral crackles on auscultation or chest x-ray showing&#xD;
           bilateral infiltrates&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. C-Reactive Protein &gt; 50mg/L&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Multi-organ failure&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Severe ARDS (requiring ventilator support on presentation in the form of invasive or&#xD;
           non-invasive ventilation)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Septic Shock&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Severe liver disease&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Acute Kidney Injury (where GFR&lt; 15 and plasma-sulfamethoxazoleconcentration cannot be&#xD;
           monitored)&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Drug allergy/intolerance to co-trimoxazole / Sulphar sensitivity&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Already receiving Tocilizumab or convalescent therapy Sampling procedure:This RCT will&#xD;
           consist of two arms, experimental group and control group.Randomized (1:1) case:&#xD;
           control, (non-blinded) trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. control group will receive standard treatment,&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. experimental group will recivestandard care and oral co-triamoxazole. Forty-seven&#xD;
                (47) patients will be enrolled for each arm. Randomization will be done by a random&#xD;
                number table. Allocations will be in sequentially numbered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment protocol Eligible patients will be received either to oral co-trimoxazole +&#xD;
      standard therapy or standard therapy alone. (According to institution /national protocol)&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following treatments are recommended as standard therapy:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Antibiotics for secondary bacterial infection as per institutional guidelines&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Supplemental oxygen (to keep saturations between 90% to 96%)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Intravenous hydration (to maintain euvolumia)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Thrombo-prophylaxis as per local guidelines&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Paracetamol (oral or I/V 1gram QDS as required or regular)&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. To consider steroids if indicated (i.e. acute exacerbation of COPD or acute severe&#xD;
           asthma) NOTE: The dose of co-trimoxazoleis 960 mg (trimethoprim 160mg +&#xD;
           sulphamethoxazole 800mg) twice daily for 7 days orally.&#xD;
&#xD;
      sample size: 94&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research instrument:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. General questionnaire for assessing socio-demographic data.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. A checklist of clinical findings&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. A checklist of investigation findings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Measures Variable:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection required for both groups (co-trimoxazole + standard therapyand standard&#xD;
      therapy alone)&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Age&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Sex&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Ethnicity&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Past medical history - Hypertension, use of ACEI or ARB, DM, IHD, COPD, CKD, Obesity&#xD;
           (BMI) andCancer&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Presenting symptoms (dry cough, productive cough, fever, sore throat, myalgia, lethargy,&#xD;
           headache, breathlessness, nausea, diarrhoea and any other)&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Baseline observations on dayof initiating treatment (Day 0): oxygen saturation(SpO2),&#xD;
           fraction of inspired oxygen (FiO2) , SpO2/FiO2 ratio, respiratory rate, body&#xD;
           temperature, neutrophil-lymphocyte ratio, C-Reactive Protein&amp;findings of bilateral&#xD;
           infiltrates on chest-x-ray.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Follow-up observations after randomization on Day 1,2,3,4 and 5 for SpO2/FiO2 ratio,&#xD;
           respiratory rate,body temperature and C-Reactive Protein&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Length of stay (in days)&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Use of ventilator support (invasive or non-invasive ventilation)&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Side effects of drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. In-patient mortality Primary end points&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. Length of stay in hospital (in days) 2. In-patient mortality&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary end points&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Change in observations after randomization on Day 1,2,3,4 and 5 for SpO2/FiO2 ratio,&#xD;
           respiratory rate, body temperature and C-Reactive Protein&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Use of ventilator support (invasive or non-invasive ventilation)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Side effects of drugs co-trimoxazole&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Collection procedure:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pre-designed case record form (CRF) will be used for collecting data, which will also contain&#xD;
      the result of the study. The information collected in the CRF will be reviewed and&#xD;
      inconsistencies will be investigated and clarified. Data from case record forms will be&#xD;
      anonymised and stored securely in a secure online web-based portal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis: Statistical analysis will be performed using t-test or Mann -Whitney U&#xD;
      test or Wilcoxon signed rank test for continuous variables and Chi- square test or Fisher's&#xD;
      exact test for categorical variables. Survival will be assessed by the Kaplan-Meier method.&#xD;
      Comparisons between two groups will be performed using the log-rank test and Hazard&#xD;
      regression test.A p-value of &lt; 0.05 will be considered to be significant. The statistical&#xD;
      software SPSS version 25 will be used for the analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 12, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 12, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Arm A :control group will receive standard treatment, Arm B: experimental group will receive standard care and oral co-triamoxazole</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of stay in hospital (in days)</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of hospital stay in days</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>In-patient mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>% of patients died after enrollment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SpO2/FiO2 ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1,2,3,4 and 5</time_frame>
    <description>ratio of Saturation of oxygen in % and Fraction of inspired oxygen</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>respiratory rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1,2,3,4 and 5</time_frame>
    <description>Respiratory rate per minute</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>C-reactive Protein</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1,2,3,4 and 5</time_frame>
    <description>CRP level in mg/litre</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fever</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1,2,3,4 and 5</time_frame>
    <description>Temperature in degree Fahrenheit</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ventilator support</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Requirement of ventilator support in hours</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of drug adverse reaction</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>% of patients developed early reaction like fever, rash, abdominal pain, urticaria, vomiting, wheezing, chest tightness</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">94</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Severe COVID-19 Patients</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Arm A :No Intervention/control: Standard treatment&#xD;
Antibiotics for secondary bacterial infection as per institutional guidelines&#xD;
Supplemental oxygen (to keep saturations between 90% to 96%)&#xD;
Intravenous hydration (to maintain euvolumia)&#xD;
Thrombo-prophylaxis as per local guidelines&#xD;
Paracetamol (oral or I/V 1gram QDS as required or regular)&#xD;
To consider steroids if indicated (i.e. acute exacerbation of COPD or acute severe asthma)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>intervention /experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Arm B: Experimental Arm received oral co-trimoxazole + standard therapy&#xD;
The following treatments are recommended as standard therapy:&#xD;
Antibiotics for secondary bacterial infection as per institutional guidelines&#xD;
Supplemental oxygen (to keep saturations between 90% to 96%)&#xD;
Intravenous hydration (to maintain euvolumia)&#xD;
Thrombo-prophylaxis as per local guidelines&#xD;
Paracetamol (oral or I/V 1gram QDS as required or regular)&#xD;
To consider steroids if indicated (i.e. acute exacerbation of COPD or acute severe asthma)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>oral co-trimoxazole</intervention_name>
    <description>oral co-trimoxazole + standard therapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>intervention /experimental</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>co-trimoxazole</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Diagnosed COVID-19 patients ( RT-PCR positive for COVID-19)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age &gt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Hypoxic respiratory failure (saturation &lt;90% on air at rest or increasing oxygen&#xD;
             requirement)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Chest examination findings of bilateral crackles on auscultation or chest x-ray&#xD;
             showing bilateral infiltrates&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. C-Reactive Protein &gt; 50mg/L&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Multi-organ failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Severe ARDS (requiring ventilator support on presentation in the form of invasive or&#xD;
             non-invasive ventilation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Septic Shock&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Severe liver disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Acute Kidney Injury (where GFR&lt; 15 and plasma-sulfamethoxazoleconcentration cannot be&#xD;
             monitored)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Drug allergy/intolerance to co-trimoxazole / Sulphar sensitivity&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Already receiving Tocilizumab or convalescent therapy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Shohael Arafat</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>ICMJE</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Shohael Arafat, FCPS</last_name>
    <phone>01732330313</phone>
    <email>arafat2001@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Rehan Quadery</last_name>
    <email>arafat2001@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujib Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dhaka</city>
        <zip>1200</zip>
        <country>Bangladesh</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Shohael Arafat, FCPS</last_name>
      <phone>01732330313</phone>
      <email>arafat2001@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Rehan Quadery</last_name>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Bangladesh</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 13, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 15, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 15, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujib Medical University, Dhaka, Bangladesh</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Prof. Dr. Shohael Mahmud Arafat</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Chairman and professor of internal medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Trimethoprim, Sulfamethoxazole Drug Combination</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data will be shared with the journal authority and make public as part of the publication</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>six months</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Available on public domain like figshare, researchgate and others</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

