<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3128">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04731870</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>60622</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04731870</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Exploring Vaccine Confidence and Uptake of Potential COVID-19 Vaccines</brief_title>
  <official_title>Exploring Vaccine Confidence and Uptake of Potential COVID-19 Vaccines Among a Cross-section of US Healthcare Providers and Key At-risk Subgroups in the Rural South</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>East Carolina University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>East Carolina University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The COVID-19 pandemic has highlighted deleterious US health inequities. Specifically, African&#xD;
      Americans, Latinos, and Native Americans have and continue to shoulder a greater burden of&#xD;
      COVID-19 infections and deaths in the US. In addition to existing racial and ethnic&#xD;
      disparities are rural health and regional disparities. Given the disproportionate impact of&#xD;
      disease in US communities of color and also in rural and southern regions of the US, there is&#xD;
      no doubt that these at-risk subgroups will continue to experience higher rates of&#xD;
      coronavirus-related mortality as well as other long-term health outcomes as compared to other&#xD;
      US populations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is unknown how healthcare providers and other key at-risk subgroups within the US will&#xD;
      receive COVID-19 vaccines. For success in immunizations, the US will need to reach their most&#xD;
      at-risk and vulnerable populations. In addition to at-risk populations, a successful&#xD;
      immunization strategy will involve engaging providers to support clear, consistent, and&#xD;
      strong vaccine recommendation. It is critical to build vaccine trust, confidence, and overall&#xD;
      acceptance of COVID-19 vaccines among healthcare providers and key at-risk subgroups,&#xD;
      especially given the accelerated production timeline of these vaccines. Likewise, tailored&#xD;
      vaccine messaging for key subgroups is vital in achieving vaccine confidence and trust.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The proposed study will explore perceptions, confidence, trust, and uptake of potential&#xD;
      COVID-19 vaccines among healthcare providers (nurses and doctors) and key at-risk population&#xD;
      subgroups (minority populations living in the rural south) and will develop and test vaccine&#xD;
      messaging that boosts vaccine confidence and trust among these key at-risk subgroups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study objectives are as follows: Objective 1: To assess COVID-19 perceptions, COVID-19&#xD;
      vaccine confidence, projected vaccine recommendation practices, and trust in the health&#xD;
      system and public health authorities among a cross-section of healthcare providers in the US&#xD;
      (nurses and physicians); Objective 2: To assess COVID-19 perceptions, COVID-19 vaccine&#xD;
      confidence, projected vaccine uptake, and trust in the health system, in healthcare&#xD;
      providers, and in public health authorities among key at-risk subgroups in the US (minority&#xD;
      populations living in the rural south); and Objective 3: To develop, tailor, and test&#xD;
      COVID-19 vaccine messaging to boost vaccine confidence and trust, and COVID-19 preventive&#xD;
      behavior, among at-risk subgroups in the US (minority populations living in the rural south).&#xD;
      Perceptions, confidence, uptake, and trust in potential COVID-19 vaccines will be assessed&#xD;
      among four identified and distinct groups via a quantitative and electronic survey and&#xD;
      qualitative focus groups with key at-risk subgroups will be utilized to develop, tailor, and&#xD;
      test COVID-19 vaccine messaging for at-risk subgroups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will: 1) provide important national-level data regarding healthcare provider&#xD;
      vaccine perceptions, confidence, trust, and projected vaccine recommendation practices for&#xD;
      COVID-19, 2) ascertain vaccine perceptions, confidence, trust, and projected uptake of&#xD;
      potential COVID-19 vaccines among at-risk populations in the US, and 3) develop tailored&#xD;
      messaging for at-risk populations that can be used to boost vaccine confidence and trust, and&#xD;
      preventive behaviors, among these high-risk groups in the coming years. This study will help&#xD;
      to inform a larger coordinated national promotion strategy and campaign that can work to&#xD;
      effectively communicate with the public about potential COVID-19 vaccines.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Covid-19 vaccine confidence (survey to be developed by study team)</measure>
    <time_frame>year 1</time_frame>
    <description>Confidence in the Covid-19 vaccine efficacy and safety among a cross-section of healthcare providers and key at-risk subgroups in the US</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Covid-19 vaccine messaging (messages to be developed by study team &amp; focus group participants)</measure>
    <time_frame>year 2</time_frame>
    <description>COVID-19 vaccine messaging (e.g. one or two sentences of culturally appropriate messages) that can be used to boost vaccine confidence and trust, and COVID-19 preventive behavior, among at-risk subgroups in the US (minority populations living in the rural south).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Covid-19 vaccine uptake (survey to be developed by study team)</measure>
    <time_frame>year 1</time_frame>
    <description>COVID-19 vaccine uptake or projected uptake among a cross-section of healthcare providers and key at-risk subgroups in the US</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Covid-19 vaccine trust (survey to be developed by study team)</measure>
    <time_frame>year 1</time_frame>
    <description>COVID-19 vaccine trust in the health system and public health authorities a cross-section of healthcare providers and key at-risk subgroups in the US</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Covid-19 vaccine recommendation practices (survey to be developed by study team)</measure>
    <time_frame>year 1</time_frame>
    <description>COVID-19 vaccine recommendation practices among a cross-section of healthcare providers in the US</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">632</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronavirus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Nurses/Doctors</arm_group_label>
    <description>Covid-19 vaccine confidence and recommendation practices of nurses/doctors</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Minority populations living in rural south</arm_group_label>
    <description>Covid-19 vaccine confidence and uptake of key at-risk subgroups and tailored Covid-10 vaccine messaging for at-risk subgroups.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Survey research</intervention_name>
    <description>This is not an intervention study. It involves social science research of surveys and focus groups.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Minority populations living in rural south</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Nurses/Doctors</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Objectives 1 and 2 will be met by administering an electronic quantitative survey among the&#xD;
        following four distinct groups: 1) Nurses (at least 50% from the south), 2) Primary&#xD;
        Care/Family Physicians (at least 50% from the south), 3) Rural, low-income, minority men&#xD;
        and women living in the south (income of $25K per year or less and 70% of respondents will&#xD;
        be Black, Latina, or Native American) and 4) Urban, low-income minority men and women&#xD;
        living in the south (income of $25K per year or less and 70% of respondents will be Black,&#xD;
        Latina, or Native American). Each group will contain at least 150 subjects for a total of&#xD;
        600 participants. Note that the urban, low-income minority group living in the south are&#xD;
        used as a reference or comparison group to the rural, low-income minority group living in&#xD;
        the south.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Nurses (at least 50% from the south),&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Primary Care/Family Physicians (at least 50% from the south),&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Rural, low-income, minority men and women living in the south (income of $25K per year&#xD;
             or less and 70% of respondents will be Black, Latina, or Native American) and&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Urban, low-income minority men and women living in the south (income of $25K per year&#xD;
             or less and 70% of respondents will be Black, Latina, or Native American).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Alice R Richman, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>252-328-6431</phone>
    <email>richmana@ecu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

