<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4649">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04465435</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FORTE2018-00402</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04465435</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sustainable UNiversity Life (SUN) Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>SUN</acronym>
  <official_title>Sustainable UNiversity Life (SUN): Mental Illness and Pain Conditions Among Students - a Cohort Study to Identify Modifiable Risk and Prognostic Factors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sophiahemmet University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Karolinska Institutet</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Forte</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sophiahemmet University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In 2017, Socialstyrelsen reported that mental ill-health in young adults had increased by&#xD;
      almost 70% in the previous10 years. A 2014 report showed that 5% of men and 11% of women&#xD;
      18-24 years were diagnosed with depression or anxiety in Stockholm County. Furthermore, 41%&#xD;
      of women 21-24 years have self reported psychological distress. Regarding pain, 28% of men&#xD;
      and 36% of women 16-24 years have disabling neck pain. Little is known about the etiology and&#xD;
      prognosis of poor mental health in university students.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim is to advance knowledge about the etiology of depression, anxiety, stress and pain in&#xD;
      undergraduate university students. The investigators will study a cohort of students at&#xD;
      full-year programs at universities in the Stockholm area. Primary research questions are&#xD;
      whether modifiable factors such as sleep quality, lifestyle, screen time and work environment&#xD;
      are independent risk factors for incident episodes or unfavorable trajectories of depression,&#xD;
      anxiety and pain in men and women? To be able to answer these research questions we designed&#xD;
      a prospective cohort study targeting 5000 university students.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall study aim is to advance the knowledge about the etiology and prognosis of common&#xD;
      mental health problems (depression, anxiety and stress) and musculoskeletal pain experienced&#xD;
      by undergraduate university students in Sweden.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific research questions:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Are modifiable factors as bad sleep quality, meal patterns, low physical activity/sedentary&#xD;
      lifestyle, pain conditions and bad study environment independent risk factors of incident&#xD;
      episodes of troublesome depressive and anxiety symptomatology and musculoskeletal pain and of&#xD;
      unfavorable trajectories of depressive, anxiety, stress and pain symptoms? Are modifiable&#xD;
      factors as bad sleep quality, meal patterns, low physical activity/sedentary lifestyle, pain&#xD;
      conditions and bad study environment independent prognostic factors for recovery from&#xD;
      troublesome depressive and anxiety symptomatology and musculoskeletal pain? Do such potential&#xD;
      risk factors and trajectories vary between men and women? What are the trajectories of sleep&#xD;
      quality, meal patterns, physical activity/sedentary lifestyle, pain and substance use during&#xD;
      one academic year (describe the fluctuations of risk factors)?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cohort study of undergraduate full time program students followed-up four times during an&#xD;
      academic year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Source populations:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The source populations for this project are undergraduate full-time program students at&#xD;
      universities in the Stockholm area.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection will be performed with questionnaires through a link sent to students e-mail&#xD;
      address, provided by the participating universities. The students will be able to access the&#xD;
      questionnaire for a four-week period at baseline and each follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exposures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sleep quality, physical activity and sedentary behavior, substance use in the past three&#xD;
      months (non-medical use), study environment, body image, perfectionism, gambling, compulsive&#xD;
      exercise, social media use, cyberbullying, procrastination and loneliness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcomes:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcomes will be measured with the Depression Anxiety Stress Scales-21 (DASS-21). The DASS-21&#xD;
      includes three subscales designed to measure depression, anxiety and stress symptoms in&#xD;
      non-clinical populations with response alternatives on a Likert scale ranging from 0-3.&#xD;
      Higher scores indicate more severe symptoms. Musculoskeletal pain will be measured with the&#xD;
      The Nordic Musculoskeletal pain Questionnaire (NMQ) that cover most potential musculoskeletal&#xD;
      pain sights. The questionnaire measure musculoskeletal symptoms, and pain intensity in nine&#xD;
      body areas: the neck, shoulder, elbow, wrists/hands, upper back, lower back,&#xD;
      hips/thighs/buttocks, knees and ankle/feet. The questions were modified to ask about the&#xD;
      previous month rather than the previous 12 months as per the original NMQ. Those reporting no&#xD;
      symptoms were assigned a pain score of zero, while those who reported having musculoskeletal&#xD;
      symptoms were also asked to report how intense pain was on average over the last month, on a&#xD;
      scale from zero, which refers to no complaints, to nine, which refers to the pain 'as bad as&#xD;
      it can be'.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential confounders:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will collect the following variables as potential confounders of the&#xD;
      association between the exposures and the outcomes. These confounders were selected based on&#xD;
      our review of the literature.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sociodemographic variables: age, gender, citizenship, marital status, number of dependents,&#xD;
      parents' marital status, parents' employment status, annual personal and household income,&#xD;
      hours of work per week, living arrangement, and commute time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Academic variables: Overall average in the past year (first year students will provide the&#xD;
      average for the final year of high school), program of study, year of study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      General health and medically diagnosed comorbidities: The investigators will ask participants&#xD;
      to rate their general health and comorbidities diagnosed by a health care provider in the&#xD;
      past year. We will selected comorbidities that are reported by &gt; 5% of the sample in our&#xD;
      pilot study. In the Canadian pilot study, these include: allergies, arthritis, asthma,&#xD;
      attention disorder/learning disability, eating disorder, hypertension, intestinal or stomach&#xD;
      ulcers, migraine headaches, mood disorder, scoliosis, and sexually transmitted infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data analysis and statistics:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Definition of trajectories: Trajectories of the outcomes depression, anxiety, stress symptoms&#xD;
      and pain will emerge by latent class growth mixture models (LCGMM) that allows for the&#xD;
      identification of multiple underlying trajectories within a defined population. In LCGMM,&#xD;
      each trajectory is defined by its own growth parameters (intercept, linear slope), which are&#xD;
      assumed to be latent. We will use the Baysian Information Criteria (BIC), Bootstrap&#xD;
      Likelihood Ratio Test (BLRT) and entropy (measure of uncertainty) to determine whether our&#xD;
      4-trajactory hypothesis offers the best fitting solution for the data. Also trajectories of&#xD;
      sleep quality, food insecurity, physical activity/sedentary lifestyle, and substance use will&#xD;
      be identified with this method.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Associations between exposures and trajectories: The investigators will use multinomial&#xD;
      logistic regression analyses to determine the associations between each of the exposures and&#xD;
      trajectories of outcomes. The investigators will report the associations as odds ratios (OR)&#xD;
      and 95% confidence intervals (95% CI). The investigators will first build bivariate models to&#xD;
      measure the crude associations between the exposures and trajectories. To identify&#xD;
      confounders, the investigators will build models to test whether the inclusion of each&#xD;
      potential confounder produced a ≥ 10% change in any of the associations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Associations between exposures and incident cases of depression, anxiety, stress symptoms and&#xD;
      pain: At baseline, the investigators will identify a sub-cohort of students at risk of&#xD;
      developing troublesome depressive and anxiety symptoms and pain respectively. The&#xD;
      investigators will use Kaplan-Meier estimates to describe the incidence and discrete time&#xD;
      survival analysis to measure the associations between the exposures and the outcome. In all&#xD;
      models, the reference category will be the level of exposure hypothesized to be associated&#xD;
      with the lowest risk of the outcome. ORs and 95% CIs will be used to describe the strength&#xD;
      and direction of association. The same approach as described above will be used to identify&#xD;
      prognostic factors (starting with a sub-cohort under &quot;risk&quot; of recovery) and for control for&#xD;
      confounding.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size: The investigators estimated the number of parameters that could be included in&#xD;
      the multinomial logistic regression models based on distributions of participants across the&#xD;
      four hypothesized trajectories (no symptoms; improvement; worsening; and persistent) using&#xD;
      two diverse distribution scenarios. In scenario 1, we hypothesized that 70% have no symptoms,&#xD;
      13% experience worsening, 10% improve and 7% have persistent symptoms. In scenario 2, the&#xD;
      investigator hypothesized equal distribution (25%) across trajectories. Based on these&#xD;
      assumptions, the investigators estimated that the models could accommodate between 32&#xD;
      parameters if the investigators recruit 1000 students (scenario 1) to as many as 234&#xD;
      parameters if the investigators recruit 5000 participants (scenario 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Covid-19 sub-study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The recruitment and data collection for the cohort study took place before and during the&#xD;
      Covid-19 pandemic.Therefore, the investigators started a more fequent recording of levels of&#xD;
      pain, axiety and depression from May 2020 with weekly text messages. The data Collection&#xD;
      before and during the pandemic provide a chance to investigate the change in symptoms of&#xD;
      depression, anxiety and stress and lifestyle behaviors in relation to the pandemic. The&#xD;
      specific research questions with regards to this Covid-19-related sub-study are: 1) Are there&#xD;
      any changes regarding symptoms of mental health problems during the first month of the&#xD;
      pandemic? 2) Will students display changes in healthy lifestyle behaviors such as sleep&#xD;
      patterns and quality, meal pattern, exercise and substance use during the first month of the&#xD;
      pandemic and 3) Different trajectories of symptoms of low mood, worry and pain during the&#xD;
      course of the pandemic will be measured weekly with the aim of identifying factors related to&#xD;
      unfavorable trajectories.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 19, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2032</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain</measure>
    <time_frame>2019-2022</time_frame>
    <description>Repeated measures with web-based questionnaires, 5 times (every 3 months), over one year. Outcome measures: Musculoskeletal pain will be measured with the The Nordic Musculoskeletal Questionnaire (NMQ). The NMQ measure musculoskeletal symptoms, and pain intensity in nine body areas: neck, shoulder, elbow, wrists/hands, upper back, lower back, hips/thighs/buttocks, knees, ankle/feet. The questions were modified to assess previous month rather than the previous 12 months as per the original NMQ. No symptoms = a pain score of 0, while the participants who report musculoskeletal symptoms also report average pain intensity over the last month, on a scale from 0 (no complaints), to 9 (pain 'worst possible'). Weekly text messages measure levels of pain.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mental health problems</measure>
    <time_frame>2019-2022</time_frame>
    <description>Repeated measures with web-based questionnaires, 5 times (every 3 months), over one year. Outcome measures: Depression Anxiety Stress Scale-21(DASS-21). DASS-21 includes three subscales (range 0-3, score 0-63, higher scores = more symptoms) to measure depression, anxiety and stress symptoms in nonclinical populations. Weekly text messages measure levels anxiety and depression.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain related to the Covid-19 pandemic.</measure>
    <time_frame>2019-2020</time_frame>
    <description>Web-based questionnaires comparing students entering the study before the Covid-19 pandemic and after. Outcome measures: Musculoskeletal pain will be measured with the The Nordic Musculoskeletal Questionnaire (NMQ). The NMQ measure musculoskeletal symptoms, and pain intensity in nine body areas: neck, shoulder, elbow, wrists/hands, upper back, lower back, hips/thighs/buttocks, knees, ankle/feet. The questions were modified to assess previous month rather than the previous 12 months as per the original NMQ. No symptoms = a pain score of 0, while the participants who report musculoskeletal symptoms also report average pain intensity over the last month, on a scale from 0 (no complaints), to 9 (pain 'worst possible'). Weekly text messages measure levels of pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mental health problems related to the Covid-19 pandemic.</measure>
    <time_frame>2019-2020</time_frame>
    <description>Web-based questionnaires comparing students entering the study before the Covid-19 pandemic and after. Outcome measures: Depression Anxiety Stress Scale-21(DASS-21). DASS-21 (3 subscales, range 0-3, score 0-63, higher scores = more symptoms) to measure depression, anxiety and stress symptoms in nonclinical populations. Weekly text messages measure levels of anxiety and depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">5000</enrollment>
  <condition>Mental Health Issue</condition>
  <condition>Musculoskeletal Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SUN-participants</arm_group_label>
    <description>University students enrolled in a selected university in Stockholm, studying on a full-time educational program with at least one academic year left before graduation.&#xD;
There is no intervention. The exposures are repeated measures, 5 times (every three months), using web-based self-report questionnaires during one academic year. Also weekley SMS are used to measure depression, anxiety and pain intensity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Web-based self-report questionnaires</intervention_name>
    <description>Web-based self-report questionnaires based on well established instruments.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SUN-participants</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Focus Group Interviews</intervention_name>
    <description>Group conversation with open-ended questions with 7-10 students/group on topics relevant to the aim of the study.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SUN-participants</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        University students attending selected universities in Stockholm, Sweden. A number of&#xD;
        universities are included representing different educational programs such as medicine and&#xD;
        life sciences, business, social sciences and technology. There is a majority of student&#xD;
        from medical. and life science educational programs. The aim is to include a total of 5000&#xD;
        students.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The inclusion criteria are students at selected universities/colleges in the Stockholm&#xD;
        attending selected educational programs with at least one remaining academic year before&#xD;
        graduating. Students from matriculation to master level studies are invited to participate.&#xD;
        Participants need to be 18 years of age or older, have access to a smart phone, laptop or&#xD;
        tablet and speak sufficient Swedish or English.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>All students invited to participate in the study answer the question about gender identity - female, male or other. All analyses with regard to gender in the study are based on self-representation based on these three categories.</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eva Skillgate, Professor, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Sophiahemmet</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sophiahemmet University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stockholm</city>
        <state>SE</state>
        <zip>11486</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 10, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 9, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 9, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 10, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cohort study</keyword>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>Stress</keyword>
  <keyword>Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Lifestyle</keyword>
  <keyword>Students</keyword>
  <keyword>Risk Factors</keyword>
  <keyword>Prognostic factors</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Parallell studies in Norway and Canada have been planned for cross-cultural comparisons with merged data sets.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

