<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4592">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04640064</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0019</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04640064</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Hb A1C Pre and Post Confinement in Latin American Children With Type 1 Diabetes: Dulce Study Group</brief_title>
  <official_title>Hb A1C Pre and Post Confinement in Latin American Children With Type 1 Diabetes: Dulce Study Group</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital General Puyo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital General Puyo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A multicenter retrospective observational study among children with type 1 diabetes will be&#xD;
      performed. The Objective of this study will be to determine a) the association between the&#xD;
      increase in Hba1c in children with type 1 diabetes and confinement due to the COVID 19&#xD;
      pandemic. b) the association between the frequency of patient care during social confinement&#xD;
      and the Hba1c values. Different centers from Latin America including Argentina, Peru, Panama,&#xD;
      Chile, and Ecuador will participate in this study. Children younger than 17 years with a&#xD;
      diagnosis of type 1 diabetes prior to 2018 will be included. Data from the medical records of&#xD;
      the participating centers will be collected on the Hb A1c value before and after confinement&#xD;
      (6 months completed). The initial (base) value will be taken as a value of HbA1c registered&#xD;
      in the patient's Clinical History for the year 2018, 2019, and 2020 pre and post quarantine&#xD;
      (Sep-Oct-Nov) 2020, considering compliance with six months of quarantine. Hb A1c should have&#xD;
      been performed in the same institution or with the same methods in order to avoid bias.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Research protocol Hb A1C pre and post Confinement in Latin American children with Type 1&#xD;
      Diabetes: Dulce Study Group&#xD;
&#xD;
      The coronavirus disease is caused by an RNA virus called SARS-CoV-2 (severe acute respiratory&#xD;
      syndrome coronavirus 2) that has spikes on its surface that give a crown appearance under the&#xD;
      electron microscope; hence its name.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A recent cluster of pneumonia cases in Wuhan, China, was caused by this new coronavirus,&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2. In December 2019, adults in Wuhan, a central transportation hub in China, began&#xD;
      presenting severe pneumonia of unknown origin in local hospitals. On December 31, 2019, China&#xD;
      notified the WHO of the outbreak. On January 7, the virus was identified as a SARS-CoV-2. It&#xD;
      soon became known that the disease could be transmitted from asymptomatic people and before&#xD;
      the onset of symptoms. The infection is acquired either by inhaling drops or touching&#xD;
      contaminated surfaces and then touching the nose, mouth, and eyes. The virus is also present&#xD;
      in the stool.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The incubation period ranges from 2 to 14 d [median 5 d]. Studies have identified the&#xD;
      angiotensin 2 receptor as the receptor through which the virus enters the respiratory mucosa.&#xD;
      (1)&#xD;
&#xD;
      What happens in children? Less than 1% of the cases were in children under the age of 10 in&#xD;
      Wuhan, China. Unlike adults, most children have a milder clinical course.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One review included 18 studies with 1065 participants with confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection.&#xD;
      All articles were from China, except for one clinical case in Singapore. Most children had&#xD;
      mild respiratory symptoms, such as fever, dry cough, fatigue, or asymptomatic. Bronchial&#xD;
      thickening and ground-glass opacities were the main radiographic features in symptomatic or&#xD;
      asymptomatic patients. There was only 1 case of severe COVID-19 infection, among the articles&#xD;
      included, in a 13-month-old baby. None died. In general, pediatric COVID-19 patients had a&#xD;
      good prognosis and recovered within 1 to 2 weeks after illness onset. However, children with&#xD;
      mild symptoms or asymptomatic can be a source of viral transmission, constituting essential&#xD;
      data for the prevention of the pandemic (2,3).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Food insecurity has been linked to the risk of obesity during the pandemic. Individuals are&#xD;
      buying ultra-processed, high-calorie foods. As farms dump food like milk and eggs, grocery&#xD;
      stores see empty shelves of cookies, chips, sodas and juices, sugary cereals, and&#xD;
      ready-to-eat processed foods. Therefore, we anticipate that many individuals will experience&#xD;
      high-calorie diets during the pandemic. (4) There is a greater impact in urban areas of an&#xD;
      increasingly sedentary lifestyle. The time in front of the screen, video games, etc., is&#xD;
      associated with overweight and obesity due to the double problem (longer sedentary time and&#xD;
      increased snacks).&#xD;
&#xD;
      What happens in children with diabetes?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Different studies observed a higher risk of morbidity and mortality in older adults who also&#xD;
      had diabetes, hypertension, and other risk factors associated with cardiovascular disease.&#xD;
      (5)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Diabetes and Pandemic&#xD;
&#xD;
      Latin America includes developing countries with limited resources. In the absence of&#xD;
      specific available and approved vaccines and treatments for COVID-19, the only public health&#xD;
      tools available are confinement and social distancing (6). These countries implemented strict&#xD;
      social restrictions to stop transmission, including complete border closures, restricted&#xD;
      movements during day and night, and inter-provincial travel cessation. However, this measure&#xD;
      could generate consequences related to the impact of confinement in vulnerable populations&#xD;
      such as patients with diabetes mellitus, worsening glycemic control, and increasing the&#xD;
      progression of chronic complications related to the disease. Diabetic children had less&#xD;
      access to physical activity, healthy eating, and the frequency of face-to-face clinical&#xD;
      consultation. Glycosylated hemoglobin (HbA1C) reflects the average blood glucose of the last&#xD;
      3 months. This test is the main tool for assessing glycemic control and is associated with a&#xD;
      high predictive value for diabetes complications. It should be performed routinely in all&#xD;
      patients with diabetes at the initial evaluation and as part of the follow-up. Measurement&#xD;
      every three months determines whether the patients' blood glucose goals have been achieved&#xD;
      and maintained (7).&#xD;
&#xD;
      We believe in the need to develop epidemiological tools to measure the impact of the control&#xD;
      of diabetes in children by the crisis and improve the understanding of the patterns of&#xD;
      diabetes care during the pandemic. We have not found in the references works on the increase&#xD;
      of A1c in Latin America before and after confinement. That is why we have developed this&#xD;
      protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Objective of this study will be to determine a) the association between the increase in&#xD;
      Hba1c in children with type 1 diabetes and confinement due to the COVID 19 pandemic. b) the&#xD;
      association between the frequency of patient care during social confinement and the Hba1c&#xD;
      values.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion Criteria: pregnancy, kidney failure, treatments that alter hydrocarbon metabolism&#xD;
      (corticosteroids, chemotherapy, etc.) and chronic iron deficiency pathologies that alter the&#xD;
      value of HbA1c.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Material and methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A multicenter retrospective observational study among children with type 1 diabetes will be&#xD;
      performed. Different centers from Latin America including Argentina, Peru, Panama, Chile, and&#xD;
      Ecuador will participate in this study. Children younger than 17 years with a diagnosis of&#xD;
      type 1 diabetes prior to 2018 will be included. Data from the medical records of the&#xD;
      participating centers will be collected on the Hb A1c value before and after confinement (6&#xD;
      months completed). The initial (base) value will be taken as a value of HbA1c registered in&#xD;
      the patient's Clinical History for the year 2018, 2019, and 2020 pre and post quarantine&#xD;
      (Sep-Oct-Nov) 2020, considering compliance with six months of quarantine. Hb A1c should have&#xD;
      been performed in the same institution or with the same methods in order to avoid bias.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The years will be divided into four-month periods (quartiles). The Hba1c will be recorded in&#xD;
      each period. If a patient had two HbA1c values in the same quarter, the values would be&#xD;
      averaged. If there is no value of HbA1C in a period, N / A would be placed in the box.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, the impact of confinement on the BMI registered in the semesters (provided that&#xD;
      the data is available) 2018, 2019, and 2020 will be completed. The number of consultations&#xD;
      made during 2018,2019 and 2020 by each patient will be completed in the corresponding boxes.&#xD;
      The number of telemedicine consultations during the quarantine period will be completed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Children with type 1 diabetes patients from different private and public centers of Latin&#xD;
      America will be included. The sampling frame will be their medical records. The sample is&#xD;
      made up of clusters (public or private center) in a single stage since all medical records&#xD;
      that meet the selection criteria will be reviewed&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other data to be recorded for analysis will be: public or private setting, date of birth, the&#xD;
      weight of birth, age, sex, nationality, blood pressure (BP), lipids ( total cholesterol,&#xD;
      triglycerides, and HDL-C), vitamin D, date of onset of diabetes, treatment type (traditional,&#xD;
      multiple doses, or insulin pump).&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the collection and processing of the data, a spreadsheet will be used and then the data&#xD;
      will be uploaded to REDCAP and statistical packages It is important to clarify that the local&#xD;
      researcher will prepare the institution's database anonymously and that when the shipment is&#xD;
      made, data to other institutions, it will not be possible to individualize patients, to&#xD;
      guarantee the anonymity of patients and the confidentiality of their health data. The last&#xD;
      four passport numbers will be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The χ2 test will be used to compare proportions. When more than 20% of the cells have&#xD;
      expected frequencies &lt;5, Fisher will use the exact test. The adjustment to the normal&#xD;
      distribution of continuous variables will be evaluated using the Shapiro-Wilks method. When&#xD;
      comparing two groups with normal distribution data, the Student's t test will be performed.&#xD;
      When the homogeneity of the variances cannot be tested, the Brown Forsyth test will be used.&#xD;
      Variables with asymmetric distribution will be log-transformed for analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Several multiple regressions analyses will be performed to examine the relationship between&#xD;
      Hb A1c as a dependent variable and BMI, age, sex, frequency of visits, age of diabetes,&#xD;
      duration of confinement, lipids, vitamin D, etc. as the independent variables. Values of P&#xD;
      &lt;0.05 will be considered significant. The Bonferroni adjustment will be carried out when&#xD;
      numerous comparisons are made. Data will be presented as means ± standard deviations. The&#xD;
      analyzes will be performed using the statistical software SPSS® (Chicago, IL) version 21.0. A&#xD;
      value of p &lt;0.05 will be considered statistically significant&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection&#xD;
&#xD;
      DATE NUMBER NAME PASSPORT SEX AGE ( years BIRTH DATE BIRTH WEIGHT (kG) DATE NUMBER OR&#xD;
      COSULTATIONS 2018 2019 2020 INSULIN type HBA1C 2018 1 2 3 HBA1C 2019 1 2 3 HBA1C 2020 1 2 3&#xD;
      HEIGHT 2018 1 2 3 WEIGHT 2018 1 2 3 BMI 2018 1 2 3 HEIGHT 2019 1 2 3 WEIGHT 2019 1 2 3 BMI&#xD;
      2019 1 2 3 HEIGHT 2020 1 2 3 WEIGHT 2020 1 2 3 BMI 2020 1 2 3 Cholesterol total mg/dL 2018&#xD;
      2019 2020 HDL-C mg/dL 2018 2019 2020 TRIGLYCERIDES mg/dL 2018 2019 2020 Vitamin D (Nanograms)&#xD;
      2018 2019 2020 SBP 2018 mmHg 1 2 3 SBP 2019 mmHg 1 2 3 SBP 2020 mmHg 1 2 3 DBP 2018 mmHg 1 2&#xD;
      3 DBP 2019 mmHg 1 2 3 DBP 2020 mmHg 1 2 3 Treatment Conventional Treatment Muultiple Doses&#xD;
      CSII COVID Positive Yes/NO&#xD;
&#xD;
      References:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. The Indian Journal of Pediatrics (April 2020) 87(4):281-286&#xD;
           https://doi.org/10.1007/s12098-020-03263-6)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. N Engl J Med 2020; 382:1663-1665 DOI: 10.1056/NEJMc2005073 &amp; Pediatrics. 2020 Mar&#xD;
           16;e20200702. doi: 10.1542/peds.2020-0702)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. JAMA Pediatr. Published online April 22, 2020. doi:10.1001/jamapediatrics.2020.146.)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Effects of COVID-19 Lockdown on Lifestyle Behaviors in Children with Obesity Living in&#xD;
           Verona, Italy: A Longitudinal Study. Obesity (Silver Spring). 2020 Apr&#xD;
           30;10.1002/oby.22861. doi: 10.1002/oby.22861)&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. BMJ 2020;368:m1198 doi: 10.1136/bmj.m1198 (Published 26 March 2020; Bo Li1 • Jing&#xD;
           Yang1,2 • Faming Zhao et. Al. Clinical Research in Cardiology (2020) 109:531-538.&#xD;
           https://doi.org/10.1007/s00392-020-01626-9).&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Miller MJ, Loaiza JR, Takyar A, Gilman RH. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2020 May; 14(5):&#xD;
           e0008265. doi: 10.1371/journal.pntd.0008265.)&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Ghosal y col, ( S. Ghosal et al. Diabetes &amp; Metabolic Syndrome: Clinical Research &amp;&#xD;
           Reviews 14 (2020) 319e323320).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 22, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 22, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 22, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Crossover</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hb A1C pre and post Confinement in Latin American children with Type 1 Diabetes</measure>
    <time_frame>six months</time_frame>
    <description>The increase in Hba1c in children with type 1 diabetes and confinement due to the COVID 19 pandemic</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">500</enrollment>
  <condition>Type1diabetes</condition>
  <condition>Childhood ALL</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patient with type 1 diabetes</arm_group_label>
    <description>Children younger than 17 years with a diagnosis of type 1 diabetes prior to 2018 will be included.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        A multicenter retrospective observational study among children with type 1 diabetes will be&#xD;
        performed. Different centers from Latin America including Argentina, Peru, Panama, Chile,&#xD;
        and Ecuador will participate in this study. Children younger than 17 years with a diagnosis&#xD;
        of type 1 diabetes prior to 2018 will be included. Data from the medical records of the&#xD;
        participating centers will be collected on the Hb A1c value before and after confinement (6&#xD;
        months completed). The initial (base) value will be taken as a value of HbA1c registered in&#xD;
        the patient's Clinical History for the year 2018, 2019, and 2020 pre and post quarantine&#xD;
        (Sep-Oct-Nov) 2020, considering compliance with six months of quarantine. Hb A1c should&#xD;
        have been performed in the same institution or with the same methods in order to avoid&#xD;
        bias.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: Children with type 1 diabetes younger than 17 years -&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: pregnancy, kidney failure, treatments that alter hydrocarbon metabolism&#xD;
        (corticosteroids, chemotherapy, etc.), and chronic iron deficiency pathologies that alter&#xD;
        the value of HbA1c.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Valeria Hirschler</name>
      <address>
        <city>Buenos Aires</city>
        <zip>1006</zip>
        <country>Argentina</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Valeria Hirschler</last_name>
      <phone>0111545690538</phone>
      <email>vhirschler@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Edgar Mora, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Angela Figueroa Sobrero, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Edit Scaiola, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Julie Pelicand, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Carlos Del Aguila Villar, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Franco Giraudo Abarca, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Fabio Palacios Porta, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kesia Granela, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nicole Monteverde, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Diana Gonzalez, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 17, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Type 1 diabetes, children, pandemic, HBA1c,</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>We will do our best to be able to share the data with other researchers</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

