<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3026">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04372693</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FON170133</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04372693</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Unplanned Shifting to Online Distance Learning: Nursing Students' Perception and Achievement</brief_title>
  <acronym>(COVID-19)</acronym>
  <official_title>Unplanned Shifting the Traditional Classroom-Based to Online Distance Learning as a Result of (COVID-19) Social Distancing Measures: Nursing Students' Perception and Achievement</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Online Distance Learning (ODL) is an educational delivery system that helps students to join&#xD;
      in an educational opportunity without physically existing in the same setting as the teacher.&#xD;
      Online learning is known as the education that takes place over the Internet, often referred&#xD;
      to as e-Learning, web-based training (WBT), distance learning, or asynchronous learning. When&#xD;
      learners participate in an online learning course at different times, it is known as&#xD;
      asynchronous learning. online learning involves the umbrella term for any learning that takes&#xD;
      place across distance and not in a traditional classroom. WHO recommends Implement social&#xD;
      distancing practices that may include; Staggering the beginning and end of the school day and&#xD;
      Use of online/e-learning strategies? The coronavirus pandemic has changed how millions around&#xD;
      the globe are educated. new shifts in education approaches could widen equality gaps. As of&#xD;
      March 13, the Organization for Economic Co-operation estimated that over 421 million students&#xD;
      are affected due to school closures announced or implemented in 39 countries. Most faculties&#xD;
      in affected areas are finding stop-gap solutions to continue teaching, but the quality of&#xD;
      learning is heavily dependent on the level and quality of digital access.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, the current study aimed to assess Nursing students' perception and achievement&#xD;
      regarding unplanned shifting the Traditional Classroom-Based to Online Distance Learning as a&#xD;
      result of (COVID-19) social distancing measures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      H1: Learning perception is lower for nursing students who learned by unplanned Online&#xD;
      Distance Learning (μ1) than for those who learned by Traditional Classroom-Based learning&#xD;
      (μ2), (H1: μ1 &lt; μ2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      H1: Scholar achievement is greater for nursing students who learned by Traditional&#xD;
      Classroom-Based learning (μ1) than for those who learned by unplanned Online Distance&#xD;
      Learning (μ2), (H1: μ1 &gt; μ2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      A quasi-experimental research design will be utilized in the current study with a comparative&#xD;
      approach.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A purposive sample of adult male and female bachelor's students of nursing will be asked to&#xD;
      participate in the current study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three tools will be adopted to collect data relevant to the current study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. A brief demographic self-administrated questionnaire&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Students' Learning Perception Questionnaire (SLPQ),&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Modified McVay's Readiness for Online Learning Questionnaire&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Online Distance Learning (ODL) is an educational delivery system that helps students to join&#xD;
      in an educational opportunity without physically existing in the same setting as the teacher.&#xD;
      Online learning is known as the education that takes place over the Internet, often referred&#xD;
      to as e-Learning, web-based training (WBT), distance learning, or asynchronous learning. When&#xD;
      learners participate in an online learning course at different times, it is known as&#xD;
      asynchronous learning. Online learning involves the umbrella term for any learning that takes&#xD;
      place across distance and not in a traditional classroom.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The reason for much of the growth in distance education programs in recent years is the&#xD;
      development of the Internet and the improvement of technologies that support online learning&#xD;
      environments. Despite the rapid growth in (OLD) use, there is a need to continuous assessment&#xD;
      of its effectiveness. Numerous studies comparing traditional classroom-based instruction with&#xD;
      technology-supported instruction have found no significant differences in critical&#xD;
      educational variables such as learning outcomes and student satisfaction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Students prefer certain methods of learning more than others. These traits, referred to as&#xD;
      learning styles, form a student's unique learning preference, and aid teachers in the&#xD;
      planning of small-group and individualized instruction. If optimal student learning is&#xD;
      dependent on learning styles, and these styles vary between distance and equivalent on-campus&#xD;
      students, then faculty should be aware of these differences and alter their preparation and&#xD;
      instructional methods accordingly. Knowledge of student learning preferences can aid faculty&#xD;
      in-class preparation, designing class delivery methods, choosing appropriate technologies,&#xD;
      and developing sensitivity to differing student learning preferences within the distance&#xD;
      education environment. Many communication skills required of the (ODL) instructor are similar&#xD;
      to those needed for effective classroom teaching. On the other hand, the online instructor's&#xD;
      role does require a paradigm shift regarding instructional time and space, virtual management&#xD;
      techniques, and the ability to engage students through virtual communication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The coronavirus pandemic has changed how millions around the globe are educated. WHO&#xD;
      recommends implementing social distancing practices that may include; staggering the&#xD;
      beginning and end of the school day and use of online/e-learning strategies . New shifts in&#xD;
      education approaches could widen equality gaps. As of March 13, the Organization for Economic&#xD;
      Co-operation estimated that over 421 million students are affected due to school closures&#xD;
      announced or implemented in 39 countries. Besides, another 22 countries have announced&#xD;
      partial &quot;localized&quot; closures. These risk-control decisions have led millions of students into&#xD;
      temporary 'home-schooling' situations, these changes have certainly caused a degree of&#xD;
      inconvenience, but they have also prompted new examples of educational innovation. To help&#xD;
      slow the virus' spread, Academic 2.7 Million students in Egypt started to learning at home,&#xD;
      in February 2020, via interactive apps, and other faculties got further simpler asynchronous&#xD;
      online learning tools (such as reading material via Google Classroom, ZOOM, sending lessons&#xD;
      and assignments via the official website, WhatsApp or email) augmented with synchronous&#xD;
      face-to-face video instruction, to help preempt school closures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Most faculties in affected areas are finding stop-gap solutions to continue teaching, but the&#xD;
      quality of learning is heavily dependent on the level and quality of digital access.&#xD;
      Moreover, the less affluent, digitally understanding, and low socioeconomic are factors&#xD;
      affecting the student's achievement. For anyone who has taught face-to-face classes, making&#xD;
      the transition to fully online may feel completely overwhelming. Course writers and&#xD;
      instructors alike might find themselves asking questions such as, &quot;How will I translate my&#xD;
      classroom materials-activities or laboratory experiences-in a way that will benefit the&#xD;
      online student? How will I generate discussion and engagement between students? Assessment of&#xD;
      students' perception toward provided learning methods was growing in recent years because the&#xD;
      best way of confirming quality in academic education is obtaining feedback from&#xD;
      undergraduates . Many studies examined students' perception as a solo dimensional scale, such&#xD;
      as self efﬁcacy, behavioral response, or effective response. While, in the current study the&#xD;
      researcher prefers to utilize a comprehensive, widely used, valid, reliable, and&#xD;
      multi-dimensional tool additionally avoid too-much items to prevent respondents fatigue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although the implementation of Online Distance Learning will be established as a result of&#xD;
      (COVID-19) social distancing measures suddenly without any plan of action, one question&#xD;
      remains a need for the answer; how prepared students are for successful Online Distance&#xD;
      Learning? Whatever the answer may be, the new method of e-learning will be administrated for&#xD;
      the student. The researcher believes that addressing the preparedness and rate the important&#xD;
      competencies required by students for effective Distance Learning performance of the student&#xD;
      is the first and important step. Although a number of the online learning readiness scales&#xD;
      have been developed to assess the readiness of students to be online learners, very few of&#xD;
      these scales provide an assessment concerning the knowledge, skills, and attitudes students&#xD;
      might require as online learners. In many of the preparedness scales, there is the tendency&#xD;
      to describe what students have to be (e.g., self-directed, self-aware) rather than what&#xD;
      students need to do . In 2000, McVay developed a Readiness for Online Learning questionnaire&#xD;
      that used attitudes and behaviors as predictors of online student learning readiness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, the current study aimed to assess Nursing students' perception and achievement&#xD;
      regarding unplanned shifting the Traditional Classroom-Based to Online Distance Learning as a&#xD;
      result of (COVID-19) social distancing measures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Theoretical framework Teachers must examine students' traditional perspectives and adopt a&#xD;
      comprehensive perspective framework of learning environments that is appropriate for online&#xD;
      teaching. Specific aspects of adult learning theory guided the development of the pedagogical&#xD;
      model that was used to develop the online learning environment. Johnson, 1997 suggests a&#xD;
      combination philosophy of learning theories rather than be confined to one preferred&#xD;
      perspective such as; behavioral, Cognitive, and social learning theories. Quality online&#xD;
      learning environments should be made up of elements of behavioral learning theory e.g. using&#xD;
      positive reinforcement and repetition. Cognitive learning theory (for example, addressing&#xD;
      Multiple senses, presenting new information in motivating ways, limiting the amount of&#xD;
      information presented, and connecting new information to prior knowledge), and social&#xD;
      learning theory (for example, encouraging group interaction, peer assessment, and personal&#xD;
      feedback). These three theories were synthesized into integrated seven general principles&#xD;
      that appear to be crucial for online learning environments. The current study adopting that&#xD;
      the powerful online learning environments need to contain a combination of these principles:&#xD;
      (1) address individual difference, (2) motivate the student, (3) avoid information overload,&#xD;
      (4) create A real-life context, (5) encourage social interaction, (6) provide hands-on&#xD;
      activities, and (7) encourage student reflection. These principles for online instruction&#xD;
      will be attempted to apply all as a framework while facing the challenge of dramatical,&#xD;
      situational, and unplanned application.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Hypothesis H1: Learning perception is lower for nursing students who learned by&#xD;
      unplanned Online Distance Learning (μ1) than for those who learned by Traditional&#xD;
      Classroom-Based learning (μ2), (H1: μ1 &lt; μ2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      H1: Scholar achievement is grater for nursing students who learned by Traditional&#xD;
      Classroom-Based learning (μ1) than for those who learned by unplanned Online Distance&#xD;
      Learning (μ2), (H1: μ1 &gt; μ2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects and Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A quasi-experimental research design will be utilized in the current study. The study group&#xD;
      will be learned (prospectively) the selected courses by Online Distance method with following&#xD;
      certain principles for effective online learning environments as a result of (COVID-19)&#xD;
      social distancing measures in comparison to the control group of nursing students who&#xD;
      (retrospectively) learned the same courses by the Traditional Classroom-Based learning. Both&#xD;
      study and control groups will be assessed for students' perception and scholar achievement as&#xD;
      a dependent effect. However, subjects of the current study will not randomly be assigned to&#xD;
      either the experimental or the comparison group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A purposive sample of adult male and female bachelor's students of nursing who studying&#xD;
      health assessment (clinical) and research in nursing courses will be asked to participate in&#xD;
      the current study. The participant students will be divided into study and control groups.&#xD;
      Students who studied in autumn Semester (Official started in September 2020) will be selected&#xD;
      as a study group. While the control group will be selected as the students who studied the&#xD;
      same courses in the autumn semester (started in 2019 September 21 to 2020 January 9). The&#xD;
      estimated sample size is 180 participant, estimated by (G Power analysis) (independent&#xD;
      t-tests - One tail, Effect size = 0.5, α = 0.05, Power (1-β) = 0.95, balanced allocation&#xD;
      ratio 1:1). The students who studying the selected courses (expected to be 500 students) as&#xD;
      well as have corresponding to the following inclusion criteria will included in the current&#xD;
      study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  None of the participants had previously taken the online-based course.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The same educational background.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Passed all pre- requisite courses.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Full-time enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Instruments of Data Collection:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three tools will be framed to collect data relevant to the current study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. A brief demographic self-administrated questionnaire was constructed to collect&#xD;
           information on aspects such as the participant's gender, age group and enrollment level&#xD;
           in addition to students' GPA, it will be collected from the student affairs of the&#xD;
           college to measure the students' scholar achievement as a dependent variable.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Students' Learning Perception Questionnaire (SLPQ), will be utilized in the current&#xD;
           study to measure students' perception as a dependent variable, (SLPQ) was adopted,&#xD;
           inventory and metric instrument to assess the effectiveness of provided learning methods&#xD;
           as perceived by the students, its reliable tool with Cronbach's Alpha 0.76 which reflect&#xD;
           the degree of internal consistency among variables. It covers two inventories; students'&#xD;
           perceptions of the teaching-learning environment (TLE) (22 items) and students'&#xD;
           approaches to learning (SAL) (12 items). [12-13]. Six factors emerged from the 22 items&#xD;
           measuring different aspects of the teaching-learning environment (TLE): (Teaching for&#xD;
           understanding, Alignment, Staff enthusiasm, and support, Interest and relevance,&#xD;
           Constructive feedback, and Support from other students). [14]. While, students'&#xD;
           approaches to learning (SAL) measure three broad approaches to learning: deep approach&#xD;
           to learning, surface approach to learning, and organized studying, each with four items.&#xD;
           (SLPQ) Items will be scored on a five-point Likert scale (&quot;Totally disagree (1)&quot; to&#xD;
           &quot;Totally agree (5)&quot;) [12-14]. The scores of each students will be summed for&#xD;
           interpretation, those who obtained less than (25%) will considered as having an low&#xD;
           perception, while who obtained (26 - 75%) will considered as a moderate perception, and&#xD;
           finally who get more than (75%) will considered as a high perception level.&#xD;
&#xD;
           The instrument will be provided as its original language of English because the students&#xD;
           learned and examined all courses in the English language. Arabic translation will be&#xD;
           available to students if they faced difﬁculty in understanding any statement. Data will&#xD;
           be collected from participants through an electronic questionnaire online using email&#xD;
           (for control and experimental group).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Modified McVay's Readiness for Online Learning Questionnaire. Watkins et al. (2004)&#xD;
           developed a 27 items adopted scale that used attitudes and behaviors of the participants&#xD;
           as predictors of students' preparedness for online learning and e-learning environments,&#xD;
           its reliable tool with Cronbach's Alpha 0.82. This self-administrated instrument&#xD;
           identified six dimensions: Technology Access (3 items), Online Skills and Relationships&#xD;
           (9 items), Motivation (3 items), Online Audio/Video (3 items), Internet Discussions (4&#xD;
           items) and Importance to your success (5 items). The instrument consisted of a 5-point&#xD;
           Likert-type scale response format (1- Completely Disagree, 2-Strongly Disagree, 3- Not&#xD;
           Sure, 4-Strongly Agree, 5-Completely Agree).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethical Consideration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation in the study is voluntary; each participant has the right to withdraw from the&#xD;
      study when he or she wants. Informed consent will be obtained from the participants.&#xD;
      Confidentiality and anonymity of the subjects are assured through coding of all data.&#xD;
      Collected data will be used for the research purpose only and will not be reused in another&#xD;
      research. All information taken will be protected and will not affect students' annual&#xD;
      appraisal by any means. The formulated database and the result of the current study will be&#xD;
      incorporating into the plan of education in the college.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedure:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once the official permission and ethical approval are granted to proceed to the proposed&#xD;
      study, the implementation will be applied in two parts:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first Part will be initiated by reviewing the selected students' data who are studying&#xD;
      the selected courses in semester (autumn- 2019) and (autumn -2020). The contact information&#xD;
      of the students who will correspond to the inclusion criteria will be obtained. Then, they&#xD;
      will be invited by sent phone messages to participate in the current study. The student who&#xD;
      willing to participate in this study will be divided into paired study and control groups.&#xD;
      The students who will study in the (autumn- 2020) will be operated as a study group, also the&#xD;
      students who are previously completed autumn 2019 semester will be manipulated as a control&#xD;
      group. The excepted number of participants will be 500 students. The purpose, nature, and&#xD;
      benefits of the study will be explained to the participants. A pilot study will be conducted&#xD;
      on 10% = 18 students to estimate the needed time for data collection, and to test the&#xD;
      feasibility, objectivity, and clarity of the study instruments. All queries of students&#xD;
      regarding the meaning of the statements and how to ﬁll in the answers will be discussed via&#xD;
      email and addressed before the actual study will start.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Second Part will be started by sending (instrument 1, 2) to the control group (students who&#xD;
      were learned by Traditional Classroom-Based Learning) via electronic online survey system&#xD;
      (Jot form) to fill out, the link of the created form was&#xD;
      (https://www.jotform.com/help/408-understanding-your-account-usage-and-limits). These&#xD;
      collected data will be considered as baseline data pertinent to the current study. About the&#xD;
      study group (students who learned by online distance way) they will be asked first to fill&#xD;
      out (instrument 1, 3) then, The following actions implemented while online learning will be&#xD;
      processing;&#xD;
&#xD;
      (1) Address and consider the students' differences in online learning application as a new&#xD;
      experience. Provide Content in Multiple Formats. use of various communication technologies.&#xD;
      Lectures are audio streamed and synchronized with the applicable PowerPoint presentation.&#xD;
      lectures are also transcribed and posted on the course Web site. Utilize links to outside Web&#xD;
      sites that provide supplemental material on the current topic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      (2) Allow for Individual Locus of Control. Access the content through links or a graphical&#xD;
      organizer. Access to organize the course material as students need. Students may even move&#xD;
      through the course topics in random order.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Encourage active and collaborative interaction. In light of the idea that the whole is&#xD;
           greater than the sum of its parts, each course is designed with activities that are both&#xD;
           individual- and group-based.&#xD;
&#xD;
           (3) Motivate the student:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Maintain students' attention by providing an environment that is engaging and&#xD;
           participative. Make the students feel that the course material is relevant. Incorporate&#xD;
           Games into the Online Environment. Use Multimedia When Appropriate.&#xD;
&#xD;
           (4) Avoid information overload,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Limit the Amount of Content and Number of Activities. Organize Instruction Around&#xD;
           Learning Cycles. Provide a Graphic Organizer for the Course.&#xD;
&#xD;
           (5) Create A real-life context,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Create Virtual Learning Teams. Simulate Reality Using Appropriate Case Studies. Require&#xD;
           Collaborative Projects (6) Encourage social interaction,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Create a Personal Connection with Students. Peer Review and Feedback. Facilitate&#xD;
           Interaction (7) Provide hands-on activities,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Organize Online Courses Around Projects. Think-Pair-Share in a Virtual Environment. Use&#xD;
           Small-Group Discussions During Synchronous Sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
           (8) Encourage student reflection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Provide Extensive and Timely Feedback and encourage online Diaries or Reflective&#xD;
           Journals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the current semester, the students of the study group will be asked to complete&#xD;
      an electronic online survey system using (Jot form) (instrument 2). Also, the GPA of all&#xD;
      participants in the study and control group will be collected from the student affairs.&#xD;
      Finally, the researcher will compare the data of the study dependent variables to the&#xD;
      collected baseline data (control group).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Analysis Upon completion of data collection, descriptive and inferential statistics will&#xD;
      be utilized to test for differences among the study and control group subjects, using the&#xD;
      SPSS program.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Online Distance Learning with certain principals will be implemented for the study group and control group who learned by Traditional Classroom-Based will be selected retrospectively as baseline data, students' perception and achievement will be measured for both.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Students' Learning Perception Questionnaire (SLPQ),</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Electronic online Questionnaire will be utilized using (Jot form) the link of the created Questionnaire is https://www.jotform.com/help/408-understanding-your-account-usage-and-limits&#xD;
Students' Learning Perception Questionnaire (SLPQ), will be utilized in the current study to measure students' perception as a dependent variable, (SLPQ) was adopted, inventory and metric instrument to assess the effectiveness of provided learning methods as perceived by the students. It covers two inventories; students' perceptions of the teaching-learning environment (TLE) (22 items) and students' approaches to learning (SAL) (12 items) (SLPQ) Items will be scored on a five-point Likert scale rated from &quot;totally disagree&quot; (1)&quot; to &quot;Totally agree (5)&quot;) . students who obtained less than (25%) will be considered as having a low perception, while who obtained (26 - 75%) will be considered as a moderate perception, and finally who get more than (75%) will be considered as a high perception level.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>students' scholar achievement.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>students' GPA, it will be collected from the student affairs of the college to measure the students' scholar achievement as a dependent variable.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Modified McVay's Readiness for Online Learning Questionnaire.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>3- Modified McVay's Readiness for Online Learning Questionnaire.&#xD;
Electronic online Questionnaire will be utilized using (Jot form) the link of created Questionnaire is https://www.jotform.com/help/408-understanding-your-account-usage-and-limits&#xD;
Watkins et al. (2004) developed a 27 items adopted scale that used attitudes and behaviors of the participants as predictors of students' preparedness for online learning and e-learning environments, its reliable tool with Cronbach's Alpha 0.82. This self-administrated instrument identified six dimensions: Technology Access (3 items), Online Skills and Relationships (9 items), Motivation (3 items), Online Audio/Video (3 items), Internet Discussions (4 items) and Importance to your success (5 items). The instrument consisted of a 5-point Likert-type scale response format (1- Completely Disagree, 2-Strongly Disagree, 3- Not Sure, 4-Strongly Agree, 5-Completely Agree).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">180</enrollment>
  <condition>Distance Learning-Online Learning</condition>
  <condition>Traditional Classroom-Based Learning</condition>
  <condition>Coronavirus Disease Social Distancing Measures</condition>
  <condition>Nursing Students' Perception and Achievement</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>group of students who are learning by Online Distance</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The following principals implemented while online learning will be processing;&#xD;
Address and consider the students' differences in online learning application as a new experience.&#xD;
Allow for Individual Locus of Control.&#xD;
Motivate the student:&#xD;
Avoid information overload,&#xD;
Create A real-life context,&#xD;
Encourage social interaction,&#xD;
Provide hands-on activities,&#xD;
Encourage student reflection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>students who were learned by Traditional Classroom-Based</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>impliminting Online Distance Learning</intervention_name>
    <description>as a result of (COVID-19) social distancing measures, the Online Distance Learning will be implemented without prior planning for undergraduate nursing students</description>
    <arm_group_label>group of students who are learning by Online Distance</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All students should have corresponded to the following inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None of the participants had previously taken the online-based course.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The same educational background.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Passed all pre-requisite courses.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Full-time enrollment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sameh Elhabashy, Lecturer</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Faculty of Nursing-Cairo University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cairo University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <zip>11612</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 30, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 30, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sameh Elhabashy</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>the study will be available to interested researchers by Publication in the indexed journal at the end of the study completion</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

