<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="751">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04707664</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PTX-001-003</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04707664</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sargramostim Use in COVID-19 to Recover Patient Health</brief_title>
  <acronym>SCOPE</acronym>
  <official_title>A Randomized Phase 2b Trial Evaluating Clinical Outcomes of Inhaled Sargramostim in High-risk Patients With Mild-moderate COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Partner Therapeutics, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>United States Department of Defense</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Partner Therapeutics, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this research is to understand if the study drug, also called sargramostim or&#xD;
      Leukine®, can help prevent the worsening of COVID-19 when the study drug is inhaled. This&#xD;
      study will also help researchers understand if inhaled sargramostim can help prevent visits&#xD;
      to the emergency room and hospitalization related to COVID-19 or death.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This Phase 2b, multicenter, placebo-controlled, double-blind study will randomize&#xD;
      approximately 400 adult patients who are symptomatic with mild or moderate COVID-19 (as&#xD;
      defined in the FDA Guidance Document: Covid-19: Developing Drugs and Biological Products for&#xD;
      Treatment or Prevention, May 2020) who are at high risk for progression to more severe&#xD;
      disease. Patients will be randomized in a 1:1 ratio to inhaled sargramostim plus standard of&#xD;
      care (SOC) or placebo plus SOC. All patients on the sargramostim arm will be treated with 250&#xD;
      mcg inhaled sargramostim once daily for 5 days delivered via a vibrating mesh nebulizer.&#xD;
      Patients on the placebo arm will receive an equivalent volume of inhaled placebo diluent once&#xD;
      daily for 5 days delivered via a vibrating mesh nebulizer. Patients will be followed for up&#xD;
      to 28 days after start of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sargramostim (Leukine) is a formulation of Granulocyte Macrophage Colony Stimulating Factor&#xD;
      (GM-CSF), which is a critical cytokine for healthy pulmonary function. Detailed studies have&#xD;
      shown that GM-CSF is necessary for alveolar macrophage (AM) maturation and maintenance.&#xD;
      Although GM-CSF was discovered as a myelopoietic growth factor, it has diverse additional&#xD;
      effects that both promote differentiation of myeloid precursors into neutrophils, monocytes,&#xD;
      and dendritic cells and control function of mature myeloid cells. GM-CSF is also known to&#xD;
      reverse immunoparalysis seen in sepsis, resulting in beneficial outcomes. In addition, GM-CSF&#xD;
      prevents bacteremia in post influenza bacterial pneumonia through locally mediated improved&#xD;
      lung antibacterial resistance and increased reactive oxygen species production by AMs.&#xD;
      Pulmonary delivery of this GM-CSF has potential to reduce morbidity and mortality due to&#xD;
      viral pneumonias, potentially including COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This Phase 2b, multicenter, placebo-controlled, double-blind study will randomize approximately 400 adult patients who are symptomatic with mild or moderate COVID-19 (as defined in the FDA Guidance Document: Covid-19: Developing Drugs and Biological Products for Treatment or Prevention, May 2020) who are at high risk for progression to more severe disease. Patients will be randomized in a 1:1 ratio to inhaled sargramostim plus standard of care (SOC) or placebo plus SOC.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Double blind</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19-related emergency room visit or COVID-19- related hospitalization, or death (any cause)</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients who experience COVID-19-related emergency room visit or COVID-19- related hospitalization, or death (any cause)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events during treatment period and up to Day 28</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Time to COVID-19-related emergency room visit or COVID-19-related hospitalization, or death (any cause)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to progression based on NIAID ordinal scale</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Time to progression of disease as determined by a ≥ 2-point increase in the NIAID ordinal scale up to Day 28</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression based on NIAID ordinal scale</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with progression of disease as determined by a ≥ 2-point increase in the NIAID ordinal scale up to Day 28</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>7, 14, 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with symptom improvement via a symptom questionnaire by days 7, 14, and 28</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom resolution</measure>
    <time_frame>7, 14, 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with symptom resolution via a symptom questionnaire by days 7, 14, and 28</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>SARS-CoV Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sargramostim Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Day 1 - 5: Sargramostim treatment in addition to standard of care for COVID-19</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Day 1 - 5: Placebo treatment in addition to standard of care for COVID-19</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sargramostim</intervention_name>
    <description>All patients randomized to the sargramostim treatment arm will be treated with 250 mcg inhaled sargramostim administered via a vibrating mesh nebulizer once daily for 5 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sargramostim Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Leukine</other_name>
    <other_name>GM-CSF</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>All patients in the control arm will receive an equivalent volume of inhaled placebo diluent administered via a vibrating mesh nebulizer once daily for 5 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with a positive laboratory diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2 infection by an antigen or&#xD;
             a molecular test ≤5 days prior to randomization. The test should have been authorized&#xD;
             by the relevant regulatory authority.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have one or more of the following mild or moderate COVID-19 symptoms for ≤5 days prior&#xD;
             to randomization:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Fever&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. New onset or worsening cough&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Sore throat&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Malaise or fatigue&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Headache&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Muscle pain (myalgias)&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Gastrointestinal symptoms (e.g., nausea, vomiting, diarrhea)&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. New onset or worsening shortness of breath (dyspnea)&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. New loss of taste (ageusia) and/or smell (anosmia). Note: any of these symptoms&#xD;
                  (ageusia, anosmia) alone or in combination cannot be used as the SOLE qualifying&#xD;
                  symptoms for enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. At higher risk for progression to more severe COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Age ≥ 60 years&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Age 18-59 years and having one or more of the following co-morbid conditions&#xD;
                  which are clinically stable in the opinion of the Investigator:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Chronic respiratory conditions such as asthma, chronic obstructive pulmonary&#xD;
                       disease (COPD), pulmonary fibrosis&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Obesity with BMI ≥ 30 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Cardiovascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Sickle cell disease&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Diabetes mellitus being managed with concomitant medications&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Hypertension being managed with concomitant medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Oxygen saturation by pulse oximeter &gt; 93% on room air&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Negative pregnancy test (if woman of childbearing potential)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Females of childbearing potential and males with female partners of childbearing&#xD;
             potential must agree to use acceptable contraceptive methods for the duration of the&#xD;
             study (screening to Day 28)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The patient must give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Hospitalized patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who have received or are receiving other treatments to prevent progression of&#xD;
             COVID-19 disease severity, including but not limited to:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Monoclonal antibodies e.g., bamlanivimab, casirivimab plus imdevimab&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Antiviral agents e.g., remdesivir&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Other COVID-19 therapies used as part of the standard of care, e.g., convalescent&#xD;
                  plasma, dexamethasone&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients who have received a COVID-19 vaccine or participated in a clinical trial for&#xD;
             a COVID19 vaccine&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients enrolled in interventional clinical trials for other experimental therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients on chronic oxygen supplementation due to cardiopulmonary or other conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with unstable comorbid conditions (e.g., decompensated congestive heart&#xD;
             failure (CHF), COPD with exacerbation, current angina pectoris, uncontrolled diabetes&#xD;
             mellitus, uncontrolled hypertension, uncontrolled asthma)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients with severe pulmonary comorbid conditions, including systemic&#xD;
             steroid-dependent asthma, systemic steroid-dependent COPD, oxygen-dependent COPD, lung&#xD;
             transplant, or cystic fibrosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients who have received highly immunosuppressive therapy (to include systemic&#xD;
             corticosteroids) or anti-cancer combination chemotherapy within 24 hours prior to&#xD;
             first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients with known or suspected intolerance or hypersensitivity to sargramostim, or&#xD;
             any component of the product&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients who have previously experienced severe and unexplained side effects during&#xD;
             aerosol delivery of any kind of medical product&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Pregnant or breastfeeding females&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients who, in the opinion of the Investigator, will not be able to comply with all&#xD;
             the study procedures and visits as outlined in the schedule of events, including&#xD;
             follow-up&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sanjeev Ahuja, MD</last_name>
    <phone>(781)819-4949</phone>
    <phone_ext>1588</phone_ext>
    <email>scopestudy@partnertx.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV2</keyword>
  <keyword>sargramostim</keyword>
  <keyword>Leukine</keyword>
  <keyword>(recombinant human) GM-CSF</keyword>
  <keyword>immune modulator</keyword>
  <keyword>SCOPE</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sargramostim</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

