<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="377">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04605757</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>714/2020/Oss/AOUBo</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04605757</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Long-term Evolution of Pulmonary Involvement of Novel SARS-COV-2 Infection (COVID-19): Follow the Covid Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pulmonary Involvement of Novel SARS-COV-2 Infection (COVID-19): Long-term Impact and Predictors of Possible Lasting Damage: Follow the Covid Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria di Bologna Policlinico S. Orsola Malpighi</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria di Bologna Policlinico S. Orsola Malpighi</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In December 2019 the first case of human infection by a new coronavirus was identified,&#xD;
      currently called SARS-COV-2 (Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome - Coronavirus - 2),&#xD;
      characterized by high contagiousness and the possibility of causing a severe acute&#xD;
      respiratory distress syndrome from which its acronym derives and which caused the state of a&#xD;
      global pandemic in a few months. The most frequent clinical manifestation of COVID-19 is&#xD;
      pneumonia, which in about 20% of cases results in acute respiratory failure. Very few studies&#xD;
      have so far addressed the problem of clinical and functional recovery in these patients, most&#xD;
      of them just before or after discharge and none specifically focused on patients admitted for&#xD;
      ARF. Indeed most of these investigations were limited to a specific field such as symptoms,&#xD;
      pulmonary function and radiological changes. There are no guidelines for the follow-up of&#xD;
      COVID-19 patients, despite the British Thoracic Society (BTS) has published a guidance for&#xD;
      scheduling post-hospitalization assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim of this study is to describe the long term (6 to 12 months) evolution of lung involvement&#xD;
      in patients discharged after an episode of ARF due to COVID-19, identifying possible factor&#xD;
      associated to lasting clinical, functional or radiological abnormalities collecting data from&#xD;
      hospital stay, 1-month after hospital discharge, 3-months after hospital discharge and&#xD;
      6-to-12-months after hospital discharge.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Coronaviruses are a family of viruses with marked tropism for the respiratory system, being&#xD;
      able to cause heterogeneous pathological states in humans ranging from the common cold to&#xD;
      more serious diseases such as Respiratory Syndrome severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS).&#xD;
      In December 2019 in Wuhan in China, the first case of human infection by a new coronavirus&#xD;
      was identified, currently called SARS-COV-2 (Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome - Coronavirus&#xD;
      - 2), characterized by high contagiousness and the possibility of causing a severe acute&#xD;
      respiratory distress syndrome from which its acronym derives and which caused the state of a&#xD;
      global pandemic in a few months. The disease caused by the SARS-COV-2 virus is called COVID&#xD;
      19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The most frequent clinical manifestation of COVID-19 is pneumonia, which in about 20% of&#xD;
      cases results in acute respiratory failure requiring oxygen therapy or ventilatory support.&#xD;
      sometimes resulting in a picture similar to that caused by acute respiratory distress&#xD;
      syndrome (ARDS), found in 60-70% of patients admitted to intensive care. The pathogenesis of&#xD;
      classical ARDS involves three phases of the disease: an exudative, a proliferative and a&#xD;
      fibrotic phase, which occurs when the removal of alveolar collagen fails and leads to&#xD;
      progressive pulmonary fibrosis. It is not known whether the long-term evolution of the COVID&#xD;
      19 disease could result in the establishment of a fibrotic phase similar to that predicted by&#xD;
      the pathogenesis of classical ARDS, which would lead to a chronic ventilatory deficit similar&#xD;
      to that of pulmonary interstitial diseases, with serious impact on quality of life and&#xD;
      mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, it is not well-known whether SARS-COV-2 pneumonia causes restitutio ad integrum or&#xD;
      whether it can induce persistent parenchymal alterations and lung function abnormalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Very few studies have so far addressed the problem of clinical and functional recovery in&#xD;
      these patients, most of them just before or after discharge and none specifically focused on&#xD;
      patients admitted for ARF. Indeed most of these investigations were limited to a specific&#xD;
      field such as symptoms, pulmonary function and radiological changes.There are no guidelines&#xD;
      for the follow-up of COVID-19 patients, despite the British Thoracic Society (BTS) has&#xD;
      published a guidance for scheduling post-hospitalization assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim of this study, spontaneous,observational, both prospectic and retrospective, is to&#xD;
      describe the long term (6 to 12 months) evolution of lung involvement in patients discharged&#xD;
      after an episode of ARF due to COVID-19, identifying possible factor associated to lasting&#xD;
      clinical, functional or radiological abnormalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investigators will collect clinical, functional and radiological parameters during:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the hospital stay due to COVID-19 (H);&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the 1-month after hospital discharge followup visit (V1);&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the 3-months after hospital discharge followup visit (V2);&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the 6-to-12-months after hospital discharge followup visit, performed for study subjects&#xD;
           that at V2 show clinical and/or functional and/or radiological abnormalities due to&#xD;
           sequelae of COVID-19 (V3).&#xD;
&#xD;
      For data analysis, all variables will be analyzed using descriptive method. Continuous&#xD;
      variables will be presented as means, standard deviation, median and respective minimum and&#xD;
      maximum values; the discrete or nominal variables will be expressed as frequencies and&#xD;
      relative percentages. Subgroup analysis will be performed using X- 2 test or Fischer test&#xD;
      when appropriate; parametric variables not normally distributed will be analyzed by&#xD;
      Kruskal-wallis non-parametric test. Association between two or more parameters will be&#xD;
      calculate with Spearman Correlation. p &lt;0.05 values will be considered statistically&#xD;
      significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study was approved by the Local Ethic Committee.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 30, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Long term evolution of clinical involvement due to SARS-COV-2 pneumonia / symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>from hospital stay to 6-to-12 months after hospital discharge for SARS-COV-2 pneumonia.</time_frame>
    <description>For long term clinical evolution of SARS-COV-2 pneumonia Investigators will evaluate the presence or absence of each of the following symptoms (yes/no respectively for presence/absence):&#xD;
dyspnea,&#xD;
fatigue,&#xD;
cough,&#xD;
fever,&#xD;
thoracic pain,&#xD;
nausea,&#xD;
diarrhea,&#xD;
dysgeusia. The presence of each of these symptoms will be collected at the time of the hospital stay due to COVID-19 (H) and at 1-month after hospital discharge followup visit (V1); at 3-months after hospital discharge followup visit (V2); at 6-to-12-months after hospital discharge followup visit (V3). V3 will be performed for study subjects that at V2 show clinical and/or functional and/or radiological abnormalities due to sequelae of COVID-19.&#xD;
Differences in terms of presence and type of each symptoms between H, V1, V2 and V3 will be evaluated.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Long term evolution of clinical involvement due to SARS-COV-2 pneumonia / respiratory rate</measure>
    <time_frame>from hospital stay to 6-to-12 months after hospital discharge for SARS-COV-2 pneumonia.</time_frame>
    <description>For long term clinical evolution of SARS-COV-2 pneumonia Investigators will collect respiratory rate (RR, breaths/minute) of study subjects collected during the hospital stay due to COVID-19 (H); at V1, V2and V3. Difference in RR between H, V1, V2 and V3 will be evaluated.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Long term evolution of functional involvement due to SARS-COV-2 pneumonia - blood gas exchange parameters/partial pressure of oxygen and partial pressure of carbon monoxide</measure>
    <time_frame>from hospital stay to 6-to-12 months after hospital discharge for SARS-COV-2 pneumonia</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will collect:&#xD;
partial pressure of oxygen [paO2, mmHg],&#xD;
partial pressure of carbon monoxide [paCO2 mmHg],&#xD;
emerged from blood gas exchange analysis performed during H, V1, V2 and V3. For each parameter (paO2, paCO2) the difference between value at H, V1,V2 and V3 will be evaluated.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Long term evolution of functional involvement due to SARS-COV-2 pneumonia - blood gas exchange parameters/ ph</measure>
    <time_frame>from hospital stay to 6-to-12 months after hospital discharge for SARS-COV-2 pneumonia</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will collect:&#xD;
- ph [absolute value],&#xD;
emerged from blood gas exchange analysis performed during H, V1, V2 and V3. Difference between pH value at H, V1,V2 and V3 will be evaluated.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Long term evolution of functional involvement due to SARS-COV-2 pneumonia - blood gas exchange parameters/ oxygen saturation</measure>
    <time_frame>from hospital stay to 6-to-12 months after hospital discharge for SARS-COV-2 pneumonia</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will collect:&#xD;
- oxygen saturation [SatO2, in %]),&#xD;
emerged from blood gas exchange analysis performed during H, V1, V2 and V3. Difference between SatO2 value at H, V1,V2 and V3 will be evaluated.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Long term evolution of functional involvement due to SARS-COV-2 pneumonia - blood gas exchange parameters: P/F ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>from hospital stay to 6-to-12 months after hospital discharge for SARS-COV-2 pneumonia</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will collect:&#xD;
- P/F ratio (ratio between the measured paO2 and fraction of inspired oxygen ratio) expressed in absolute ratio;&#xD;
emerged from blood gas exchange analysis performed during H, V1, V2 and V3. Difference between P/F ratio value at H, V1,V2 and V3 will be evaluated.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Long term evolution of functional involvement due to SARS-COV-2 pneumonia - pulmonary function tests/ forced expiratory volume in the first second; forced vital capacity; total lung capacity; residual volume</measure>
    <time_frame>from 1 month after hospital discharge for SARS-COV-2 pneumonia to 6-to-12 months after hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will consider the following parameters:&#xD;
forced expiratory volume in the first second [FEV1,expressed in % of predicted value];&#xD;
forced vital capacity [FVC, expressed in % of predicted value];&#xD;
total lung capacity [TLC, expressed in % of predicted value];&#xD;
residual volume [RV, expressed in % of predicted value];&#xD;
collected through pulmonary function tests performed at V1, V2 and V3. For each parameter (FEV1, FVC, TLC, RV) the difference between value at V1,V2 and V3 will be evaluated.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Long term evolution of functional involvement due to SARS-COV-2 pneumonia - pulmonary function tests/ FEV1/FVC ratio and RV/TLC ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>from 1 month after hospital discharge for SARS-COV-2 pneumonia to 6-to-12 months after hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will consider the following parameters:&#xD;
FEV1/FVC absolute ratio;&#xD;
RV/TLC absolute ratio;&#xD;
collected through pulmonary function tests performed at V1, V2 and V3. For each parameter (FEV1/FVC, RV/TLC) the difference between value at V1,V2 and V3 will be evaluated.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Long term evolution of functional involvement due to SARS-COV-2 pneumonia - diffusing capacity of carbon monoxide</measure>
    <time_frame>from 1 month after hospital discharge for SARS-COV-2 pneumonia to 6-to-12 months after hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will consider diffusing capacity of carbon monoxide (DLCO), expressed in % of the predicted value collected during V1, V2 and V3. Differences in terms of DLCO values between V1, V2 and V3 will be calculated.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Long term evolution of functional involvement due to SARS-COV-2 pneumonia - six minute walking test distance</measure>
    <time_frame>from 1 month after hospital discharge for SARS-COV-2 pneumonia to 6-to-12 months after hospital discharge.</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will consider 6 minute walking test [6MWT] distance, expressed in meters collected during V1, V2 and V3. Differences in terms of 6MWT distance between V1, V2 and V3 will be calculated.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Long term evolution of functional involvement due to SARS-COV-2 pneumonia - presence of desaturation during six minute walking test</measure>
    <time_frame>from 1 month after hospital discharge for SARS-COV-2 pneumonia to 6-to-12 months after hospital discharge.</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will consider the presence (yes/no) of desaturation at 6MWT (defined as a difference &gt; 3% between baseline SatO2% and minimum SatO2% during test) collected during V1, V2 and V3. Differences in terms of presence of desaturation at 6MWT between V1, V2 and V3 will be calculated.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>long term evolution of radiological involvement due to SARS-COV-2 pneumonia</measure>
    <time_frame>from hospital stay to 6-to-12 months after hospital discharge for SARS-COV-2 pneumonia.</time_frame>
    <description>For long term radiological evolution of SARS-COV-2 pneumonia Investigators will consider:&#xD;
presence [yes/no] of consolidation and/or ground-glass opacities at chest X-ray and high resolution computed tomography (HRCT) of the lungs,&#xD;
presence/absence [yes/no] of lung abnormalities in lung ultrasound (LUS) evaluation,&#xD;
collected each during H, V1, V2 and V3. Differences between H,V1,V2 and V3 for each characteristics will be described.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>identifying possible factors associated to the persistency of clinical, functional and radiological long term lung involvement due to COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>from hospital stay to 6-to-12 months after hospital discharge for SARS-COV-2 pneumonia.</time_frame>
    <description>To identify possible factors associated or correlated to the persistency of clinical and/or functional and/or radiological long term lung involvement due to SARS-COV-2 pneumonia at V1, V2, V3, primary outcome measurements will be stratified according to:&#xD;
the presence [yes/no] of comorbidities (cardiovascular, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, asthma, immunological disorders, solid cancer, hematological malignancy, diabetes mellitus, immunodepression);&#xD;
age (expressed in years, age≥60 versus age&lt;60 years);&#xD;
sex (male versus female);&#xD;
hospital stay duration (expressed in days);&#xD;
acute respiratory failure duration (expressed in days);&#xD;
of study subjects.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-COV-2 Pneumonia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with acute respiratory failure due to SARS-COV-2</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients admitted to hospital with acute respiratory failure due to SARS-COV-2 infection causing pneumonia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Clinical, functional and radiological lung involvement evolution</intervention_name>
    <description>Observational / Clinical, functional and radiological long term evolution of SARS-COV-2 lung involvement</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with acute respiratory failure due to SARS-COV-2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        all patients with SARS-COV-2 pneumonia discharged from our Insitution (Respiratory and&#xD;
        Critical Care Unit - S.Orsola-Malpighi University Hospital, Bologna, IT) or patients&#xD;
        referred to our Clinic for the followup of SARS-COV-2 pneumonia after hospital stay.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  acute respiratory failure due to SARS-COV-2 pneumonia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  sign of informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  none&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Irene Prediletto, MD-PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+390512143253</phone>
    <email>irene.prediletto@aosp.bo.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Stefano Nava, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+390512143253</phone>
    <email>stefano.nava@aosp.bo.it</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Respiratory and Critical Care Unit - S.Orsola-Malpighi University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bologna</city>
        <zip>40138</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Irene Prediletto, MD-Phd</last_name>
      <phone>+390512143253</phone>
      <email>irene.prediletto@aosp.bo.it</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Stefano Nava, MD, FERS</last_name>
      <phone>+390512143253</phone>
      <email>stefano.nava@aosp.bo.it</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Irene Prediletto, MD-PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Stefano Nava, MD, FERS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 27, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria di Bologna Policlinico S. Orsola Malpighi</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>dr. Stefano Nava</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Stefano Nava, Professor of Respiratory Medicine/ Alma Mater Studiorum University of Bologna (IT)- Director of Respiratory and Critical Care Unit/ S.Orsola-Malpighi University Hospital, Bologna (IT)</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS-COV-2</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

