<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4434">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04706299</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-1303</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04706299</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Surgical Mask Use on Peak Torque, Total Work and Interset Fatigability During Isokinetic Strength Testing</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Surgical Mask Use on Peak Torque, Total Work and Interset Fatigability During Isokinetic Strength Testing</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The Cleveland Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The Cleveland Clinic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome&#xD;
      coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) is highly transmittable person-to-person when an infected&#xD;
      individual coughs, sneezes or talks while within at least 6 feet (1.8 m) of a neighboring&#xD;
      individual. Guidelines set forth by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)&#xD;
      state that nose and mouth facial coverings are recommended at all levels for source control&#xD;
      as a simple barrier to help prevent respiratory droplet transmission. It is important to&#xD;
      remember that increased viral shedding occurs during elevated ventilatory rates that are&#xD;
      observed during exercise within a shared space, such as gyms or fitness studios increase the&#xD;
      rate of transmission. However, there is limited research studying the effects of mask use&#xD;
      during exercise, and no research evaluating these effects specifically during&#xD;
      resistance-based exercise. Therefore, the purpose of this investigation is to examine the&#xD;
      effects of wearing a surgical face mask while performing resistance exercise on average peak&#xD;
      force, total work, heart rate (HR), oxygen saturation (SpO2) and breathing discomfort.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Despite the accumulating evidence supporting the favorable impact and potentially life-saving&#xD;
      benefits of routine public mask wearing has on lowering the risk of COVID-19 transmission,&#xD;
      recommendations for mask use have been met with resistance by some individuals. With the&#xD;
      numerous health benefits greatly outweighing the document complaints of discomfort and&#xD;
      headaches, it becomes puzzling why there is not universal support for these recommendations&#xD;
      made by experts. Additional insight to this ongoing issue is provided in an extremely&#xD;
      informative commentary provided by Scheid et al, in which they present theoretical evidence&#xD;
      suggesting that there may be consequential psychological impacts of mask wearing on the basic&#xD;
      psychological needs of competence, autonomy, and relatedness. Which may contribute to the&#xD;
      controversy associated with mask use. It is also important to consider that such subjective&#xD;
      experiences caused by mask wearing have been demonstrated to be exacerbated when physical&#xD;
      exertion is performed at intensities above activities of daily living, such as during&#xD;
      incremental aerobic or resistance exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Currently, the CDC identifies age &gt; 65, BMI &gt; 30, diabetes, smoking, chronic obstructive&#xD;
      pulmonary disease, heart conditions, or an immunocompromised state as risk factors for severe&#xD;
      illness from COVID-19. Research conducted by Barkley et al, revealed that university closure&#xD;
      increased sedentary behavior in all study participants, but only decreased physical activity&#xD;
      in individuals who were the most active pre-cancellation. Highlighting concerns that&#xD;
      pandemic-related closure of facilities such as gyms, which are designed for physical activity&#xD;
      may disproportionately impact a more active population. Increased sedentary behavior and&#xD;
      reduced physical activity will likely exacerbate these known risk factors for severe illness&#xD;
      from COVID-19, and contribute to overloading our healthcare systems . While it is still&#xD;
      recommended that adults of all ages should achieve 150-300 minutes of moderate or 75-150&#xD;
      minutes of vigorous (or an equivalent combination) physical activity per week, along with at&#xD;
      least 2 days per week of muscle strengthening activities. Unfortunately, evidence based&#xD;
      guidelines have not yet been developed to guide universal mask use during exercise and&#xD;
      sporting events.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this proposed randomized controlled cross-over study, we aim to evaluate in non-COVID-19&#xD;
      infected and otherwise healthy young-to-middle aged adults whether compared with performing&#xD;
      resistance exercise (RE) with no mask (NM), 1) are there effects of wearing a surgical mask&#xD;
      on physiological or psychological responses during RE that limit peak force or work performed&#xD;
      in an exercise session, and 2) does wearing a surgical mask during resistance exercise yield&#xD;
      clinically relevant and dangerous absolute indications warranting early exercise termination.&#xD;
      Isokinetic testing can be used to provide valid, reliable, objective measure of a muscle's&#xD;
      performance and offers significant clinical controls to simulate a resistance training&#xD;
      workout. The lever arm speed measuring muscular output by the participant can be adjusted&#xD;
      depending on the desired number of repetitions or duration test performed. Various skeletal&#xD;
      muscle metabolic systems could be stressed depending on the effort and duration of time under&#xD;
      tension, making it an efficient and reliable method for the assessment of muscle performance&#xD;
      under various environmental conditions, including wearing a mask during a resistance training&#xD;
      workout. To our knowledge this is the first study to assess the effects of wearing protective&#xD;
      nose and face covering on resistance exercise capacity, estimate arterial oxyhemoglobin&#xD;
      saturation (SpO2), and degree of discomfort.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 12, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a prospective study conducted using a randomized-control crossover design where participants will complete resistance exercise (RE) protocol utilizing a Biodex System 4 and Advantage V5 software with a standard leg attachment, on 2 separate days with at least 48 hours and no greater than seven days between tests.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participants will perform a RE protocol under 2 different conditions, once without a mask and once while wearing a surgical mask. A coin flip wil be utlize to minimize the possibility of familiarization or training effects, and maintain complete randomness of the assignment of which RE conditions is performed first, in addition to which leg is tested first. This simple randomization method to determine the assignment will follow (heads = No mask, tails = surgical mask and heads = dominant leg 1st, tails = nondominant leg 1st, on the 1st and 2nd coin toss, respectively). Study participants will be asked which leg they prefer to kick a ball with to identify their dominant leg for data collection purposes</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the effects of wearing a surgical face mask while performing resistance exercise on average peak force and total work performed.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week</time_frame>
    <description>For this we will utilize the Biodex system to measure average peak torque (highest force output in a repetition) and total work (muscle's cumulative ability to produce force throughout range of motion for the entire set of repetitions). Working Hypothesis: There will not be a statistically significant difference of peak torque and total work while wearing a mask compared without a mask.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Identify changes in the level of discomfort experienced while wearing a surgical mask during resistance exercise.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week</time_frame>
    <description>For this, subjective experience of wearing or not wearing a facial covering will be evaluated at both pre and post- exercise utilizing a perceptions instrument questionnaire (12,16,20). Working hypothesis: Participants performing resistance training while wearing surgical mask covering their nose and mouth with experience an increased perception of elevated breathing resistance.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Prevention of COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No Mask</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Will not wear a mask</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Surgical mask</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Will wear a surgical nose and face covering</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Resistance Exercise</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will perform for each leg, 3 sets comprised of 15 repetitions set to 180 degrees per second of an isokinetic, concentric knee extension and flexion. Resulting in a 20 second long working set (10 seconds extension, 10 seconds flexion), per set. Each set will be followed by a 90 second period of recovery. After completing 3 sets on initial leg, testing will be set up for second leg.</description>
    <arm_group_label>No Mask</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Surgical mask</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Study inclusion criteria required potential participants must be apparently healthy&#xD;
             without a history of any chronic disease (including absence of exercise induced&#xD;
             asthma),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Asymptomatic and without previous positive COVID-19 test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Demonstrate no orthopedic or medical limitation that could be the cause of exercise&#xD;
             termination&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Matthew Kampert</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Staff Physician</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Matthew Kampert, DO</last_name>
    <phone>2162195751</phone>
    <email>kamperm@ccf.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cleveland Clinic Sports Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Garfield Heights</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44125</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lexi Martins</last_name>
      <phone>724-323-6084</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The Cleveland Clinic</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Matthew Kampert</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Staff Physician</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>Face Mask</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Resistance Training</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

