<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="601">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04565067</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10000140</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>000140-AG</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04565067</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Identification and Characterization of SARS-CoV-2 Specific CD8 T Cells in Humans</brief_title>
  <official_title>Identification and Characterization of SARS-CoV-2 Specific CD8 T Cells in Humans a Clinical Observation Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute on Aging (NIA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The higher death rate from COVID-19 in the older population is associated with low CD8 T cell&#xD;
      counts in the blood. Researchers want to learn the status of CD8 T cells specific to&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 and their changes with aging and in COVID-19. This may help to identify why&#xD;
      COVID-19 is particularly lethal in the elderly and help to create an effective vaccine&#xD;
      against SARS-CoV-2 in the elderly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To identify SARS-CoV-2 specific CD8 T cells in humans, and to determine their quantity and&#xD;
      quality in people who have recovered from COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Maryland residents age 18 and older who have tested positive for and recovered from COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened by phone. They must be able to provide a copy of their positive&#xD;
      COVID-19 test result.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will visit the NIA/Clinical Research Unit. The visit will take about 1 hour.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Laboratory tests showing a positive COVID-19 result will be verified.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants vital signs will be checked. This will include blood pressure, temperature,&#xD;
      pulse, and respiration. Height and weight will be measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have a medical history and medicine review. They will complete a COVID-19&#xD;
      questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have blood drawn. They will give a urine sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will give a saliva sample. They will rinse their mouth with water. After about 3&#xD;
      minutes, they will let saliva pool in the base of their mouth and then spit into a sterile&#xD;
      container.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may be asked if they would be willing to return for optional visits at about 4&#xD;
      months and 1 year later. They will repeat the same laboratory sampling performed at the first&#xD;
      visit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is to identify epitopes of SARS-CoV-2 that are recognized by CD8 T cells in the&#xD;
      blood of healthy young and old participants as well as COVID-19 recovered. We will also&#xD;
      measure general health factors using blood, saliva and urine samples. By analyzing the&#xD;
      frequency, differentiation, and expansion of these SARS-CoV-2 recognizing CD8 T cells, we&#xD;
      hope to shed light into the T cell immunity against SARS-CoV-2 and its change with age and&#xD;
      post-infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To identify SARS-CoV-2 specific CD8 T cells in humans, and to determine their quantity and&#xD;
      quality in recovered COVID-19 patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 11, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine CD8 T cells that are responsive to SARS-CoV-2.</measure>
    <time_frame>4 month and 1 year data</time_frame>
    <description>We are investigating the presence or absence of various SARS-CoV-2 specific CD8 T cells in healthy adults and in COVID-19 recovered patients to understand the composition of CD8 T cell immunity in COVID-19 pathogenesis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine CD8 T cells that are responsive to SARS-CoV-2.</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the number and quality of SARS-CoV-2 specific CD8 T cells inrelationship with the severity of COVID-19 disease.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <description>COVID-19 recovered adult patients</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        COVID-19 recovered adult patients: sample size =100, both genders, 18 years of age and&#xD;
        older, all races, and residents of the state of Maryland.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        In order to be eligible to participate in this study, an individual must meet all of the&#xD;
        following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Ability of subject to understand the study and stated willingness to comply with all&#xD;
             study procedures and availability for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Male or female, aged 18 years or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Able to speak and read English.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Willingness and ability to come to the NIA Clinical Research Unit at MedStar Harbor&#xD;
             Hospital in Baltimore for study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Proof of positive SARS-CoV-2 testing exhibiting no current clinical symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        An individual who meets any of the following criteria will be excluded from participation&#xD;
        in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Unable to verify identification of volunteer by state issued ID card, driver's&#xD;
             license, or military ID. Participants earning greater than $600.00/year are issued a&#xD;
             1099 form, therefore, positive identification is required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Unable to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Current use of steroids, immunosuppressive medications, radiation therapy, or&#xD;
             chemotherapy medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Received immunization therapy for COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
        In addition, eligible participants may not be immediately able to participate in the study&#xD;
        but might be eligible at a later date. These include:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Symptoms of a viral infection on visit 1 (defer until resolved).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Medication: Volunteers taking the following medications would be deferred for 2 weeks&#xD;
             after course has been completed and volunteer is feeling well: Antibiotics,&#xD;
             antifungals, antimalarials.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Temporary steroids (tapers): Deferred for 72 hours after symptoms are resolved and&#xD;
             prescription is completed if taken orally, intravenously, or intramuscular. No&#xD;
             deferral if taken intranasal, inhaled, or for joint injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Infection or Fever: Deferred until 2 weeks after antibiotics are completed and /or&#xD;
             volunteer is feeling well.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. We wish to only select recovered confirmed COVID-19 patients. Therefore, those who may&#xD;
             have a household member (co-habitant) who is newly diagnosed with COVID-19 or who has&#xD;
             symptoms will be deferred for 14 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Treatment with another investigational drug or other intervention within 14 days of&#xD;
             visit 1 per the discretion of the Principal Investigator.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nan-Ping Weng, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute on Aging (NIA)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Julia L McKelvey, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(410) 350-3929</phone>
    <email>mckelveyju@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institute of Aging, Clinical Research Unit</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21224</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Julia McKelvey</last_name>
      <phone>410-350-3929</phone>
      <email>mckelveyju@nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 9, 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 24, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 25, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CD8 T Cell</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Immune Response</keyword>
  <keyword>Epitope</keyword>
  <keyword>Aging</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

