<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4599">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04658550</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Remote v In Person Weight Loss</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04658550</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Remote vs In Person Weight Loss Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Mixed Retrospective-prospective, Observational Study Evaluating the Efficacy of Counselling in a Remote Setting Compared to an In-person Setting on Weight Loss, in Obese Patients With Body Mass Index &gt; 35 Kg/m2 and Enrolled in the Behaviour Modification Program at the Bariatric Centre of Excellence at St Joseph's Healthcare Hamilton.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>St. Joseph's Healthcare Hamilton</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>St. Joseph's Healthcare Hamilton</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The COVID-19 pandemic has created fear, financial difficulties and interruptions in the lives&#xD;
      of patients and healthcare providers. As a result, many patients suffering from chronic&#xD;
      conditions such as obesity have had their treatment disrupted by the pandemic. The Bariatric&#xD;
      Medical Weight Management Clinic at St. Joseph's Healthcare Hamilton transitioned its weight&#xD;
      loss and maintenance counselling classes to a remote (online) platform in response to the&#xD;
      pandemic. The remote weight loss and maintenance classes allows patients to continue&#xD;
      receiving treatment for obesity from their homes. The remote weight loss and maintenance&#xD;
      program is conducted on a safe platform that has been thoroughly reviewed and approved by St.&#xD;
      Joseph's Privacy Committees.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to learn whether the remote weight loss and maintenance classes can&#xD;
      lead to similar weight loss compared to the in-person weight loss and maintenance classes&#xD;
      that were offered to patients before the COVID-19 pandemic. This study also aims to gather&#xD;
      feedback about the program to improve its delivery and patients' experiences.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The COVID-19 pandemic has created fear, financial difficulties and interruptions in the lives&#xD;
      of patients and healthcare providers. As a result, many patients suffering from chronic&#xD;
      conditions such as obesity have had their treatment disrupted by the pandemic. The Bariatric&#xD;
      Medical Weight Management Clinic at St. Joseph's Healthcare Hamilton transitioned its&#xD;
      behaviour modification program, also known as weight loss and maintenance counselling&#xD;
      classes, to a remote (online) platform in response to the pandemic. The remote weight loss&#xD;
      and maintenance classes allow patients to continue receiving treatment for obesity from their&#xD;
      homes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a 26-week, single-centre, mixed retrospective and prospective, observational study&#xD;
      evaluating the efficacy of counselling in a remote setting compared to an in-person setting&#xD;
      in achieving weight loss among adult patients with obesity enrolled in the behaviour&#xD;
      modification program. This study also aims to gather feedback about the program to improve&#xD;
      its delivery and patients' experiences.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 120 patients participating in the behaviour modification program and providing&#xD;
      informed consent will be observed in this study. This study involves a prospective and&#xD;
      retrospective component. The prospective component will be an observational study of 60&#xD;
      subjects who will receive 26-weeks of weight loss and maintenance counselling in a remote&#xD;
      setting and a low-calorie meal replacement as part of their usual care. The retrospective&#xD;
      component will involve using historical data from 60 subjects who received 26-weeks of weight&#xD;
      loss and maintenance counselling in an in-person setting and a low-calorie meal replacement&#xD;
      as part of their usual care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Parameters measured as part of standard of care at the start and end of the program, such as&#xD;
      body weight, blood pressure and lab tests will be collected for analysis of study endpoints.&#xD;
      Participants will also be asked to complete a satisfaction survey at the end. There will be&#xD;
      no blinding of patients, study investigators, or data analysts.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 16, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Percentage Change in Body Weight</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 26</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the efficacy of counselling in a remote setting compared to an in-person setting in achieving weight loss among adult patients with obesity enrolled in the behaviour modification program</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction and barriers to participation</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 26</time_frame>
    <description>Patient satisfaction and barriers to participation associated with the remote weight loss and maintenance program as assessed by the Bariatric Centre of Excellence Virtual Medical Program Satisfaction Survey.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 26</time_frame>
    <description>Change in blood pressure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in lipid profile</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 26</time_frame>
    <description>Change in lipid profile including total cholesterol, triglycerides, low density lipoprotein and high density lipoprotein</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in fasting blood glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 26</time_frame>
    <description>Change in fasting blood glucose</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in heart rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 26</time_frame>
    <description>Change in heart rate</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in HbA1C</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 26</time_frame>
    <description>Change in HbA1C</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Remote Weight Loss Behaviour Modification Program with Meal Replacements</arm_group_label>
    <description>This is the prospective study group who will receive 26-weeks of weight loss and maintenance counselling in a remote setting and a low-calorie meal replacement as part of their usual care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>In Person Weight Bahaviour Modification Program with Meal Replacements</arm_group_label>
    <description>This is the retrospective study group who received 26-weeks of weight loss and maintenance counselling in person and a low-calorie meal replacement as part of their usual care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Remote Behaviour Modification Program</intervention_name>
    <description>The standard of care behaviour modification program for weight loss will be offered virtually due to the COVID-19 pandemic (prospective).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Remote Weight Loss Behaviour Modification Program with Meal Replacements</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>In Person Behaviour Modification Program</intervention_name>
    <description>The standard of care behaviour modification program for weight loss was offered in person prior to the COVID-19 pandemic (retrospective).</description>
    <arm_group_label>In Person Weight Bahaviour Modification Program with Meal Replacements</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Obese patients with Body Mass Index &gt; 35 Kg/m2 and enrolled in the behaviour modification&#xD;
        program for weight loss at the Bariatric Centre of Excellence at St Joseph's Healthcare&#xD;
        Hamilton&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥ 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Enrolled in 26-week BCoE behaviour modification program with meal replacements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to provide signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Subjects will be excluded if they contact clinic or study personnel to withdraw consent&#xD;
        or withdraw data from the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tony Chetty, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>St. Joseph's Healthcare Hamilton</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sue Damjanovic</last_name>
    <phone>905-522-1155</phone>
    <phone_ext>33201</phone_ext>
    <email>sdamjano@stjoes.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St Joseph's Healthcare Hamilton</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamilton</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>L9C0E3</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sue Damjanovic</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 1, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 8, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 1, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 1, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 8, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>St. Joseph's Healthcare Hamilton</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Tony Chetty</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor Pathology and Molecular Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

