<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4942">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03684980</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>18-410</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03684980</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>LTA Pilot Study of Glucarpidase in Patients With Central Nervous System Lymphoma - ARM A</brief_title>
  <official_title>LTA Pilot Study of Glucarpidase in Patients With Central Nervous System Lymphoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Alabama at Birmingham</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to test the effects of a drug called Voraxaze when it's&#xD;
      routinely given in combination with methotrexate and rituximab, the standard treatment for&#xD;
      CNSL.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 14, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is an open-label, non-randomized, pilot study of Voraxaze administered following standard of care MTX and rituximab in patients with CNS lymphoma.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>number of patients that have significant reduction of serum methotrexate levels</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>All serum samples will be tested via MTX immunoassay (measures MTX levels in addition to byproducts) as well as HPLC or mass spectroscopy which will reveal plasma concentrations of MTX and DAMPA separately.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">44</enrollment>
  <condition>Central Nervous System Lymphoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A - Rituximab + MTX</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive rituximab Day 1 (+/- 7 days) and MTX Day 2 (+/- 7 days) as per standard of care. Voraxaze will be administered each cycle 24 hours (+/- 2 h) after start of MTX infusion. Dose of Voraxaze will be 2000 units during cycles 1-4, and 1000 units during cycles 5-8. Patients will be treated with rituximab 500 mg/m^2. (Cohort A) will receive MTX 3 g/m2. Patients will also receive standard of care leucovorin rescue starting at least 24 hours after MTX and 2 hours after Voraxaze. Cycles will be 14 days long.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B - Rituximab + MTX</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive up to 8 cycles of treatment consisting of rituximab Day 1 (+/- 7 days) and MTX Day 2 (+/- 7 days) as per standard of care. Voraxaze will be administered each cycle 24 hours (+/- 2 h) after start of MTX infusion. Dose of Voraxaze will be 2000 units during cycles 1-4, and 1000 units during cycles 5-8. Patients will be treated with rituximab 500 mg/m^2. (Cohort B) will receive MTX 8 g/m2. Patients will also receive standard of care leucovorin rescue starting at least 24 hours after MTX and 2 hours after Voraxaze. Cycles will be 14 days long.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm C - HD-MTX</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In Arm COVID-19, the primary endpoint is HD-MTX levels &lt;100 nmol/L 48 hours post-MTX administration. This will be determined via mass spectrometry/HPLC drawn 48 hours after start of MTX infusion +/- 2 hours.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm D - MTX + Voraxaze</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive MTX 3.5 g/m2 followed by reduced-dose Voraxaze (2000u, determined in Arm A). MTX will be administered in both the inpatient and outpatient settings.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Voraxaze</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose of Voraxaze will be 2000 units during cycles 1-4, and 1000 units during cycles 5-8.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A - Rituximab + MTX</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B - Rituximab + MTX</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Methotrexate</intervention_name>
    <description>(Cohort A) will receive MTX 3 g/m2 or (Cohort B) will receive MTX 8 g/m^2</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A - Rituximab + MTX</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm C - HD-MTX</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm D - MTX + Voraxaze</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rituximab</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will be treated with rituximab 500 mg/m^2.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A - Rituximab + MTX</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B - Rituximab + MTX</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>leucovorin</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will also receive standard of care leucovorin rescue starting at least 24 hours after MTX and 2 hours after Voraxaze. Cycles will be 14 days long.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A - Rituximab + MTX</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Glucarpidase</intervention_name>
    <description>Glucarpidase 2000 units</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A - Rituximab + MTX</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B - Rituximab + MTX</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm C - HD-MTX</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm D - MTX + Voraxaze</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Arm A:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically documented B-cell non-Hodgkin&quot;s lymphoma involving the brain, spinal&#xD;
             cord, and/or leptomeningeal space.&#xD;
&#xD;
             °Patients in whom the type of lymphoma could not be determined or is unknown (e.g.,&#xD;
             not enough tissue for further analysis) are assumed to have a B cell lymphoma and are&#xD;
             eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with parenchymal lesions must have received no more than two cycles of&#xD;
             treatment for treatment of CNS lymphoma or have unequivocal evidence of disease&#xD;
             progression on imaging (MRI of the brain/spine or CT head) 28 days prior to study&#xD;
             registration. For patients with leptomeningeal disease only, CSF cytology must&#xD;
             document lymphoma cells and/or imaging findings must be consistent with CSF disease 28&#xD;
             days prior to study registration (at the discretion of the investigator).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have already received two doses of treatment of CNS lymphoma are eligible&#xD;
             for enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (Arm A only) as long as they are planned for at least 6 additional doses of&#xD;
             methotrexate. Patients must not have evidence of systemic non-Hodgkin lymphoma&#xD;
             requiring active treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men and woman must be at least 18 years of age on the day of consenting to the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a Karnofsky Performance Status (KPS) ≥ 50 (See Appendix 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be willing and able to comply with scheduled visits, treatment plan, and&#xD;
             laboratory tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have adequate bone marrow and organ function shown by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.0 x 10^9/L;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥ 100 x 10^9/L and no platelet transfusion within the past 28 days&#xD;
                  prior to study registration;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin (Hgb) ≥ 8 g/dL and no red blood cells (RBC) transfusion within the&#xD;
                  past 28 days prior to study registration;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  International Normalized Ratio (INR) ≤ 1.5 and PTT (aPTT) ≤ 1.5 times the upper&#xD;
                  limit of normal;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤ 3 times the&#xD;
                  upper limit of normal;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times the upper limit of normal; or total bilirubin ≤ 3&#xD;
                  times the upper limit of normal with direct bilirubin within the normal range in&#xD;
                  patients with well documented Gilbert Syndrome;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CrCl ≥ 60 mL/min using the Cockcroft-Gault equation. Men: CrCl (min/mL) =&#xD;
                  (140-age) X (actual weight in kg) / 72 X serum creatinine (mg/dL) Women: CrCl&#xD;
                  (mL/min) = (140-age) X (actual weight in kg) X 0.85 / 72 X serum creatinine&#xD;
                  (mg/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of reproductive potential must agree to use highly effective methods of birth&#xD;
             control during the period of therapy and for 30 days after the last dose of the study&#xD;
             drug. Men who are sexually active must agree to use highly effective contraception&#xD;
             during the period of therapy and for 3 months after the last dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative plasma pregnancy test&#xD;
             upon study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be able to tolerate MRI/CT scans.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be able to tolerate lumbar puncture and/or Ommaya taps.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must have recovered to grade 1 toxicity from prior therapy. NOTE:&#xD;
             Patients who have initiated and received up to two cycles of treatment will NOT be&#xD;
             excluded from study Arm A as long as all pretreatment assessments have been completed&#xD;
             within 28 days of trial initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Arms B and D:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically documented B-cell non-Hodgkin's lymphoma involving the brain, spinal&#xD;
             cord, and/or leptomeningeal space&#xD;
&#xD;
             ° Patients in whom the type of lymphoma could not be determined or is unknown (e.g.,&#xD;
             not enough tissue for further analysis) are assumed to have a B cell lymphoma and are&#xD;
             eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be treatment naïve or have unequivocal evidence of disease progression&#xD;
             on imaging (MRI of the brain/spine or CT head) 28 days prior to study registration.&#xD;
             For patients with leptomeningeal disease only, CSF cytology must document lymphoma&#xD;
             cells and/or imaging findings must be consistent with CSF disease 28 days prior to&#xD;
             study registration (at the discretion of the investigator)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must not have evidence of systemic non-Hodgkin lymphoma requiring active&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men and woman must be at least 18 years of age on the day of consenting to the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a Karnofsky Performance Status (KPS) &gt;/= 70 or &gt;/= 50 if KPS is due&#xD;
             to a neurologic deficit attributed to active disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be willing and able to comply with scheduled visits, treatment plan, and&#xD;
             laboratory tests&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have adequate bone marrow and organ function shown by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;/= 1.0 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets &gt;/= 100 x 10^9/L and no platelet transfusion within the past 28 days&#xD;
                  prior to study registration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin (Hgb) &gt;/= 8g/dL and no red blood cells (RBC) transfusion within the&#xD;
                  past 28 days prior to study registration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  International Normalized Ratio (INR) &lt;/= 1.5 and PTT (aPTT) &lt;/= 1.5 times the&#xD;
                  upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &lt;/= 3 times&#xD;
                  the upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum bilirubin &lt;/= 1.5 times the upper limit of normal; or total bilirubin &lt;/= 3&#xD;
                  times the upper limit of normal with direct bilirubin within the normal range in&#xD;
                  patients with well documented Gilbert Syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CrCl &gt;/= 60 mL/min using the Cockcroft-Gault equation Men: CrCl (min/mL) =&#xD;
                  (140-age) X (actual weight in kg) / 72 X serum creatinine (mg/dL) Women: CrCl&#xD;
                  (mL/min) = (140-age) X (actual weight in kg) X 0.85 / 72 X serum creatinine&#xD;
                  (mg/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of reproductive potential must agree to use highly effective methods of birth&#xD;
             control during the period of therapy and for 30 days after the last dose of the study&#xD;
             drug. Men who are sexually active must agree to use highly effective contraception&#xD;
             during the period of therapy and for 3 months after the last dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative plasma pregnancy test&#xD;
             upon study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be able to tolerate MRI/CT scans&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be able to tolerate lumbar puncture and/or Ommaya taps&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must have recovered to grade 1 toxicity from prior therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with ocular manifestation of systemic lymphoma are allowed if repeat&#xD;
             ophthalmologic exam is planned for the end of therapy. If ocular disease remains&#xD;
             present, ocular-directed therapy may be administered after treatment with&#xD;
             methotrexate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be able to tolerate po hydration (Arm D only)&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: Prior autologous stem cell transplant as well as prior radiation to the CNS does NOT&#xD;
        prevent patients from enrollment into the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Arm Outpatient MTX Therapy in times of COVID-19:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients eligible for inclusion in this arm must be eligible for inpatient MTX&#xD;
             administration for treatment of CNS lymphoma. Patients should have received prior MTX&#xD;
             therapy without major adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative plasma pregnancy test&#xD;
             upon study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Arms A, B and D:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with SCNSL requiring treatment for extra-CNS disease are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient concurrently using other approved or investigational antineoplastic agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has received chemotherapy, monoclonal antibodies or targeted anticancer&#xD;
             therapy ≤ 4 weeks or 5 half-lives, whichever is shorter, or 6 weeks for nitrosoureas&#xD;
             or mitomycin-C prior to starting the study drug, or the patient has not recovered from&#xD;
             the side effects of such therapy. Exceptions are allowed for rituximab and&#xD;
             methotrexate for patients enrolling Arm A as long as patients have recovered from side&#xD;
             effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has received external beam radiation therapy to the CNS within 28 days of the&#xD;
             first dose of the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has an active concurrent malignancy requiring active therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has been treated with radio- or toxin-immunoconjugates within 70 days of&#xD;
             the first dose of the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient weighs &lt;40kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is allergic to components of the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is known to have human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is known to have a history of active or chronic infection with hepatitis C&#xD;
             virus (HCV) or hepatitis B virus (HBV) as determined by serologic tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe, active medical co-morbidity such as unstable angina and/or congestive heart&#xD;
             failure, coronary artery disease, significant abnormalities on electrocardiogram&#xD;
             (EKG), uncontrolled or symptomatic arrhythmias or valvular disease; active infection,&#xD;
             severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease or other respiratory illness, hepatic&#xD;
             insufficiency, known pre-existing immunodeficiency as seen in organ transplant&#xD;
             recipients, renal failure with CrCl &lt;60 mL/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a life-threatening illness, medical condition, or organ system dysfunction&#xD;
             that, in the opinion of the investigator, could compromise the subject&quot;s safety or put&#xD;
             the study outcomes at undue risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has large pleural or ascetic fluid collection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or women of childbearing potential and men who are sexually active and not&#xD;
             willing/able to use medically acceptable forms of contraception; this exclusion is&#xD;
             necessary because the treatment involved in this study may be significantly&#xD;
             teratogenic.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior severe allergic reaction to any of the study drugs that cannot be resolved with&#xD;
             medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has undergone prior allogenic stem cell transplant (autologous stem cell&#xD;
             transplant is NOT an exclusion).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Arm Outpatient MTX Therapy in times of COVID-19:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients eligible for this arm must not meet any of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with SCNSL requiring treatment for extra-CNS disease are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients weighing &lt;40kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inadequate bone marrow and organ function shown by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt;/= 0.5 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets &lt;/= 75 x 10^9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin (Hgb) &lt;/= 8 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &gt;/= 3 times&#xD;
                  the upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum bilirubin &gt;/= 1.5 times the upper limit of normal; or total bilirubin &gt;/= 3&#xD;
                  times the upper limit of normal with direct bilirubin outside of the normal range&#xD;
                  in patients with well documented Gilbert Syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine &gt;/= 1.3 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients allergic to components of the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with severe, active medical co-morbidity such as unstable angina and/or&#xD;
             congestive heart failure, coronary artery disease, significant abnormalities on&#xD;
             electrocardiogram (EKG), uncontrolled or symptomatic arrhythmias or valvular disease;&#xD;
             active infection, severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease or other respiratory&#xD;
             illness, hepatic insufficiency, known pre-existing immunodeficiency as seen in organ&#xD;
             transplant recipients, renal failure with creatinine &gt;/= 1.3 mg/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a life-threatening illness, medical condition, or organ system&#xD;
             dysfunction that, in the opinion of the investigator, could compromise the subject's&#xD;
             safety or put the study outcomes at undue risk&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with large pleural or ascetic fluid collection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or women of childbearing potential and men who are sexually active and not&#xD;
             willing/able to use medically acceptable forms of contraception; this exclusion is&#xD;
             necessary because the treatment involved in this study may be significantly&#xD;
             teratogenic. Women of reproductive potential must agree to use highly effective&#xD;
             methods of birth control during the period of therapy and for 30 days after the last&#xD;
             dose of the study drug. Men who are sexually active must agree to use highly effective&#xD;
             contraception during the period of therapy and for 3 months after the last dose&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lauren Schaff, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lauren Schaff, MD</last_name>
    <phone>212-610-0485</phone>
    <email>schaffl@mskcc.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Christian Grommes, MD</last_name>
    <phone>212-639-4058</phone>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama at Birmingham</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35294</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Burt Nabors, MD</last_name>
      <phone>205-934-1432</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Burt Nabors, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memoral Sloan Kettering Basking Ridge</name>
      <address>
        <city>Basking Ridge</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07920</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lauren Schaff, MD</last_name>
      <phone>212-610-0485</phone>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Christian Grommes</last_name>
      <phone>212-639-4058</phone>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Monmouth</name>
      <address>
        <city>Middletown</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07748</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lauren Schaff, MD</last_name>
      <phone>212-610-0485</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Bergen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montvale</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07645</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lauren Schaff, MD</last_name>
      <phone>212-610-0485</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Commack</name>
      <address>
        <city>Commack</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11725</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lauren Schaff, MD</last_name>
      <phone>212-610-0485</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Westchester</name>
      <address>
        <city>Harrison</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10604</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lauren Schaff, MD</last_name>
      <phone>212-610-0485</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lauren Schaff, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Christian Grommes, MD</last_name>
      <phone>212-639-4058</phone>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Nassau</name>
      <address>
        <city>Uniondale</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11553</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lauren Schaff, MD</last_name>
      <phone>212-610-0485</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mskcc.org/mskcc/html/44.cfm</url>
    <description>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 24, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 25, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 26, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 22, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 22, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 23, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Voraxaze (glucarpidase)</keyword>
  <keyword>B-cell non-Hodgkin&quot;s lymphoma involving the brain</keyword>
  <keyword>B-cell non-Hodgkin&quot;s lymphoma involving spinal cord, and/or leptomeningeal space</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leucovorin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Methotrexate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

