<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4536">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04727762</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ID0031</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04727762</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Use of the Mask and Current Pandemic</brief_title>
  <acronym>Mask</acronym>
  <official_title>Population Impact on the Continued Use of the Mask Due to the Avoidance of COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Valencia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Valencia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Due to the continued use of the mask in order to prevent the spread of COVID-19, an impact on&#xD;
      people is observed in different areas. The objective of our study was to collect impact&#xD;
      aspects related to the continued use of the mask that may affect the quality of life of the&#xD;
      population. For this, an observational study has been carried out that includes an interview&#xD;
      with aspects related to headaches, problems in the temporomandibular joint, respiratory and&#xD;
      musculoskeletal disorders.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction. Due to the continued use of the mask in order to prevent the spread of&#xD;
      COVID-19, an impact on people is observed in different areas. The objective of our study was&#xD;
      to collect impact aspects related to the continued use of the mask that may affect the&#xD;
      quality of life of the population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Material and methods Diseny. For this, an observational study has been carried out that&#xD;
      includes an interview with aspects related to headaches, problems in the temporomandibular&#xD;
      joint, respiratory and musculoskeletal disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants. Subjects of all ages from 18 years old will be recruited who use a mask daily&#xD;
      for the avoidance of COVID-19 and with the ability to answer the questions and complete the&#xD;
      questionnaires. The study will be carried out at the Faculty of Physiotherapy of the&#xD;
      University of Valencia. The participants will sign an informed consent guaranteeing the&#xD;
      confidentiality of the data. The study is approved by the ethics committee of our&#xD;
      institution.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcomes. The sociodemographic characteristics and the use of the mask will be collected.&#xD;
      Subsequently, the evaluation instruments without the use of a mask and with the use of the&#xD;
      same in: Quality of life through the EuroQol-5D questionnaire and the Cantril ladder of life.&#xD;
      The impact on headaches using the HIT-6, disorders related to oral health using the&#xD;
      self-report screening test, dyspnoea using the modified scale of the Medical Research Council&#xD;
      (MMRC) and using the Borg dyspnea scale. Finally, aspects related to the quality of sleep&#xD;
      with The Minimal Insomnia Symptom Scale (MISS) and on the aspects of physical activity using&#xD;
      the IPAQ SHORT FORM.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All data will be coded in a database and analyzed later.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 4, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Generic health</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>By EuroQoL 5D: The EQ-5D is a preference-based instrument designed to measure generic health status across 5 dimensions of health: mobility, selfcare, usual activities, pain/discomfort, and anxiety/depression. Patients rated each dimension between 1 and 3, with 1 being no disability and 3 representing significant disability. Visual analog scale was also used to assess health outcomes on a scale of 0 to 100, with 100 presenting no health issues and 0 representing debilitating health issues</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Global well-be-ing</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>By Cantril LAdder of life: This instrument has been used in various cardiovascular studies and is considered to be a valid measure of &quot;global well-be-ing.&quot;It does not cover QoL as a multidimensional concept, but it is related to aspects of QoL such as psychosocial adjustment and functional ca-pabilities.Patients were asked to rate their sense of well-being on a scale from 0 to 10 (10 reflecting the best and 0 reflecting the worst possible life).They were asked to do so with regard to the time of interview (during hospital admission, after being treated and stabilized), with regard to the month before hospital admission and their expectation of well-being for 3 years in the future.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Headache Impact</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Headache Impact Test-6 (HIT-6). Published by Ware et al. To measure the impact of headache. The score is calculated as follows: never (6 points), few times (8 points), sometimes (10 points), very often (11 points) and always (13 points). With a total of 49 or less points is considered &quot;little or no impact&quot;, between 50-55 &quot;some impact&quot;, between 56-59 &quot;significant impact&quot; and 60 or more &quot;very severe impact&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oral health</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>The self-report test for oral health contains 11 questions, to which they must answer &quot;yes&quot; or &quot;no&quot;, referring to subjective signs, detected by themselves, in relation to Temporomandibular joint, occlusion, masticatory muscles, jaw movements, bruxism, knocks or accidents and previous treatments.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dyspnea disability</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>The modified Medical Research Council (mMRC) scale employing a self-reported questionnaire is useful for assessing dyspnea and disability, and it's reliability has been confirmed. The mMRC dyspnea scale is an instrument that establishes the severity of dyspnea in relation to various physical tasks. The mMRCquestionnaire is a 5-point scale and asks patients to rate dyspnea from 0(absent) to 4 (dyspnea at rest).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quantification of dyspnea</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>By Borg dyspnea scale. The scale comprises a 10-point scale including written indicators of severity trough specific numbers on the scale, it has been used more widely to quantify various &quot;perceived symptoms&quot; such as breathlessness and muscle fatigue during exercise. This is a vertical scale quantified from 0 to 10, in which 0 represents no symptoms and 10 represents maximum symptoms, providing an individual measurement of the intensity of the breathelesness. The Borg scale is a user-friendly scale that measures an individual's self-rated breathlessness.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of Physical activity</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Physical activity by the Short Form-International Physical Activity Questionnaire (s-IPAQ). The s-IPAQ contains seven items for identifying the frequency and duration of light, moderate, and vigorous physical activity as well as inactivity during the past week. The questions focus on four activity types: &quot;vigorous activity&quot; periods of at least 10 minutes, &quot;moderate activity&quot; periods of at least 10 minutes, &quot;walking&quot; periods of at least 10 minutes, and times spent &quot;sitting&quot; on weekdays. Frequency of activity is measured in days, and duration in hours and minutes. The patients were classified into three physical activity categories: low, moderate, and high. Typical s-IPAQ correlations with an accelerometer were 0.80 for reliability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Insomnia Symptom</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>By Minimal Insomnia Symptom Scale: The MISS is an insomnia-screening tool consisting of three items, with five response categories (no, minor, moderate, severeand very severe problems), which are scored 0-4, respectively. Thisyields a total score ranging from 0 to 12 (12=more insomnia). Pre-vious studies have suggested cut-offs of≥6 among adults and≥7 among the elderly</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">500</enrollment>
  <condition>Face Mask Squeeze</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Subjects of all ages from 18 years old will be recruited who use a mask daily for the&#xD;
        avoidance of COVID-19 and with the ability to answer the questions and complete the&#xD;
        questionnaires.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  from 18 years old will be recruited who use a mask daily for the avoidance of&#xD;
             COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  with the ability to answer the questions and complete the questionnaires.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  I do not use the mask&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gemma V Espí-López</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>fisiotherapy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Gemma V Espí-López</last_name>
    <phone>+34651948635</phone>
    <email>gemma.espi@uv.es</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Gemma V Espí-López</last_name>
    <phone>651948635</phone>
    <email>gemma.espi@uv.es</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gemma Victoria Espí-López</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <zip>46010</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gemma V Espí-López</last_name>
      <phone>651948635</phone>
      <email>gemma.espi@uv.es</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Valencia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>GEMMA V ESPÍ LÓPEZ, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

