<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3160">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04581018</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Synbiotic COV study</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04581018</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Evaluation of a Synbiotic Formula for Patients With COVID-19 Infection</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Evaluation of a Synbiotic Formula for Symptom Improvement in Hospitalised Patients With COVID-19 Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Siew Chien NG</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Chinese University of Hong Kong</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In December 2019, a cluster of pneumonia cases of unidentified cause emerged in Wuhan,was&#xD;
      identified as the culprit of this disease currently being identified as &quot;Coronavirus Disease&#xD;
      2019&quot; (COVID-19) by World Health Organization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Coronavirus was found to not only target the patient's lungs but also multiple organs. Around&#xD;
      2-33% of Coronavirus Disease-19 patients developed gastrointestinal symptoms. Studies have&#xD;
      shown that Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SAR-CoV-2) was found in patient's&#xD;
      feces, suggesting that the virus can spread through feces. In our previous study, stool&#xD;
      samples from 15 patients with COVID-19 were analysed. Depleted symbionts and gut dysbiosis&#xD;
      were noted even after patients were detected negative of SARS-CoV-2. A series of microbiota&#xD;
      were correlated inversely with the disease severity and virus load. Gut microbiota could play&#xD;
      a role in modulating host immune response and potentially influence disease severity and&#xD;
      outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators are uncertain about the impact of synbiotic on patients with COVID-19.&#xD;
      However, a therapeutic strategy aiming at investigating the gut Imicrobiota of patients with&#xD;
      COVID-9 who take synbiotic or not, leading to lesser progression to severe disease, less&#xD;
      hospital stay and improved quality of life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In December 2019, a cluster of pneumonia cases of unidentified cause emerged in Wuhan, Hubei&#xD;
      province, China. In early January, a novel betacoronavirus forming another clade within the&#xD;
      subgenus sarbecovirus, now named SARS-CoV-2, was identified as the culprit of this disease&#xD;
      currently being identified as &quot;Coronavirus Disease 2019&quot; (COVID-19) by WHO.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Coronavirus was found to not only target the patient's lungs, but also multiple organs.&#xD;
      Around 2-33% of COVID-19 patients developed gastrointestinal symptoms. Studies have shown&#xD;
      that SAR-CoV-2 was found in patient's feces, suggesting that the virus can spread through&#xD;
      feces. In our previous study, stool samples from 15 patients with COVID-19 were analysed.&#xD;
      Depleted symbionts and gut dysbiosis were noted even after patients were detected negative of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2. A series of microbiota were correlated inversely with the disease severity and&#xD;
      virus load. Gut microbiota could play a role in modulating host immune response and&#xD;
      potentially influence disease severity and outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In July 2020, there are more than 15 million confirmed cases globally with 620 thousand&#xD;
      deaths. Currently, there are more than 2000 confirmed cases of COVID-19 in Hong Kong. The&#xD;
      investigators are uncertain about the impact of synbiotic on patients with COVID-19. However,&#xD;
      a therapeutic strategy aiming at investigating the gut Imicrobiota of patients with COVID-9&#xD;
      who take synbiotic or not, leading to lesser progression to severe disease, less hospital&#xD;
      stay and improved quality of life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 13, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Combined symptom score</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Combined symptom score improvement of the first 4 weeks. Symptoms score assessment ranges from 20-80. The higher the score, the worse the symptoms.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Compare the number and severity of symptoms existing by checking the list in symptoms assessment such as cough, shortness of breath, fever and gastrointestinal symptoms like anorexia, nausea, vomiting, abdominal pain, bloating before and during the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to develop antibody against SARS-CoV-2</measure>
    <time_frame>16 days</time_frame>
    <description>Compare the time to develop antibody against SARS-CoV-2 in both group</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life measured by EQ-5D-5L</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement of quality of life measured by EQ-5D-5L. EQ-5D-5L is a self-assessed, health related, quality of life questionnaire. The scale measures quality of life on a 5-component scale including mobility, self-care, usual activities, pain/discomfort, and anxiety/depression.The index can be calculated by deducting the appropriate weights from 1, the value for full health (i.e. state 11111). Each category ranges from 1 to 5. The small the number, the better the health. The EQ-VAS is a vertical visual analogue scale that ranges 0-100 (higher score indicates better imaginable health).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life measured by SF-12</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement of quality of life measured by SF-12. SF-12 is a self-reported outcome measure assessing the impact of health on an individual's everyday life. There are formulas for transformation of scale scores so that they will range from 0-100. High score in functioning items indicates better functioning while high score in pain items indicates freedom from pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of hospital stay</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measure the duration of hospital stay in both group</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to negative PCR</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Compare the time to negative PCR in both group</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Trend of symptom score</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Trend of symptom score, ranges from 26-104. The higher the score, the worse the symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gastrointestinal symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of gastrointestinal symptoms such as anorexia, nausea, vomiting, abdominal pain, bloating within 4 week.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in fecal bacteria metabolites</measure>
    <time_frame>weeks 2, 4, 5 and 8 months 3, 6, 9 and 12</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in fecal bacteria metabolites measured by PCR at different time points</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in plasma cytokines level</measure>
    <time_frame>week 2 and week 5</time_frame>
    <description>Change in plasma cytokines level at week 2 and week 5 compared with baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in the gut microbiome</measure>
    <time_frame>weeks 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 8 and months 3, 6, 9 and 12</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in the gut microbiome (bacteria, virome and fungome) measured by metagenomics at different time points (weeks 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 and months 3, 6, 9 and 12) compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of admission to Intensive Care Unit</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of admission to Intensive Care Unit</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of subjects with home discharge</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of subjects with home discharge</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of mortality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of days absent from work</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days absent from work since admission</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of quality of life questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>week 8, months 3, 6, 9 and 12</time_frame>
    <description>Change in score on Quality of life using EQ-5D-5L and SF-12. EQ-5D-5L is a self-assessed, health related, quality of life questionnaire. The scale measures quality of life on a 5-component scale including mobility, self-care, usual activities, pain/discomfort, and anxiety/depression.The index can be calculated by deducting the appropriate weights from 1, the value for full health (i.e. state 11111). Each category ranges from 1 to 5. The small the number, the better the health. The EQ-VAS is a vertical visual analogue scale that ranges 0-100 (higher score indicates better imaginable health). While the SF-12 is a self-reported outcome measure assessing the impact of health on an individual's everyday life. There are formulas for transformation of scale scores so that they will range from 0-100. High score in functioning items indicates better functioning while high score in pain items indicates freedom from pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of adverse event</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Microbiota</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Health supplements + standard care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>28 days of health supplements (Synbiotic) daily plus standard care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>No intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Health supplements</intervention_name>
    <description>28 days of health supplements (synbiotic), 4g daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>Health supplements + standard care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Aged 18 or above; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. A confirmed diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2 infection using the PCR according to the standard&#xD;
             of according to Centre for Health Protection, Department of Health, HK at recruitment&#xD;
             and that require admission to the hospitalization area; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Written informed consent is obtained&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects admitted to Intensive Care Unit or on ventilator&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known allergy or intolerance to the intervention product or its components&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any known medical condition that would prevent taking oral probiotics or increase&#xD;
             risks associated with probiotics including but not limited to inability to&#xD;
             swallow/aspiration risk and no other methods of delivery (e.g no G/J tube)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Known increased infection risk due to immunosuppression such as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prior organ or hematopoietic stem cell transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Neutropenia (ANC &lt;500 cells/ul)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HIV and CD4 &lt;200 cells/ul&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Known history or active endocarditis&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Recent on CAPD or hemodialysis-&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Documented pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Siew Chien Ng</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Chinese University of Hong Kong</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Amy Li</last_name>
    <phone>852-26373225</phone>
    <email>amyli@cuhk.edu.hk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kitty Cheung</last_name>
    <phone>852-26373225</phone>
    <email>kittyccy@cuhk.edu.hk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Chinese University of Hong Kong</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sha Tin</city>
        <zip>000000</zip>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Siew Chien Ng, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>35053996</phone>
      <email>siewchienng@cuhk.edu.hk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Zhao J, Hu Y, Zhang L, Fan G, Xu J, Gu X, Cheng Z, Yu T, Xia J, Wei Y, Wu W, Xie X, Yin W, Li H, Liu M, Xiao Y, Gao H, Guo L, Xie J, Wang G, Jiang R, Gao Z, Jin Q, Wang J, Cao B. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020 Feb 15;395(10223):497-506. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5. Epub 2020 Jan 24. Erratum in: Lancet. 2020 Jan 30;:.</citation>
    <PMID>31986264</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhu N, Zhang D, Wang W, Li X, Yang B, Song J, Zhao X, Huang B, Shi W, Lu R, Niu P, Zhan F, Ma X, Wang D, Xu W, Wu G, Gao GF, Tan W; China Novel Coronavirus Investigating and Research Team. A Novel Coronavirus from Patients with Pneumonia in China, 2019. N Engl J Med. 2020 Feb 20;382(8):727-733. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2001017. Epub 2020 Jan 24.</citation>
    <PMID>31978945</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wong CK, Lam CW, Wu AK, Ip WK, Lee NL, Chan IH, Lit LC, Hui DS, Chan MH, Chung SS, Sung JJ. Plasma inflammatory cytokines and chemokines in severe acute respiratory syndrome. Clin Exp Immunol. 2004 Apr;136(1):95-103.</citation>
    <PMID>15030519</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Holshue ML, DeBolt C, Lindquist S, Lofy KH, Wiesman J, Bruce H, Spitters C, Ericson K, Wilkerson S, Tural A, Diaz G, Cohn A, Fox L, Patel A, Gerber SI, Kim L, Tong S, Lu X, Lindstrom S, Pallansch MA, Weldon WC, Biggs HM, Uyeki TM, Pillai SK; Washington State 2019-nCoV Case Investigation Team. First Case of 2019 Novel Coronavirus in the United States. N Engl J Med. 2020 Mar 5;382(10):929-936. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2001191. Epub 2020 Jan 31.</citation>
    <PMID>32004427</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yeo C, Kaushal S, Yeo D. Enteric involvement of coronaviruses: is faecal-oral transmission of SARS-CoV-2 possible? Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020 Apr;5(4):335-337. doi: 10.1016/S2468-1253(20)30048-0. Epub 2020 Feb 20.</citation>
    <PMID>32087098</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Liang W, Feng Z, Rao S, Xiao C, Xue X, Lin Z, Zhang Q, Qi W. Diarrhoea may be underestimated: a missing link in 2019 novel coronavirus. Gut. 2020 Jun;69(6):1141-1143. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2020-320832. Epub 2020 Feb 26.</citation>
    <PMID>32102928</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hashimoto T, Perlot T, Rehman A, Trichereau J, Ishiguro H, Paolino M, Sigl V, Hanada T, Hanada R, Lipinski S, Wild B, Camargo SM, Singer D, Richter A, Kuba K, Fukamizu A, Schreiber S, Clevers H, Verrey F, Rosenstiel P, Penninger JM. ACE2 links amino acid malnutrition to microbial ecology and intestinal inflammation. Nature. 2012 Jul 25;487(7408):477-81. doi: 10.1038/nature11228.</citation>
    <PMID>22837003</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zuo T, Zhan H, Zhang F, Liu Q, Tso EYK, Lui GCY, Chen N, Li A, Lu W, Chan FKL, Chan PKS, Ng SC. Alterations in Fecal Fungal Microbiome of Patients With COVID-19 During Time of Hospitalization until Discharge. Gastroenterology. 2020 Oct;159(4):1302-1310.e5. doi: 10.1053/j.gastro.2020.06.048. Epub 2020 Jun 26.</citation>
    <PMID>32598884</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>WHO Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) Dashboard. [Assessed on 24 Jul 2020]. https://covid19.who.int/</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Latest situation of cases of COVID-19. [Assessed on 24 Jul 2020]. https://www.chp.gov.hk/files/pdf/local_situation_covid19_en.pdf</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cao B, Wang Y, Wen D, Liu W, Wang J, Fan G, Ruan L, Song B, Cai Y, Wei M, Li X, Xia J, Chen N, Xiang J, Yu T, Bai T, Xie X, Zhang L, Li C, Yuan Y, Chen H, Li H, Huang H, Tu S, Gong F, Liu Y, Wei Y, Dong C, Zhou F, Gu X, Xu J, Liu Z, Zhang Y, Li H, Shang L, Wang K, Li K, Zhou X, Dong X, Qu Z, Lu S, Hu X, Ruan S, Luo S, Wu J, Peng L, Cheng F, Pan L, Zou J, Jia C, Wang J, Liu X, Wang S, Wu X, Ge Q, He J, Zhan H, Qiu F, Guo L, Huang C, Jaki T, Hayden FG, Horby PW, Zhang D, Wang C. A Trial of Lopinavir-Ritonavir in Adults Hospitalized with Severe Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020 May 7;382(19):1787-1799. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2001282. Epub 2020 Mar 18.</citation>
    <PMID>32187464</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Docherty AB, Harrison EM, Green CA, Hardwick HE, Pius R, Norman L, Holden KA, Read JM, Dondelinger F, Carson G, Merson L, Lee J, Plotkin D, Sigfrid L, Halpin S, Jackson C, Gamble C, Horby PW, Nguyen-Van-Tam JS, Ho A, Russell CD, Dunning J, Openshaw PJ, Baillie JK, Semple MG; ISARIC4C investigators. Features of 20 133 UK patients in hospital with covid-19 using the ISARIC WHO Clinical Characterisation Protocol: prospective observational cohort study. BMJ. 2020 May 22;369:m1985. doi: 10.1136/bmj.m1985.</citation>
    <PMID>32444460</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Janowitz T, Gablenz E, Pattinson D, Wang TC, Conigliaro J, Tracey K, Tuveson D. Famotidine use and quantitative symptom tracking for COVID-19 in non-hospitalised patients: a case series. Gut. 2020 Sep;69(9):1592-1597. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2020-321852. Epub 2020 Jun 4.</citation>
    <PMID>32499303</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 6, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 12, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 12, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Chinese University of Hong Kong</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Siew Chien NG</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

