<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1340">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04707742</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Interventional</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04707742</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Antiseptic Mouth Rinses to Reduce Salivary Viral Load in COVID-19 Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>BUCOSARS</acronym>
  <official_title>Clinical Evaluation of Antiseptic Mouth Rinses to Reduce Salivary Viral Load of SARS-CoV-2 in COVID-19 Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fundación para el Fomento de la Investigación Sanitaria y Biomédica de la Comunitat Valenciana</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital Universitario Fundación Jiménez Díaz</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital Universitario General de Villalba</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital Universitario Infanta Elena</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital Universitario Virgen de la Arrixaca</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital Clínico Universitario de Valencia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dentaid SL</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fundación para el Fomento de la Investigación Sanitaria y Biomédica de la Comunitat Valenciana</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      As no curative treatment for SARS-CoV-2 is currently available, most public health measures&#xD;
      to contain the pandemic are based on preventing the spread of the pathogen. The virus is&#xD;
      transmitted by the respiratory route and by direct contact with contaminated surfaces and&#xD;
      subsequent contact with nasal, oral or ocular mucosa. Although patients with symptomatic&#xD;
      coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) have been the main source of transmission, observations&#xD;
      suggest that asymptomatic and incubating patients also have the ability to transmit&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2. Angiotensin II converting enzyme (ACE2) is the main cellular receptor for&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2, which interacts with the spike protein to facilitate its entry. ACE2 receptors&#xD;
      are highly expressed in the oral cavity and present at high levels in oral epithelial cells.&#xD;
      The mean expression of ACE2 was higher in the tongue compared to that in other oral tissues&#xD;
      and it has been found to be higher in the minor salivary glands than in the lungs. These&#xD;
      findings strongly suggest that the oral cavity and specifically the saliva may be a high-risk&#xD;
      route for SARS-CoV-2 infection. Thus, strategies reducing salivary viral load could&#xD;
      contribute to reduce the risk of transmission. Furthermore, studies using macaques as animal&#xD;
      models have shown that SARS-CoV persists for two days in oral mucous membranes before its&#xD;
      diffusion to the lower respiratory tract. This offers an interesting preventive and&#xD;
      therapeutic window of opportunity for the control of this disease. For this reason, the use&#xD;
      of mouthwashes with antiseptics that have virucidal activity can be a simple preventive&#xD;
      strategy that could easily be applied both by infected patients before being examined by&#xD;
      sanitary personnel and in the general population. This study is a multi-centered, blinded,&#xD;
      parallel-group, placebo-controlled randomised clinical trial that tests the effect of four&#xD;
      different mouthwashes (CPC, chlorhexidine, povidone-iodine and H2O2) in the salivary viral&#xD;
      load of SARS-CoV-2 measured by qPCR at three different timepoints. A fifth group of patients&#xD;
      using a distilled water mouth rinse is used as a control. Viral particles per ml of saliva&#xD;
      are quantified at baseline and 30, 60 and 120 minutes after a 1-minute mouth rinse with the&#xD;
      antiseptic or water. Our study aims to test whether any of these standard oral antiseptics&#xD;
      appear to diminish viral load in saliva and could therefore be used as a strategy to reduce&#xD;
      transmission risk in clinical and social settings.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Strategies reducing salivary viral load could contribute to reduce the risk of transmission&#xD;
      of SARS-CoV-2. Thus, the use of mouthwashes with antiseptics that have virucidal activity can&#xD;
      be a simple and low-cost preventive strategy that could easily be applied in the general&#xD;
      population. To evaluate the effect of several antiseptics to neutralize or reduce the&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 viral load in vivo in saliva samples, a multicentre, randomized, blind,&#xD;
      five-parallel-group, placebo-controlled trial has been designed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be performed in Madrid, Valencia and Murcia regions in Spain, in five&#xD;
      different hospitals: Fundación Jiménez Díaz University Hospital (Madrid, Spain), Villalba&#xD;
      University General Hospital (Madrid, Spain), Infanta Elena University Hospital (Madrid,&#xD;
      Spain), Virgen de la Arixaca University Hospital (Murcia, Spain) and Clínico de Valencia&#xD;
      University Hospital (Valencia, Spain).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Every patient included is previously diagnosed and hospitalized because of SARS-COV-2&#xD;
      infection, being admitted mainly for respiratory pathology. All of them will be adults (age&#xD;
      &gt;18 years) and provide their voluntary written or oral consent to participation according to&#xD;
      the hospital's ethics committee recommendations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After approval of consent, the hospital staff responsible for the interventions will&#xD;
      consecutively assign each participant a code following the order from a previously randomly&#xD;
      generated table. The code will consist of a patient number and a letter corresponding to one&#xD;
      of the five study groups (A, B, C, D and E), that will be known to the clinical personnel but&#xD;
      unknown to the laboratory personnel who will process samples and extract RNA, as well as to&#xD;
      those that will analyse the data. In this way, participants will be randomly assigned to one&#xD;
      of the five treatment groups and the blind will be achieved by using identical tubes with the&#xD;
      same volume for both mouthwashes and placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Every included patient is asked not to eat, drink anything but water, chew gum, smoke, brush&#xD;
      their teeth, or use any mouthwash for one hour prior to sample collection. In addition, they&#xD;
      are not allowed to drink for half an hour after the mouthwash and eat for the entire test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Five mouthwashes are randomized: 2% povidone-iodine (group A), 1% hydrogen peroxide (group&#xD;
      B), 0.12% chlorhexidine (group C), 0.07% cetylpyridinium chloride (group D) and distilled&#xD;
      water (group E), as the control group. Group C (Clorhexidina dental PHB©) and D (Vitis Xtra&#xD;
      Forte©) rinses are ready to use in their commercial formulas. In the case of the mouthwashes&#xD;
      A and B, the concentrations have to be adjusted to those previously indicated by diluting&#xD;
      commercial formulas with distilled water minutes before rinsing (3 mL of povidone-iodine 10%&#xD;
      for oral use with 12 mL of distilled water, in group A; and 5 mL of hydrogen peroxide 3%-&#xD;
      Oximen© with 10 mL of distilled water, in group B). All mouthwashes and their respective&#xD;
      dilutions are commercial products classified as safe.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of 4 non stimulated saliva samples will be collected for each patient: one basal and&#xD;
      three after the mouthwash, at 30 minutes, at 60 minutes and at 120 minutes, respectively. The&#xD;
      patients will be asked to provide each unstimulated saliva sample into a sterile 10 cm&#xD;
      diameter plastic container (at least 0.5 mL of sample) by drooling, avoiding spilling&#xD;
      secretions of bronchial origin. Immediately after each sampling, 0.5 mL of saliva will be&#xD;
      transferred to a sterile Eppendorf tube with 1.5 mL of virus inactivating buffer labeled with&#xD;
      the patient code and sample time and kept at 4 °C. The four Eppendorf tubes per patient will&#xD;
      be introduced in an airtight bag, containing protecting absorbent material in case of&#xD;
      undesired opening or breaking. The secondary containers will be introduced in a rigid box&#xD;
      according to UN3733 standards and sent to laboratory by courier service for analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An aliquot of 1 ml of each saliva sample diluted in the virus inactivating buffer in&#xD;
      proportion 1:3, will be used for RNA extraction using a standard TRIzol-based method.&#xD;
      Briefly, 3 ml of TRIzol and 600 ul of chloroform will be added, vortexed vigorously for 15&#xD;
      seconds and incubated on ice for 10 minutes. Then, samples will be centrifuged at 12,000 g&#xD;
      for 15 min at 4 °C and the aqueous phase transferred to two clean microtubes with 750 ul of&#xD;
      isopropanol. Tubes will be mixed by inversion and incubated during 15 minutes before&#xD;
      centrifugation at 12,000 g for 10 minutes at 4 °C. Supernatant will be discarded by&#xD;
      decantation and pellets washed with 1 ml 80% cold ethanol, vortexed to mix thoroughly and&#xD;
      centrifugated at 7,500 g for 5 minutes at 4 °C. Supernatants will be carefully aspirated and&#xD;
      discarded, and pellets dried at room temperature for 10 minutes before being resuspended in&#xD;
      15 ul of RNAse -free water and pooled in a single tube.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One step rRT-PCR will be performed using SuperScript™ III One-Step RT-PCR System with&#xD;
      Platinum™ Taq DNA Polymerase (Invitrogen-12574026) according to manufacturer's instructions.&#xD;
      For the amplification of the SARSCoV-2 E (betacoronavirus screening assay) gene, PCR will be&#xD;
      performed following the Charité-Berlin protocol in a LightCycler 480 2.0 (Roche) platform. In&#xD;
      the same run, samples will be amplified with housekeeping human gene RNP (Ribonuclease P)&#xD;
      primers to assess specimen quality. All samples will be run in two replicates, together with&#xD;
      a previously known positive and negative controls. Virus copies will be quantified using a&#xD;
      10-fold dilution standard curve of RNA transcripts previously generated (EDX SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      Standard, EXACT DIAGNOSTICS EDX). Virus copies were normalized by ml of saliva.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Regarding the analyses to be performed, the main objective of the study is to determine the&#xD;
      effect of the different mouthwashes on the SARS-Cov2 viral load in saliva tested in vivo.&#xD;
      Thus, the primary outcome will be the change in salivary viral load between baseline and the&#xD;
      three post-mouthwash timepoints in each treatment. In addition, the correlations between the&#xD;
      basal viral load prior to rinsing with the different clinical data collected, such as age,&#xD;
      sex, days since the appearance of symptoms and days since the patients' virus positivity&#xD;
      determined by PCR of nasopharyngeal samples will also be studied. Finally, the possible&#xD;
      associations between categorical clinical variables and the frequency of patients who improve&#xD;
      in viral load at different times for the different treatments will be evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Considering that each volunteer act as their own control, when comparing the viral load&#xD;
      values in saliva at every time with respect to the levels prior to rinsing with the&#xD;
      mouthwash, a sample size of 15 patients per branch was considered sufficient to identify&#xD;
      significant viral load differences of more than 20% between timepoints, assuming a 10% loss&#xD;
      of patients due to abandonment or low viral load and adopting an alpha of 0.05 and a power of&#xD;
      0.8. As 5 branches were programmed in the trial (povidone-iodine, hydrogen peroxide,&#xD;
      chlorhexidine, cetylpyridinium chloride and the control), 75 patients were the minimum number&#xD;
      of total individuals to be recruited, who will be distributed among the different hospitals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A Wilcoxon signed-rank test will be used to test average differences, both for the paired&#xD;
      case, (when comparing observations in different timepoints for the same individuals), and for&#xD;
      the un-paired case (when comparing different treatments based on relative changes of viral&#xD;
      load). In addition, some tests for association between paired samples using Spearman's&#xD;
      correlation coefficients will be performed to assess the relationship between viral load and&#xD;
      other clinical continuous variables. Finally, in order to evaluate associations between&#xD;
      clinical categorical variables and the frequency of responders/non-responders to the&#xD;
      treatments, the investigators will carry out chi-squared contingency table tests. The&#xD;
      investigators define as responder an individual exhibiting an improvement equal to or greater&#xD;
      than 90% of basal viral load. All computations and tests will be performed using R&#xD;
      environment for statistical computing version 3.6.3 and its 'stats' package [R Core Team&#xD;
      2020].&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 18, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 18, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A multicentre, randomized, blind, five-parallel-group, placebo-controlled trial.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The hospital staff consecutively assigned each participant a code following the order from a previously randomly generated table.&#xD;
The code were unknown to the personnel who processed the samples and to those that analyzed the data.&#xD;
Participants were blinded by using identical tubes with the same volume for both mouthwashes and placebo.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of 5 different mouthwashes on the SARS-Cov2 viral load.</measure>
    <time_frame>Minute 0 (before mouthwash) - Minute 30 (after mouthwash) - Minute 60 (after mouthwash) - Minute 120 (after mouthwash)</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the changes on the SARS-Cov2 viral load in saliva tested in vivo, between baseline values and those obtained at 30 minutes, at 60 minutes and at 120 minutes, after the use of 5 different mouthwashes randomized on 98 COVID-19 patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">84</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Povidone-iodine 2% (Betadine© bucal 100 mg/ml)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Povidone-iodine 2% (Betadine© bucal 100 mg/ml) (Mylan Pharmaceuticals, S.L., Spain).&#xD;
The concentration was adjusted to those previously indicated by diluting commercial formulas with distilled water minutes before rinsing (3 mL of povidone-iodine 10% for oral use - Betadine© with 12 mL of distilled water).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hydrogen peroxide 1% (Oximen® 3%)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Hydrogen peroxide 1% (Oximen® 3%) (Reig Jofré, S.A., Spain). The concentration was adjusted to those previously indicated by diluting commercial formulas with distilled water minutes before rinsing (5 mL of hydrogen peroxide 3% - Oximen© with 10 mL of distilled water).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Clorhexidine 0,12% (Clorhexidine Dental PHB©)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Clorhexidine 0,12% (Clorhexidine Dental PHB©) contains clorhexidine (C22H30N10Cl2).&#xD;
Rinses were ready to use in their commercial formulas.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cetylpyridinium chloride 0,07% (Vitis Xtra Forte©)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cetylpyridinium chloride 0,07% (Vitis Xtra Forte©) contains cetylpyridinium chloride (C21H38ClN).&#xD;
Rinses were ready to use in their commercial formulas.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control (Distilled Water)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Distilled water.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Betadine© bucal 100 mg/ml</intervention_name>
    <description>15 ml 2% povidone-iodine, one minute rinse.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Povidone-iodine 2% (Betadine© bucal 100 mg/ml)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Povidone-iodine</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Oximen® 3%</intervention_name>
    <description>15 ml 1% hydrogen peroxide, one minute rinse.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hydrogen peroxide 1% (Oximen® 3%)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>H2O2</other_name>
    <other_name>Hydrogen peroxide</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Clorhexidine Dental PHB©</intervention_name>
    <description>15 ml 0,12% clorhexidine, one minute rinse.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Clorhexidine 0,12% (Clorhexidine Dental PHB©)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>C22H30N10Cl2</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vitis Xtra Forte©</intervention_name>
    <description>15 ml 0,07% cetylpyridinium chloride, one minute rinse.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cetylpyridinium chloride 0,07% (Vitis Xtra Forte©)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>C21H38ClN</other_name>
    <other_name>Cetylpyridinium chloride</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Distilled Water</intervention_name>
    <description>15 ml distilled water, one minute rinse.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control (Distilled Water)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>H2O</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lower than 7 days from the positive SARS-COV-2 PCR test of a nasopharyngeal sample&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have the ability to donate saliva samples and perform mouthwash&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient participation in a COVID-19 research study using experimental drugs,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of an antiseptic mouthwash for 48 h before the start of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any known hypersensitivity or allergy to components of the mouthwashes.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alejandro Mira, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Fundación para el Fomento de la Investigación Sanitaria y Biomédica de la Comunitat Valenciana</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alejandro Mira</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <zip>46020</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Fundación para el Fomento de la Investigación Sanitaria y Biomédica de la Comunitat Valenciana</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Alejandro Mira Obrador</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>BSc in Biological Sciences (Alicante University), MSc PhD (Oxford University), Senior Researcher (FISABIO Foundation)</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>MOUTHWASHES</keyword>
  <keyword>SALIVA</keyword>
  <keyword>VIRAL LOAD</keyword>
  <keyword>ORAL</keyword>
  <keyword>CLINICAL TRIAL</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Povidone-Iodine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hydrogen Peroxide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cetylpyridinium</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Povidone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

