<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4112">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04652505</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-0451</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2020-06556</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-0451</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04652505</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of the COVID-19 Public Health Crisis on the Mental Health and Physical Well-Being of Cancer Patients, the Coping With COVID Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Coping With COVID: The Effect of the COVID-19 Public Health Crisis on Mental Well-Being in Cancer Patients Seen at the Psychiatric Oncology Clinic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study determines how the threat of the coronavirus has affected the mental health and&#xD;
      physical well-being of cancer patients seen at the psychiatric oncology clinic, and how they&#xD;
      have coped with any related stress. Questionnaires that assess coping strategies and&#xD;
      behaviors for decreasing disease transmission may help researchers create recommendations for&#xD;
      future public health crises and pandemics.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine how the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) public health crisis affected&#xD;
      mental well-being in cancer patients seen at the psychiatric oncology clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine how the COVID-19 public health crisis affected physical well-being and&#xD;
      substance use in cancer patients seen at the psychiatric oncology clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To determine how patient coping strategies and levels of apathy affected mental and&#xD;
      physical health symptoms and substance use during COVID-19 in patients seen at the&#xD;
      psychiatric oncology clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To determine the association of coping strategies and levels of apathy with proclivity&#xD;
      to engage in health behaviors intended to decrease the transmission of the disease during the&#xD;
      COVID-19 pandemic in patients seen at the psychiatric oncology clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients complete 3 questionnaires online over 15 minutes regarding coping strategies that&#xD;
      may have been used, mental health and physical well-being in the past month, and if they have&#xD;
      been following certain behaviors which the World Health Organization (WHO) has recommended&#xD;
      during the coronavirus pandemic, such as regular hand washing and social distancing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 13, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported severity of depression</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>sum score on the Patient Health Questionnaire, a 9-item scale with a sumscore ranging between 0 and 27, with a higher score indicating more-severe depression.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported severity of anxiety</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>sum score on the generalized anxiety disorder questionnaire, a 7-item scale with sumscore range between 0 and 21. A higher score indicates higher severity of anxiety.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported severity of distress</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>score on the National Comprehensive Cancer Network Distress Thermometer, a one-item 0-10 scale. A higher score indicates higher distress.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported physical symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Physical symptoms are assessed with individual-item response on the Edmonton Symptom Assessment Scale by the clinic. The ESAS includes 6 somatic symptom items, each of which is to be rated on a 0-10 scale, with higher scores indicating higher severity of the symptom.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Substance use</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Substance use is documented by the treating physician and will be abstracted from clinic notes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported coping strategy</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed using the brief COPE questionnaire. Will examine active versus avoidant coping. Active coping, planning, positive reframing, acceptance, humor, religion, emotional support-seeking, and instrumental support-seeking will be considered active coping strategies. Self-distraction, denial, venting, substance use, behavioral disengagement, and self-blame will be considered maladaptive coping strategies.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported levels of apathy</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The Apathy evaluation Scale is an 18-item scale with a sum score ranging between 18 and 72. A higher scores indicates higher apathy..</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported engagement in the 5 health behaviors endorsed by World Health Organization intended to curb the spread of the coronavirus</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Patients indicate how often during the pandemic they engaged in the following 5 behaviors endorsed by the World Health Organization to decrease the transmission of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): washing hands regularly for 20 seconds with soap and water or alcohol-based hand rub, covering nose and mouth with a disposable tissue or flexed elbow when you cough or sneeze, avoiding close contact with people who are unwell, staying home and self-isolating from others in the household when feeling unwell, avoiding touching eyes, nose, and mouth when hands are unclean. The behaviors will be assessed on a Likert scale of 1-5, with 1 being &quot;never&quot; and 5 being &quot;always&quot;. A not available (N/A) option will be given for staying home and self-isolating from others when feeling unwell, since participants may not experience a period of feeling unwell.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">700</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19 Infection</condition>
  <condition>Hematopoietic and Lymphoid Cell Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Observational (questionnaires)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients complete 3 questionnaires online over 15 minutes regarding coping strategies that may have been used, mental health and physical well-being in the past month, and if they have been following certain behaviors which the WHO has recommended during the coronavirus pandemic, such as regular hand washing and social distancing.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaire Administration</intervention_name>
    <description>Complete questionnaires</description>
    <arm_group_label>Observational (questionnaires)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Cancer patients who received care at the psychiatric oncology clinic during the COVID-19&#xD;
        pandemic&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Outpatients seen by providers of the psychiatric oncology clinic at least once between&#xD;
             November 1, 2019 and February 29, 2020 and at least once between April 10, 2020 and&#xD;
             June 10, 2020&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Speaking English as indicated in their medical chart&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are pregnant as recorded in their medical chart&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Incarcerated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With a recorded diagnosis of a formal thought disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tamara E Lacourt</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tamara E Lacourt</last_name>
    <phone>713-792-3768</phone>
    <email>TLacourt@MDAnderson.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M D Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tamara E. Lacourt</last_name>
      <phone>713-792-3768</phone>
      <email>TLacourt@MDAnderson.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tamara E. Lacourt</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>MD Anderson Cancer Center Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 3, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 2, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 2, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 3, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

