<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1705">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04628104</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CMR in myocardial infarction</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04628104</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>CMR Findings in COVID-19 Patients Presenting With Myocardial Infarction</brief_title>
  <official_title>CMR Findings in COVID-19 Patients Presenting With Myocardial Infarction</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To compare myocardial injury in COVID 19 patients presented with myocardial infarction and&#xD;
      non COVID Patients presented with myocardial infarction evaluated with CMR&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) is a global pandemic affecting 185 countries and &gt;3 000&#xD;
      000 patients worldwide as of April 28, 2020. COVID-19 is caused by severe acute respiratory&#xD;
      syndrome coronavirus 2,. Among patients with COVID-19, there is a high prevalence of&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease, and &gt;7% of patients experience myocardial injury from the infection&#xD;
      (22% of critically ill patients). Although angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 serves as the&#xD;
      portal for infection, the role of angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitors or angiotensin&#xD;
      receptor blockers requires further investigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, much like any other respiratory tract infection, pre-existing cardiovascular disease&#xD;
      (CVD) and CV risk factors enhance vulnerability to COVID-19. Further, COVID-19 can worsen&#xD;
      underly- ing CVD and even precipitate de novo cardiac complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preliminary reports suggest that haemostatic abnormalities, including disseminated&#xD;
      intravascular coagulation (DIC), occur in patients affected by COVID-19. Additionally, the&#xD;
      severe inflammatory response, critical illness, and underlying traditional risk factors may&#xD;
      all predispose to thrombotic events, similar to prior virulent zoonotic coronavirus outbreaks&#xD;
      CMR is the reference non-invasive standard for cardiac function and tissue characterization&#xD;
      and may offer an effective and efficient diagnostic imaging choice to obtain critical&#xD;
      information for clinical decision-making.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>3 Days</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>comparison between COVID-19 and COVID-19 presented with myocardial infarction</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Distribution and Extent of myocardial injury in COVID 19 patients presented with myocardial infarction and non COVID Patients presented with myocardial infarction evaluated with CMR.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Myocardial Infarction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 patients presented with myocardial infarction</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Non-COVID-19 patients presented with myocardial infarction</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>cardiac magnetic resonance</intervention_name>
    <description>o CMR protocol:&#xD;
Cine imaging to assess regional &amp; global ventricular function according to the AHA 16-segment model.&#xD;
T2-weighted imaging to detect extent &amp; distribution of myocardial edema.&#xD;
Early Gd enhancement imaging to detect extent &amp; distribution of myocardial hyperemia.&#xD;
Late Gd enhancement imaging to detect extent &amp; distribution of myocardial necrosis.&#xD;
Single-short sequences &amp; other acceleration techniques will be used as appropriate in patients with poor ability to hold their breath.&#xD;
Post-processing analysis will be done on a dedicated workstation</description>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 patients presented with myocardial infarction</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Non-COVID-19 patients presented with myocardial infarction</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Included patients will be randomly divided in a 1:1 pattern into two groups. The 1st group&#xD;
        are COVID 19 patients and the 2nd group are non COVID 19 patients as a control.&#xD;
&#xD;
        All patients will be subjected to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A. Full history taking: including age, sex, history of DM, HTN, Smoking, dyslipidemia,&#xD;
        symptoms of COVID 19 infection, chest pain analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        B. Thorough physical examination:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  General examination including Systolic and diastolic blood pressure, heart rate&#xD;
             assessment and O2 Saturation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiac examination C. Twelve lead ECG: to search for STEMI criteria according to ECS&#xD;
             guidelines of STEMI 2017.5 D. lab investigation: Cardiac enzymes, Renal function,&#xD;
             Liver function, CBC, CRP, Lipid profile, RBG, Serum ferritin, ESR, D-Dimer, PCR.&#xD;
&#xD;
        E.MSCT chest: to detect finding suggestive of COVID 19 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        F.CMR:&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients presenting with symptoms and ECG indicative of acute MI (both STEMI &amp; NSTEMI)&#xD;
             AND confirmed COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients admitted with acute MI (both STEMI &amp; NSTEMI) who develop COVID-19 symptoms&#xD;
             during hospital admission &amp; are confirmed by RT-PCR to have COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of previous diagnosis of STEMI or myocarditis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of previous PCI in infarcted related artery or NSTEMI&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Severe respiratory distress that precludes lying supine in the CMR scanner.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Acute kidney injury with rapidly declining GFR or GFR that is persistently below 30&#xD;
             ml/min/1.73 m2 (contraindication for Gadopentetate dimeglumine contrast).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>mohamed ahmed, Master</last_name>
    <phone>01061605533</phone>
    <email>mohamedalnaqady@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>hosam hasan, master</last_name>
    <phone>01223971327</phone>
    <email>Hosam_hasan@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Stefanini GG, Montorfano M, Trabattoni D, Andreini D, Ferrante G, Ancona M, Metra M, Curello S, Maffeo D, Pero G, Cacucci M, Assanelli E, Bellini B, Russo F, Ielasi A, Tespili M, Danzi GB, Vandoni P, Bollati M, Barbieri L, Oreglia J, Lettieri C, Cremonesi A, Carugo S, Reimers B, Condorelli G, Chieffo A. ST-Elevation Myocardial Infarction in Patients With COVID-19: Clinical and Angiographic Outcomes. Circulation. 2020 Jun 23;141(25):2113-2116. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.047525. Epub 2020 Apr 30.</citation>
    <PMID>32352306</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mahmud E, Dauerman HL, Welt FGP, Messenger JC, Rao SV, Grines C, Mattu A, Kirtane AJ, Jauhar R, Meraj P, Rokos IC, Rumsfeld JS, Henry TD. Management of Acute Myocardial Infarction During the COVID-19 Pandemic: A Position Statement From the Society for Cardiovascular Angiography and Interventions (SCAI), the American College of Cardiology (ACC), and the American College of Emergency Physicians (ACEP). J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020 Sep 15;76(11):1375-1384. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2020.04.039. Epub 2020 Apr 21.</citation>
    <PMID>32330544</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bikdeli B, Madhavan MV, Jimenez D, Chuich T, Dreyfus I, Driggin E, Nigoghossian C, Ageno W, Madjid M, Guo Y, Tang LV, Hu Y, Giri J, Cushman M, Quéré I, Dimakakos EP, Gibson CM, Lippi G, Favaloro EJ, Fareed J, Caprini JA, Tafur AJ, Burton JR, Francese DP, Wang EY, Falanga A, McLintock C, Hunt BJ, Spyropoulos AC, Barnes GD, Eikelboom JW, Weinberg I, Schulman S, Carrier M, Piazza G, Beckman JA, Steg PG, Stone GW, Rosenkranz S, Goldhaber SZ, Parikh SA, Monreal M, Krumholz HM, Konstantinides SV, Weitz JI, Lip GYH; Global COVID-19 Thrombosis Collaborative Group, Endorsed by the ISTH, NATF, ESVM, and the IUA, Supported by the ESC Working Group on Pulmonary Circulation and Right Ventricular Function. COVID-19 and Thrombotic or Thromboembolic Disease: Implications for Prevention, Antithrombotic Therapy, and Follow-Up: JACC State-of-the-Art Review. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020 Jun 16;75(23):2950-2973. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2020.04.031. Epub 2020 Apr 17. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32311448</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chen C, Chen C, Yan JT, Zhou N, Zhao JP, Wang DW. [Analysis of myocardial injury in patients with COVID-19 and association between concomitant cardiovascular diseases and severity of COVID-19]. Zhonghua Xin Xue Guan Bing Za Zhi. 2020 Jul 24;48(7):567-571. doi: 10.3760/cma.j.cn112148-20200225-00123. Chinese.</citation>
    <PMID>32141280</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Thygesen K, Alpert JS, Jaffe AS, Chaitman BR, Bax JJ, Morrow DA, White HD; Executive Group on behalf of the Joint European Society of Cardiology (ESC)/American College of Cardiology (ACC)/American Heart Association (AHA)/World Heart Federation (WHF) Task Force for the Universal Definition of Myocardial Infarction. Fourth Universal Definition of Myocardial Infarction (2018). J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018 Oct 30;72(18):2231-2264. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2018.08.1038. Epub 2018 Aug 25. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30153967</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 12, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 13, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 12, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 12, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mohamed Ahmed Abdallah Hamada</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

