<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4059">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04587245</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PIRStudy</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04587245</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Provider Insurance Revenue Study in Healthcare Providers in the United States of America</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Provider Insurance Revenue Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>ND Sciences, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of California, Irvine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>ND Sciences, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators are enrolling 100 healthcare Provider volunteers (n=100) from across the&#xD;
      United States to help to evaluate and document the financial impact of COVID-19 on Physicians&#xD;
      and other healthcare Providers. This investigation will compare individual Physician revenues&#xD;
      before and after the advent of the COVID-19 pandemic. The investigators expect to be able to&#xD;
      differentiate between revenues lost due to the COVID-19-driven business recession and&#xD;
      revenues lost due to the manipulation of reimbursement processes by insurance companies. The&#xD;
      inextricable linkage between Payer and Physician revenues suggests that Payer revenues are&#xD;
      higher at the direct expense of Physicians, since both streams come from the same sources of&#xD;
      funding. The secondary objective is aimed at revealing the methods Payers use to retain more&#xD;
      money.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Since the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic in March, 2020, Physicians and other medical&#xD;
      Providers have taken devastating hits to their practice revenues. Most of the losses are due&#xD;
      to doctors being forced to curtail elective procedures and office visits as Americans were&#xD;
      ordered to stay home during the height of the national health emergency.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As Physicians were able to return to work in the early Summer, even if only partially, many&#xD;
      had to adjust to the newer medical practice of telehealth, and the lower revenues that came&#xD;
      with it. The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) gave assurances to Physicians&#xD;
      that Medicare would reimburse telehealth encounters at 100% of the office visit rate. But&#xD;
      private Payers were under no such obligation. Across the country, Physicians are reporting&#xD;
      that they're being reimbursed at about 70% of an office visit rate despite the fact that&#xD;
      telehealth requires both resources and expertise to implement effectively, and each encounter&#xD;
      takes up to twice as long as an office visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adding to financial hardships, Physicians across the nation are reporting that legitimate&#xD;
      insurance claims are being held up and denied by the insurance companies at a higher rate&#xD;
      than ever, cutting off the cash that they need so desperately. As of June 1, only half of&#xD;
      Physician practices say they have enough cash to stay open for another month.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In just 2 months in the spring of 2020, over 45 million Americans lost their jobs and for&#xD;
      many, that also meant the loss of their employment-related health insurance. Despite shedding&#xD;
      a massive number of members from their rolls, health insurance companies are actually&#xD;
      predicting record profits for 2020. The pandemic it seems, is very good indeed for the health&#xD;
      insurance business. Private investors and executives are taking huge dividends and bonuses&#xD;
      out of the system just at a time when US healthcare needs a vast new investment of healthcare&#xD;
      resources into the system. The good fortune of a few individuals and corporations comes at an&#xD;
      as yet untold expense to American society.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The formula for insurance company success in a pandemic only happens one way. By keeping&#xD;
      member premiums, delaying payments, and denying treatment authorizations, the large health&#xD;
      insurance companies are taking advantage of the profound misfortunes of both doctors and&#xD;
      patients during a national health emergency.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The COVID-19 pandemic will have adverse effects on the health of Americans that will be&#xD;
      sprawling and long-felt. However, it is not for this study to decide whether private&#xD;
      interests will always be antithetical to public interests when it comes to healthcare. That&#xD;
      is a public debate that will continue to evolve as the profound weaknesses of the American&#xD;
      way of distributing healthcare are magnified and exposed in a time of social upheaval.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators do know that in order to get a handle on the major damage we see occurring&#xD;
      in real-time- and to inform that debate, it is first necessary to measure it.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in monthly income of healthcare Providers from baseline to 6, 9 and 12 months after the beginning of the COVID-related events</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in monthly income of healthcare Providers from baseline to 6, 9 and 12 months after the beginning of the COVID-related events</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Differences in Accounts Receivable (AR) due to claim denials over 4 quarters: Differences in recoveries of AR.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Differences in Accounts Receivable (AR) due to claim denials over 4 quarters: Differences in recoveries of AR.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Financial Disclosure</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Physicians</arm_group_label>
    <description>Physician or healthcare Provider based anywhere in the United States who is eligible to submit claims to an insurance company on behalf of patients</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Online questionnaire and interviews</intervention_name>
    <description>Online questionnaire, financial statements (one month per quarter in 2020) submitted electronically, interview with professional accounting firm and review of data and exit Interview</description>
    <arm_group_label>Physicians</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Healthcare Provider based anywhere in the United States who is eligible to submit claims to&#xD;
        an insurance company on behalf of patients.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthcare Provider based anywhere in the United States who is eligible to submit&#xD;
             claims to an insurance company on behalf of patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  To agree to participate in this study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that at the discretion of the principal investigator renders the subject&#xD;
             ineligible to participate in this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Henry Broeska, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California Irvine Beall Applied Innovation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Henry Broeska, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>949-332-9638</phone>
    <email>hbroeska0@saddleback.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Charles Bronson, MBA</last_name>
    <phone>415-530-8742</phone>
    <email>chasbronoson@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California Irvine Beall Applied Innovation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Irvine</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92617</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Henry Broeska</last_name>
      <phone>949-332-9638</phone>
      <email>hbroeska0@saddleback.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Charles Bronson</last_name>
      <phone>415-530-8742</phone>
      <email>chasbronson@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sheridan Merrick, BA</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 7, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 14, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 14, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Healthcare providers</keyword>
  <keyword>Covid19</keyword>
  <keyword>Financial impact</keyword>
  <keyword>Income</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

