<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3941">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04341285</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ECMO-VID</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04341285</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Early Versus Late ECMO Therapy in COVID-19 Induced ARDS (ECMO-VID)</brief_title>
  <acronym>ECMO-VID</acronym>
  <official_title>Early Versus Late ECMO Therapy in COVID-19 Induced ARDS (ECMO-VID)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital Tuebingen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital Freiburg</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>RWTH Aachen University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital Muenster</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital Tuebingen</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Experimental intervention: Insertion of Extracorporal Membrane Oxygenation (ECMO) within 24&#xD;
      hours of referral to an Intensive Care Unit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control intervention: Insertion of Extracorporal Membrane Oxygenation (ECMO) as rescue&#xD;
      therapy following failure of conventional therapy for ARDS. This conventional therapy will be&#xD;
      standardized to reduce bias.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Duration of intervention per patient: varies, depending on severity of pulmonary compromise&#xD;
      Follow-up per patient: Until hospital discharge Accompanying measures: Serum Samples and&#xD;
      bronchoscopy samples of patients included into the trial for secondary analysis of&#xD;
      inflammatory parameters and potential biomarkers&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The severe form of COVID-19 infection is characterized and marked by severe pneumonia and the&#xD;
      Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome (ARDS). ARDS is characterized by the loss of pulmonary&#xD;
      tissue compliance and severe hypoxia. The central pathophysiologic changes of COVID-19+ ARDS&#xD;
      are dysregulated inflammation within the alveolar space and altered permeability of the&#xD;
      alveolar-capillary barrier. The public health impact of this COVID-19+ ARDS is considerable&#xD;
      with a large number of ARDS cases that need to be treated currently on German Intensive Care&#xD;
      Units. To date, the associated mortality ranges between 30 to 50%. In the ongoing COVID-19&#xD;
      crisis cases of ARDS will still increase and pose a significant challenge to the German&#xD;
      Medical System. Despite the emerging understanding of COVID-19+ ARDS, treatment only remains&#xD;
      to be symptomatic using mechanical ventilation, prone positioning and in severe cases of&#xD;
      hypoxia extracorporal membrane oxygenation (ECMO). Current evidence generated by clinical&#xD;
      trials demonstrates that patients with ARDS should be referred to a specialized center to&#xD;
      receive expert treatment. The use of ECMO might have a beneficial effect on overall patient&#xD;
      outcome, yet this has not been proven by clinical trials and to date ECMO is recommended as&#xD;
      measure of last resort in the current ARDS treatment guidelines. The timing of ECMO placement&#xD;
      to relieve hypoxia is an important question for the treating clinician but is not well&#xD;
      studied to date. This might also have impact on the long-term functional outcome of patients.&#xD;
      In addition, evidence about the role of ECMO in the outcome of COVID-19+ patients might have&#xD;
      significant impact on the referral of patients to a specialized center and is important for&#xD;
      the treating physician. Therefore, the investigators want to pursue the questions whether&#xD;
      early ECMO placement is superior than the placement of ECMO as a rescue measure, and whether&#xD;
      this could result in improved overall outcome of patients with COVID-19+ ARDS.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Experimental intervention: Insertion of Extracorporal Membrane Oxygenation (ECMO) within 24 hours Control intervention: Insertion of Extracorporal Membrane Oxygenation (ECMO) as rescue therapy following failure of conventional therapy for ARDS. This conventional therapy will be standardized to reduce bias.&#xD;
Duration of intervention per patient: varies, depending on severity of pulmonary compromise Follow-up per patient: 90days or until hospital discharge Accompanying measures: Serum Samples and bronchoscopy samples of patients included into the trial for secondary analysis of inflammatory parameters and potential biomarkers</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>28 day all cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>28 Days</time_frame>
    <description>survival in 28-day follow-up period (28 day all cause mortality)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>90 day all cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>90 day all cause mortality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sepsis-related organ failure assessment score at day 1-14, 28 and 90 days</measure>
    <time_frame>day 1-14, 28 and 90</time_frame>
    <description>Sepsis-related organ failure assessment score at day 1-14, 28 and 90 days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>duration of mechanical ventilation support</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>duration of mechanical ventilation support</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ventilator Associated Pneumonia</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients with Ventilator Associated Pneumonia</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bleeding complications</measure>
    <time_frame>28 das</time_frame>
    <description>number of blood transfusion units</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acute Renal Failure</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Days on real replacement therapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Discharge Location</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Discharge to (home, skilled nursing facility, rehabilitation)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>ARDS, Human</condition>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Early ECMO</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Experimental intervention: Insertion of Extracorporal Membrane Oxygenation (ECMO) within 24 hours of referral to an Intensive Care Unit.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Late ECMO</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Insertion of Extracorporal Membrane Oxygenation (ECMO) as rescue therapy following failure of conventional therapy for ARDS. This conventional therapy will be standardized to reduce bias.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ECMO Implantation</intervention_name>
    <description>Insertion of Extracorporal Membrane Oxygenation (ECMO) within 24 hours of referral to an Intensive Care Unit.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Early ECMO</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Late ECMO</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19positive(+) ARDS as defined according to the Berlin Definition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ratio of partial pressure arterial oxygen and fraction of inspired oxygen (PaO2/ FiO2)&#xD;
             ≤100&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bilateral opacities consistent with pulmonary edema on frontal chest radiograph&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  requirement for positive pressure ventilation via an endotracheal tube or non-invasive&#xD;
             ventilation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no clinical evidence of left atrial hypertension, or if measured, a Pulmonary Arterial&#xD;
             Wedge Pressure (PAOP) less than or equal to 18 mmHg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≤ 7 days from the initiation of mechanical ventilation at the time of randomization. -&#xD;
             Patients must be enrolled within 96 hours of onset of ARDS -&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19negative(-) ARDS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age less than 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  More than 7 days since initiation of mechanical ventilation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  more than 96 hours since meeting ARDS criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patient, surrogate or physician not committed to full intensive care support.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Peter Rosenberger, Prof.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>+4970712986622</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Peter Rosenberger, Prof.</last_name>
    <phone>+49707129</phone>
    <phone_ext>86622</phone_ext>
    <email>peter.rosenberger@med.uni-tuebingen.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Tuebingen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tuebingen</city>
        <zip>72076</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 30, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 7, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 10, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 22, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 22, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 23, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Adult</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

