<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2110">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04565392</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pykonsult 201</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04565392</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Remotely-conducted Trial of Famotidine vs Placebo for Patients at Home With Coronavirus (COVID) of 2019 (COVID-19)</brief_title>
  <acronym>Pepcid4COV19</acronym>
  <official_title>Proof-of-concept Randomized Placebo-controlled Trial of Famotidine for Outpatients With COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>drpykessupplements.com</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>drpykessupplements.com</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Kit for reading vital signs (thermometer, wrist blood pressure device, finger oximeter) and&#xD;
      with study drug is overnighted to qualified subjects with early symptoms of COVID-19.&#xD;
      Subjects take a 20-milligram (mg) tab of famotidine or matching placebo twice a day, increase&#xD;
      to 1 tablet every 8 hours if not better the 2nd day, and continue same for 30 days. Vital&#xD;
      signs, symptoms, compliance etc are rechecked daily for the 30 days and once again 60 days&#xD;
      after starting study drug. Consent, baseline, and follow-up are handled via internet plus&#xD;
      calls/texts/virtual visits from study nurse or doctor as needed for clarifications and&#xD;
      compliance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      If an Over-The-Counter (OTC) medication could prevent worsening and hospitalization for&#xD;
      COVID-19, it could stop the devastation wrought by the pandemic, and do so at a low cost. One&#xD;
      OTC medication has a pre-clinical and clinical rationale to help: famotidine. For this study,&#xD;
      150 subjects are randomly assigned 50:50 to blinded treatment with 1 (20-milligram) tablet&#xD;
      famotidine or matching placebo twice a day and can increase to 1 tablet three times a day.&#xD;
      This internet-driven study requires subjects to maintain contact with and follow advice of&#xD;
      their local MD, so it does not increase their risks from the disease. Baseline eligibility&#xD;
      checklist follows informed consent. Subjects must have at least 5 of the standard symptoms of&#xD;
      COVID19, be willing to keep taking study medicine and reporting results daily for 30 days,&#xD;
      must start within the first 6 days of symptoms, and must have a study partner to complete&#xD;
      their follow-up in case they become unable. The rate of subjects worsening or getting&#xD;
      hospitalized is the main outcome measure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Parallel double-blind placebo-controlled interventional trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>study medication is Pepcid AC or matching placebo</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Course Binary Outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>30th (last) day of treatment, or if discontinues treatment early, last observation carried forward</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients who self-rate as 6 on Patients Global Impression or are hospitalized for COVID-19 or similar symptoms or seek medical help for worsening symptoms, or get short of breath and have oxygen saturation below 90%, or die of COVID-19</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Serious Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>30th (last) day of treatment, or if discontinues treatment early, last observation carried forward]</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients who report a serious adverse event, i.e., one that causes hospitalization or death</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to symptomatic recovery</measure>
    <time_frame>There is no baseline rating. Outcome is rated on the 30th (last) day of treatment, or if discontinues treatment early, last observation carried forward</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion who answer the daily Global Recovery Question affirmatively: &quot;Have you returned to your usual health (before your COVID-19 illness)? yes/no&quot; if verified on the same day's evaluation by at least one category of improvement in each of the symptoms endorsed at baseline on the SCL18 (see Outcome 4).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SCL18 (self-check list of 18 symptoms of COVID-19)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline at 30th (last) day of treatment, or if discontinues treatment early, last observation carried forward</time_frame>
    <description>a) mean change in total (18-item) score since baseline; b) proportion self-rating each item (symptom) at a lower or 0 intensity value than at baseline; c) subtotal on: Major Acute Physical Symptoms (SCL18 #2, Pains in heart or chest, #4 Nausea, vomiting or upset stomach, #6 Sore throat, #7 Cough, #9 Chills or shivering, #11 Diarrhea, or #13, Trouble getting your breath), d) physical symptoms (first 13 items of SCL18), f) cognitive symptoms (last 5 items of SCL18). Each item is rated as (0) not at all, (1) a little bit (2) moderately, (3) quite a bit, or (4) extremely</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient's Global Impression of Change</measure>
    <time_frame>There is no rating at baseline. Outcome is for the 30th (last) day of treatment, or if discontinues treatment early, last observation carried forward</time_frame>
    <description>Proportions rating Patient's Global Impression of Change: as 1-4; as 1-3; as 1-2; as 6 (answer set: 1, very much improved, 2/much improved, 3/moderately improved, 4/minimally improved, 5/about the same, 6/worse)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>30th (last) day of treatment, or if discontinues treatment early, last observation carried forward</time_frame>
    <description>Proportions of patients reporting new or worsening symptoms: a) any adverse event; b) the expected adverse events for famotidine (headache, dizziness, constipation, diarrhea); c) other adverse events, grouped by type</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Day-60 Follow-up</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days after the start of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Each of the same endpoints as above but evaluated 30 days after the end of treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>famotidine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A 20-milligram tablet of Pepcid in the morning and evening the first day, to be increased thereafter to one tablet every 8 hours if not improving</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>A placebo tablet to match a 20-milligram (mg) tablet of Pepcid in the morning and evening the first day, to be increased thereafter to one tablet every 8 hours if not improving</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Famotidine 20 milligram tablet</intervention_name>
    <description>1 tablet every 12 hours and increase to 1 tablet every 8 hours if not improved by the second day of treatment</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>famotidine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Pepcid</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. - Probable COVID-19 based on presence of at least 5 of the following symptoms of acute&#xD;
             onset within the prior 4 days: fever, cough, sore throat, fatigue, episodic chest pain&#xD;
             or shortness of breath with exercise, muscle or body aches, headache, loss of smell or&#xD;
             taste, stuffy or runny nose, chills or shivering, feeling hot or feverish, nausea,&#xD;
             diarrhea&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. - Subjects must signify that they have contacted a doctor about their current&#xD;
             symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. - Subject gives informed consent for study and is willing to take the treatments and&#xD;
             complete the scheduled evaluations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. - Subject has acquired a study partner who has agreed to complete the follow-up forms&#xD;
             for the subject if the subject unable or has been hospitalized.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. - Constant rather than episodic trouble breathing, Persistent pain or pressure in the&#xD;
             chest, New confusion, Inability to wake or stay awake, Bluish lips or face, or any&#xD;
             other severe symptom [symptoms CDC urges immediate medical care for].&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. - Known sensitivity or intolerance to famotidine or another acid-blocking drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. - Lack of access to the internet at home.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. - Using tizanidine (Zanaflex® , a muscle relaxant), dasatinib (Sprycel®, a drug for&#xD;
             leukemia), cefditoren (Pivoxil®, an antibiotic), or fosamprenavir or delavirdine&#xD;
             (drugs for HIV) [Drug exclusions are per US label for Pepcid].&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. - Significant heart or kidney disease in the last 3 months according to subject's&#xD;
             primary doctor&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. - Pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. - Taking any investigational medications to treat COVID-19, famotidine, anti-viral&#xD;
             drugs or corticosteroids and not stopping them within 48 hours before starting study&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: patients are allowed to take over-the-counter agents for temporary relief of symptoms&#xD;
        such as antipyretics and analgesics (aspirin, ibuprofen etc), cough remedies,&#xD;
        anti-diarrheals, etc.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Robert E Pyke, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Pykonsult LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Robert Pyke, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>2033993490</phone>
    <email>pykonsult@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Robert Pyke, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>2033120257</phone>
    <email>robertepyke@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pykonsult headquarters</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Fairfield</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06812</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Robert Pyke, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>203-399-2390</phone>
      <email>pykonsult@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 21, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 25, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>famotidine</keyword>
  <keyword>Internet trial</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Famotidine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

