<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1840">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04732663</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00107436</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04732663</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Understanding Exertional Dyspnea and Exercise Intolerance in COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Understanding Exertional Dyspnea and Exercise Intolerance in COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alberta</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alberta</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A novel corona virus emerged in 2019 causing Corona Virus Disease 2019 (covid-19). In one&#xD;
      year more than 80 000 000 cases worldwide were documented. Some patients experience symptoms,&#xD;
      specifically shortness of breath, long after the viral infection has passed. These patients&#xD;
      are colloquially known as &quot;Covid-19 Long-Haulers&quot; and it is currently unknown why symptoms&#xD;
      remain after infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Shortness of breath and exercise intolerance may be caused by corona virus infection,&#xD;
      covid-19 therapy, and reduced physical activity. Exercise intolerance may be due to lung,&#xD;
      heart, blood vessel and muscle changes. During infection, the corona virus appears to cause&#xD;
      lung blood vessel and gas exchange surface damage. Early reports show heart dysfunction,&#xD;
      secondary to pulmonary blood vessel dysfunction or damage. Critically, no data is available&#xD;
      on lung blood vessel function or cardiac function during exercise. Moreover, no data are&#xD;
      available to link persistent symptoms to physiology parameters. To better understand symptom&#xD;
      persistence in Covid-19, we aim to measure exercise tolerance and heart and lung function in&#xD;
      covid-19 survivors and compare them to covid-19 free controls.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Purpose and Justification:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In less than one year, the novel coronavirus has infected more than 80 000 000 people&#xD;
      worldwide. Infection causes Corona Virus Disease 2019 (covid-19) and in some cases severe&#xD;
      acute respiratory syndrome. Overall risk of mortality from covid-19 is low, however, risk&#xD;
      radically increases with age and cardiovascular comorbidity.1 The long-term consequences of&#xD;
      covid-19 are not known. Already a phenotype of survivors with prolonged symptom burden has&#xD;
      presented; this phenotype is characterized by persistent respiratory (cough, sputum, dyspnea,&#xD;
      wheeze) and musculoskeletal (pain, fatigue) symptoms.2 Preliminary data from clinical&#xD;
      exercise testing conducted at the UofA pulmonary function laboratory suggests covid-19&#xD;
      survivors with prolonged symptoms have significantly reduced exercise tolerance and increased&#xD;
      exertional dyspnea.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Impaired exercise tolerance measured as peak oxygen uptake (VO2peak) is the strongest&#xD;
      independent predictor of cardiovascular and all-cause mortality.3 Our preliminary data in&#xD;
      seven persistently symptomatic covid-19 survivors (PS-CoV) 3-months post molecular&#xD;
      confirmation of infection shows a mean 30% impairment in VO2peak relative to age-, sex- and&#xD;
      body mass index matched controls. Several facets of covid-19, including treatment and&#xD;
      recovery, may contribute to the range and severity of debilitation and impairment in VO2peak&#xD;
      in PS-CoV. The purpose of this study is to investigate impairments in VO2peak, and pulmonary,&#xD;
      cardiac and peripheral factors contributing to impaired VO2peak, exercise intolerance, and&#xD;
      persistent dyspnea in PS-CoV.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Coronavirus gains cellular entry through binding angiotensin converting enzyme in the lungs,&#xD;
      making the lungs and pulmonary vasculature a logical starting point for investigation of&#xD;
      persistent symptomology.4 During active infection, pulmonary vascular dysfunction,&#xD;
      microthromboemboli, micro-angiopathy and pulmonary inflammation and/or fibrosis are&#xD;
      reported.5-9 Accompanying this is a reduction in diffusion capacity at rest, increased&#xD;
      tortuosity of pulmonary vasculature, and elevated pulmonary vascular resistance.10 One&#xD;
      mechanistic explanation is that regions downstream of micro-thromboemboli become fibrotic&#xD;
      secondary to reduced blood flow resulting in reduced diffusion capacity. Physiological&#xD;
      adaptation through intussusceptive angiogenesis results in increased tortuosity of pulmonary&#xD;
      vasculature, with a secondary consequence of increased pulmonary vascular resistance.10,11&#xD;
      However, evidence of isolated decreases in diffusion capacity in the absence of pulmonary&#xD;
      fibrosis are at odds with this theory.6,12 An alternative explanation is that pulmonary&#xD;
      vascular dysfunction precedes lesions viewed by computed tomography (CT) and changes in lung&#xD;
      volumes. Regardless of incipient damage, for ~1/3 of hospitalized covid-19 patients, the end&#xD;
      result is pulmonary fibrosis, impaired diffusion capacity (measured as the diffusion&#xD;
      limitation of carbon monoxide, DLCO), reduced forced vital capacity (FVC) and proportionately&#xD;
      reduced forced expiratory volume in one second (FEV1).13&#xD;
&#xD;
      In PS-CoV, lung impairment at 3-month follow-up is characterized by reduced resting DLCO, FVC&#xD;
      and FEV1, and incomplete normalization of pulmonary CT consolidation and opacities.13 Our&#xD;
      preliminary data in PS-CoV show increased respiratory rate and VE/VCO2 (indicative of&#xD;
      increased deadspace or excessive ventilatory drive) at peak exercise- characteristic of&#xD;
      parenchymal or restrictive lung disease and consistent with pathology of covid-19 including&#xD;
      parenchymal cell death and pulmonary fibrosis.6,12 Despite these findings, our initial data&#xD;
      suggest that PS-CoV patients' operating lung volumes during exercise and peak breathing&#xD;
      reserve are relatively preserved. Previous work in COPD has shown that an elevated VE/VCO2&#xD;
      during exercise is explained by higher deadspace, and this increased VE/VCO2 contributes to&#xD;
      increased dyspnea secondary to increased drive to breathe. Our work in COPD has shown that&#xD;
      the increase VE/VCO2 is due to hypoperfusion of the pulmonary capillaries as demonstrated by&#xD;
      a reduced DLCO and reduced pulmonary capillary blood volume during exercise, and that when&#xD;
      pulmonary perfusion is improved by using inspired NO, VE/VCO2 and dyspnea are decreased&#xD;
      resulting in an increase in VO2peak.14,15&#xD;
&#xD;
      No data are currently available examining symptoms of dyspnea, pulmonary mechanics, VE/VCO2,&#xD;
      and impaired VO2peak in PS-CoV. Moreover, no data are available examining diffusion capacity&#xD;
      or pulmonary capillary blood volume responses during exercise, which may contribute to&#xD;
      increased VE/VCO2, pulmonary inefficiency, perceived dyspnea, and secondary cardiac&#xD;
      consequences.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiac complications of covid-19 have been demonstrated and may contribute to impaired&#xD;
      VO2peak through a reduction in peak cardiac output (Qpeak).16-18 Limited data are available,&#xD;
      but, cardiac effects appear to be (mal)adaptation secondary to pulmonary vascular&#xD;
      dysfunction, angiopathy and increased pulmonary vascular resistance.7,16-18 Importantly,&#xD;
      pulmonary vascular dysfunction may impose a cardiac limitation to exercise in the absence of&#xD;
      or preceding structural cardiac changes as in early pulmonary hypertension (exercise induced&#xD;
      pulmonary hypertension).19 Complications mimic those observed in pulmonary hypertension&#xD;
      whereby the thin walled right ventricle insidiously adapts to and eventually fails against&#xD;
      chronically increased pulmonary artery pressure.20 This includes right ventricular&#xD;
      hypertrophy, dilation and hypokinesis, and in failure, uncoupling of tricuspid annular plane&#xD;
      systolic excursion (TAPSE) and pulmonary artery systolic pressure (PASP).21 In a study of 100&#xD;
      consecutive covid-19 patients at rest, 39% of patients had right ventricular dilation and&#xD;
      dysfunction and 16% of patients had left ventricular diastolic dysfunction.16 No reports of&#xD;
      cardiac function during exercise or cardiac mechanics in response to stress are available&#xD;
      following covid-19, and it is unknown whether cardiac consequences of covid-19 limit VO2peak&#xD;
      or contribute to symptom persistence in PS-CoV.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Detrimental changes in body composition occur in hospitalized covid-19 patients.22 During&#xD;
      active infection, frailty (in part characterized by muscle loss) is associated with increased&#xD;
      covid-19 severity and mortality.23,24 Reduced lean tissue mass and increased adiposity,&#xD;
      particularly in the thigh, are reported following bedrest and are known to impair VO2peak.25&#xD;
      Reductions in VO2peak are twofold: absolute VO2peak is reduced due to loss of muscle mass,&#xD;
      and relative VO2peak (ml/kg/min) is reduced due to a combination of reduced absolute VO2peak&#xD;
      and a decrease in the ratio of muscle mass to total body mass. Moreover, bedrest is&#xD;
      associated with reduced mitochondrial density and oxidative enzymatic activity.26 No data are&#xD;
      available linking increased adiposity, reduced thigh muscle, or impaired muscle quality to&#xD;
      VO2peak or symptom persistence in PS-CoV.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our preliminary data indicate VO2peak is impaired in PS-CoV survivors. The magnitude of&#xD;
      VO2peak, pulmonary, cardiac and peripheral impairment is not known in PS-CoV or symptom free&#xD;
      covid-19 survivors. Through this proposed study, we aim to comprehensively test VO2peak&#xD;
      impairment in PS-CoV survivors and link physiology to symptom persistence in covid-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are 3 objectives of this study: 1) to evaluate VO2peak in PS-CoV and recovered covid-19&#xD;
      survivors (no longer symptomatic) compared to covid-19 naïve controls matched for age, sex&#xD;
      and body mass index; 2) to evaluate DLCO and pulmonary capillary blood volume at rest and&#xD;
      during exercise in these three groups; and 3) evaluate cardiac structure and function at rest&#xD;
      and during exercise in the three groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypotheses:&#xD;
&#xD;
      We hypothesize that:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. VO2peak will be impaired in PS-CoV relative to recovered (symptom free) covid-19&#xD;
           survivors and covid naïve controls, and that recovered covid-19 survivors will have&#xD;
           impaired VO2peak relative to covid naïve controls;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Relative to covid-19 naïve controls, PS-CoV will have reduced rest and exercise&#xD;
           pulmonary capillary blood volume and diffusion capacity, which will be correlated with&#xD;
           exercise VE/VCO2.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. PS-CoV will have reduced peak cardiac output, increased PASP, and uncoupling of&#xD;
           PASP:TAPSE.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak Oxygen Uptake (VO2peak)</measure>
    <time_frame>2022</time_frame>
    <description>Staged cardiopulmonary exercise test</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak Cardiac Output (Qpeak)</measure>
    <time_frame>2022</time_frame>
    <description>Impedance cardiography derived Qpeak from staged CPET</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pulmonary Capillary Blood Volume (Vc)</measure>
    <time_frame>2022</time_frame>
    <description>Multiple fraction of inspired oxygen DLCO derived pulmonary capillary blood volume at rest and during exercise.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ventilatory Efficiency (VE/VCO2)</measure>
    <time_frame>2022</time_frame>
    <description>Measured from expired gas analysis during cardiopulmonary exercise testing.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dyspnea</measure>
    <time_frame>2022</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using the modified Borg scale, perceived dyspnea during cardiopulmonary exercise testing.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Membrane Diffusion Capacity (Dm)</measure>
    <time_frame>2022</time_frame>
    <description>Measured at rest and during exercise using the multiple fraction of inspired oxygen DLCO technique.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pulmonary Artery Systolic Pressure (PASP)</measure>
    <time_frame>2022</time_frame>
    <description>Echocardiography estimated pulmonary artery systolic pressure.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Right Ventricular Function</measure>
    <time_frame>2022</time_frame>
    <description>Reported as PASP:TAPSE (tricuspid annular plane systolic excursion) measured using echocardiography.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Left Ventricular Stiffness</measure>
    <time_frame>2022</time_frame>
    <description>Estimated from E/e' using echocardiography.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">225</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Dyspnea</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Persistently Symptomatic Covid-19 (PS-CoV)</arm_group_label>
    <description>PS-CoV will be defined as individuals with a history of molecular testing confirmed COVID-19 infection, recovered from acute infection but with ongoing symptoms (self-reported, pulmonary, cardiac, musculoskeletal or other symptoms) of at least 4 weeks' duration. Recovery from acute infection will be defined according to provincial health guidelines: at least 10 days' (14 in those hospitalized; 21 in those with immunocompromise) from onset of symptoms with at least 24 hours without a fever, without taking anti-pyretic medications and improvement of other symptoms.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Recovered Covid-19</arm_group_label>
    <description>Recovered Covid-19 Survivors will be defined as individuals without complaint of a persisting covid-19 symptom. Recovered Covid-19 survivors will be matched to PS-CoV for age, sex, body mass index and time post corona virus infection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <description>Covid Naïve Controls will be defined as individuals who have no known history of covid-19. Control participants will be matched to PS-CoV for age, sex and body mass index.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Cross-sectional study, no intervention.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Persistently Symptomatic Covid-19 (PS-CoV)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Recovered Covid-19</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adults with or without a history of covid-19, with or without persistent symptoms.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Covid-19/Symptom status as defined under each group.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Previous diagnosis of pulmonary hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Obesity (body mass index &gt;30 kg/m2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Absolute contraindication to exercise testing or an orthopedic limitation that may&#xD;
             interfere with cardiopulmonary exercise testing&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Michael K Stickland, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>780-492-3995</phone>
    <email>michael.stickland@ualberta.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Rhys I Beaudry, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>780-492-8027</phone>
    <email>rhys.beaudry@ualberta.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Physiology Laboratory</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edmonton</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T6G2R3</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>DLCO</keyword>
  <keyword>Pulmonary Capillary Blood Volume</keyword>
  <keyword>VO2peak</keyword>
  <keyword>Exercise Capacity</keyword>
  <keyword>Cardiac Function</keyword>
  <keyword>Impedance Cardiography</keyword>
  <keyword>Echocardiography</keyword>
  <keyword>Shortness of Breath</keyword>
  <keyword>Ventilatory Efficiency</keyword>
  <keyword>Lung Restriction</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dyspnea</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

