<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="164">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04720794</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>07A-CLI-006</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04720794</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study To Evaluate The Performance of the Lucira Health All-In-One COVID-19 Test Kit vs Hologic Panther Fusion</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Study To Evaluate The Performance of the Lucira Health All-In-One COVID-19 Test Kit As Compared To The Hologic Panther Fusion SARS-CoV-2 RT-PCR Assay</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Lucira Health Inc</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Lucira Health Inc</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This Lucira COVID-19 All-In-One Test Kit performance study will be used to establish the&#xD;
      performance of the Lucira COVID-19 All-In-One Test Kit as compared to a known high&#xD;
      sensitivity RT-PCR molecular assay. The results of this study will be used to demonstrate the&#xD;
      Lucira COVID-19 'swab to result in 30 minutes' test kit is similar in performance to known&#xD;
      high sensitivity best-in-class molecular assays performed in high complexity labs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results of this study will be combined with other studies the Sponsor has underway and&#xD;
      will support a FDA Emergency Use Authorization (EUA) of the Lucira COVID-19 All-In-One Test&#xD;
      Kit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This performance study will include nasal swabs self-collected by study subjects at&#xD;
      community-based locations with trained medical staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A subject's participation in this study will consist of one study visit and one collection&#xD;
      event. The subject self-collects a nasal swab sample according to Lucira COVID-19 Test Kit&#xD;
      instructions and runs test according to Quick Reference Instructions (QRI).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following the Lucira COVID-19 All-In-One Test Kit self-collection will be an additional swab&#xD;
      collection for reference method testing. One (1) additional NS specimen will be collected&#xD;
      either by the health care professional or self-collection, prepared in Transport Medium and&#xD;
      sent to a reference laboratory.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study is a prospective, single site study with community-based sampling in high COVID-19&#xD;
      prevalence communities in California. The Investigational device will be tested on-site and&#xD;
      the reference samples will be sent to one (1) reference laboratory in the U.S. Testing in the&#xD;
      reference laboratory will be performed by trained laboratory personnel. This study, to be&#xD;
      performed with medical staff on site, and will include nasal swabs self-collected by study&#xD;
      subjects per the QRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Community based sampling will be conducted only by trained medical study staff. Study staff&#xD;
      will bring all study materials-the Lucira investigational device as well as the reference&#xD;
      swab collection kit-to all subjects enrolled in the study. This mobile, outdoor,&#xD;
      community-based sampling method will ensure that COVID-symptomatic persons with fever do not&#xD;
      travel from their homes, thus risking exposure to others. All medical staff participating in&#xD;
      the study will be under the oversight of the study Principal Investigators and wear&#xD;
      appropriate PPE during community visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A qualified research person will be designated as the Investigator at each site, with the&#xD;
      responsibility for oversight of the study in accordance with Good Clinical Practice (GCP) and&#xD;
      regulatory requirements. The protocol and subject informed consent will be reviewed by an&#xD;
      Institutional Review Board (IRB) and written IRB approval will be issued prior to enrollment&#xD;
      of subjects into the study at that site.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A subject's participation in this study will consist of a single visit. Following completion&#xD;
      of the informed consent process and a review of Inclusion/Exclusion criteria to determine&#xD;
      eligibility, each subject will receive a unique study identification number. Subject&#xD;
      demographics including age, sex, race, and ethnicity, will also be collected at this time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All subjects will be observed during the swabbing collection by the HCP and HCP will document&#xD;
      collection details and any collection issues. The HCP will confirm the Lucira COVID-19 Test&#xD;
      Kit is running and will interpret the test results once completed. Nasal swabs obtained from&#xD;
      self-collection will be discarded after it has been used for testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following the Lucira COVID-19 Test Kit collection will be a collection for reference method&#xD;
      testing. A reference swab should not be collected until the Lucira Test Kit is running. The&#xD;
      nasal swab reference swab shall be collected in the same manner as the initial collection,&#xD;
      prepared in Transport Medium and sent to the Sutter Shared Laboratory.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate performance, all reference samples collected will be tested using EUA-cleared&#xD;
      molecular method:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Hologic Panther Fusion SARS-CoV-2 RT-PCR Assay *&#xD;
&#xD;
      Reference testing will characterize specimens as negative or positive for SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
      Therefore, sensitivity and specificity of the Lucira COVID-19 Test will be calculated by&#xD;
      comparison with the reference methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additional testing on remaining remnant aliquots may be performed to investigate any&#xD;
      discrepant and discordant results as needed, and samples may undergo additional testing by&#xD;
      other EUA-cleared molecular methods. The Roche Cobas 6800 SARS-CoV-2 assay will be used for&#xD;
      discrepant testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If subject consents to storage and future testing of samples, any extra remnants at the end&#xD;
      of the study will be returned to the Sponsor for storage.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 25, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 20, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 20, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 Prevalence Rate / Expected Values counts</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Study prevalence of SARS-CoV-2 will be summarized by counts and grouped by age</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 Prevalence Rate / Expected Values percentages</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Study prevalence of SARS-CoV-2 will be summarized by percentages and grouped by age</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Collection Performance/ Incidence Rate counts</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Study observations will be summarized by counts:&#xD;
Self-Collection, Self-tested&#xD;
User Experience</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Collection Performance/ Incidence Rate percentages</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Study observations will be summarized by percentages:&#xD;
Self-Collection, Self-tested&#xD;
User Experience</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity and specificity</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Sensitivity and specificity along with their associated 2-sided Wilson Score 95% Confidence Intervals will be estimated for SARS-CoV-2, on the Lucira COVID-19 All-In-One Test in comparison to the reference test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Invalid Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Months</time_frame>
    <description>The invalid rates, along with their associated 2-sided Wilson Score 95% Confidence Intervals will be estimated for SARS-CoV-2 on the Lucira COVID-19 All-In-One Test</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">101</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>SARS (Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome)</condition>
  <condition>Corona Virus Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Subject Self-Collection and Specimen Testing</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will be provided with the Lucira COVID-19 Test Kit and collect one (1) nasal swab according to the QRI and test the sample on the Lucira COVID-19 All-In-One Test. HCP will observe subject during this process and document any observations and deviations from the QRI.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lucira COVID-19 All-In-One test kit</intervention_name>
    <description>The Lucira COVID-19 All-In-One Test Kit is intended to detect the novel coronavirus SARS-CoV-2 that causes COVID-19 in nasal swab samples. This test is a single-use test kit that determines whether there is active shedding of the virus which causes COVID-19. This test utilizes a molecular amplification technology for the detection of SARS-CoV-2 RNA.&#xD;
Positive results are indicative of active infection with SARS-CoV-2. Persons who test positive should self-isolate and seek care from their healthcare provider.&#xD;
Negative results do not preclude SARS-CoV-2 infection. Persons who continue to experience COVID-like symptoms should seek follow up care from their healthcare provider</description>
    <arm_group_label>Subject Self-Collection and Specimen Testing</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Ages 18-75&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Must be able to read and write in English or Spanish&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Must be willing to try rapid COVID-19 test and self-collect a nasal swab sample in&#xD;
             both nostrils&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Must be one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Currently experiencing a Fever of 100﮲ Fahrenheit and above or self-reports&#xD;
                  having fever within the past 48 hours, and experiencing at least one (1)&#xD;
                  additional associated CDC COVID-19 symptom:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Cough&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Shortness of breath or difficulty breathing&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Fatigue&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Muscle or body aches&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Headache&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  New loss of taste or smell&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Sore throat&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Congestion or runny nose&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Nausea or vomiting&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Diarrhea&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previously tested positive for COVID-19 in past 14 days, and experiencing at&#xD;
                  least one (1) additional associated CDC COVID-19 symptom&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Currently experiencing at least three (3) additional associated CDC COVID-19&#xD;
                  symptoms so long as at least at least one (1) symptom is either: cough, shortness&#xD;
                  of breath, and/or new loss of taste or smell.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Currently suffering from nasal trauma such as a nosebleed&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Received a nasal rinse/wash/aspirates for standard of care testing&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Neeraj Kochhar, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Neeraj Kochhar Family Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Neeraj Kochhar Family Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Gatos</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 13, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

