<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1366">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04511949</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CREPATS 012</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04511949</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19: Epidemiological Study of the Spread of SARS-CoV-2 in the Household of a Person Who Has Had a COVID-19 Disease</brief_title>
  <acronym>FAMICOV</acronym>
  <official_title>Epidemiological Study of the Spread of SARS-CoV-2 in the Household of a Person Who Has Had a COVID-19 Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre de Recherches et d'Etude sur la Pathologie Tropicale et le Sida</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre de Recherches et d'Etude sur la Pathologie Tropicale et le Sida</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Evaluating the rate of exposure to the virus in the close contact population who shared the&#xD;
      home of a person infected with SARS-CoV-2 at the time of infection of the index case - adults&#xD;
      or children - is a major factor in assessing the spread. virus in the family environment,&#xD;
      assess the factors of circulation and determine whether immunity has been acquired. Screening&#xD;
      for specific antibodies to SARS-CoV-2 will determine the exposure and protection acquired&#xD;
      against this virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Knowing the intra-family secondary transmission rate is essential for supporting the&#xD;
      strategies for lifting the confinement envisaged and implementing a personalized approach.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As of March 8, a platform for the home management of COVID + patients was set up when they,&#xD;
      pauci or moderately symptomatic, do not require hospitalization. As of May 6, 2020, 881&#xD;
      patients have been registered in COVID and followed, constituting the active COVIDOM / PSL&#xD;
      file. Of the 512 patients included between March 1 and 31, 45% have a household consisting of&#xD;
      3 people.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients had weekly clinical follow-up by telephone for the duration of the disease with&#xD;
      a maximum of 4 weeks having been achieved.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the recommendations of barrier gestures, isolation in an apartment were made during the&#xD;
      symptomatic phase, the absence of masks available to all did not allow, in practice, to&#xD;
      achieve the isolation and quarantine recommended ideally. to break the transmission of the&#xD;
      virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The FAMI-CoV study proposes to assess the rate of exposure to the virus in contacts sharing&#xD;
      the same focus of index cases. A sub-study will assess the proportion of antibodies that have&#xD;
      been neutralizing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Transmission of the virus is possible from patients without or with very few symptoms. The&#xD;
      viral load is high from the onset of symptoms and then decreases to the limit of detection on&#xD;
      D21. The period of contagiousness would start 2.3 days before the symptoms (95% CI, 0.8-3.0&#xD;
      J) and would reach a peak at 0.7 J (95% CI, -0.2-2.0 J). This contagiousness would then&#xD;
      decrease rapidly within 7 days with an estimated proportion of pre-symptomatic transmission&#xD;
      of 44%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The IgG and IgM antibodies generated by SARS-CoV-2 can be detected 1 to 3 weeks after&#xD;
      exposure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Guo et al studied the kinetics of IgM, IgA and IgG responses by an ELISA based on the&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 core on 208 plasma from 82 confirmed cases and 58 probable cases of COVID-19. The&#xD;
      antibodies are found from the first day after the onset of symptoms. The median time to&#xD;
      detection of IgM and IgA was 5 days (IQR, 3-6), while IgG was detected 14 days (IQR, 10-18)&#xD;
      after onset of symptoms, with a positive rate of 85, 4%, 92.7% and 77.9%, respectively. In&#xD;
      confirmed and probable cases, the positive IgM antibody levels were 75.6% and 93.1%,&#xD;
      respectively. The detection efficiency by IgM ELISA is superior to that of PCR after 5.5 days&#xD;
      of onset of symptoms. The infection detection rate is increased (98.6%) by combining ELISA&#xD;
      IgM test with PCR for each patient compared to a single qPCR test (51.9%). No&#xD;
      cross-reactivity was found with common coronaviruses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Zhao et al looked for total antibodies, IgM and IgG in 173 patients (median age, 48 years)&#xD;
      with COVID-19 confirmed by PCR. The overall seroconversion rate, IgM and IgG, were 93%, 82.7%&#xD;
      and 64.7%, respectively, with a median time to seroconversion around day 12. The presence of&#xD;
      antibodies is less than 40% during the week following the onset of the disease to reach 100%&#xD;
      (Ab), 94% (IgM) and 80% (IgG) by day 15.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a study of 285 patients with COVID-19, 100% of patients developed specific antibodies&#xD;
      within an average of 19 days after the onset of symptoms. The IgG and IgM antibody plateau is&#xD;
      reached six days after seroconversion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Few data exist on the intra-family spread of the COVID 19 disease, in particular in its minor&#xD;
      or moderate form followed on an outpatient basis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A study, carried out in China, evaluated 318 clusters of at least 3 grouped cases&gt; 3 cases&#xD;
      which concerned a total of 1245 cases, occurring in 320 municipalities. The majority of cases&#xD;
      are grouped at home (80%) then in transport (26%). Most cases grouped at home concern 3 to 5&#xD;
      cases. Sharing a home appears to be a major risk of contamination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Shenzhen, the investigation of 39 COVID / PCR cases and their 1,286 contacts shows a&#xD;
      transmission rate (measured by PCR) of 111.2% [9.1 - 13.8]. Transmission rates are important&#xD;
      when contacts live in the household or have traveled with the index case.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In France, few data are still available. An epidemiological study, carried out at the end of&#xD;
      March 2020, tested 661 people in serology in connection with the high school of&#xD;
      Crépy-en-Valois (Oise) where a teacher worked, the first case of French COVID. It appears&#xD;
      that the infection attack rate was highest among secondary school staff, teachers and&#xD;
      students, and much lower among parents and siblings of students.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The suddenness of the COVID-19 epidemic, its spread, its new character have taken many health&#xD;
      care systems to fail.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the absence of effective treatment against COVID-19 to date, only preventive measures can&#xD;
      be effective.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The rapidly epidemic nature and the lack of sufficient protective equipment made it&#xD;
      impossible to have perfectly adequate protective measures, even after confinement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Likewise, in the entourage of a patient with COVID-19, the scarcity of direct diagnostic&#xD;
      tests (PCR) from February to April made it possible to diagnose only symptomatic people&#xD;
      having recourse to the hospital system or working in a system of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For an appropriate public health response, an estimate of the number of people who have&#xD;
      encountered the virus and potentially protected is fundamental.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is little data on exposure to the virus, measured by the presence of specific&#xD;
      antibodies in the family circle of an index case.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Several confinement situations in enclosed spaces (cruise ships) have led to transmission&#xD;
      rates of around 20%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The FAMI-CoV study proposes to assess the rate of exposure to the virus in contacts sharing&#xD;
      the same focus of index cases. A sub-study will assess the proportion of antibodies that have&#xD;
      been neutralizing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a cross-sectional, single-center study carried out on the cohort of index patients&#xD;
      followed on an outpatient basis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment will be done from the active file of patients included in the COVID / PSL cohort&#xD;
      or patients followed in city medicine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Screening This visit makes it possible to offer the study to each patient (INDEX case)&#xD;
      corresponding to the inclusion criteria and to their contacts living in the same household on&#xD;
      the data recorded in the clinical follow-up files.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It takes place after checking the inclusion and exclusion criteria of subjects. This visit&#xD;
      can be done over the phone. The patient information and consent form is issued to the patient&#xD;
      or his family.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion visit and serological test&#xD;
&#xD;
      This visit allows you to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. explain the objectives of the study and the test methods&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. give consent and obtain signatures&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. complete the questionnaire for index cases and contacts&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. perform a rapid test looking for anti SARS-CoV-2 antibodies, at the fingertip (sample&#xD;
           taken by a professional authorized to perform these tests)&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. reading of the result is immediate&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. the result is given and commented on to each member of the household; they will be kept.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This process is repeated for each index case and each contact case.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Performing the anti-SARS-CoV-2 rapid antibody test Choice of test The COVID-19 IgG / IgM&#xD;
      rapid test (whole blood / serum / plasma) (COVID-PRESTO manufactured by the firm AAZ) is a&#xD;
      solid phase immunochromatographic test for the rapid, qualitative and differential detection&#xD;
      of IgG and IgM antibodies directed against SARSCoV -2 which allows to affirm, in the absence&#xD;
      of symptoms, contact with the virus and an acquired immunity a prioriprotective. The test&#xD;
      uses anti human IgM antibodies (IgM test line), anti human IgG antibodies (IgG test line) and&#xD;
      rabbit IgG (control line (C)) immobilized on a nitrocellulose strip. The conjugate&#xD;
      (recombinant COVID-19 antigens labeled with colloidal gold) is also integrated into the&#xD;
      strip.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This test was evaluated by 3 laboratories (Bichat Hospital virology laboratory, Orléans&#xD;
      laboratory, CNR Lyon reference laboratory Pr B. Lina.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Practice of the test&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The rapid test is performed using a drop of blood obtained at the fingertip (10&#xD;
           microliters) using a lancet.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The dropper pipette, held vertically, collects the drop of whole blood up to the &quot;sample&#xD;
           line&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Place 1 drop of whole blood (10 μL in the sample well (S) of the cassette.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Immediately add 2 drops (80μL) of buffer to the well (B) of the cassette.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Avoid air bubbles; if there is an air bubble, add a 3rd drop of buffer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The reading is taken after 10 minutes at most by the healthcare professional under medical&#xD;
      supervision. Positivity can appear after 1 to 3 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The reading should not exceed 30 minutes. The rapid tests will be carried out either by&#xD;
      authorized personnel who practice them regularly in the context of HIV / Hepatitis screening&#xD;
      actions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In case of sepositivity of the rapid test, it may be offered to index cases and adult&#xD;
      contacts, a blood sample of 5 ml of blood for a serothèque allowing a characterization of the&#xD;
      antibodies and in particular of the neutralizing antibodies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 12, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 30, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a cross-sectional, single-center study carried out on the cohort of index patients followed on an outpatient basis</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of the proportion of contact persons who have developed anti-SARS-CoV-2 antibodies (secondary transmission rate) within the same household of a subject who had a COVID-19 disease assessed by a rapid diagnostic-oriented test</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Measure of anti-SARS-CoV-2 antibodies using COVID-PRESTO (AAZ company)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">500</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronavirus Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>No arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>COVID-19 IgG / IgM rapid test (whole blood, serum, plasma)</intervention_name>
    <description>The rapid test is performed using a drop of blood obtained at the fingertip (10 microliters) using a lancet.&#xD;
The dropper pipette, held vertically, collects the drop of whole blood up to the &quot;sample line&quot;&#xD;
Place 1 drop of whole blood (10 μL in the sample well (S) of the cassette.&#xD;
Immediately add 2 drops (80μL) of buffer to the well (B) of the cassette.&#xD;
Avoid air bubbles; if there is an air bubble, add a 3rd drop of buffer.&#xD;
The reading is taken after 10 minutes at most by the healthcare professional under medical supervision.&#xD;
In case of sepositivity of the rapid test, it may be offered to index cases and adult contacts, a blood sample of 5 ml of blood for a serothèque allowing a characterization of the antibodies and in particular of the neutralizing antibodies.</description>
    <arm_group_label>No arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Index case&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult&gt; 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having presented a SARS-CoV-2 infection confirmed by PCR (INDEX COVID / PCR +)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  or having presented clinical symptoms compatible with the diagnosis of COVID-19&#xD;
             (COVID-like) with at least 3 of the following symptoms for ⩾ 48 hours: fever, cough,&#xD;
             anosmia, ageusia, headache, diarrhea, or CT scan with pneumopathy image in frosted&#xD;
             glass&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Living at the time of symptoms with at least 2 other people in the same household&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written consent for himself and for minors for whom he is responsible&#xD;
&#xD;
        Contact case&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult (s) or child (ren), aged 3 to 17 (school age including kindergarten), living in&#xD;
             the same household as the index case at the time of the symptoms of the index case&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written consent for adults&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consent given by parents for minors&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient protected by law (patient under guardianship and guardianship, person deprived&#xD;
             of liberty)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with major cognitive disorders.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Christine KATLAMA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <state>Ile De France</state>
        <zip>75013</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 12, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

