<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4827">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04562350</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20/137-P</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04562350</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>XatJove Anoia, as a Tool to Bring Health Services Closer to Teenagers</brief_title>
  <official_title>XatJove Anoia, as a Tool to Bring Health Services Closer to Teenagers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Jordi Gol i Gurina Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut Català de la Salut</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Jordi Gol i Gurina Foundation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Programs such as &quot;Salut i Escola&quot; aim to improve the health of teenagers through actions to&#xD;
      promote health, prevent risk situations and provide early care for problems related to mental&#xD;
      health, emotional health and sexual, drug, alcohol and tobacco use, in collaboration with&#xD;
      schools and community health services present in the territory. The massive use of new&#xD;
      technologies among adolescents means that health programs have to adapt to this reality.&#xD;
      XatJove Anoia offers a secure and completely confidential chat with nursing professionals via&#xD;
      mobile without having to download any App. In the age of COVID-19, it is important to reduce&#xD;
      the risk of infection caused by contact with health services while minimizing non-essential&#xD;
      face-to-face visits.Hypothesis: The use of XatJove can increase teenagers' consultations with&#xD;
      nursing professionals at Primary Care Centers.Objectives: To demonstrate that through the use&#xD;
      of mobile phones and messaging applications, the number of health consultations in &quot;Salut i&#xD;
      Escola&quot; program of the Anoia region increases.Methodology: The study uses a mixed methodology&#xD;
      comparing the total number of visits (face-to-face and with XatJove) of the &quot;Salut i Escola&quot;&#xD;
      program in the Anoia region during the 2020-2021 academic year with the number of&#xD;
      face-to-face visits of the same program in the Osona region.Determinations: Number of total&#xD;
      consultations in the &quot;Salut i Escola&quot; program during the 2020-2021 academic year in Anoia and&#xD;
      Osona. XatJove user satisfaction survey.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Internet has become an important tool for many people with health concerns [1,2]&#xD;
      specially for adolescents [3,4]. Concerns about confidentiality, coupled with the stigma and&#xD;
      shame associated with some conditions, specially sexually transmitted infections and other&#xD;
      Health related problems make the internet a safe enviroment for adolescents to seek for&#xD;
      information. This is thought to lead to an under-utilization of traditionally providers as&#xD;
      the primary care health services.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These consultations, often made by young people, include sexual and reproductive health&#xD;
      problems [5] and mental health disorders [6]. This can be a major problem, since the&#xD;
      under-utilization of primary care services for certain topics and the search for advice on&#xD;
      the Internet that is not usually trusted can subsequently lead to health complications that&#xD;
      may require more expensive specialized medical interventions. long-term and, therefore, can&#xD;
      translate into an increase in healthcare costs [7].&#xD;
&#xD;
      School programmes as Salut i Escola, have had as an objective all these years, to provide a&#xD;
      more readily access to health care practitioners in order to improve their health related&#xD;
      problems, doubts in sexual orientation, mental Health issues, drug related consultations and&#xD;
      prevention of high-risk sexual behaviors by collaboration with educational centers and the&#xD;
      community health services present in the territory.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nowadays, with all the Advanced Technology we dispose, and because of the enormous amount of&#xD;
      unstructured online content and the importance and difficulty of determining health&#xD;
      information quality[8], it is almost obligatory to try to provide access to verified and make&#xD;
      this study a tool to engage with adolescents and rovide them with accedd to trustful&#xD;
      information.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, the Salut i Escola program together with the software of a well known company AGH&#xD;
      Health, have been tried to minimize hesitation in seeking health advice through a chat&#xD;
      application called Xatjove [9]. This is an asynchronous mobile text-based communication agent&#xD;
      that connects users with healthcare professionals. These professionals provide appropriate&#xD;
      guidance and advice to users in order to help them take Health related decisions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As an anonymous digital health intervention, XatJove has the potential to address cost&#xD;
      ineffectiveness caused by under-utilization health services in terms of shameful and&#xD;
      stigmatized disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to a pilot study on e-Consultation (then known as WebGP), some of the top ten&#xD;
      reasons for consultation of patients using this virtual tool included cystitis and problems&#xD;
      with contraception (in women) [10]. It is known that if ignored, these conditions can lead to&#xD;
      more serious, unwanted and costly complications (lack of contraception can lead to unwanted&#xD;
      pregnancies and sexually transmitted infections) [11,12]. The fact that users routinely&#xD;
      reported these problems through interventions health services such as e-Consultation is a&#xD;
      positive sign in terms of an increased use of health services for sensitive but important&#xD;
      conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the current time of the health crisis caused by the Covid-19 pandemic and to reduce the&#xD;
      risk of infection, it makes more sense than ever to try to avoid face-to-face consultations&#xD;
      of nursing professionals in institutes and also the visits of young people. to Primary Care&#xD;
      Centers (CAPs). Great care must be taken that this does not mean a reduction in consultations&#xD;
      on topics related to the health and school program. In addition, the health crisis is&#xD;
      expected to lead to an increase in the need for emotional support by young people and agile&#xD;
      tools are needed that use technologies that this sector of the population dominates and uses&#xD;
      on a regular basis [13].&#xD;
&#xD;
      A sample of students aged 12 to 16 years from middle school and high school in the sanitary&#xD;
      regions of the Anoia and Osona, province of Barcelona in the acadèmic course of 2020-2021.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A confidentiality form will be filled by every person partisipating in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The parent or guardian of every student signed an informed consent document that described&#xD;
      the purpose and procedure of the study. Students also signed separate assent forms with&#xD;
      similar information.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design Quasi-experimental design were the data collected by our coustomised close-end&#xD;
      survey, initial registration of the participants and the number of visits will be collected&#xD;
      for further data analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Place and Period of the Study Demografic region of Anoia and Osona, Barcelona. Duration of&#xD;
      the study: Academic course of 2020-2021.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 11, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 20, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Survey</measure>
    <time_frame>eigtht months</time_frame>
    <description>Anoia students survey response of 6 multiple options and will be asked to rate on a scale of 1 to 10, the satisfaction of the service provided.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">500</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A sample of students aged 12 to 16 years from middle school and high school in the sanitary region of Anoia in the course of 2020-21.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>A sample of students aged 12 to 16 years from middle school and high school in the sanitary region of Osona in the course of 2020-21.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>XatJove Anoia Aplication</intervention_name>
    <description>All students (age 12-16 years) from middle school and high school in the sanitary region of Anoia, province of Barcelona, will access a Platform ( ABH Health), where the users will enter specific registration data ( age, sex..etc), after every visit the users will be provided with a 6 multiple choice questionary and asked to punctuate in a scale from 1 to 10, the satisfaction of the service provided. Appart from this data, researchers will use a software to register specific Health-related words and classify them as Health-problems. While Osona students will attend face-to-face consultations as usual, apart from this data,Registrations will be reviewed later and specific search techniques and strategies will be coded. A qualitative review will be performed too.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All Anoia Students aged 12 to 16 years from middle school and high school&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Josep Vidal-Alaball, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>936930040</phone>
    <email>jvidal.cc.ics@gencat.cat</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Núria Carré Llopis, RN</last_name>
    <phone>938054477</phone>
    <email>ncarre.cc.ics@gencat.cat</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>SAP Anoia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Igualada</city>
        <state>Barcelona</state>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nuria Carré Llopis, RN</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 18, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 18, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Jordi Gol i Gurina Foundation</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Glòria Saüch Valmaña</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PhD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>mHealth</keyword>
  <keyword>Telehealth</keyword>
  <keyword>teenager</keyword>
  <keyword>health promotion and sexual Health</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

