<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3060">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04686721</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TS1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04686721</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Observational Study for the Evaluation of Tracheal Stenosis in COVID-19 Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>TS1</acronym>
  <official_title>A Retrospective and Prospective Observational, Multicentric, Case-control Clinical Study for the Evaluation of Tracheal Stenosis Among Patients With COVID-19 and Prolonged Intubation or Tracheostomy.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istituto Clinico Humanitas</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istituto Clinico Humanitas</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Define the actual incidence of tracheal stenosis in patients who underwent either prolonged&#xD;
      intubation or tracheostomy and to compare incidence, clinical course and outcome between&#xD;
      COVID-19 and non-COVID-19 patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The TS1 is a national observational, multicentric, case-control clinical aiming at defining&#xD;
      the actual incidence of tracheal stenosis in patients with COVID-19 that underwent prolonged&#xD;
      intubation or tracheal stenosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Information regarding anamnestic data, demographics, smoking or alcohol habits, comorbidity,&#xD;
      previous history of prolonged ventilation or tracheostomy, and data about intensive care unit&#xD;
      stay and treatment will be collected before discharging patients from hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients enrolled will perform an initial evaluation with a chest CT scan without&#xD;
      contrast-enhancing within 2 months from hospital discharge along with pulmonary function&#xD;
      test. If tracheal stenosis is detected, treatment according to currently available guidelines&#xD;
      will be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with no signs of clinical, functional and radiological evidence of tracheal stenosis&#xD;
      will perform a 3 and 6 months clinical follow-up from initial evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A chest CT scan with pulmonary function test will be administered if symptoms of tracheal&#xD;
      stenosis arise during clinical follow-up. If necessary, treatment according to currently&#xD;
      available guidelines will be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be followed-up for 8 months after hospital discharge.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 20, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>8 Months</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of tracheal stenosis following either prolonged intubation or tracheostomy in COVID-19 patients</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Observe how many subject in the population at risk will develop tracheal stenosis during follow-up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical presentation of tracheal stenosis</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Describe symptoms most commonly associated with tracheal stenosis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical course of tracheal stenosis</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Analyse the clinical evolution of tracheal stenosis during follow-up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Outcome of tracheal stenosis</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Collect data on morbidity and mortality of tracheal stenosis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Identification of demographic factor with a predictive and prognostic value for tracheal stenosis</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient's characteristic (e.g. sex, age, weight and height) will be collected during follow-up to search for any statistically significant association with risk of developing tracheal stenosis or disease-free survival</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Identification of clinical factor with a predictive and prognostic value for tracheal stenosis</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Information regarding hospitalisation (e.g. personal history of diabetes, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, previous prolonged intubation or tracheostomy) will be collected during follow-up to search for any statistically significant association with risk of developing tracheal stenosis or disease-free survival</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Identification of radiological factor with a predictive and prognostic value for tracheal stenosis</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Data collected from CT scan performed during follow-up (e.g. distance of stenosis from vocal chords, length and diameter) will be collected during follow-up to search for any statistically significant association with risk of developing tracheal stenosis or disease-free survival</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Identification of instrumental factor with a predictive and prognostic value for tracheal stenosis</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Results obtained from pulmonary function test (e.g. forced expiratory volume at one second, forced vital capacity and peak expiratory flow rate) will be collected during follow-up to search for any statistically significant association with risk of developing tracheal stenosis or disease-free survival</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare COVID-19 and non-COVID-19 patients at risk of developing tracheal stenosis</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>A control-group of patient who underwent either prolonged intubation or tracheostomy without diagnosis of COVID-19 will be used as comparison to search for any difference in primary and secondary outcome</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Tracheal Stenosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients at risk of developing tracheal stenosis after prolonged intubation or tracheostomy</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients older than 18 years of age who underwent either prolonged intubation or tracheostomy will be enrolled. A minimum of 2 months follow-up from hospital discharge is required. Patients tested negative for SARS-CoV-2 will be used as a control group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Chest CT scan + baseline spirometry</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will perform an initial evaluation at 2 months from hospital discharge using a chest CT scan without contrast-enhancing along with a pulmonary function test using spirometry. Based on results and according to current guidelines, further follow-up or intervention will be administered.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients at risk of developing tracheal stenosis after prolonged intubation or tracheostomy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This study is addressed to an adult population (&gt; 18 years of age) and will enroll subjects&#xD;
        who underwent prolonged intubation or tracheostomy. Patient data collection will be divided&#xD;
        in two cohorts:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a retrospective cohort admitted to intensive care unit (ICU) from 21/02/2020 to&#xD;
             30/11/2020&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a prospective cohort will include patients admitted to ICU from 01/12/2020&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  prolonged intubation, defined as the permanence of naso or oro- tracheal tube for more&#xD;
             than 7 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  tracheostomy, whether surgical or percutaneous&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  minimum of 2 months follow-up from hospital discharge&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positivity to SARS-CoV-2 infection confirmed using PCR on either nasal swab or&#xD;
             bronchoalveolar lavage will be not an inclusion criterion; patients tested negative&#xD;
             will be used as a control group&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pediatric patients (&lt; 18 years of age)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients without a minimum of 2 months follow-up from hospital discharge&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Umberto Cariboni, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+393385700988</phone>
    <email>umberto.cariboni@humanitas.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Valentina Giatti</last_name>
    <phone>+393336766200</phone>
    <email>valentina.giatti@humanitas.it</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Humanitas Research Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rozzano</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Cariboni</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 21, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Tracheal Stenosis</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Prolonged intubation</keyword>
  <keyword>Tracheostomy</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tracheal Stenosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Constriction, Pathologic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

