<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4854">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04737252</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PRG-0-057-19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04737252</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Development and Initial Testing of a Couple-Based Intervention to Optimize Suicide and Self-Injury Treatment: COMPASS (Connecting, Overcoming, and Moving Past Suicide and Self-Injury)</brief_title>
  <acronym>COMPASS</acronym>
  <official_title>Development and Initial Testing of a Couple-Based Intervention to Optimize Suicide and Self-Injury Treatment: COMPASS (Connecting, Overcoming, and Moving Past Suicide and Self-Injury)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>York University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ryerson University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>York University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Self-injurious thoughts and behaviors (SITBs), including suicide, thinking about suicide, and&#xD;
      self-injury without intent to die, are major public health crises, with variably effective,&#xD;
      and sometimes long and expensive, interventions. SITBs are particularly common in borderline&#xD;
      personality disorder (BPD). Moreover, people with BPD often cannot access SITB treatment,&#xD;
      drop out of them, and may lose their improvements after them. Reducing SITBs in BPD requires&#xD;
      innovative interventions that have greater impact and are faster to deliver. SITBs are&#xD;
      particularly influenced by emotion dysregulation (i.e., intense, negative emotion and&#xD;
      difficulties changing it) and intimate relationship dysfunction, but leading evidence-based&#xD;
      SITB interventions typically focus on the former, while neglecting the latter. For other&#xD;
      mental health problems, couple treatments result in comparable or better individual outcomes&#xD;
      relative to individually-delivered treatments, with added benefits of enhanced intimate&#xD;
      relationship functioning. SITB treatment outcomes in BPD could likely be expedited and&#xD;
      optimized with a couple intervention that targets emotion dysregulation in a relational&#xD;
      context and intimate relationship dysfunction. This project aims to develop, refine, and test&#xD;
      a brief SITB intervention delivered conjointly to individuals with BPD and SITBs (i.e.,&#xD;
      &quot;patients&quot;) and their intimate partners (i.e., &quot;partners&quot;)- COMPASS (Connecting, Overcoming,&#xD;
      and Moving Past Suicide and Self- injury)- that targets both emotion dysregulation and&#xD;
      intimate relationship dysfunction to reduce SITBs and BPD symptoms in the short- and&#xD;
      long-term. Prior to formal testing in an uncontrolled trial, it is important to solicit&#xD;
      preliminary data regarding the clarity, accessibility, safety, tolerability, and efficacy of&#xD;
      COMPASS. This project involves 3 Phases: translating COMPASS outlines into a manual (Phase&#xD;
      1); refining COMPASS (Phase 2); and an uncontrolled pilot trial of COMPASS (Phase 3). In&#xD;
      Phase 1, the three stages of COMPASS will be manualized to focus on (1) developing a conjoint&#xD;
      safety plan to reduce SITB risk, (2) reducing emotion dysregulation and intimate relationship&#xD;
      dysfunction, and (3) changing patterns that maintain SITBs. In Phase 2, COMPASS will be&#xD;
      delivered to 5-10 patients with BPD and SITBs and their partners (i.e., 5-10 couples) who&#xD;
      will provide feedback about whether COMPASS is clear, helpful, and useable. This feedback&#xD;
      will be used to refine the COMPASS manual. In Phase 3, the investigators will test whether&#xD;
      COMPASS is safe, initially efficacious, and feasible by administering it to 15-20 patients&#xD;
      with BPD and SITB and their partners (i.e., 15-20 couples). The investigators will examine&#xD;
      whether COMPASS results in changes in SITBs and BPD symptoms in patients with BPD and SITBs,&#xD;
      and SITB risk factors (e.g., emotion dysregulation and intimate relationship dysfunction) in&#xD;
      both patients and partners. These outcomes will be measured multiple times per day during&#xD;
      treatment using participant's smartphones (i.e., ecological momentary assessment), and&#xD;
      interviews/questionnaires administered at the beginning, middle, end, and at 3 months after&#xD;
      the intervention. The investigators predict that COMPASS will reduce SITBs and BPD symptoms&#xD;
      in the patient with BPD and SITBs and improve emotion dysregulation and intimate relationship&#xD;
      dysfunction in both patients with BPD and SITBs and their partners. This study offers a novel&#xD;
      SITB and BPD treatment that directly targets SITBs, BPD symptoms, and the factors that drive&#xD;
      them. Its short duration broadens the accessibility of BPD and SITB interventions with the&#xD;
      potential to contribute to reducing SITBs and BPD symptoms on a large scale. During this&#xD;
      period of social distancing due to COVID-19, COMPASS will be delivered remotely via secure&#xD;
      videoconferencing (Zoom Healthcare). As social distancing restrictions lift, COMPASS will be&#xD;
      delivered in the laboratory.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 18, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Uncontrolled pilot trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in the frequency and intensity of self-injury thoughts and behaviours from baseline will be examined through ecological momentary assessment.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered daily (three times per day) for five weeks throughout the intervention; from baseline to post intervention</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in frequency of self-injury thoughts and behaviours from baseline, as measured by the Suicide Attempt Self-Injury Interview-modified.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in severity of suicidal ideation from baseline, as measured by the Beck Scale for Suicidal Ideation.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
    <description>The Beck Scale for Suicidal Ideation has a minimum possible score of 0, and maximum possible score of 38, wherein higher scores reflect more severe suicidal ideation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Borderline Personality Symptom severity from baseline, as measured by the Borderline Symptom List-23.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
    <description>The Borderline Symptom List-23 has a minimum possible score of 0, and maximum possible score of 92, wherein higher scores reflect more severe borderline personality disorder symptoms.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in severity of depression from baseline, as measured by the Patient Health Questionnaire-9.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
    <description>The Patient Health Questionnaire-9 has a minimum possible score of 0 and a maximum possible score of 27, wherein higher scores reflect higher severity of depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes is emotion dysregulation from baseline, as measured by The Difficulties in Emotion Regulation Scale (DERS).</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
    <description>The Difficulties in Emotion Regulation scale has a minimum possible score of 36, and maximum possible score of 180, wherein higher scores reflect greater emotion dysregulation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in one's report of their partner's emotion dysregulation from baseline, as measured by the Difficulties in Emotion Regulation Scale - Partner Version (DERS-Partner).</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
    <description>The Difficulties in Emotion Regulation Scale - Partner has a minimum possible score of 8, and maximum possible score of 40, wherein higher scores reflect more severe emotion dysregulation reported of one's partner.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in relationship satisfaction from baseline, as measured by mean change from baseline on the Couples Satisfaction Index.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
    <description>The Couples Satisfaction Index has a minimum possible score of 0, and a maximum possible score of 161, wherein higher scores reflect higher levels of relationship satisfaction.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in participants psychiatric and medical treatments (e.g., medication, day treatment programs) from baseline, measured by The Mental Health Utilization Interview-Modified.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention) and immediately after the intervention.</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in severity of conflict from baseline, as measured by the Ineffective Arguing Inventory.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
    <description>The Ineffective Arguing Inventory has a minimum possible score of 8, and a maximum possible score of 40, wherein higher scores indicate decreased satisfaction with the style of arguing in a relationship.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in severity of Anxiety from baseline, as measured by Generalized Anxiety Disorder-7.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
    <description>The Generalized Anxiety Disorder-7 has a minimum possible score of 0 and maximum possible score of 21, wherein higher scores reflect more severe levels of anxiety.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Posttraumatic Stress Disorder severity from baseline, as measured by the Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 5th Edition (DSM-5).</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
    <description>The Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder Checklist for Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 5th Edition (DSM-5) has a minimum possible score of 0 and a maximum possible score of 80, wherein higher scores reflect more severe posttraumatic stress disorder symptomatology.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in one's report of their partner's Borderline Personality Symptoms severity from baseline, as measured by the Borderline Symptom List-23 - Partner Report.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in suicidal ideation severity from baseline, as measured by the Suicide Behaviours Questionnaire-Revised.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
    <description>The Suicide Behaviours Questionnaire-Revised has a minimum possible score of 3, and a maximum possible score of 18, wherein higher scores indicate more severe suicidal ideation.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in one's report of their partner's suicidal ideation from baseline, as measured by the suicide Behaviours Questionnaire-Revised - Partner Report.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
    <description>The Suicide Behaviours Questionnaire-Revised - Partner Report has a minimum possible score of 3, and a maximum possible score of 18, wherein higher scores indicate more severe suicidal ideation reported of their partner.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in emotional reactivity from baseline, as measured by the Emotional Reactivity.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
    <description>The Emotional Reactivity Scale has a minimum possible score of 0, and a maximum possible score of 84, wherein higher scores reflect greater emotional reactivity.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in affect from baseline, as measured by the Positive and Negative Affect Schedule-Modified.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in addiction severity from baseline, as measured by the Addiction Severity Index.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in Work, Health, and Life Quality from baseline, as measured by 3 one-item self-report measurements that assess work functioning, perceived health status, and overall quality of life.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in shame from baseline, as measured by the Experience of Shame Scale.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
    <description>The Experience of Shame Scale has a minimum possible score of 25, and a maximum possible score of 100, wherein higher scores reflect higher levels of shame.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of Emergency Department Visits and Hospitalizations with change measured as mean change from baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only at baseline (pre-intervention), half-way through intervention, immediately after the intervention, and three months after the intervention (Phase 3 only).</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Client satisfaction with the intervention as measured by the Client Satisfaction Questionnaire.</measure>
    <time_frame>It will be administered only immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The Client Satisfaction Questionnaire has a minimum possible score of 8, and a maximum possible score of 32, wherein higher scores reflect greater satisfaction with the intervention.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Self-injurious Thoughts and Behaviours</condition>
  <condition>Borderline Personality Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COMPASS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Immediately receives 8-12 sessions of couple intervention aimed to improve self-injury thoughts and behaviours, emotion dysregulation, borderline personality disorder symptoms, and intimate relationship dysfunction.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Connecting, Overcoming and Moving Past Suicide and Self-Injury</intervention_name>
    <description>COMPASS is a remote 8-12 session intervention for couples wherein one individual has Borderline Personality Disorder (BPD) and engages in self-injury thoughts and behaviours. The intervention consists of elements of Cognitive Behavioural Conjoint Therapy (CBCT) and has been adapted for this population. Couples will meet remotely with a clinician (registered psychologists and/or graduate level clinicians) for 8-12 sessions via Zoom Healthcare. The primary outcomes are self-injury thoughts and behaviours (as measured by the Suicide Attempt and Self-Injury Interview-modified, and the Beck Scale for Suicidal Ideation and ecological momentary assessment) and borderline personality disorder symptoms (as measured by the Borderline Symptom List-23).</description>
    <arm_group_label>COMPASS</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients have either engaged in 2+ suicidal or non-suicidal self-injurious behaviors&#xD;
             in the past two weeks (i.e., chronic and recent SITBs, consistent with previous&#xD;
             research evaluating non-suicidal self-injury (Kranzler et al., 2018)), or have severe&#xD;
             suicidal ideation as indicated by a score ≥15 on the Beck Scale for Suicidal Ideation&#xD;
             (Beck, 1991)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients also meet diagnostic criteria for BPD&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients are between the ages of 18 and 70 years-old&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients have a romantic partner who is between the ages of 18 and 70 years-old&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient's romantic partner is willing to participate in the study with them&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Past-year severe intimate aggression in their relationship such that participants who&#xD;
             endorse any severe physical and/or sexual assault behaviors in the past year will be&#xD;
             excluded from the study (Monson et al., 2012; Abramowitz et al., 2013), as assessed by&#xD;
             the Revised Conflict Tactics Scale, Severe Items Subscale (CTS-2; Straus, Hamby,&#xD;
             Boney-McCoy, &amp; Sugarman, 1996)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Either partner has a severe substance use disorder that would interfere with the&#xD;
             capacity to attend and participate in this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Either partner has clinically significant psychotic symptoms or bipolar I disorder&#xD;
             (e.g., McMain et al., 2018; McMain et al., 2009)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Either partner has a major cognitive or intellectual impairment that would prevent the&#xD;
             individual's ability to attend intervention and participate in the research study&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Either partner has illiteracy in English language&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Either partner is unable or unwilling to download and use a mobile application on&#xD;
             their smart phone to complete daily Ecological Momentary Assessment (EMA) measures&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. If partners meet inclusion criterion #1, or #2, or meet the self-harm/suicidal&#xD;
             behaviour diagnostic criterion for BPD.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. If either partner of the couple is unwilling to have assessments and sessions audio or&#xD;
             videorecorded&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. If either partner is currently not residing in Ontario&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr. Skye Fitzpatrick, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>York University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Dr. Skye Fitzpatrick, PhD</last_name>
    <email>skyefitz@yorku.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sonya Varma, BSc</last_name>
    <email>svarma@yorku.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>York University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M3J 1P3</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dr. Skye Fitzpatrick, PhD</last_name>
      <email>skyefitz@yorku.ca</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fitzpatrick S, Wagner AC, Monson CM. Optimizing borderline personality disorder treatment by incorporating significant others: A review and synthesis. Personal Disord. 2019 Jul;10(4):297-308. doi: 10.1037/per0000328. Epub 2019 Feb 4.</citation>
    <PMID>30714800</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fitzpatrick S, Liebman R, Candice MM. The borderline interpersonal-affective systems (BIAS) model: Extending understanding of the interpersonal context of borderline personality disorder. Clinical Psychology Review. In press.</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>York University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Skye Fitzpatrick</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Self-injury Thoughts and Behaviours</keyword>
  <keyword>Suicide</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-suicidal Self-injury</keyword>
  <keyword>Couple Intervention</keyword>
  <keyword>Emotion Dysregulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Intimate Relationship Dysfunction</keyword>
  <keyword>Borderline Personality Disorder</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Suicide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Personality Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Borderline Personality Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Self-Injurious Behavior</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

