<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4197">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04635618</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20200213_Treatment</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04635618</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Psychotherapy Strategies for the Treatment of Professionals and Students From Essential Services With High Levels of Emotional Distress in the Context of COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pragmatic Superiority Randomized Controlled Trial Comparing Brief Cognitive Behavioral Telepsychotherapy, Brief Interpersonal Telepsychotherapy and Telepsychoeducation for the Reduction of Emotional Distress During COVID-19 Outbreak in Professionals and Students From Essential Services With a High Level of Emotional Distress in Brazil in the Context of COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital de Clinicas de Porto Alegre</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital de Clinicas de Porto Alegre</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study consists in a pragmatic superiority randomized controlled trial comparing different&#xD;
      strategies of psychotherapy for professionals and students from essential services with high&#xD;
      levels of emotional distress during the COVID-19 pandemic in Brazil. Therapeutic strategies&#xD;
      to be evaluated are Brief Cognitive Behavioral Telepsychotherapy, Brief Interpersonal&#xD;
      Telepsychotherapy and Telepsychoeducation, as an active control.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Note: This study was approved by the Ethics and Research Committee of the Hospital de&#xD;
      Clínicas de Porto Alegre and is originally registered at Plataforma Brasil, a Brazilian study&#xD;
      registration platform (under CAAE: 30608420.5.0000.5327). Recruitment began in May 28th 2020.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRAGMATIC TREATMENT TRIAL&#xD;
&#xD;
      TITLE: &quot;A pragmatic superiority randomized controlled trial comparing Brief Cognitive&#xD;
      Behavioral Telepsychotherapy, Brief Interpersonal Telepsychotherapy and Telepsychoeducation&#xD;
      for the reduction of emotional distress during COVID-19 outbreak in professionals and&#xD;
      students from essential services with a high level of emotional distress in Brazil&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IMPORTANCE: COVID-19 outbreak is associated with increased emotional distress (depression,&#xD;
      anxiety, and irritability) all over the world. Currently, there are no large randomized&#xD;
      trials testing interventions to reduce the burden caused by mental disorders during a&#xD;
      pandemic outbreak of these proportions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OBJECTIVE: To test the effectiveness of two modalities of Brief-Telepsychotherapy (Cognitive&#xD;
      Behavioral and Interpersonal) to the reduction of symptoms of emotional distress (anxiety,&#xD;
      depression, and irritability) in professionals and students from essential services with a&#xD;
      high level of those symptoms in Brazil during the COVID-19 outbreak.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DESIGN, SETTING, AND PARTICIPANTS Thee-arm randomized clinical trial. Participants were&#xD;
      recruited in Brazil from the national service of telehealth provided by the ministry of&#xD;
      health. Participants included professional and students from essential services suffering&#xD;
      from high levels of anxiety, depression, and irritability symptoms during the COVID-19&#xD;
      outbreak. High levels of symptoms were defined by either of the following: (1) T score higher&#xD;
      than 70 on the PROMIS Anxiety Scale; (2) T score higher than 70 on the PROMIS Depression&#xD;
      Scale; (3) T score higher than 70 on the PROMIS Anger Scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      INTERVENTIONS: All participants will be randomized 1:1:1: to the Cognitive Behavioral&#xD;
      Brief-Telepsychotherapy group (B-CBT, four sessions), Brief Interpersonal Telepsychotherapy&#xD;
      (B-IPT, four sessions) or Telepsychoeducation group (a single session psychoeducation group&#xD;
      plus weekly personalized pre-recorded videos for 4 weeks).&#xD;
&#xD;
      MAIN OUTCOMES AND MEASURES: The primary outcome will be the proportion of participants with a&#xD;
      50% reduction in T-scores in all the scales that were scored above 70 at baseline at 1-month.&#xD;
      Secondary outcomes (1) the same measure of the primary outcome but measured at 3-month and&#xD;
      6-months follow-up; (2) mean score change in individual scales, quality of life and remission&#xD;
      levels (proportion of patients with T-score of 50 or below in all of the four emotional&#xD;
      distress subscales); (3) the same measure of the primary outcome but measured at midpoint&#xD;
      (after the second session or 2-weeks); and (4) service satisfaction and net-promoter score at&#xD;
      the end of the treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPECTED RESULTS: To detect a 15% group difference between each group, an alpha of 0.017 (3&#xD;
      comparisons, 0,05/3), power of 90%, and 20% loss to follow up, we would need a total of 333&#xD;
      participants per group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 5, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 20, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 13, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Three-arm randomized clinical trial , including professionals and students from essential services suffering from high levels of anxiety, depression, and irritability symptoms during the COVID-19 outbreak randomized 1:1:1: to the Cognitive Behavioral Brief-Telepsychotherapy group (B-CBT, four sessions), Brief Interpersonal Telepsychotherapy (B-IPT, four sessions) or Telepsychoeducation group (a single session psychoeducation group plus weekly personalized pre-recorded videos for 4 weeks).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom Reduction at 1-month</measure>
    <time_frame>1-month</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants with a 50% reduction in T-scores at 1-month in the scales Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS) of Depression, Anxiety and Anger that were scored above 70 at baseline.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom Reduction at 3 and 6-months follow-up</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6-month</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants with a 50% reduction in T-scores at 3 and 6-months follow-up in the scales Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS) of Depression, Anxiety and Anger that were scored above 70 at baseline measured</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Remission Levels in distress scales</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 3 and 6-months</time_frame>
    <description>Remission levels (proportion of patients with T-score of 50 or below) in distress scales (PROMIS of Depression, Anxiety and Anger)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Service Satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>1-month</time_frame>
    <description>Service satisfaction measured by the net-promoter score at the end of the treatment (proportion of promoters - scores of 9 or 10)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Improvement in Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 3 and 6-months</time_frame>
    <description>Mean score change in quality of life scale (PROMIS General Life Satisfaction Scale or GLSS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">999</enrollment>
  <condition>Mental Disorder</condition>
  <condition>COVID</condition>
  <condition>Emotional Distress</condition>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <condition>Irritable Mood</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention I: Cognitive Behavioral Brief-Telepsychotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Four sessions of cognitive-behavioral therapy (CBT) conducted through a video call by a psychologist, accompanied by sending videos of 2 to 3 minutes with psychoeducational content and content related to CBT technique.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention II: Brief Interpersonal Telepsychotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Four sessions of interpersonal therapy (IPT) conducted by video call by a psychologist, accompanied by the sending of 2 to 3 minute videos with psychoeducational content and content related to the ITP technique.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active Comparator: Telepsychoeducation group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>One single session of psychoeducation conducted through a video call by a psychologist, accompanied by sending videos of 2 to 3 minutes with psychoeducational content for 4 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cognitive Behavioral Brief-Telepsychotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Four sections of Cognitive Behavioral Brief-Telepsychotherapy plus personalized pre-recorded videos</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention I: Cognitive Behavioral Brief-Telepsychotherapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Brief Interpersonal Telepsychotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Four sections of Brief Interpersonal Telepsychotherapy plus personalized pre-recorded videos</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention II: Brief Interpersonal Telepsychotherapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Telepsychoeducation</intervention_name>
    <description>A single session psychoeducation group plus weekly personalized pre-recorded videos for 4 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active Comparator: Telepsychoeducation group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Professionals and students from essential services suffering from high levels of emotional&#xD;
        distress&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  T score higher than 70 on the PROMIS Anxiety Scale&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  T score higher than 70 on the PROMIS Depression Scale&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  T score higher than 70 on the PROMIS Anger Scale&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate to severe suicide risk assessed by a psychiatrist&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Giovanni Salum, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hospital de Clínicas de Porto Alegre, Porto Alegre/Brazil</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital de Clínicas de Porto Alegre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Porto Alegre</city>
        <state>Rio Grande Do Sul</state>
        <zip>90035-903</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 19, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hospital de Clinicas de Porto Alegre</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Giovanni Abrahao Salum Junior</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Plan to share study protocol, SAP, ICF, CRS, analytic code and individual-based variables.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Avaliable six months after study completion (antecipated - January 2022)</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Researchers and civil society</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

