<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3970">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04726163</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>8078</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04726163</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Tele-expertise in Patients With Diabetes Hospitalized for Covid-19 Infection</brief_title>
  <acronym>COVIDEX</acronym>
  <official_title>Tele-expertise for Glycemic Control Monitoring in Patients With Diabetes Hospitalized for Covid-19 Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Strasbourg, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Strasbourg, France</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Diabetes is a major factor of morbi-mortality in Covid-19 infection. Currently, steroid&#xD;
      therapy is required in patients under oxygen therapy. This treatment is associated with hyper&#xD;
      glycaemia in patients with diabetes. Recommendations for the management of diabetes during&#xD;
      Covid-19 infection is to use insulin treatment. The majority of units involves in the&#xD;
      management of patient with Covid19 infection are not the experience in managing intensive&#xD;
      insulin therapy and the time to ensure this follow-up. All the data in the literature are in&#xD;
      favor of a positive impact of telemedicine on the metabolic control of diabetic patients.&#xD;
      However, the routine use of telemedicine and more particularly tele-expertise within hospital&#xD;
      units is very underdeveloped in France. The epidemic of Covid-19 represents a unique&#xD;
      situation where the health authorities recommend to physicians to use telemedicine to ensure&#xD;
      the follow-up and optimal management of patients. The aim of this study was to compare the&#xD;
      metabolic control of diabetic patients infected with Covid-19 followed in tele-expertise to a&#xD;
      group of diabetic patients infected with Covid-19 managed in standard conditions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study will take place in the infectious diseases department of the University Hospitals&#xD;
      of Strasbourg. All diabetic patients or patients with corticosteroid-induced diabetes&#xD;
      hospitalized for Covid-19 infection and requiring corticosteroid therapy (Dexamethasone 6mg /&#xD;
      day IV for 10 days or Solupred 40mg / day per os) can be recruited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects meeting the eligibility criteria will be informed of the research orally and by the&#xD;
      delivery of a written information notice from the start of their hospitalization in the&#xD;
      department:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The allocation of the study group will be made according to the patient's hospitalization&#xD;
      unit in the infectious disease department, unit 1 will benefit from tele-expertise (TE group)&#xD;
      and patients in unit 2 will belong to the standard group (group S). Unit 1 and Unit 2 of the&#xD;
      infectious disease department take care of patients in the same way..&#xD;
&#xD;
      The TE group consists of patients treated from the start of steroid therapy with a basal /&#xD;
      bolus insulin regimen at a dose of 0.5U / kg / day: 50% in basal insulin Abasaglar and 50% in&#xD;
      rapid insulin Humalog divided into three prandial injections with adaptation of insulin doses&#xD;
      on the basis of the MCG. The use of the MCG with a collection of 90 glycemia / day allows the&#xD;
      establishment of an intensive insulin treatment in complete safety because of the access to&#xD;
      postprandial glycemia for the adaptation of rapid insulin and glycemia nocturnal for&#xD;
      adaptation of basal insulin. The implementation of a basal bolus insulin therapy in a&#xD;
      non-diabetes unit is made possible by continuous glucose measurement. Freestyle libre will&#xD;
      therefore be implemented as soon as the insulin treatment is carried out. The Freestyle libre&#xD;
      continuous glucose measurement sensor provides access to 90 interstitial glucose measurements&#xD;
      / day and the establishment of continuous glucose measurement curves sent by secure computer&#xD;
      every 48 hours for diabetes advice and dose adjustment insulin It is suggested for the study&#xD;
      to carry out at least 8 glucose measurements / day per Free style Libre scanner. Therefore,&#xD;
      there will be no achievement of capillary blood glucose in the TE group&#xD;
&#xD;
      The standard group (S) consists of patients for whom diabetes management is carried out&#xD;
      according to the habits of the infectious disease department. This standard care includes the&#xD;
      initiation of insulin therapy (one to several injections of insulin per day) in a context of&#xD;
      hyperglycemia according to the habits of the department. The adjustment of the insulin doses&#xD;
      in the S group will be carried out on the basis of at least 3 capillary blood glucose tests&#xD;
      per day carried out before each meal. Group S will benefit from the fitting of a Freestyle&#xD;
      Libre Pro, that is to say a continuous glucose sensor fitted throughout the hospital stay.&#xD;
      The Freestyle Libre Pro, does not provide access to real-time interstitial glucose readings&#xD;
      but has the option once removed to be able to analyze all 90 interstitial glucose readings.&#xD;
      Its interest is to avoid interfering with the standard diabetes management of the infectious&#xD;
      disease department.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 29, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 14, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 14, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of time spent in the range 70-180 mg / dl (TIR)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of hospitalization (maximum day 14)</time_frame>
    <description>measured every day in the group followed by tele-expertise compared with group under standard care (comparison of the daily evolution of the TIR in both groups).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of hospitalization (maximum day 14)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intensive Care Unit Transfers</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of hospitalization (maximum day 14)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiovascular and infectious complications</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of hospitalization (maximum day 14)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acute metabolic complications: keto acidosis, severe hypoglycaemia</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of hospitalization (maximum day 14)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of hospitalization and treatments administered</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of hospitalization (maximum day 14)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of hospitalization (maximum day 14)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent above glycaemia &gt; 180mg/dl</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of hospitalization (maximum day 14)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent bellow glycaemia &lt; 70mg/dl</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of hospitalization (maximum day 14)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetic Patient (Type 1,2, MODY, Secondary) or With Corticosteroid-induced Diabetes Following Initiation of Corticosteroid Treatment</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Tele-expertise</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Basal-bolus insulin treatment with adaptation of insulin doses according to continuous glucose measurement</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard treatment and adaptation of insulin doses according to the usual management of the unit</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Continuous blind glucose measurement device (Free style Pro)</intervention_name>
    <description>A continuous blind glucose measurement device (Free style Pro) will be set up on the first day and throughout the entire hospital stay</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient adult hospitalized for Covid-19 infection in the Infectious Diseases&#xD;
             Department of the University Hospital of Strasbourg (HUS)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient requiring steroid treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diabetic patient (type 1,2, MODY, secondary) or with corticosteroid-induced diabetes&#xD;
             following initiation of corticosteroid treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to the use of the Free-Style Medical Device&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hopitaux Universitaires de Strasbourg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Strasbourg</city>
        <zip>67091</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Laurence KESSLER, Pr</last_name>
      <phone>03.88.11.62.67</phone>
      <email>laurence.kessler@chru-strasbourg.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Laurence KESSLER, Pr</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Covid-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Telemedecine</keyword>
  <keyword>Continuous glucose monitoring</keyword>
  <keyword>Steroid therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

