<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4956">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04480255</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STU00212196</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04480255</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>NICU2HOME+: Supporting Illinois Families</brief_title>
  <official_title>NICU2HOME+: Supporting Illinois Families of Premature Infants With Smartphone Technology</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Craig Garfield</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Blue Cross Blue Shield</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Northwestern University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this project is to provide a stepwise, methodical approach to developing and&#xD;
      testing the ability of NICU2HOME+ to support diverse Illinois families of premature infants&#xD;
      during and after their NICU stays in an effort to address health equity, improve parenting,&#xD;
      and reduce costs. There are 3 objectives of the study: 1) Identify and assess the&#xD;
      requirements for expansion of NICU2HOME+, a suite of mobile patient education and engagement&#xD;
      applications with EMR integration that is culturally appropriate and customized to the needs&#xD;
      of a diverse population of patients and families to 3 additional level III Illinois NICUS; 2)&#xD;
      develop and deploy NICU2HOME+ to these 3 additional NICUs; and 3)determine if it is effective&#xD;
      in: a) addressing health equity issues, b) improving parenting self-efficacy and&#xD;
      satisfaction, and c) improving NICU outcomes such as a reduced length of stay and lower&#xD;
      readmission rates that result in lower healthcare costs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All research recruitment and participation will take place in the following spaces:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Northwestern Medicine's Central Dupage Hospital (25 N.Winfield Rd., Winfield, IL)- NICU,&#xD;
           Postpartum, and Research Offices&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Northwest Community Hospital (800 W. Central Rd., Arlington Heights, IL)-&#xD;
           NICU,Postpartum, and Research Offices&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Rush University Medical Center (Chicago, IL)- NICU, Postpartum, and Research Offices&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigators propose to address the goals of the Affordability Cures Initiative and&#xD;
      promote health equity by developing NICU2HOME+, a smartphone app designed to support NICU&#xD;
      parents in a culturally appropriate manner in community level III NICUs in Illinois and to&#xD;
      include EMR integration. Mobile technology such as NICU2HOME+ offers an innovative way to&#xD;
      reduce costs in two ways. First, parents who are better informed and supported, who feel more&#xD;
      confident and competent in caring for their premature infants, may be more prepared for an&#xD;
      earlier discharge. Second, cost savings may be realized after discharge, if better educated&#xD;
      and more competent parents are less likely to inappropriately visit the ER or their infant's&#xD;
      physicians as they know what to expect and can provide better, more competent care to their&#xD;
      baby. At its center, NICU2HOME+is able to achieve four &quot;rights&quot; of adaptive personalization&#xD;
      and parent-centric care: delivering the &quot;right&quot; information at the &quot;right&quot; time to the&#xD;
      &quot;right&quot; person via the &quot;right&quot; medium. The ultimate goal of this proposal, therefore, is to&#xD;
      develop a scalable, evidence-based.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be divided into two research groups based on when their infant was born.&#xD;
      The first group, parents of infants born between June 15th and December 31st 2020, will&#xD;
      receive the standard care provided in the NICU. The second group of participants, those with&#xD;
      infants born between January 1 and July 31 2021, will also receive the NICU standard care and&#xD;
      additionally be asked to use a smartphone app related to NICU and at-home care. Participation&#xD;
      in the second groups requires ownership of a smartphone and the ability to use a smartphone&#xD;
      app.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the participant has been assigned to the first group, the investigators would like both&#xD;
      parents to participate in the study independently and therefore complete individual consent&#xD;
      forms. However, the investigators recognize not all families will have two parents that are&#xD;
      interested or able to participate and ultimately participation from some families will&#xD;
      include only one parent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As part of the study, participants will be asked to complete four surveys. They will be&#xD;
      administered at the time of admission, infant's discharge from the NICU, fourteen days after&#xD;
      discharge and thirty days after discharge. For those families who have a longer stay in the&#xD;
      NICU, the investigators will ask parents to complete two additional surveys; one 30 days&#xD;
      after admission and one 60 days after admission.Each survey will take approximately five to&#xD;
      ten minutes to complete. The main benefit of participation is that this research that may&#xD;
      help improve the NICU experience for other families in the future. The primary risk of&#xD;
      participation is the potential loss of confidentiality, but strict measures are in place to&#xD;
      minimize the chance of this happening.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, if participants agree to the option at the end of this Consent Form,&#xD;
      participants may or may not be invited to participate in a separate research interview to&#xD;
      take place during the participants NICU stay, around the time of the infant's discharge from&#xD;
      the hospital, or within a year of the transition to home. These optional, voluntary&#xD;
      interviews will be conducted at a time, location and method (phone or in-person) agreed upon&#xD;
      by the parent. All interviews will be conducted with our research staff with experience&#xD;
      interviewing parents of NICU graduates. While the investigators encourage both parents to&#xD;
      participate in order to hear about differences in experiences, one or both parents can&#xD;
      ultimately participate. The purpose of the research interview is to better understand&#xD;
      participants' experience in the NICU and at home as the parent of a premature infant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be divided into two research groups based on when their infant was born.&#xD;
      The first group, parents of infants born between July 15th and December 31st 2020, will&#xD;
      receive the standard care provided in the NICU. The second group of participants, those with&#xD;
      infants born between January 1 and July 31 2021, will also receive the NICU standard care and&#xD;
      additionally be asked to use a smartphone app related to NICU and at-home care. Participation&#xD;
      in the second groups requires ownership of a smartphone and the ability to use a smartphone&#xD;
      app.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If a participants are assigned to the first or second groups, the investigators would like&#xD;
      both parents to participate in the study independently and therefore complete individual&#xD;
      consent forms. However, the investigators recognize not all families will have two parents&#xD;
      that are interested or able to participate and ultimately participation from some families&#xD;
      will include only one parent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As part of the study, participants will be asked to complete four surveys. They will be&#xD;
      administered at the time of admission, infant's discharge from the NICU, fourteen days after&#xD;
      discharge and thirty days after discharge. For those families who have a longer stay in the&#xD;
      NICU, the investigators will ask parents to complete two additional surveys; one 30 days&#xD;
      after admission and one 60 days after admission. Each survey will take approximately five to&#xD;
      ten minutes to complete. The main benefit of participation is that this research that may&#xD;
      help improve the NICU experience for other families in the future. The primary risk of&#xD;
      participation is the potential loss of confidentiality, but strict measures are in place to&#xD;
      minimize the chance of this happening.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, if participants agree to the option at the end of this Consent Form,&#xD;
      participants may or may not be invited to participate in a separate research interview to&#xD;
      take place during the participants' NICU stay, around the time of the participants' infant's&#xD;
      discharge from the hospital, or within a year of the participants transition home. These&#xD;
      optional, voluntary interviews will be conducted at a time, location and method (phone or&#xD;
      in-person) agreed upon by the parent. All interviews will be conducted with our research&#xD;
      staff with experience interviewing parents of NICU graduates. While the investigators&#xD;
      encourage both parents to participate in order to hear about differences in experiences, one&#xD;
      or both parents can ultimately participate. The purpose of the research interview is to&#xD;
      better understand the participants' experience in the NICU and at home as the parent of a&#xD;
      premature infant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Optional Interview:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to the intervention study, optional qualitative interviews will be conducted with&#xD;
      participants using a maximum variability approach. Interviews will focus on the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Their overall experience of using the app&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Educational Content&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Relationship/communication through app with extended family/friends&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Readiness for discharge&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Empowerment, ability to communicate better with doctors and nurses, and being able to&#xD;
           participate in child health care confidently&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Being ready to go home and did the app help&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Information, communication and support needs across the NICU stay, discharge and beyond&#xD;
&#xD;
      This voluntary interview will be described to parents at the time of consent. To maintain&#xD;
      confidentiality all subjects will be given a unique study code (PIN) and all information&#xD;
      collected for app development will be linked to that number, not to any other identifier. All&#xD;
      documents that include identifiers will be stored in a locked, secure location that only key&#xD;
      authorized study personnel (e.g. PI, research team members) will have access to.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The interviews will be audio recorded. The recordings will be given an ID number and kept in&#xD;
      locked cabinets and on secure computers. The audio recordings will be transcribed and kept on&#xD;
      password protected computers. (There will be no personal identifiers (such as names) in the&#xD;
      transcribed documents.) After the recordings are transcribed, the audio files will be erased.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Only the people listed on the Authorized Research Personnel list will have access to the&#xD;
      data. All paper data will be kept in locked files and rooms. Electronic data will be kept in&#xD;
      on password- encrypted computers and files with identifying information will be individually&#xD;
      password protected. Names and contact information will be stored only for the purpose of&#xD;
      contacting participants. This information will be stored separately from study data and the&#xD;
      two will only be linked by a study ID, kept in a password protected document. Upon completion&#xD;
      of data collection all name and contact information as will be destroyed by file deletion.&#xD;
      All data collected for this study will be kept in a locked, secure location and anything that&#xD;
      can be destroyed (deleted, shredded, etc.) after it has been coded, will be.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 3, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mobile Application Outcome 1</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome measure understand how the smartphone application improves patient/parent experiences in the NICU. This will be measured through a survey.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mobile Application Outcome 2</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome measure will addressing the association of the smartphone application with parenting self-efficacy to improve infants' and parents' health outcomes. This will be measured through a survey.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>State-Trait Anxiety Inventory (STAI)</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient anxiety will be measured through a survey. The response options range from 1 to 4 (Almost never, Sometimes, Often, and Almost always)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parenting Sense of Competence Scale (PSOC)</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Self-efficacy will be measured through a survey. The response options range from 1 to 6 (Strongly Disagree to Strongly Agree)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Edinburgh Postnatal Depression Scale (EPDS)</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Depression will be measured through a survey. The response options range from 0 (for example, no, not at all or no, never again) to 3 (for example, yes, most of the time or yes, very often). The total score ranges from 0 to 30, where higher values indicate more severe symptoms of depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Press Ganey Questionnaire (PG)</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measures all aspects of patient satisfaction during hospital stay.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Healthcare encounters (HE)</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient satisfaction of healthcare provider's will be measured through survey.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Readmission rate (RR)</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Readmission rates will be measured through a survey.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>User Version of the Mobile Application Rating Scale (uMARS)</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Quality and reliability of mobile application will be measured through a survey. All items are rated on a 5-point scale from &quot;1. Inadequate&quot; to &quot;5. Excellent&quot;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Perinatal PTSD Questionnaire - Modified (PPQ-M)</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Perinatal Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) will be measured through a survey.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 Impact Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Given the uncertainty of the global pandemic, we measuring if COVID will have an impact on the use of the mobile application.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceived Stress Scale (PSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Stress will be measured through a survey. The response options range from 1 to 4 (Never Almost; Never Sometimes; Fairly Often; Very Often). The total score ranges from 0 to 16, where higher values indicate more severe symptoms of stress.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>MOS- Social Support Scale (MOS)</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Social Support will be measured through a survey. The response options range from 1 to 5 (None of the time - All of the time). The survey consists of four separate social support subscales and an overall functional social support index. A higher score for an individual scale or for the overall support index indicates more support.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health Behavior (HB)</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Health behavior questions relating to physical health, mental health, stress, breastfeeding, and reproductive health will be measured through a survey.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CDC- Hear Her Campaign</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Questions surrounding maternal mortality and morbidity will be asked through a survey.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Premature Birth</condition>
  <condition>NICU</condition>
  <condition>Premature</condition>
  <condition>Infant</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Parents of infants born from date July 2020-December 2020</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: NICU2HOME+ app</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Parents of infants born from mid Jan 2021-May2021</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Group 1: Standard of Care</intervention_name>
    <description>Those who are in Group 1 will receive the usual care which includes:&#xD;
a welcome packet from the nursing staff&#xD;
access to their infant's medical team including doctors and nurse&#xD;
opportunities to ask any questions and understand the care their baby is receiving through participation in daily work rounds or through setting up family meetings with the medical team.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1: Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Group 2: NICU2HOME+ app</intervention_name>
    <description>In addition to the usual care made available to Group 1 as described above, Group 2 parents will receive the smartphone app. Group 2 parents will be asked to download the NICU2HOME app.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2: NICU2HOME+ app</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parents (including single parents) of premature infants (&lt;35 weeks) admitted to&#xD;
             Central Dupage Hospital (CDH), Northwest Community Hospital (NCH), and Rush University&#xD;
             Medical Center (RUSH)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants born prematurely with a gestational age of &lt;35 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minimum stay in NICU of 7 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Competent in English or Spanish (i.e. to fully understand the questions asked in the&#xD;
             surveys)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smartphone owner&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-adults unable to consent/Cognitively Impaired&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prisoners or other detained individuals&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joshua Santiago, MA</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Northwestern University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Joshua Santiago, MA</last_name>
    <phone>7733192578</phone>
    <email>joshua.santiago@northwestern.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Craig Garfield, MD</last_name>
    <phone>(312)503-5463</phone>
    <email>c-garfield@northwestern.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Northwest Community Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Arlington Heights</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60005</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Joel Fisher, MA</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joel Fisher, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rush University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Patra, MA</last_name>
      <phone>312-942-6640</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kousiki Patra, MA</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centra Dupage Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winfield</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60192</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jeff Loughead, MD</last_name>
      <phone>630-933-1600</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Behrman RE, Butler AS, Institute of Medicine (US) Committee on understanding premature birth and assuring healthy outcomes. Preterm birth: Causes, consequences, and prevention. Washington, DC: National Academies Press; 2007: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK11358/.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Garfield CF, Lee Y, Kim HN. Paternal and maternal concerns for their very low-birth-weight infants transitioning from the NICU to home. J Perinat Neonatal Nurs. 2014 Oct-Dec;28(4):305-12. doi: 10.1097/JPN.0000000000000021.</citation>
    <PMID>24927295</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Braveman P. What is health equity: and how does a life-course approach take us further toward it? Matern Child Health J. 2014 Feb;18(2):366-72. doi: 10.1007/s10995-013-1226-9.</citation>
    <PMID>23397099</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Blumenshine P, Egerter S, Barclay CJ, Cubbin C, Braveman PA. Socioeconomic disparities in adverse birth outcomes: a systematic review. Am J Prev Med. 2010 Sep;39(3):263-72. doi: 10.1016/j.amepre.2010.05.012. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20709259</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>MacDorman MF. Race and ethnic disparities in fetal mortality, preterm birth, and infant mortality in the United States: an overview. Semin Perinatol. 2011 Aug;35(4):200-8. doi: 10.1053/j.semperi.2011.02.017. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21798400</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pew Research Center: Internet Science &amp; Technology. Mobile technology fact sheet. 2018; http://www.pewinternet.org/fact-sheet/mobile/. Accessed January 14, 2019, 2015.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Anderson-Lewis C, Darville G, Mercado RE, Howell S, Di Maggio S. mHealth Technology Use and Implications in Historically Underserved and Minority Populations in the United States: Systematic Literature Review. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2018 Jun 18;6(6):e128. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.8383. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29914860</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Anoshiravani A, Gaskin G, Kopetsky E, Sandborg C, Longhurst CA. Implementing an Interoperable Personal Health Record in Pediatrics: Lessons Learned at an Academic Children's Hospital. J Particip Med. 2011 Jul 10;3. pii: e30.</citation>
    <PMID>21853160</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cooper LG, Gooding JS, Gallagher J, Sternesky L, Ledsky R, Berns SD. Impact of a family-centered care initiative on NICU care, staff and families. J Perinatol. 2007 Dec;27 Suppl 2:S32-7.</citation>
    <PMID>18034178</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>De Rouck S, Leys M. Information needs of parents of children admitted to a neonatal intensive care unit: a review of the literature (1990-2008). Patient Educ Couns. 2009 Aug;76(2):159-73. doi: 10.1016/j.pec.2009.01.014. Epub 2009 Mar 24. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19321288</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Escobar GJ, Joffe S, Gardner MN, Armstrong MA, Folck BF, Carpenter DM. Rehospitalization in the first two weeks after discharge from the neonatal intensive care unit. Pediatrics. 1999 Jul;104(1):e2.</citation>
    <PMID>10390288</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Garfield CF, Lee YS, Kim HN, Rutsohn J, Kahn JY, Mustanski B, Mohr DC. Supporting Parents of Premature Infants Transitioning from the NICU to Home: A Pilot Randomized Control Trial of a Smartphone Application. Internet Interv. 2016 May;4(Pt 2):131-137. Epub 2016 Jun 4.</citation>
    <PMID>27990350</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kim HN, Garfield C, Lee YS. Paternal and maternal information and communication technology usage as their very low birth weight infants transition home from the NICU. Int J Hum Comput Interact. 2015;31(1):44-54.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lee Y, Garfield C, Massey N, Chaysinh S, Hassan S. NICU-2-home: Supporting the transition to home from the neonatal intensive care unit using a mobile application. Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems; May 7 - 11,</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gilmore L, Cuskelly M. Factor structure of the Parenting Sense of Competence scale using a normative sample. Child Care Health Dev. 2009 Jan;35(1):48-55. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2214.2008.00867.x. Epub 2008 Oct 22.</citation>
    <PMID>18991983</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 8, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 21, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Northwestern University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Craig Garfield</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Pediatrics; and Attending physician and neonatal hospitalist at the Lurie Children's Hospital of Chicago where he is the Director of Research for the Division</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Premature Infant; NICU</keyword>
  <keyword>Premature Birth</keyword>
  <keyword>Smartphone App</keyword>
  <keyword>NICU</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>July 8, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/55/NCT04480255/ICF_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

