<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4754">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04654585</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STOP-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04654585</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Preference-based Tools for Smoking Cessation Among Disadvantaged Smokers, a Pragmatic Randomised Controlled Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>STOP</acronym>
  <official_title>Sevrage Tabagique à l'Aide Des Outils dédiés Selon la Préférence, un Essai randomisé contrôlé Pragmatique</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Société de Formation Thérapeutique du Généraliste Recherche</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut National de la Santé Et de la Recherche Médicale, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Société de Formation Thérapeutique du Généraliste</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      - Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our study aims to evaluate the effectiveness of the &quot;STOP&quot; (Sevrage Tabagique à l'aide&#xD;
      d'Outils dédiés selon la Préférence: Smoking Cessation using preference-based tools)&#xD;
      intervention, a preference-based smoking cessation intervention for smokers with low&#xD;
      socio-economic position (SEP).&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Methods :&#xD;
&#xD;
      STOP is a randomised, multi-centre, single blinded, intent-to-treat trial. Participating&#xD;
      centres include primary care practices (community, municipal or general health clinics),&#xD;
      hospital-based facilities, and healthcare institutions specialised in addiction treatment.&#xD;
      Smokers with low SEP will be randomised into either the intervention or control group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Persons randomised to the control group will be accompanied by their health professional&#xD;
      according to standard practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants randomised to the intervention group will receive the same smoking cessation&#xD;
      advice, drug (varenicline, champix,..) prescription and support as participants in the&#xD;
      control group, but they will also have a choice of being given free Nicotine Replacement&#xD;
      Therapy (NRT) (transdermal patch, gum, spray, inhaler, sublingual tablets/lozenges) and/or an&#xD;
      electronic cigarette + e-liquid on the spot to aid their quit attempt.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up appointments will take place at around 7 to 14 days, 1 month, 3 months and 6 months&#xD;
      after inclusion, according to the participant and health professional availability.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main outcome measure of this study will be smoking abstinence at 6 months after&#xD;
      inclusion, defined as self-reported abstinence, with a possibility to validate this outcome&#xD;
      by measured exhaled carbon monoxide.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomised, multi-centre, single blinded, intent-to-treat pragmatic trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Recruitment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be recruited by medical doctors in the different study centres. After a&#xD;
      clear presentation of the study objective, a written informed consent will be asked from&#xD;
      eligible patients before proceeding with randomisation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The recruitment period in each centre will last for up to one year, while each participant&#xD;
      will be followed for 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Intervention standardisation: training of medical doctors:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participating medical doctors (investigators) will receive an individual training&#xD;
      session, during which the study protocol, the randomisation procedure and the data entry&#xD;
      software will be presented to them.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study protocol as well as a brief reminder of recommendations regarding the use of&#xD;
      Nicotine Replacement Therapy (NRT) and e-cigarettes will be presented to all participating&#xD;
      medical doctors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A printed study booklet summarising the study protocol will be given out to investigators as&#xD;
      well as a digital version on the provided tablet, as well as a video format of the training&#xD;
      session.&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Randomisation and blinding:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each medical doctor (investigator) will be provided with a tablet with access to a web-based&#xD;
      randomisation module and an Electronic Case Report Form interface (eCRF). The Randomisation&#xD;
      will be investigator-stratified. This software is supplied by a company specialised in&#xD;
      clinical research and will be in accordance with the latest European and French regulations&#xD;
      regarding the protection of personal data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After a verification of inclusion criteria, and informed consent, the module will randomise&#xD;
      the participant either to the intervention or to the control group (1:1), and will&#xD;
      simultaneously notify the coordinator of the study by e-mail. In order to minimise selection&#xD;
      bias, no substitution or change of group will be permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      - The control group (standard care):&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants randomised to the control group will be given standard care in assisting their&#xD;
      smoking cessation attempt, but without free access to NRT or e-cigarettes. Standard care&#xD;
      depends on each health professional habitual practice, it includes motivational interviewing,&#xD;
      advice to quit and prescription of NRTs. Health professionals will also be in position to&#xD;
      prescribe other treatments (for example: Varenicline which is covered at 65% by the French&#xD;
      health universal insurance and might be completely covered by an additional complementary&#xD;
      health insurance - or Bupropion which has to be paid completely). An investigator could also&#xD;
      give advice on e-cigarette use if he or she finds it suitable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the follow-up, participants randomised to the control group will be offered an&#xD;
      e-cigarette + e-liquid and/or NRT in sufficient quantity for one month, if needed and&#xD;
      desired.&#xD;
&#xD;
      - The intervention:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants randomised to the intervention group will receive the same routine care smoking&#xD;
      cessation advice, drug prescription and support as participants in the control group.&#xD;
      Further, participants will also have a choice of being given free NRT (transdermal patch,&#xD;
      gum, spray, inhaler, and sublingual tablets/lozenges) and/or e-cigarettes on the spot to aid&#xD;
      with their quit attempt. E-cigarettes would be provided with e-liquids with different&#xD;
      nicotine levels (6, 12 and 18 mg/ml), and different flavours (tobacco, mint, and fruit).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, a brief and clear description of each smoking cessation aid will be given to each&#xD;
      participant, and depending on his/her choice, they will be provided a sufficient quantity to&#xD;
      last until the following appointment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Short didactic videos explaining how to use different NRTs and an e-cigarette will be made&#xD;
      available for participants in the intervention group (a link to the video will be given), as&#xD;
      well as for medical doctors accompanying participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During follow-up, participants in the intervention group can also be given other tools than&#xD;
      the one(s) previously delivered, according to their preference and after seeing their medical&#xD;
      doctor (they can be given NRTs at the second appointment if they initially chose e-cigarette&#xD;
      only and vice versa, or the type of given NRTs can be changed or they can receive NRT in&#xD;
      addition to e-cigarette).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each participant in both groups will be given a diary or a &quot;calendar postcard&quot;, on which&#xD;
      he/she will document daily the use of any smoking cessation aid, and the number of cigarettes&#xD;
      smoked every day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These postcards will be pre-paid and pre-addressed to return to the study investigators who&#xD;
      would automatically fill in the data in the centralised data system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up appointments will take place around 10 (7 to 14) days, 1 month, 3 months and 6&#xD;
      months after inclusion. The first follow-up can take place between 7 to 14 days after&#xD;
      inclusion. Additional follow-up appointments can take place upon the request of the medical&#xD;
      doctor and/or the participant in both groups. If needed, follow-up interviews can be&#xD;
      conducted via telephone by the health professional or a research assistant.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Smoking abstinence at 6 months after inclusion (yes/no)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported continuous abstinence for at least 7 days, validated by measured exhaled carbon monoxide, if this measurement is available (depending on the sanitary measures in place due to the ongoing covid-19 pandemic).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total number of days of abstinence at 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported number of days without any puff</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Smoking abstinence at 1 and 3 months after inclusion (yes/no)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 and 3 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported continuous abstinence for at least 7 days, validated by measured exhaled carbon monoxide, if this measurement is available (depending on the sanitary measures in place due to the ongoing covid-19 pandemic)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of relapses</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The number of cigarettes smoked per day</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Self-reported</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants who have significantly reduced daily smoking</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as a reduction in consumption by at least 50% in terms of the number of cigarettes smoked per day or the weight of roll-your-own tobacco per day</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">528</enrollment>
  <condition>Smoking</condition>
  <condition>Smoking Cessation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>The STOP intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The stop intervention is a heath professional (medical doctor) led intervention assisting smokers with low socioeconomic position in their smoking cessation attempt. It consists of routine care and adapted advice supplemented with a free delivery of any or several type(s) of nicotine replacement therapy (NRT) (patches, inhalers, gum, tablets, etc.) and/or an e-cigarette + e-liquid. The delivery of those smoking aids is based on the smokers' preference and choice.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomised to the standard care group will be given standard care in assisting their smoking cessation attempt, but without free delivery of NRT or e-cigarettes.&#xD;
Standard care includes motivational interviewing, advice to quit and prescription for NRTs. The number and online address of the French smoking cessation support helpline could also be provided. Health professionals will also be in position to prescribe NRT or other treatments (for example: Varenicline or Bupropion) which can help with smoking cessation, according to routine practice. The health professional could also give advice on e-cigarette use if he or she finds it suitable.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>The STOP intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>The stop intervention is a heath professional (medical doctor) led intervention assisting smokers with low socioeconomic position in their smoking cessation attempt. It consists of routine care and adapted advice supplemented with a free delivery of any or several type(s) of nicotine replacement therapy (NRT) (patches, inhalers, gum, tablets, etc.) and/or an e-cigarette + e-liquid. The delivery of those smoking aids is based on the smokers' preference and choice.</description>
    <arm_group_label>The STOP intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard Care</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants randomised to the standard care group will be given standard care in assisting their smoking cessation attempt, but without free delivery of NRT or e-cigarettes.&#xD;
Standard care includes motivational interviewing, advice to quit and prescription for NRTs. The number and online address of the French smoking cessation support helpline could also be provided. Health professionals will also be in position to prescribe NRT or other treatments (for example: Varenicline or Bupropion) which can help with smoking cessation, according to routine practice. The health professional could also give advice on e-cigarette use if he or she finds it suitable.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard Care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Daily smokers (5≥ cigarettes/day)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A low socio-economic position (meaning being unemployed or being a recipient of one of&#xD;
             the state programs for low income individuals)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being available for at least 4 appointments over a 6 month period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Affiliation to or benefiting from social security or state medical support&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who do not speak French, or who have cognitive impairments making it&#xD;
             impossible to understand study information or a condition that makes it impossible for&#xD;
             them to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major citizens protected by law, adults unable to express their consent and subject to&#xD;
             a protective measure (guardianship, curatorship, safeguard of justice)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women or with a pregnancy project, mothers breastfeeding their child(ren).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Regular smokers who vape daily (at least once a day).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People who at the time of inclusion are already being managed for smoking cessation&#xD;
             (whatever treatment: varenicline, electronic cigarette, NRT, hypnosis, acupuncture,&#xD;
             psychotherapy, talk groups, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are already participating in another clinical study (self-reported).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Fabienne El-Khoury Lesueur, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0033778816091</phone>
    <email>fabienne.khoury@inserm.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Maria Melchior, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0033624793904</phone>
    <email>maria.melchior@inserm.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre municipal et universitaire de santé Marcel Trigon</name>
      <address>
        <city>Arcueil</city>
        <zip>94250</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>André Soares, MD</last_name>
      <phone>06 08 81 61 83</phone>
      <email>andre.soares@sorbonne-universite.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>André Soares, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre d'addictologie et d'alcoologie Guillaume Broutet</name>
      <address>
        <city>Avignon</city>
        <zip>84000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michel Cadart, MD</last_name>
      <phone>04 90 82 41 02</phone>
      <email>michel.cadart@ch-montfavet.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michel Cadart, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Laura Piras (medical practice)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Castelnau-d'Estrétefonds</city>
        <zip>31620</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Laura Piras, MD</last_name>
      <phone>06 83 61 36 22</phone>
      <email>dr.piras@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Laura Piras, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Antoine Beclere</name>
      <address>
        <city>Clamart</city>
        <zip>92140</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marion Adler, MD</last_name>
      <phone>06 32 32 95 66</phone>
      <email>marion.adler@yahoo.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marion Adler, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Henri Mondor</name>
      <address>
        <city>Créteil</city>
        <zip>94000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Boyer Laurent, MD</last_name>
      <phone>01 49 81 26 90</phone>
      <email>laurent.boyer@aphp.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Boyer Laurent, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Municipal de Santé Savattero</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montreuil</city>
        <zip>93100</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>André Nguyen Van Nhieu, MD</last_name>
      <phone>06 51 09 23 26</phone>
      <email>andre.nvn@univ-paris-diderot.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>André Nguyen Van Nhieu, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Cécile Roche Dominguez, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mathilde Roze (medical practice)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75003</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mathilde Roze, MD</last_name>
      <phone>06.88.35.65.73</phone>
      <email>mathilde.roze@ipsosante.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mathilde Roze, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ghislaine Hacke Mela (medical practice)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75005</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ghislaine Hacke Mela, MD</last_name>
      <phone>01 46 33 52 50</phone>
      <email>hackemela@noos.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ghislaine Hacke Mela, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier Sainte Anne</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75014</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kebir Oussama, MD</last_name>
      <phone>06 20 23 23 26</phone>
      <email>oussama.kebir@inserm.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kebir Oussama, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital européen Georges-Pompidou</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75015</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anne-Laurence Le Faou, MD</last_name>
      <phone>01 56 09 24 88</phone>
      <email>anne-laurence.lefaou@aphp.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anne-Laurence Le Faou, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Tenon</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75020</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anne-Marie Ruppert, MD</last_name>
      <phone>01 56 01 78 47</phone>
      <email>anne-marie.ruppert@aphp.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anne-Marie Ruppert, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Anne Kerharo-Nicolas (medical practice)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint-Rogatien</city>
        <zip>17220</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anne Kerharo-Nicolas, MD</last_name>
      <phone>06 09 27 03 74</phone>
      <email>anne.kerharo@wanadoo.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anne Kerharo-Nicolas, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Carole Plaussu (medical practice)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Suresnes</city>
        <zip>92150</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carole Plaussu, MD</last_name>
      <email>carole.plaussu@free.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Carole Plaussu, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kinouani Shérazade (medical practice)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Targon</city>
        <zip>33760</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kinouani Shérazade, MD</last_name>
      <phone>06 10 29 68 47</phone>
      <email>skjk26@yahoo.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kinouani Shérazade, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre de Santé Pierre-Rouquès</name>
      <address>
        <city>Villejuif</city>
        <zip>94800</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gladys Ibanez, MD</last_name>
      <phone>06 70 15 37 60</phone>
      <email>gladys.ibanez@sorbonne-universite.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gladys Ibanez, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://etude-stop.fr/</url>
    <description>Study website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 27, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 10, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 10, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Institut National de la Santé Et de la Recherche Médicale, France</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Fabienne El-Khoury</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Senior researcher, principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Electronic Nicotine Delivery Systems</keyword>
  <keyword>Tobacco Use Cessation Devices</keyword>
  <keyword>Preference-based</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

