<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3650">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04602260</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>COREG-Extension_14567</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04602260</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Functional Recovery of Hospitalised Patients With COVID-19: The COREG Extension Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Functional Recovery of Older Hospitalised Patients With COVID-19: a Prospective and Retrospective Cohort Study Extension to the Coronavirus Registry (COREG)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>McMaster University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>McMaster University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Older adults and those with chronic underlying health conditions are the most susceptible to&#xD;
      COVID-19 and its complications. Although there has been a rapid response to studying the&#xD;
      effects of COVID-19 in the acute stages, little is known about recovery over the longer-term.&#xD;
      Older adults who survive the diseases are at risk of developing persistent mobility&#xD;
      limitations due to extensive bed rest during hospitalization. For older patients and those&#xD;
      with underlying frailty recovering from COVID-19, this could rapidly lead to significant&#xD;
      physical deconditioning and rapid declines in mobility. Understanding the trajectory of&#xD;
      functional recovery of older hospitalised patients with COVID-19 in the short- and long-term&#xD;
      is critical to improving patient outcomes and informing health and rehabilitative&#xD;
      interventions for survivors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The coronavirus disease of 2019 (COVID-19) is an international public health challenge with&#xD;
      far-reaching social, economic and health impacts. Older adults and those with chronic&#xD;
      underlying health conditions are the most susceptible to COVID-19 and its complications. Of&#xD;
      the 15,381 reported cases of COVID-19 in Ontario to date, approximately 22.2% (n=3,420) are&#xD;
      aged 60-79 and 22.4% (n=3,443) are 80 and over. Although there has been a rapid and&#xD;
      coordinated response to studying the effects of COVID-19 in the acute stages, little is known&#xD;
      about recovery over the longer-term. Anecdotally, we are seeing severe declines in function,&#xD;
      persistent symptoms, and new and worsening chronic conditions among older survivors of&#xD;
      COVID-19. It is known that older adults who survive acute respiratory distress syndrome and&#xD;
      associated diseases are at risk of developing persistent mobility limitations due to&#xD;
      extensive bed rest and/or long stays in the intensive care unit (ICU) during hospitalization.&#xD;
      Recent studies have shown that many older patients spend only 4% of their hospital stay out&#xD;
      of bed, and each day in bed is associated with a 1-5% loss in muscle strength. For older&#xD;
      patients and those with underlying frailty recovering from COVID-19, this could rapidly lead&#xD;
      to significant physical deconditioning and rapid declines in mobility; with further losses in&#xD;
      physiological reserve and resilience. Understanding the trajectory of functional recovery of&#xD;
      older hospitalised patients with COVID-19 in the short- and long-term is critical to&#xD;
      improving patient outcomes and informing health and rehabilitative interventions for&#xD;
      survivors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our study is an extension of the Coronavirus (COVID-19) Registry (COREG) platform (PI Andrew&#xD;
      Costa)- a unique Kitchener-Waterloo-Hamilton registry of suspected and confirmed COVID-19&#xD;
      hospital admissions based on (and in collaboration with) the WHO International Severe Acute&#xD;
      Respiratory and Emerging Infection Consortium (ISARIC). The addition of a prospective cohort&#xD;
      study extension to COREG will allow us to follow-older hospitalised COVID-19 patients over&#xD;
      the longer-term in order to gain an understanding of the trajectory of functional recovery of&#xD;
      the disease. Combining the primary data collection with COREG will also allow us to identify&#xD;
      determinants of long-term outcomes for at-risk older adults. These data are necessary to&#xD;
      guide the clinical care and optimal management of older patients who survive serious COVID-19&#xD;
      illness.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 9, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Activity Measure for Post Acute Care (AM-PAC) Basic Mobility Inpatient Version</measure>
    <time_frame>Admission to hospital ward (0-14 days post ward admission) and discharge from hospital (0-14 days post discharge or up to 6 months, whichever comes first)</time_frame>
    <description>The AM-PAC is an activity limitation instrument based on the International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health (ICF) that assesses 3 functional domains: basic mobility, daily activities and applied cognition.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Activity Measure for Post Acute Care (AM-PAC) Basic Mobility Outpatient Version</measure>
    <time_frame>Admission to hospital ward (0-14 days post ward admission, to capture pre-morbid function), and at 3,6,9 and 12-months post hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>The AM-PAC is an activity limitation instrument based on the International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health (ICF) that assesses 3 functional domains: basic mobility, daily activities and applied cognition.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Activity Measure for Post Acute Care (AM-PAC) Applied Cognitive Inpatient Version</measure>
    <time_frame>Admission to hospital ward (0-14 days post ward admission) and discharge from hospital (0-14 days post discharge or up to 6 months, whichever comes first)</time_frame>
    <description>The AM-PAC is an activity limitation instrument based on the International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health (ICF) that assesses 3 functional domains: basic mobility, daily activities and applied cognition.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Activity Measure for Post Acute Care (AM-PAC) Daily Activity</measure>
    <time_frame>3,6,9 and 12-months post hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>The AM-PAC is an activity limitation instrument based on the International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health (ICF) that assesses 3 functional domains: basic mobility, daily activities and applied cognition.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Short Physical Performance Battery (SPPB)</measure>
    <time_frame>3,6,9 and 12-months post hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>The SPPB combines the results of gait speed over 3 meters, the 5-repetition chair-stand, and a progressive balance test to assess lower extremity function.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Clinical Frailty Scale (CFS) for participants over 60 years of age</measure>
    <time_frame>Admission to hospital ward (0-14 days post ward admission, to capture pre-morbid function ), and at 3,6,9 and 12-months post hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>The CFS is an interview-based scale wherein the assessor may ask the patient questions about things such as their independence or physical abilities to determine where the patient falls along the 9-point scale, from 1 (Very Fit) to 9 (Terminally Ill).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Forced Expiratory Volume (FEV1)</measure>
    <time_frame>3,6,9 and 12-months post hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>The Forced Expiratory Volume in 1 Second parameter measures the volume of air that was exhaled into the mouthpiece in the first second after a full inhalation as measured by spirometry.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Forced Vital Capacity (FVC)</measure>
    <time_frame>3,6,9 and 12-months post hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>The amount of air that can be forcibly exhaled from your lungs after taking the deepest breath possible, as measured by spirometry. FVC is the total amount of air exhaled during the FEV test.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Forced Expiratory Volume Percentage (FEV1%)</measure>
    <time_frame>3,6,9 and 12-months post hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>The FEV1/FVC Ratio (FEV1%) parameter is calculated by dividing the measured FEV1 value by the measured FVC value.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Baseline Dyspnea Index (BDI)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months post hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>The BDI rates the severity of dyspnea at a single point in time (baseline) based on a 24-item interviewer administered rating scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Transition Dyspnea Index (TDI)</measure>
    <time_frame>6,9 and 12-months post hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Measures changes in dyspnea severity from the baseline as established by the BDI.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Patient Health Questionnaire - 9 (PHQ-9)</measure>
    <time_frame>3,6,9 and 12-months post hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>The PHQ-9 is a self-rating instrument for depression based on nine questions that the patient responds to by indicating how much they have been bothered by these symptoms over the last two weeks.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Functional Independence Measure (FIM)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6 months post hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>The FIM assesses the functional status of a person based on the level of assistance the person requires.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Impact of Event Scale - Revised (IES-R)</measure>
    <time_frame>3,6,9 and 12-months post hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>The IES-R is a 22-item self-report measure that asks questions about subjective distress caused by traumatic events. Each item is rated on a 5-point scale, from 0 (&quot;not at all&quot;) to 4 (&quot;extremely&quot;).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Health status (EQ-5D-5L)</measure>
    <time_frame>3,6,9 and 12-months post hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>The EQ-5D-5L is a generic and well-established instrument for describing health status or disease-specific outcome measures. It defines health in terms of five dimensions: Mobility, Self- Care, Usual Activities, Pain/Discomfort, and Anxiety/ Depression. The response options are of five levels, from no, slight, moderate, severe, to extreme problems</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">211</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Corona Virus Infection</condition>
  <condition>Mobility Limitation</condition>
  <condition>Frailty</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <description>The prospective cohort will assess patients upon admission to general internal medicine, at hospital discharge, and at 3, 6, and 12-month follow-up.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Retrospective Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <description>The retrospective cohort will assess patients at 3, 6, and 12-months after being discharged from the hospital.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Consecutive patients included in the COREG registry that meet inclusion criteria will be&#xD;
        approached for enrollment in this extension study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  40 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently hospitalised/recently discharged due to/since confirmed or suspected COVID-&#xD;
             19 infection using the ISARIC definition.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previously institutionalized&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-morbid severe mobility limitation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marla K Beauchamp, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>McMaster University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hope Morrison, BA</last_name>
    <phone>905-525-9140</phone>
    <phone_ext>20810</phone_ext>
    <email>morrih12@mcmaster.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>McMaster University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamilton</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>L8S1C7</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hope Morrison, BA</last_name>
      <phone>905-525-9140</phone>
      <phone_ext>20810</phone_ext>
      <email>morrih12@mcmaster.ca</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 3, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>McMaster University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Marla Beauchamp</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>mobility</keyword>
  <keyword>functional recovery</keyword>
  <keyword>pulmonary function</keyword>
  <keyword>Covid-19</keyword>
  <keyword>coronavirus</keyword>
  <keyword>health outcomes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Frailty</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mobility Limitation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

