<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3930">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04682197</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB00066997</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04682197</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cereset Research In Healthcare Workers During COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Cereset Research To Reduce Stress And Anxiety In Healthcare Workers In The Time Of COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Wake Forest University Health Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>William Madison Satterwhite III, MD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Wake Forest University Health Sciences</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the use of Cereset Research to improve the symptoms&#xD;
      of stress and anxiety in healthcare workers in an open label, waitlist controlled pilot&#xD;
      clinical trial, during the period of COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this open label exploratory study is to evaluate the effect of CR to&#xD;
      improve the Impact of Event Scale-Revised (IES-R) in healthcare workers at Wake Forest&#xD;
      Baptist Health with symptoms of stress and anxiety.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objective is to evaluate the effect of CR on a variety of self-reported symptom&#xD;
      inventories (sleep, perceived stress, mood, anxiety, post-traumatic stress, quality of life,&#xD;
      social support, and cognitive function).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory Objective: Assess the impact of CR on autonomic cardiovascular regulation (heart&#xD;
      rate variability, HRV).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: This will be a single site, open label, randomized, waitlist controlled pilot&#xD;
      clinical trial, enrolling adults aged 18 or older, who have self-reported symptoms of stress&#xD;
      or anxiety, and meet a threshold score on self-reported inventories. Up to 120 participants&#xD;
      will be enrolled in order to have at least 100 to complete the study. Participants will be&#xD;
      randomly assigned to either an Early Intervention (EI) group which will receive 2 CR sessions&#xD;
      of audible tones echoing current brainwave activity, following enrollment, or a Delayed&#xD;
      Intervention (DI) group which will continue current care only, and will serve as a control&#xD;
      group. Participants in both groups will continue their other current care throughout the&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome will be interval change in the Impact of Event Scale-Revised (IES-R)&#xD;
      which assesses reactions to stressful life events like COVID-19 by looking at avoidance,&#xD;
      intrusion, and hyperarousal. Secondary outcomes to be collected include symptom inventories&#xD;
      for insomnia (Insomnia Severity Index, ISI), depression (Center for Epidemiological Studies-&#xD;
      Depression Scale, CES-D), anxiety (Generalized Anxiety Disorder-7, GAD-7), stress (Perceived&#xD;
      Stress Scale, PSS), traumatic stress (PTSD Checklist for civilians, PCL-C), overall quality&#xD;
      of life (QOLS), social support (ISEL-12), and the Multiple Ability Self-Report Questionnaire&#xD;
      (MASQ) for cognitive function. Pre- and post-intervention data collection of physiological&#xD;
      parameters (Heart rate, HR, and measures of autonomic cardiovascular regulation assessed by&#xD;
      heart rate variability) will be assessed as exploratory outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All measures will be collected at an enrollment visit (V1), and participants will be randomly&#xD;
      assigned to the EI or DI groups. For those in the EI group, the intervention will begin 0-7&#xD;
      days thereafter. Post-intervention data collections will be obtained at 0-7 days (V2) after&#xD;
      completion of the intervention, and 4-6 weeks (V3, primary outcome) after the V2. Following&#xD;
      V3, those in the DI group will be offered the opportunity to cross over to receive two&#xD;
      sessions of Cereset Research, and will continue to be followed for data collections at 0-7&#xD;
      days (V4) after completing their crossover sessions, and 4-6 weeks (V5) after V4. Mean&#xD;
      contrasts will be used to compare the changes in measures of autonomic cardiovascular&#xD;
      regulation from V1 to V3, the primary outcome, as well as for secondary outcomes. Linear&#xD;
      mixed models, which can accommodate within-subject correlations due to repeated assessments&#xD;
      over time, will be used to generate point estimates for effect size along with 95% confidence&#xD;
      intervals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This will be a single site, open label, randomized, waitlist controlled pilot clinical trial, enrolling healthcare workers at Wake Forest Baptist Health, aged 18 or older, who have self-reported symptoms of stress or anxiety, and meet a threshold score on self-reported inventories. Up to 120 participants will be enrolled in order to have at least 100 to complete the study. Participants will be randomly assigned to either an Early Intervention (EI) group which will receive 2 CR sessions of audible tones echoing current brainwave activity, following enrollment, or a Delayed Intervention (DI) group which will continue current care only, and will serve as a control group. Participants in both groups will continue their other current care throughout the study.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Impact of Event Scale-Revised (IES-R)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, V2 (0-7 days after final session), and V3 (4-6 weeks after V2)</time_frame>
    <description>The Impact of Event Scale- Revised Scale assess intrusion, avoidance, and hyperarousal. The scale includes five new questions in addition to the original Impact of Event Scale created by Mardi Horowitz. Scores range from 0 to 88. Total scores ranging between 24-43 suggest that PTSD is a clinical concern; scores between 33-38 suggest best cutoff for probably PTSD; and scores of 39 and above suggest suppressed immune system functioning. The higher the score, the larger the impact of recent stress. There are three subscales evaluating intrusion avoidance, and hyperarousal.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Insomnia Severity Index (ISI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, V2 (0-7 days after final session), and V3 (4-6 weeks after V2)</time_frame>
    <description>The severity of insomnia symptoms is measured using two self-report symptom inventories with each data collection visit. This includes the Insomnia Severity Index (ISI). The ISI is a 7-question measure, with responses from 0-4 for each question, yielding scores ranging from 0-28. The higher the score, the more suggestive of insomnia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Center for Epidemiologic Studies Depression Scale (CES-D)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, V2 (0-7 days after final session), and V3 (4-6 weeks after V2)</time_frame>
    <description>The Center for Epidemiologic Studies Depression Scale (CES-D) is a depression scale, which will help to assess this co-morbidity. CES-D is a 20-item survey assessing affective depressive symptomatology to screen for risk of depression. Scores range from 0-60, with a score of 16 commonly used as a clinically relevant cut-off. Higher scores suggest increased depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Generalized Anxiety Disorder-7 (GAD-7)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, V2 (0-7 days after final session), and V3 (4-6 weeks after V2)</time_frame>
    <description>The Generalized Anxiety Disorder-7 (GAD-7) is a seven-item screening tool for anxiety that is widely used in primary care. GAD-7 is a brief, reliable and valid measure of assessing generalized anxiety disorder. Higher scores suggest increased anxiety.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in PTSD Checklist for Civilians (PCL-C)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, V2 (0-7 days after final session), and V3 (4-6 weeks after V2)</time_frame>
    <description>The PTSD Checklist for civilians (PCL-C), measures the American Psychiatric Association's Diagnostic and statistical manual of mental disorders (DSM-IV) Criteria B, C, &amp; D of PTSD symptoms based on traumatic life experience either in civilian life, or related to military service, respectively. Seventeen items are rated on a Likert scale with a composite score range of 17 to 85. A score of 44 or higher correlates with probability of civilian-related PTSD.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Perceived Stress Scale (PSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, V2 (0-7 days after final session), and V3 (4-6 weeks after V2)</time_frame>
    <description>The Perceived Stress Scale (PSS) is a ten-item psychological instrument for measuring the perception of stress. It is a measure of the degree to which situations in one's life are appraised as stressful. Items were designed to tap how unpredictable, uncontrollable, and overloaded respondents find their lives. The scale, with answers rated from 0-4, also includes a number of direct queries about current levels of experienced stress. Higher scores suggest increase perceived stress.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Quality of Life Scale (QOLS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, V2 (0-7 days after final session), and V3 (4-6 weeks after V2)</time_frame>
    <description>The Quality of Life Scale (QOLS) is a 16-item scale that was modified from a 15-item scale used in chronic disease patients. Topics include different components of daily life such as relationships, community engagement, personal fulfillment, and recreation. Each item is scaled from 1 to 7 and a sum score is calculated to represent higher levels of satisfaction in life (range is 16-112).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Interpersonal Support Evaluation List (ISEL-12)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, V2 (0-7 days after final session), and V3 (4-6 weeks after V2)</time_frame>
    <description>The Interpersonal Support Evaluation List - Shortened Version (ISEL-12) is a 12-item scale that was modified from a 40-item scale used to assess perceptions of social support. Three dimensions are evaluated: appraisal support, belonging support, and tangible support. Each item is scaled from 1 to 4 for &quot;Definitely True&quot; to &quot;Definitely False.&quot; Scores are summed and higher scores correlate with more perceived social support.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Multiple Ability Self-Report Questionnaire (MASQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, V2 (0-7 days after final session), and V3 (4-6 weeks after V2)</time_frame>
    <description>The Multiple Ability Self-Report Questionnaire (MASQ) is a self-report questionnaire commonly used to assess perceived cognitive dysfunction. The MASQ has 38 items and assesses five cognitive domains, including language, visual/perceptual ability, verbal memory, visual memory, and attention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Health Personnel</condition>
  <condition>Stress</condition>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <condition>Insomnia</condition>
  <condition>Hyperarousal</condition>
  <condition>Corona Virus Infection</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cereset Research</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>For this single arm, open label, exploratory trial this will be the intervention arm using 2 CR sessions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Continued Current Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will continue their current care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cereset Research</intervention_name>
    <description>The upgraded platform for medical research using the HIRREM technology has been rebranded as Cereset Research® (CR). This system uses the same core technology and algorithms to echo brainwaves in real-time using audible tones, as with HIRREM. The CR system also includes 64-bit processing architecture for faster feedback, the use of 4 sensors, and the use of standard protocols (with flexibility regarding the length and sequencing of the standard protocols), all done with eyes closed. Four sensors are applied to the scalp at a time. However, only two sensors are actively echoing feedback. The software automatically switches from one sensor pair to the other when needed. This reduces the number of sensor placement changes needed, resulting in shorter session time and fewer interruptions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cereset Research</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Continued Current Care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthcare workers at Wake Forest Baptist Health aged 18 years and older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to comply with basic instructions and be able to sit still, comfortably during&#xD;
             sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects experiencing symptoms of stress or anxiety who meet threshold scores on one&#xD;
             or more self-reported inventories for the same. This includes the Perceived Stress&#xD;
             Index (PSS, ≥ 14), or the Generalized Anxiety Disorder 7-item (GAD-7, ≥ 5) scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable, unwilling, or incompetent to provide informed consent/assent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physically unable to come to the study visits, or to sit still, comfortably in a chair&#xD;
             for up to 1 hour.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe hearing impairment (because the subject will be using ear buds during CR).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weight is over the chair limit (400 pounds).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently enrolled in another active intervention research study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior use of: HIRREM, HIRREM-SOP, Brainwave Optimization (BWO), Cereset, Cereset Home,&#xD;
             or a wearable configuration of the same (B2, or B2v2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior use of: electroconvulsive therapy (ECT), prior use of transcranial magnetic&#xD;
             stimulation (TMS), transcranial direct current stimulation (TDCS), alpha stimulation,&#xD;
             Eye movement desensitization and reprocessing (EMDR), brain spotting, neurofeedback,&#xD;
             biofeedback, or deep brain stimulation (DBS) within one month before enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known seizure disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thoughts of suicide within the last 3 months.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Charles H Tegeler, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Wake Forest University Health Sciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
    <phone>336-716-9447</phone>
    <email>BBRP@wakehealth.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 22, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 23, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 22, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 22, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 23, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>Stress</keyword>
  <keyword>Insomnia</keyword>
  <keyword>Cereset Research</keyword>
  <keyword>Hyperarousal</keyword>
  <keyword>Brain electrical activity</keyword>
  <keyword>Autonomic Dysregulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Neurotechnology</keyword>
  <keyword>HIRREM</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Coronavirus</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

