<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3441">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04672291</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ONV2020-003</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04672291</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Nasal Poly-ICLC (Hiltonol®) for Prophylaxis of COVID-19 in Healthy Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I-Ib, Double-blinded, Randomized Repeated Dose Multicenter, Safety and Immunogenicity Study of Nasal Poly-ICLC (Hiltonol®) for Prophylaxis of COVID-19 in Healthy Adults</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Oncovir, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Calgary</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Oncovir, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized (4:1) Phase 1 b safety trial in SARS CoV-2 negative subjects at high&#xD;
      risk for infection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      An initial cohort of 13 patients will receive 2 cycles of drug or placebo per the schedule&#xD;
      below under carefully monitored conditions, including examinations to rule out evidence of&#xD;
      chronic mucosal inflammation due to the drug. 10 patients will receive drug and 3 will&#xD;
      receive placebo. The safety stopping rule is to stop the trial early if 2 out of the first&#xD;
      six, or 3 out of the first 10, or 4 out of the 13 patients receiving drug experience a dose&#xD;
      limiting toxicity (DLT, see section 5.1 ) in either cycle 1 or cycle 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If at most 3 patients out of the 10 receiving drug experience a DLT, then a Phase Ib&#xD;
      expansion cohort will open. The expansion cohort will receive 3 cycles of therapy. A total of&#xD;
      30 patients will be accrued and randomized 4:1 to receive drug (N=24) or placebo (N=6). There&#xD;
      will be extensive assessment of toxicity and an early stopping rule will be employed as&#xD;
      above. Safety and tolerability will be the primary endpoint but secondary endpoints include&#xD;
      changes in immunological parameters.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 16, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Intranasal Poly-ICLC (Hiltonol®)</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>This study consists of 2 treatment groups. Study subjects will be assigned by chance to a treatment group. Group 1 receives the study drug; group 2 receives the placebo. Neither the study subject or the study team will know the group assignments. There will be a 4 out 5 chance of receiving the study drug and 1 out 5 chance of receiving the placebo.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability, Dose Limiting Toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>91 days</time_frame>
    <description>Safety will be measured and tabulated by the number (percent) of participants who experience DLTs (grade 3/4 adverse events) from the start of therapy through the end of the follow up period (day 91), according to DAIDS.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the response of the body to the study drug (pharmacodynamics)</measure>
    <time_frame>91 days</time_frame>
    <description>Determining the effect on local and systemic inflammatory markers through blood collection and collection of nasal mononuclear cells</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">43</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID - 19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Safety Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A randomized (4:1) initial safety cohort of 13 patients will receive 2 cycles of drug (N=10) or placebo (N=3)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Expansion Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A randomized (4:1) expansion cohort will receive 3 cycles of drug (N=24) or placebo (N=6). A total of 30 patients will be accrued.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Poly-ICLC (Hiltonol®)</intervention_name>
    <description>The safety cohort (Cohort A) consists of 13 patients who will be randomized to receive 2 cycles of the study drug (N10) or 2 placebo cycles (N3).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Safety Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Safety</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Poly-ICLC (Hiltonol®)</intervention_name>
    <description>The expansion cohort will receive 3 cycles of therapy. A total of 30 patients will be accrued and randomized 4:1 to receive drug (N=24) or placebo (N=6).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Expansion Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Expansion</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects must be 18 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Asymptomatic&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Nasopharyngeal swab for COVID-9 taken within 3 days of first treatment with negative&#xD;
             diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Negative serology for SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Willing and able to provide blood and nasopharyngeal samples&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Health care personnel or subjects with high-risk of exposure to SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Able to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Female patients of childbearing potential and male patients with partners of&#xD;
             childbearing potential must agree to use adequate methods of contraception (described&#xD;
             below) during the study treatment and through 90 days after the last dose of study&#xD;
             medication. Female patients of childbearing potential are all those except patients&#xD;
             who are surgically sterile, who have medically documented ovarian failure, or who are&#xD;
             at least 1 year postmenopausal.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Acceptable Hematologic, renal and liver functions as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count &gt; 1000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets &gt; 50,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin &gt;9 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum Creatinine ≤ 2.5 mg/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Liver Function:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Total bilirubin ≤1.5 mg/dl; AST ≤ 2.0 mg/dl (≤120 IU or 3x ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Receipt of any blood product in past 120 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Allergic rhinitis, chronic sinusitis, or other nasal inflammatory disease that&#xD;
             requires daily intranasal or oral medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Chronic medical problems that require daily nasal administration of medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Prior nasal or sinus surgery including trans nasal approaches to brain&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Chronic pulmonary conditions including severe asthma, COPD, or chronic bronchitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Autoimmune hepatitis, decompensated liver disease, cardiac ischemia, congestive heart&#xD;
             failure, cardiac arrhythmia, neutropenia, thrombocytopenia, severe renal insufficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Psychiatric or cognitive illness or recreational drug/alcohol use that in the opinion&#xD;
             of the principal investigator, would affect subject safety and/or compliance&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Symptoms consistent with COVID-19 infection (fevers, acute onset cough, shortness of&#xD;
             breath) at time of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Nucleic acid testing evidence of COVID-19 infection at time of screening or on Day 0&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Inability to complete therapy with the study product within 24 hours after enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients must not be pregnant or nursing due to the unknown potential for congenital&#xD;
             abnormalities and the potential of this regimen to harm nursing infants.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Has a diagnosis of primary immunodeficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Has active autoimmune disease that has required systemic treatment in the past 1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. (i.e. with use of disease modifying agents, corticosteroids or immunosuppressive&#xD;
                  drugs)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Replacement therapy (e.g. thyroxine, insulin, or physiologic corticosteroid&#xD;
                  replacement therapy for adrenal or pituitary insufficiency, etc.) is acceptable&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Has a history or current evidence of any condition, therapy, or laboratory abnormality&#xD;
             that might confound the results of the trial, interfere with the patient's&#xD;
             participation for the full duration of the trial, or is not in the best interest of&#xD;
             the patient to participate, in the opinion of the treating Investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Principle investigator believes that for one or multiple reasons the patient will be&#xD;
             unable to comply with all study visits, or if they believe the trial is not clinically&#xD;
             in the best interest of the patient&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Documented allergic or hypersensitivity response to any protein therapeutics (e.g.,&#xD;
             recombinant proteins, vaccines, intravenous immune globulins, monoclonal antibodies,&#xD;
             receptor traps)&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Active, untreated tuberculosis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andres M Salazar, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Sponsor GmbH</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andres M Salazar, MD</last_name>
    <phone>207 505 7144</phone>
    <email>asalazar@oncovir.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Richard Bhardwaj, MBChB, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>403-220-2123</phone>
    <email>rleigh@ucalgary.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Health Research Innovation Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Calgary</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T2N 4Z6</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Curtis Dumonceaux, BSc, CCRP</last_name>
      <phone>403-220-2123</phone>
      <email>cjdumonc@ucalgary.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Linda Knox, RN, CRE</last_name>
      <phone>403-220-2123</phone>
      <email>lknox@ucalgary.ca</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Richard Leigh, MBChB, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Adams JG, Walls RM. Supporting the Health Care Workforce During the COVID-19 Global Epidemic. JAMA. 2020 Apr 21;323(15):1439-1440. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.3972.</citation>
    <PMID>32163102</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Antonelli LR, Gigliotti Rothfuchs A, Gonçalves R, Roffê E, Cheever AW, Bafica A, Salazar AM, Feng CG, Sher A. Intranasal Poly-IC treatment exacerbates tuberculosis in mice through the pulmonary recruitment of a pathogen-permissive monocyte/macrophage population. J Clin Invest. 2010 May;120(5):1674-82. doi: 10.1172/JCI40817. Epub 2010 Apr 12.</citation>
    <PMID>20389020</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Balan S, Arnold-Schrauf C, Abbas A, Couespel N, Savoret J, Imperatore F, Villani AC, Vu Manh TP, Bhardwaj N, Dalod M. Large-Scale Human Dendritic Cell Differentiation Revealing Notch-Dependent Lineage Bifurcation and Heterogeneity. Cell Rep. 2018 Aug 14;24(7):1902-1915.e6. doi: 10.1016/j.celrep.2018.07.033.</citation>
    <PMID>30110645</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Benveniste EN, Qin H. Type I interferons as anti-inflammatory mediators. Sci STKE. 2007 Dec 11;2007(416):pe70.</citation>
    <PMID>18073382</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Boukhvalova MS, Sotomayor TB, Point RC, Pletneva LM, Prince GA, Blanco JC. Activation of interferon response through toll-like receptor 3 impacts viral pathogenesis and pulmonary toll-like receptor expression during respiratory syncytial virus and influenza infections in the cotton rat Sigmodon hispidus model. J Interferon Cytokine Res. 2010 Apr;30(4):229-42. doi: 10.1089/jir.2009.0025.</citation>
    <PMID>20038196</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Burrer S, Ma D, Hughes M, Kuhar D, Luckhaupt S, McDaniel C, et al. Characteristics of Health Care Personnel with COVID-19 - United States, February 12-April 9, 2020. CDC Morbidity and Mortality Report. 2020;69.</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Caskey M, Lefebvre F, Filali-Mouhim A, Cameron MJ, Goulet JP, Haddad EK, Breton G, Trumpfheller C, Pollak S, Shimeliovich I, Duque-Alarcon A, Pan L, Nelkenbaum A, Salazar AM, Schlesinger SJ, Steinman RM, Sékaly RP. Synthetic double-stranded RNA induces innate immune responses similar to a live viral vaccine in humans. J Exp Med. 2011 Nov 21;208(12):2357-66. doi: 10.1084/jem.20111171. Epub 2011 Nov 7.</citation>
    <PMID>22065672</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Christopher ME, Wong JP. Use of TLR3 receptor agaonists against respiratory viral infections. Anti-inflammatory &amp; Anti-Allergy Agents in Medicinal Chemistry. 2011;10:327-38.</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Flynn BJ, Kastenmüller K, Wille-Reece U, Tomaras GD, Alam M, Lindsay RW, Salazar AM, Perdiguero B, Gomez CE, Wagner R, Esteban M, Park CG, Trumpfheller C, Keler T, Pantaleo G, Steinman RM, Seder R. Immunization with HIV Gag targeted to dendritic cells followed by recombinant New York vaccinia virus induces robust T-cell immunity in nonhuman primates. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2011 Apr 26;108(17):7131-6. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1103869108. Epub 2011 Apr 5.</citation>
    <PMID>21467219</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Guerrero-Plata A, Baron S, Poast JS, Adegboyega PA, Casola A, Garofalo RP. Activity and regulation of alpha interferon in respiratory syncytial virus and human metapneumovirus experimental infections. J Virol. 2005 Aug;79(16):10190-9.</citation>
    <PMID>16051812</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hill DA, Baron S, Perkins JC, Worthington M, Van Kirk JE, Mills J, Kapikian AZ, Chanock RM. Evaluation of an interferon inducer in viral respiratory disease. JAMA. 1972 Feb 28;219(9):1179-84.</citation>
    <PMID>4334380</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Huang C, Wang Y, Li X, Ren L, Zhao J, Hu Y, Zhang L, Fan G, Xu J, Gu X, Cheng Z, Yu T, Xia J, Wei Y, Wu W, Xie X, Yin W, Li H, Liu M, Xiao Y, Gao H, Guo L, Xie J, Wang G, Jiang R, Gao Z, Jin Q, Wang J, Cao B. Clinical features of patients infected with 2019 novel coronavirus in Wuhan, China. Lancet. 2020 Feb 15;395(10223):497-506. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30183-5. Epub 2020 Jan 24. Erratum in: Lancet. 2020 Jan 30;:.</citation>
    <PMID>31986264</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kato H, Takeuchi O, Sato S, Yoneyama M, Yamamoto M, Matsui K, Uematsu S, Jung A, Kawai T, Ishii KJ, Yamaguchi O, Otsu K, Tsujimura T, Koh CS, Reis e Sousa C, Matsuura Y, Fujita T, Akira S. Differential roles of MDA5 and RIG-I helicases in the recognition of RNA viruses. Nature. 2006 May 4;441(7089):101-5. Epub 2006 Apr 9.</citation>
    <PMID>16625202</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kende M, Paragas J, Salazar AM. The efficacy of poly-ICLC against Ebola-Zaire virus (EBOV) infection in mice and cynomolgus monkeys. Antiviral Res. 2019 Mar;163:179-184. doi: 10.1016/j.antiviral.2018.12.020. Epub 2019 Jan 3.</citation>
    <PMID>30611774</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kindler E, Gil-Cruz C, Spanier J, Li Y, Wilhelm J, Rabouw HH, Züst R, Hwang M, V'kovski P, Stalder H, Marti S, Habjan M, Cervantes-Barragan L, Elliot R, Karl N, Gaughan C, van Kuppeveld FJ, Silverman RH, Keller M, Ludewig B, Bergmann CC, Ziebuhr J, Weiss SR, Kalinke U, Thiel V. Early endonuclease-mediated evasion of RNA sensing ensures efficient coronavirus replication. PLoS Pathog. 2017 Feb 3;13(2):e1006195. doi: 10.1371/journal.ppat.1006195. eCollection 2017 Feb.</citation>
    <PMID>28158275</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kumaki Y, Salazar AM, Wandersee MK, Barnard DL. Prophylactic and therapeutic intranasal administration with an immunomodulator, Hiltonol(®) (Poly IC:LC), in a lethal SARS-CoV-infected BALB/c mouse model. Antiviral Res. 2017 Mar;139:1-12. doi: 10.1016/j.antiviral.2016.12.007. Epub 2016 Dec 9.</citation>
    <PMID>27956136</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Longhi MP, Trumpfheller C, Idoyaga J, Caskey M, Matos I, Kluger C, Salazar AM, Colonna M, Steinman RM. Dendritic cells require a systemic type I interferon response to mature and induce CD4+ Th1 immunity with poly IC as adjuvant. J Exp Med. 2009 Jul 6;206(7):1589-602. doi: 10.1084/jem.20090247. Epub 2009 Jun 29.</citation>
    <PMID>19564349</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Marcus PI, Sekellick MJ. Combined sequential treatment with interferon and dsRNA abrogates virus resistance to interferon action. J Interferon Cytokine Res. 2001 Jun;21(6):423-9.</citation>
    <PMID>11440640</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Packard AE, Hedges JC, Bahjat FR, Stevens SL, Conlin MJ, Salazar AM, Stenzel-Poore MP. Poly-IC preconditioning protects against cerebral and renal ischemia-reperfusion injury. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2012 Feb;32(2):242-7. doi: 10.1038/jcbfm.2011.160. Epub 2011 Nov 16.</citation>
    <PMID>22086194</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Pavlick A, Blazquez AB, Meseck M, Lattanzi M, Ott PA, Marron TU, Holman RM, Mandeli J, Salazar AM, McClain CB, Gimenez G, Balan S, Gnjatic S, Sabado RL, Bhardwaj N. Combined Vaccination with NY-ESO-1 Protein, Poly-ICLC, and Montanide Improves Humoral and Cellular Immune Responses in Patients with High-Risk Melanoma. Cancer Immunol Res. 2020 Jan;8(1):70-80. doi: 10.1158/2326-6066.CIR-19-0545. Epub 2019 Nov 7.</citation>
    <PMID>31699709</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Rockx B, Baas T, Zornetzer GA, Haagmans B, Sheahan T, Frieman M, Dyer MD, Teal TH, Proll S, van den Brand J, Baric R, Katze MG. Early upregulation of acute respiratory distress syndrome-associated cytokines promotes lethal disease in an aged-mouse model of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus infection. J Virol. 2009 Jul;83(14):7062-74. doi: 10.1128/JVI.00127-09. Epub 2009 May 6. Erratum in: J Virol. 2009 Sep;83(17):9022.</citation>
    <PMID>19420084</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ruan Q, Yang K, Wang W, Jiang L, Song J. Clinical predictors of mortality due to COVID-19 based on an analysis of data of 150 patients from Wuhan, China. Intensive Care Med. 2020 May;46(5):846-848. doi: 10.1007/s00134-020-05991-x. Epub 2020 Mar 3. Erratum in: Intensive Care Med. 2020 Apr 6;:.</citation>
    <PMID>32125452</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sabbatini P, Tsuji T, Ferran L, Ritter E, Sedrak C, Tuballes K, Jungbluth AA, Ritter G, Aghajanian C, Bell-McGuinn K, Hensley ML, Konner J, Tew W, Spriggs DR, Hoffman EW, Venhaus R, Pan L, Salazar AM, Diefenbach CM, Old LJ, Gnjatic S. Phase I trial of overlapping long peptides from a tumor self-antigen and poly-ICLC shows rapid induction of integrated immune response in ovarian cancer patients. Clin Cancer Res. 2012 Dec 1;18(23):6497-508. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-12-2189. Epub 2012 Oct 2.</citation>
    <PMID>23032745</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Salazar AM, Levy HB, Ondra S, Kende M, Scherokman B, Brown D, Mena H, Martin N, Schwab K, Donovan D, Dougherty D, Pulliam M, Ippolito M, Graves M, Brown H, Ommaya A. Long-term treatment of malignant gliomas with intramuscularly administered polyinosinic-polycytidylic acid stabilized with polylysine and carboxymethylcellulose: an open pilot study. Neurosurgery. 1996 Jun;38(6):1096-103; discussion 1103-4.</citation>
    <PMID>8727138</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sultan H, Wu J, Kumai T, Salazar AM, Celis E. Role of MDA5 and interferon-I in dendritic cells for T cell expansion by anti-tumor peptide vaccines in mice. Cancer Immunol Immunother. 2018 Jul;67(7):1091-1103. doi: 10.1007/s00262-018-2164-6. Epub 2018 Apr 25.</citation>
    <PMID>29696308</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Walberg K, Baron S, Poast J, Schwartz B, Izotova L, Pestka S, Peterson JW. Interferon protects mice against inhalation anthrax. J Interferon Cytokine Res. 2008 Oct;28(10):597-601. doi: 10.1089/jir.2007.0143.</citation>
    <PMID>18778201</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Wang Y, Wang Y, Chen Y, Qin Q. Unique epidemiological and clinical features of the emerging 2019 novel coronavirus pneumonia (COVID-19) implicate special control measures. J Med Virol. 2020 Jun;92(6):568-576. doi: 10.1002/jmv.25748. Epub 2020 Mar 29. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32134116</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Wong JP, Christopher ME, Viswanathan S, Dai X, Salazar AM, Sun LQ, Wang M. Antiviral role of toll-like receptor-3 agonists against seasonal and avian influenza viruses. Curr Pharm Des. 2009;15(11):1269-74. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19355966</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Wong JP, Saravolac EG, Sabuda D, Levy HB, Kende M. Prophylactic and therapeutic efficacies of poly(IC.LC) against respiratory influenza A virus infection in mice. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 1995 Nov;39(11):2574-6.</citation>
    <PMID>8585749</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Zhou Q, Chen V, Shannon CP, Wei XS, Xiang X, Wang X, Wang ZH, Tebbutt SJ, Kollmann TR, Fish EN. Interferon-α2b Treatment for COVID-19. Front Immunol. 2020 May 15;11:1061. doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2020.01061. eCollection 2020. Erratum in: Front Immunol. 2020 Oct 27;11:615275.</citation>
    <PMID>32574262</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Zhu X, Fallert-Junecko BA, Fujita M, Ueda R, Kohanbash G, Kastenhuber ER, McDonald HA, Liu Y, Kalinski P, Reinhart TA, Salazar AM, Okada H. Poly-ICLC promotes the infiltration of effector T cells into intracranial gliomas via induction of CXCL10 in IFN-alpha and IFN-gamma dependent manners. Cancer Immunol Immunother. 2010 Sep;59(9):1401-9. doi: 10.1007/s00262-010-0876-3. Epub 2010 Jun 12.</citation>
    <PMID>20549206</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 19, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 19, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 22, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID</keyword>
  <keyword>Prevention</keyword>
  <keyword>Poly-ICLC</keyword>
  <keyword>Viral Infection</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Poly I-C</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carboxymethylcellulose Sodium</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Poly ICLC</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

