<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4927">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03683394</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1R01AG057508</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03683394</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Systematic Multi-domain Alzheimer's Risk Reduction Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>SMARRT</acronym>
  <official_title>Multidomain Alzheimers Risk Reduction Study (MARRS) Pilot</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kaiser Permanente</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of California, San Francisco</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kaiser Permanente</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary goal of this randomized controlled trial (RCT) is to pilot-test a personalized,&#xD;
      pragmatic, multi-domain Alzheimer's disease risk reduction intervention in a U.S. integrated&#xD;
      healthcare delivery system.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      We propose to randomize 200 higher-risk older adults (age 70-89 with low-normal performance&#xD;
      on cognitive testing and 2+ modifiable risk factors that will be targeted by our&#xD;
      intervention) to a two-year Systematic Multi-Domain Alzheimer's Risk Reduction Trial (SMARRT)&#xD;
      intervention or a Health Education (HE) control.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The SMARRT team will work with participants randomized to the intervention arm to develop a&#xD;
      tailored action plan to address risk reduction. Targeted areas will include: increasing&#xD;
      physical, mental and social activities; controlling cardiovascular risk factors (diabetes,&#xD;
      hypertension); quitting smoking; reducing depressive symptoms; improving sleep;&#xD;
      neuroprotective diet; and decreasing use of potentially harmful medications. HE participants&#xD;
      will receive periodic handouts on these topics by mail.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 30, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants will be randomized after baseline assessments to the SMARRT intervention arm or Health Education (HE) control arm. Randomization will be stratified by clinic, race/ethnicity (non-Hispanic white vs. non-white or Hispanic) and age (70-79, 80-89).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cognitive Change</measure>
    <time_frame>2 Years</time_frame>
    <description>Cognitive function will be measured by the modified Neuropsychological Test Battery (mNTB) global score, which is a composite z score, an average of z scores from tests of several cognitive domains. The total score is reported. Higher values signify higher cognitive performance.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Improvement in Targeted Risk Factors</measure>
    <time_frame>2 Years</time_frame>
    <description>Risk factors include poorly controlled hypertension, diabetes with evidence of hyper- or hypoglycemia, depressive symptoms, poor sleep quality, contraindicated medications, physical inactivity, low cognitive stimulation, social isolation, poor diet, and smoking. We will use a combination of validated objective and self-report measures as well as electronic health record (EHR) data to assess changes in Alzheimer's risk factors.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical Performance</measure>
    <time_frame>2 Years</time_frame>
    <description>Measured with Short Physical Performance Battery (SPPB)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional Ability</measure>
    <time_frame>2 Years</time_frame>
    <description>Measured with Cognitive Function Instrument (CFI)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life Measure</measure>
    <time_frame>2 Years</time_frame>
    <description>Measured with Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS) Global Health</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Mild Cognitive Impairment, Alzheimer's Disease, and Dementia</measure>
    <time_frame>2 Years</time_frame>
    <description>consensus conferences using standard clinical criteria</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">172</enrollment>
  <condition>Dementia</condition>
  <condition>Alzheimer Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SMARRT Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The SMARRT intervention team will use a standardized procedure to develop an individualized Alzheimer's risk profile for each participant randomized to the SMARRT intervention arm. Participants will then meet in-person with an interventionist to review their risk profile and develop an initial personalized risk reduction action plan. For the few participants enrolled during COVID, initial interventionist visits were conducted by phone. Targeted areas will include: increasing physical, mental and social activities; quitting smoking; healthy diet; controlling cardiovascular risk factors (diabetes, hypertension), including avoiding hypoglycemia in people with diabetes; reducing depressive symptoms; improving sleep; and decreasing use of potentially harmful medications.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Health Education Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the Health Education arm will be mailed general information that will address factors that will be targeted in the SMARRT intervention, including physical, mental and social engagement; management of cardiovascular risk factors; quitting smoking, healthy diet; depression; sleep; and contraindicated medications. HE participants will not be provided with personalized information about their risk of Alzheimer's and dementia.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SMARRT Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Interventionists will follow a standard protocol for delivering the SMARRT intervention that allows for personalization of the specific risk reduction action plan; these plans will evolve over time according to participant progress, motivation and preferences or newly identified risk factors. Staff will use a tracking database to record information for each participant, including session dates, identified risk factors, motivational barriers and important values, and the outcome of discussions around developing goals. For each participant, the exact number and mode (phone or in-person) of contacts will differ, but we will aim to have at least 1 contact per month with each participant. Best practice will include in-person meetings twice a year during the 2-year intervention period.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SMARRT Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Health Education Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants randomized to the Health Education (HE) group will receive mailed materials (typically 1-2 pages) every 3 months. This will include general information on Alzheimer's and dementia risk reduction using materials from sources such as the Alzheimer's Association and educational materials commonly provided as part of routine care at Kaiser Permanente Washington (KPWA).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Health Education Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  70-89 Years of Age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fluent in the English Language&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Low-normal performance on a brief telephone cognitive screen, measured using the&#xD;
             Cognitive Abilities Screening Instruments (CASI). Low-normal scores are defined as&#xD;
             26-29.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has at least two additional risk factors that will be targeted by the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residing in a skilled nursing or rehabilitation facility&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving palliative care or hospice services&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Charlson comorbidity index score of greater than 5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bipolar illness or schizophrenia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current alcohol or drug use disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving chronic opioid therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parkinson's disease, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, or multiple sclerosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe visual or hearing impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Requests not to be contacted or not to have their medical record reviewed for research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior evidence of dementia&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>70 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eric B Larson, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kristine Yaffe, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, San Francisco</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98101</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Alzheimer's Disease International. World Alzheimer Report 2015: The Global Impact of Dementia, An Analysis of Prevalence, Incidence, Cost and Trends. London: Alzheimer's Disease International (ADI); 2015.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Alzheimer's Association. 2017 Alzheimer's disease facts and figures. Alzheimer's &amp; dementia : the journal of the Alzheimer's Association. 2017;13:325-373.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Atri A, Frölich L, Ballard C, Tariot PN, Molinuevo JL, Boneva N, Windfeld K, Raket LL, Cummings JL. Effect of Idalopirdine as Adjunct to Cholinesterase Inhibitors on Change in Cognition in Patients With Alzheimer Disease: Three Randomized Clinical Trials. JAMA. 2018 Jan 9;319(2):130-142. doi: 10.1001/jama.2017.20373.</citation>
    <PMID>29318278</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bezprozvanny I. The rise and fall of Dimebon. Drug News Perspect. 2010 Oct;23(8):518-23. doi: 10.1358/dnp.2010.23.8.1500435.</citation>
    <PMID>21031168</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cummings JL, Morstorf T, Zhong K. Alzheimer's disease drug-development pipeline: few candidates, frequent failures. Alzheimers Res Ther. 2014 Jul 3;6(4):37. doi: 10.1186/alzrt269. eCollection 2014.</citation>
    <PMID>25024750</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fagan T. Clinical Trials of Intravenous Bapineuzumab Halted. Alzheimer Research Forum onlineAugust 8, 2012.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fagan T. Lilly Halts IDENTITY Trials as Patients Worsen on Secretase Inhibitor. Alzheimer Research Forum onlineAugust 18, 2010.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Honig LS, Vellas B, Woodward M, Boada M, Bullock R, Borrie M, Hager K, Andreasen N, Scarpini E, Liu-Seifert H, Case M, Dean RA, Hake A, Sundell K, Poole Hoffmann V, Carlson C, Khanna R, Mintun M, DeMattos R, Selzler KJ, Siemers E. Trial of Solanezumab for Mild Dementia Due to Alzheimer's Disease. N Engl J Med. 2018 Jan 25;378(4):321-330. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1705971.</citation>
    <PMID>29365294</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jeffrey S. IVIG Fails in Phase 3 for Alzheimer's. Medscape Today May 7, 2013.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Salloway S, Sperling R, Fox NC, Blennow K, Klunk W, Raskind M, Sabbagh M, Honig LS, Porsteinsson AP, Ferris S, Reichert M, Ketter N, Nejadnik B, Guenzler V, Miloslavsky M, Wang D, Lu Y, Lull J, Tudor IC, Liu E, Grundman M, Yuen E, Black R, Brashear HR; Bapineuzumab 301 and 302 Clinical Trial Investigators. Two phase 3 trials of bapineuzumab in mild-to-moderate Alzheimer's disease. N Engl J Med. 2014 Jan 23;370(4):322-33. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1304839.</citation>
    <PMID>24450891</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Larson EB, Yaffe K, Langa KM. New insights into the dementia epidemic. N Engl J Med. 2013 Dec 12;369(24):2275-7. doi: 10.1056/NEJMp1311405. Epub 2013 Nov 27.</citation>
    <PMID>24283198</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yaffe K. Modifiable Risk Factors and Prevention of Dementia: What Is the Latest Evidence? JAMA Intern Med. 2018 Feb 1;178(2):281-282. doi: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2017.7299.</citation>
    <PMID>29255907</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Barnes DE, Yaffe K. The projected effect of risk factor reduction on Alzheimer's disease prevalence. Lancet Neurol. 2011 Sep;10(9):819-28. doi: 10.1016/S1474-4422(11)70072-2. Epub 2011 Jul 19. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21775213</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Norton S, Matthews FE, Barnes DE, Yaffe K, Brayne C. Potential for primary prevention of Alzheimer's disease: an analysis of population-based data. Lancet Neurol. 2014 Aug;13(8):788-94. doi: 10.1016/S1474-4422(14)70136-X. Erratum in: Lancet Neurol. 2014 Nov;13(11):1070.</citation>
    <PMID>25030513</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Langa KM, Larson EB, Crimmins EM, Faul JD, Levine DA, Kabeto MU, Weir DR. A Comparison of the Prevalence of Dementia in the United States in 2000 and 2012. JAMA Intern Med. 2017 Jan 1;177(1):51-58. doi: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2016.6807.</citation>
    <PMID>27893041</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Manton KC, Gu XL, Ukraintseva SV. Declining prevalence of dementia in the U.S. elderly population. Adv Gerontol. 2005;16:30-7.</citation>
    <PMID>16075674</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Matthews FE, Arthur A, Barnes LE, Bond J, Jagger C, Robinson L, Brayne C; Medical Research Council Cognitive Function and Ageing Collaboration. A two-decade comparison of prevalence of dementia in individuals aged 65 years and older from three geographical areas of England: results of the Cognitive Function and Ageing Study I and II. Lancet. 2013 Oct 26;382(9902):1405-12. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(13)61570-6. Epub 2013 Jul 17.</citation>
    <PMID>23871492</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Qiu C, von Strauss E, Bäckman L, Winblad B, Fratiglioni L. Twenty-year changes in dementia occurrence suggest decreasing incidence in central Stockholm, Sweden. Neurology. 2013 May 14;80(20):1888-94. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e318292a2f9. Epub 2013 Apr 17.</citation>
    <PMID>23596063</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rocca WA, Petersen RC, Knopman DS, Hebert LE, Evans DA, Hall KS, Gao S, Unverzagt FW, Langa KM, Larson EB, White LR. Trends in the incidence and prevalence of Alzheimer's disease, dementia, and cognitive impairment in the United States. Alzheimers Dement. 2011 Jan;7(1):80-93. doi: 10.1016/j.jalz.2010.11.002.</citation>
    <PMID>21255746</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schrijvers EM, Verhaaren BF, Koudstaal PJ, Hofman A, Ikram MA, Breteler MM. Is dementia incidence declining?: Trends in dementia incidence since 1990 in the Rotterdam Study. Neurology. 2012 May 8;78(19):1456-63. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182553be6. Epub 2012 May 2.</citation>
    <PMID>22551732</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu YT, Beiser AS, Breteler MMB, Fratiglioni L, Helmer C, Hendrie HC, Honda H, Ikram MA, Langa KM, Lobo A, Matthews FE, Ohara T, Pérès K, Qiu C, Seshadri S, Sjölund BM, Skoog I, Brayne C. The changing prevalence and incidence of dementia over time - current evidence. Nat Rev Neurol. 2017 Jun;13(6):327-339. doi: 10.1038/nrneurol.2017.63. Epub 2017 May 12. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28497805</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lee KS, Lee Y, Back JH, Son SJ, Choi SH, Chung YK, Lim KY, Noh JS, Koh SH, Oh BH, Hong CH. Effects of a multidomain lifestyle modification on cognitive function in older adults: an eighteen-month community-based cluster randomized controlled trial. Psychother Psychosom. 2014;83(5):270-8. doi: 10.1159/000360820. Epub 2014 Aug 6.</citation>
    <PMID>25116574</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ngandu T, Lehtisalo J, Solomon A, Levälahti E, Ahtiluoto S, Antikainen R, Bäckman L, Hänninen T, Jula A, Laatikainen T, Lindström J, Mangialasche F, Paajanen T, Pajala S, Peltonen M, Rauramaa R, Stigsdotter-Neely A, Strandberg T, Tuomilehto J, Soininen H, Kivipelto M. A 2 year multidomain intervention of diet, exercise, cognitive training, and vascular risk monitoring versus control to prevent cognitive decline in at-risk elderly people (FINGER): a randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2015 Jun 6;385(9984):2255-63. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(15)60461-5. Epub 2015 Mar 12.</citation>
    <PMID>25771249</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rosenberg A, Ngandu T, Rusanen M, Antikainen R, Bäckman L, Havulinna S, Hänninen T, Laatikainen T, Lehtisalo J, Levälahti E, Lindström J, Paajanen T, Peltonen M, Soininen H, Stigsdotter-Neely A, Strandberg T, Tuomilehto J, Solomon A, Kivipelto M. Multidomain lifestyle intervention benefits a large elderly population at risk for cognitive decline and dementia regardless of baseline characteristics: The FINGER trial. Alzheimers Dement. 2018 Mar;14(3):263-270. doi: 10.1016/j.jalz.2017.09.006. Epub 2017 Oct 19.</citation>
    <PMID>29055814</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Andrieu S, Guyonnet S, Coley N, Cantet C, Bonnefoy M, Bordes S, Bories L, Cufi MN, Dantoine T, Dartigues JF, Desclaux F, Gabelle A, Gasnier Y, Pesce A, Sudres K, Touchon J, Robert P, Rouaud O, Legrand P, Payoux P, Caubere JP, Weiner M, Carrié I, Ousset PJ, Vellas B; MAPT Study Group. Effect of long-term omega 3 polyunsaturated fatty acid supplementation with or without multidomain intervention on cognitive function in elderly adults with memory complaints (MAPT): a randomised, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2017 May;16(5):377-389. doi: 10.1016/S1474-4422(17)30040-6. Epub 2017 Mar 27.</citation>
    <PMID>28359749</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lam LC, Chan WC, Leung T, Fung AW, Leung EM. Would older adults with mild cognitive impairment adhere to and benefit from a structured lifestyle activity intervention to enhance cognition?: a cluster randomized controlled trial. PLoS One. 2015 Mar 31;10(3):e0118173. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0118173. eCollection 2015.</citation>
    <PMID>25826620</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Moll van Charante EP, Richard E, Eurelings LS, van Dalen JW, Ligthart SA, van Bussel EF, Hoevenaar-Blom MP, Vermeulen M, van Gool WA. Effectiveness of a 6-year multidomain vascular care intervention to prevent dementia (preDIVA): a cluster-randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2016 Aug 20;388(10046):797-805. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(16)30950-3. Epub 2016 Jul 26.</citation>
    <PMID>27474376</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Teng EL, Hasegawa K, Homma A, Imai Y, Larson E, Graves A, Sugimoto K, Yamaguchi T, Sasaki H, Chiu D, et al. The Cognitive Abilities Screening Instrument (CASI): a practical test for cross-cultural epidemiological studies of dementia. Int Psychogeriatr. 1994 Spring;6(1):45-58; discussion 62.</citation>
    <PMID>8054493</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kukull WA, Higdon R, Bowen JD, McCormick WC, Teri L, Schellenberg GD, van Belle G, Jolley L, Larson EB. Dementia and Alzheimer disease incidence: a prospective cohort study. Arch Neurol. 2002 Nov;59(11):1737-46.</citation>
    <PMID>12433261</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Corrada MM, Brookmeyer R, Paganini-Hill A, Berlau D, Kawas CH. Dementia incidence continues to increase with age in the oldest old: the 90+ study. Ann Neurol. 2010 Jan;67(1):114-21. doi: 10.1002/ana.21915.</citation>
    <PMID>20186856</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Charlson M, Szatrowski TP, Peterson J, Gold J. Validation of a combined comorbidity index. J Clin Epidemiol. 1994 Nov;47(11):1245-51.</citation>
    <PMID>7722560</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kivipelto M, Solomon A, Ahtiluoto S, Ngandu T, Lehtisalo J, Antikainen R, Bäckman L, Hänninen T, Jula A, Laatikainen T, Lindström J, Mangialasche F, Nissinen A, Paajanen T, Pajala S, Peltonen M, Rauramaa R, Stigsdotter-Neely A, Strandberg T, Tuomilehto J, Soininen H. The Finnish Geriatric Intervention Study to Prevent Cognitive Impairment and Disability (FINGER): study design and progress. Alzheimers Dement. 2013 Nov;9(6):657-65. doi: 10.1016/j.jalz.2012.09.012. Epub 2013 Jan 17.</citation>
    <PMID>23332672</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Harrison J, Minassian SL, Jenkins L, Black RS, Koller M, Grundman M. A neuropsychological test battery for use in Alzheimer disease clinical trials. Arch Neurol. 2007 Sep;64(9):1323-9.</citation>
    <PMID>17846273</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Harrison J, Rentz DM, McLaughlin T, Niecko T, Gregg KM, Black RS, Buchanan J, Liu E, Grundman M; ELN-AIP-901 Study Investigator Group. Cognition in MCI and Alzheimer's disease: baseline data from a longitudinal study of the NTB. Clin Neuropsychol. 2014;28(2):252-68. doi: 10.1080/13854046.2013.875595. Epub 2014 Feb 13.</citation>
    <PMID>24521259</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Topolski TD, LoGerfo J, Patrick DL, Williams B, Walwick J, Patrick MB. The Rapid Assessment of Physical Activity (RAPA) among older adults. Prev Chronic Dis. 2006 Oct;3(4):A118. Epub 2006 Sep 15. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>16978493</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hahn EA, Beaumont JL, Pilkonis PA, Garcia SF, Magasi S, DeWalt DA, Cella D. The PROMIS satisfaction with social participation measures demonstrated responsiveness in diverse clinical populations. J Clin Epidemiol. 2016 May;73:135-41. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2015.08.034. Epub 2016 Feb 27.</citation>
    <PMID>26931288</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vemuri P, Lesnick TG, Przybelski SA, Machulda M, Knopman DS, Mielke MM, Roberts RO, Geda YE, Rocca WA, Petersen RC, Jack CR Jr. Association of lifetime intellectual enrichment with cognitive decline in the older population. JAMA Neurol. 2014 Aug;71(8):1017-24. doi: 10.1001/jamaneurol.2014.963.</citation>
    <PMID>25054282</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Morris MC, Tangney CC, Wang Y, Sacks FM, Barnes LL, Bennett DA, Aggarwal NT. MIND diet slows cognitive decline with aging. Alzheimers Dement. 2015 Sep;11(9):1015-22. doi: 10.1016/j.jalz.2015.04.011. Epub 2015 Jun 15.</citation>
    <PMID>26086182</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Morris MC, Tangney CC, Wang Y, Sacks FM, Bennett DA, Aggarwal NT. MIND diet associated with reduced incidence of Alzheimer's disease. Alzheimers Dement. 2015 Sep;11(9):1007-14. doi: 10.1016/j.jalz.2014.11.009. Epub 2015 Feb 11.</citation>
    <PMID>25681666</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Radloff LS. The CES-D scale: A self-report depression scale for research in the general population. Applied Psychological Measurement. 1977;1(3):385-401.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF 3rd, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989 May;28(2):193-213.</citation>
    <PMID>2748771</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>By the American Geriatrics Society 2015 Beers Criteria Update Expert Panel. American Geriatrics Society 2015 Updated Beers Criteria for Potentially Inappropriate Medication Use in Older Adults. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2015 Nov;63(11):2227-46. doi: 10.1111/jgs.13702. Epub 2015 Oct 8.</citation>
    <PMID>26446832</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Guralnik JM, Simonsick EM, Ferrucci L, Glynn RJ, Berkman LF, Blazer DG, Scherr PA, Wallace RB. A short physical performance battery assessing lower extremity function: association with self-reported disability and prediction of mortality and nursing home admission. J Gerontol. 1994 Mar;49(2):M85-94.</citation>
    <PMID>8126356</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Amariglio RE, Donohue MC, Marshall GA, Rentz DM, Salmon DP, Ferris SH, Karantzoulis S, Aisen PS, Sperling RA; Alzheimer's Disease Cooperative Study. Tracking early decline in cognitive function in older individuals at risk for Alzheimer disease dementia: the Alzheimer's Disease Cooperative Study Cognitive Function Instrument. JAMA Neurol. 2015 Apr;72(4):446-54. doi: 10.1001/jamaneurol.2014.3375. Erratum in: JAMA Neurol. 2015 May;72(5):608.</citation>
    <PMID>25706191</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hays RD, Bjorner JB, Revicki DA, Spritzer KL, Cella D. Development of physical and mental health summary scores from the patient-reported outcomes measurement information system (PROMIS) global items. Qual Life Res. 2009 Sep;18(7):873-80. doi: 10.1007/s11136-009-9496-9. Epub 2009 Jun 19.</citation>
    <PMID>19543809</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Petersen RC, Lopez O, Armstrong MJ, Getchius TSD, Ganguli M, Gloss D, Gronseth GS, Marson D, Pringsheim T, Day GS, Sager M, Stevens J, Rae-Grant A. Practice guideline update summary: Mild cognitive impairment: Report of the Guideline Development, Dissemination, and Implementation Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2018 Jan 16;90(3):126-135. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0000000000004826. Epub 2017 Dec 27.</citation>
    <PMID>29282327</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sperling RA, Aisen PS, Beckett LA, Bennett DA, Craft S, Fagan AM, Iwatsubo T, Jack CR Jr, Kaye J, Montine TJ, Park DC, Reiman EM, Rowe CC, Siemers E, Stern Y, Yaffe K, Carrillo MC, Thies B, Morrison-Bogorad M, Wagster MV, Phelps CH. Toward defining the preclinical stages of Alzheimer's disease: recommendations from the National Institute on Aging-Alzheimer's Association workgroups on diagnostic guidelines for Alzheimer's disease. Alzheimers Dement. 2011 May;7(3):280-92. doi: 10.1016/j.jalz.2011.03.003. Epub 2011 Apr 21.</citation>
    <PMID>21514248</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Winblad B, Palmer K, Kivipelto M, Jelic V, Fratiglioni L, Wahlund LO, Nordberg A, Bäckman L, Albert M, Almkvist O, Arai H, Basun H, Blennow K, de Leon M, DeCarli C, Erkinjuntti T, Giacobini E, Graff C, Hardy J, Jack C, Jorm A, Ritchie K, van Duijn C, Visser P, Petersen RC. Mild cognitive impairment--beyond controversies, towards a consensus: report of the International Working Group on Mild Cognitive Impairment. J Intern Med. 2004 Sep;256(3):240-6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15324367</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences (2nd ed). Hillsdale, N.J.: Lawrence Earlbaum Associates; 1988.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Li C, Friedman B, Conwell Y, Fiscella K. Validity of the Patient Health Questionnaire 2 (PHQ-2) in identifying major depression in older people. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2007 Apr;55(4):596-602.</citation>
    <PMID>17397440</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kroenke K, Strine TW, Spitzer RL, Williams JB, Berry JT, Mokdad AH. The PHQ-8 as a measure of current depression in the general population. J Affect Disord. 2009 Apr;114(1-3):163-73. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2008.06.026. Epub 2008 Aug 27.</citation>
    <PMID>18752852</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 20, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 21, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 25, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 8, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 8, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 10, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alzheimer Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

