<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3922">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04380961</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CR108820</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>CNTO136COV2001</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-003056-32</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04380961</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Sirukumab in Confirmed Severe or Critical Confirmed Coronavirus Disease (COVID)-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase 2, Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Sirukumab in Confirmed Severe or Critical COVID-19 Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Janssen Pharmaceutica N.V., Belgium</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Janssen Pharmaceutica N.V., Belgium</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the clinical response of sirukumab (administered as&#xD;
      a single intravenous dose) plus standard of care (SOC) compared to placebo plus SOC in&#xD;
      COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2), the causative agent of&#xD;
      coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), is an enveloped, positive-sense, single-stranded&#xD;
      ribonucleic acid (RNA) betacoronavirus. Symptoms of COVID-19 infection may appear from 2 to&#xD;
      14 days following exposure, with the spectrum of illnesses ranging from mild symptoms to&#xD;
      severe illness or death. The identification of SARS-CoV-2 follows the emergence of 2 other&#xD;
      novel betacoronaviruses: SARS-CoV and Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus&#xD;
      (MERS-CoV). Current management of COVID-19 is supportive, and respiratory failure from acute&#xD;
      respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) is the leading cause of mortality. While an&#xD;
      understanding of the epidemiology and clinical spectrum of COVID-19 is still evolving during&#xD;
      the ongoing pandemic, the current knowledge of the disease burden highlights the urgent&#xD;
      medical need to develop a treatment. Sirukumab (also known as CNTO136) is a human&#xD;
      anti-interleukin (IL)-6 immunoglobulin G1 kappa (IgG1k) monoclonal antibody (mAb). Sirukumab&#xD;
      binds with high affinity and specificity to human IL-6 and as a result inhibits IL-6-mediated&#xD;
      signaling and the biological effects of IL-6. The study will include a Screening Phase (up to&#xD;
      1 Day), a Treatment Phase (Day 1 to Day 28) and a Follow-up Phase (post Day 28, follow-up&#xD;
      phone calls on Week 8, Week 12 and Week 16). Safety evaluations will include monitoring of&#xD;
      adverse events and serious adverse events, physical examinations, vital sign measurements,&#xD;
      electrocardiograms, clinical laboratory tests, pregnancy testing, and checking of vital&#xD;
      status. The entire study duration for each participant will be 16 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 24, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 28, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 28, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Improvement of at Least 2 Categories Relative to Baseline on the 6-Point Ordinal Clinical Recovery Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Time to improvement is defined as an improvement of at least 2 categories relative to baseline on the 6-point ordinal clinical recovery scale. The 6-point ordinal clinical recovery scale provides 6 mutually exclusive conditions ordered from best to worst, and the score reflects the participant's worst situation on the day assessed. The ordinal clinical recovery scale categories are : not hospitalized (category 1); Hospitalization; not requiring supplemental oxygen (category 2); hospitalized, requiring low flow supplemental oxygen (category 3); hospitalized, on non-invasive pressure ventilation or high flow oxygen devices (category 4); hospitalized, on invasive mechanical ventilation or extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO (category 5); death (category 6).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with an Improvement of at Least 2 Categories Relative to Baseline on the 6-Point Ordinal Clinical Recovery Scale on Day 28</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with an improvement of at Least 2 categories relative to baseline on the 6-point ordinal clinical recovery scale on Day 28 will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with All-cause Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with all-cause mortality will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>A SAE is any adverse event (AE) that results in: death, is life-threatening, requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of existing hospitalization, results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity, is a congenital anomaly/birth defect and is a suspected transmission of any infectious agent via a medicinal product, is medically important.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Related Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical study participant administered a medicinal (investigational or non-investigational) product.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Severe or Life Threatening Bacterial, Invasive Fungal, Viral or Opportunistic Infections</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with severe or life-threatening, bacterial, invasive fungal, viral or opportunistic infections (other than severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 [SARS-CoV-2]) will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Grade 3 and 4 Neutropenia</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with grade 3 (severe) or 4 (life-threatening) neutropenia will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Grade 3 and 4 Lymphocytopenia</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with grade 3 (severe) or 4 (life-threatening) lymphocytopenia will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Increased Alanine Aminotransferase (ALT) Greater than or equal to 3 Times Upper Limit of Normal (ULN) Combined with Increased Bilirubin &gt; 2 Times ULN</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with increased ALT &gt;=3 times ULN combined with increased bilirubin &gt;2 times ULN (up to Day 28) will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Improvement of at least 1 Category Relative to Baseline on the 6-Point Ordinal Clinical Recovery Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Time to improvement of at least 1 category relative to baseline on the 6-point ordinal clinical recovery scale will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with an Improvement of at Least 1 Category Relative to Baseline on the 6-Point Ordinal Clinical Recovery Scale on Day 28</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with an improvement of at Least 1 category relative to baseline on the 6-point ordinal clinical recovery scale on Day 28 will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time from Study Intervention to end of Oxygen Supplementation</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Time from study intervention to end of oxygen supplementation is defined as achieving category 1 or 2 on the 6-point ordinal clinical recovery scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time from Study Intervention to Hospital Discharge Among the Surviving Participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Time from study intervention to hospital discharge among the surviving participants will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total Length of Hospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Total length of hospitalization (days from admission to hospital discharge) among the surviving participants will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Ventilation Free Days</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Number of Ventilation free Days will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Participant's Clinical Status at Day 7, 14, 21, 28 as Assessed by 6-Point Ordinal Clinical Recovery Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7, 14, 21, 28</time_frame>
    <description>Participant's clinical status at Day 7, 14, 21, 28 will be assessed by 6-point ordinal clinical recovery scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total Time on Invasive Mechanical Ventilation</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Total time on invasive mechanical ventilation will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with a Worse Category Relative to Baseline on the 6-Point Ordinal Clinical Recovery Scale over Time</measure>
    <time_frame>From Day 5 up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of participants with a worsening of at least 1 category on the 6-point ordinal clinical recovery scale over time (between Day 5 and Day 28) will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants on Extracorporeal Membrane Oxygenation (ECMO) Over Time</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage participants on ECMO over time will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total Time on ECMO</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Total time on ECMO will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Alive Participants at Day 28, Week 8 and Week 16</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28, Week 8 and Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of alive participants at Day 28, Week 8 and Week 16 will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Alive Participants that Required Readmission at Week 8 and Week 16</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 8 and Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of alive participants that required readmission (if previously discharged) at Week 8 and Week 16 will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>A SAE is any adverse event (AE) that results in: death, is life-threatening, requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of existing hospitalization, results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity, is a congenital anomaly/birth defect and is a suspected transmission of any infectious agent via a medicinal product, is medically important.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">270</enrollment>
  <condition>Severe or Critical Confirmed Coronavirus Disease (COVID)-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sirukumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive single intravenously (IV) dose infusion of sirukumab 5 milligram per kilogram (mg/kg) on Day 1 along with standard of care treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive IV single dose infusion of placebo on Day 1 along with standard of care treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sirukumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive sirukumab 5 mg/kg IV single dose infusion on Day 1.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sirukumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CNTO136</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive placebo IV single dose infusion on Day 1.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard of Care (SOC)</intervention_name>
    <description>SOC treatment will be determined by the investigator based on local practice and consists of supportive care.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sirukumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hospitalized&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has laboratory-confirmed severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2)&#xD;
             infection as determined by real time-polymerase chain reaction (PCR) at any time&#xD;
             before randomization&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of infiltrates by chest X-ray, chest computed tomography (CT), lung&#xD;
             ultrasound, or chest auscultation (rales, crackles)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent must be obtained from the participant indicating that he or she&#xD;
             understands the purpose of, and procedures required for, the study and is willing to&#xD;
             participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SEVERE OR CRITICAL COVID-19 DISEASE: Severe disease: requires supplemental oxygen&#xD;
             administration by nasal cannula, simple face mask, or other similar oxygen delivery&#xD;
             device. Critical disease: Requires supplemental oxygen delivered by nonrebreather mask&#xD;
             or high-flow nasal cannula or use of non-invasive or invasive ventilation or requiring&#xD;
             treatment in an intensive care unit.&#xD;
&#xD;
        AND at least one of the following: Not receiving supplemental oxygen and having a&#xD;
        peripheral capillary oxygen saturation (SpO2) of &lt;=93% sustained for 5 minutes (corresponds&#xD;
        to category 3 on the 6-point ordinal scale) OR receiving supplemental oxygen to sustain a&#xD;
        peripheral capillary oxygen saturation (SpO2) greater than (&gt;) 93 percent (%) regardless of&#xD;
        device/route used, OR partial pressure of oxygen in arterial per percentage of inspired&#xD;
        oxygen (PaO2/FiO2) ratio &lt; 300 millimeter of mercury (mmHg) while on invasive mechanical&#xD;
        ventilation or veno-venous ECMO for less than 48 hours prior to screening) (corresponds to&#xD;
        category 5 on the 6-point ordinal scale)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  On invasive mechanical ventilation or on veno-venous ECMO for &gt;48 hours at time of&#xD;
             screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received an investigational intervention (including investigational vaccines) or used&#xD;
             an invasive investigational medical device within 30 days before the planned dose of&#xD;
             study intervention. Note: the investigator must ensure that the participant is not&#xD;
             enrolled in another COVID-19 study with an investigational intervention (apart from&#xD;
             the exception specified below) prior to completion of Day 28 of the current study.&#xD;
             Exception: participation in a single arm study, a non-blinded controlled study,&#xD;
             expanded access, compassionate use program or any other program that is not a blinded&#xD;
             study is allowed if it is conducted with one of the following: agents with&#xD;
             demonstrated in vitro-effect against SARSCoV- 2, as mentioned in the center of disease&#xD;
             control and prevention (CDC) guidelines and convalescent plasma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current confirmed or high suspicion for pulmonary embolus, hemodynamic significant&#xD;
             pericardial effusion, myocarditis, or Class 3 or 4 congestive heart failure as defined&#xD;
             by the New York Heart Association Functional Classification AND/OR Current evidence of&#xD;
             active cardiac ischemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of respiratory condition (that is, asthma, chronic obstructive pulmonary&#xD;
             disease (COPD), cystic fibrosis, fibrotic lung disease) that requires home oxygen&#xD;
             supplementation, supportive non-invasive ventilation or, is status/post lung volume&#xD;
             reduction surgery (LVRS). Exception: Participants with sleep apnea using supportive&#xD;
             non-invasive ventilation (continuous positive airway pressure [CPAP]) at screening may&#xD;
             be included&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  On renal replacement therapy (defined as peritoneal dialysis or hemodialysis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Screening laboratory test result as follows: absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt;1.0*10^3&#xD;
             cells/microliter; Platelet count &lt;50*10^3 cells/microliter; estimated glomerular&#xD;
             filtration rate (eGFR) &lt;=30 milliliter per minute per 1.73 square meter (mL/min/1.73&#xD;
             m^2); Bilirubin &gt;2* upper limit of normal (ULN) unless bilirubin rise is due to&#xD;
             Gilbert's syndrome or of non-hepatic origin; alanine aminotransferase/ aspartate&#xD;
             aminotransferase (ALT) &gt;5*ULN; Prothrombin time (PT)/international normalized ratio&#xD;
             (INR) &gt;1.5*ULN or activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) &gt;1.5*ULN related to&#xD;
             known coagulopathy or bleeding disorder (the participant can receive anticoagulant&#xD;
             therapies for underlying conditions, or as systematic thromboprophylaxis due to&#xD;
             COVID-19, or as part of the treatment of complications of COVID-19, but cannot&#xD;
             participate in a clinical study with anticoagulants for COVID-19)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding, unless in the opinion of the investigator, the benefit&#xD;
             outweighs the risks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has active hepatitis B or C infection or human immunodeficiency virus infection or&#xD;
             acquired immune deficiency syndrome (HIV/AIDS) based on medical history and/or&#xD;
             concomitant medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known active or latent tuberculosis (TB), history of incompletely treated TB,&#xD;
             suspected or known extrapulmonary TB based on medical history and/or concomitant&#xD;
             medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of active bacterial (including but not limited to bacterial pneumonia),&#xD;
             fungal, viral or opportunistic infection (other than SARS-CoV-2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently active clinically significant (example, causing hemodynamic instability&#xD;
             and/or causing hypoxemia) and uncontrolled arrhythmia&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>84 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janssen Pharmaceutica N.V., Belgium Clinical Trial</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Janssen Pharmaceutica N.V., Belgium</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Study Contact</last_name>
    <phone>844-434-4210</phone>
    <email>JNJ.CT@sylogent.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCSF Fresno</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fresno</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>93701</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MemorialCare Research Miller Children's and Women's Hospital Long Beach</name>
      <address>
        <city>Long Beach</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90806</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hoag Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Newport Beach</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92663</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sutter Institute for Medical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roseville</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95661</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sutter Medical Foundation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95816</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Holy Cross Hospital - Michael and Dianne Bienes Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Lauderdale</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33308</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Corporation of Mercer University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Macon</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>31201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Great Lakes Clinical Trials</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60640</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Loyola University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Maywood</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60153</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Illinois College of Medicine at Peoria</name>
      <address>
        <city>Peoria</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>61637</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Louisiana State University Health Sciences Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Orleans</city>
        <state>Louisiana</state>
        <zip>70012</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Henry Ford Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Beaumont Health Systems</name>
      <address>
        <city>Royal Oak</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48073</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington University School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mercury Street Medical Group, PLLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Butte</city>
        <state>Montana</state>
        <zip>59701</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Saint Michael's Medical Center - Infectious Disease</name>
      <address>
        <city>Newark</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07102</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>SUNY Upstate Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Syracuse</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>13210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>East Carolina University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Greenville</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27834</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baylor Scott &amp; White Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75246</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baylor All Saints Medical Center at Fort Worth</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Worth</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>76104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
    <country>Brazil</country>
    <country>Mexico</country>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
    <country>South Africa</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://pam.sylogent.com/cr/CR108820</url>
    <description>To learn how to participate in this trial please click here.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 7, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 8, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The data sharing policy of the Janssen Pharmaceutical Companies of Johnson &amp; Johnson is available at www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency.&#xD;
As noted on this site, requests for access to the study data can be submitted through Yale Open Data Access (YODA) Project site at yoda.yale.edu</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>https://www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

