<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4661">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04663594</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0009275</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04663594</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Online Culture for Mental Health in People Aged 16-24</brief_title>
  <acronym>O-ACEPOP</acronym>
  <official_title>An Online Cultural Experience to Support Mental Health in People Aged 16-24 During COVID-19: the O-ACEPOP (Online Active Community Engagement Proof of Principle) Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Oxford</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Oxford</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      O-ACE POP is a randomised controlled trial of an online cultural experience named Ways of&#xD;
      Being, compared to a typical museum website (the Ashmolean Museum). The primary aim is to&#xD;
      compare these two interventions by efficacy on mood, distress (depression and anxiety),&#xD;
      flourishing and investigate potential mechanisms of action, as well as the feasibility of a&#xD;
      larger scale RCT.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      People of target age will be actively recruited with a link to Participant information and&#xD;
      E-consent procedures for those who fulfil inclusion criteria and consent to entering their&#xD;
      email address.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consenting participants will enter a demographic questionnaire. Participants will then be&#xD;
      emailed a unique ID number and requested to complete a baseline assessment on a computer,&#xD;
      including self-report measures and online tasks. Participants will then be randomised to WoB&#xD;
      or the Ashmolean Website. Once randomised participants will be requested to log on to the&#xD;
      intervention at least once a day for the next three days&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomisation and blinding Randomisation procedures will be followed. The participants will&#xD;
      be aware of which intervention they have been allocated to. All measures are online and&#xD;
      self-report.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ways of Being (WoB) is an online cultural experience designed to reduce distress (symptoms of&#xD;
      anxiety and depression) and promote positive mental health in people aged 16-24. It is a&#xD;
      web-experience based on qualitative research and co-production with people aged 16-24. The&#xD;
      experience is based on human centred narratives related to the objects and artworks of the&#xD;
      Ashmolean Museum in Oxford and partner museums. In addition, other people's viewpoints on the&#xD;
      objects and artworks or narrative, are a focus of the experience. The experience combines&#xD;
      text, audio and aesthetic elements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Ashmolean Website is a generic museum website owned by the Ashmolean Museum of Art and&#xD;
      Archaeology at the University of Oxford. The Ashmolean is the oldest public museum in the UK,&#xD;
      and has incredibly rich and diverse collections from around the globe, ranging from classical&#xD;
      civilisation to the Pre-Raphaelites and modern art. The website is aimed at general museum&#xD;
      visitors, tourists, families, primary, secondary and tertiary learners, teachers, and those&#xD;
      with specialist cultural interests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analysis Plan The main outcome will be the mean PANAS score at each time point.&#xD;
      These will be regressed on time (pre-intervention vs. during, exit and follow up), a group&#xD;
      indicator (WoB vs. the Ashmolean Website), and their interaction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 4, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Two arm study, 1:1 randomisation (stratified by gender)</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PANAS</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Days 2-4 (morning and evening), Day 5, six weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Is a widely used scale of emotion and comprises 20 items, 10 measuring positive affect (excited, inspired etc) and 10 measuring negative affect (upset, afraid etc), on a Likert Scale of 1 (very slightly) to 5 (extremely). We will be measuring change between baseline and time-points (in Timeframe)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>K10</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Day 5, six weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The K10 is a well validated self-report measure of distress (depression and anxiety). We will be measuring change between baseline and time-points (in Timeframe)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Facial expression recognition task</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Day 5, six weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The facial expression recognition task provides an objective measure of emotional bias which is associated with vulnerability to depression. We will be measuring change between baseline and time-points (in Timeframe)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Probabilistic Incentive Learning Task</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Day 5, six weeks</time_frame>
    <description>This is an instrumental learning task in which the participant gains or loses points by choosing between two paired images. The participant is told that some images are more likely (but not always) to be associated with gains and some with losses. The explicit aim is to maximize points. We will be measuring change between baseline and time-points (in Timeframe)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Flourishing</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Day 5, six weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The Flourishing Scale is an 8-item measure of self-perceived success in domains such as self-esteem, relationships, optimism and purpose. We will be measuring change between baseline and time-points (in Timeframe)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Loneliness</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Day 5, six weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The UCLA Loneliness Scale is a self-report inventory that uses a Likert-type scale to assess subjective feelings of loneliness. In addition we will add an item directly asking about loneliness. We will be measuring change between baseline and time-points (in Timeframe).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ways of Being online Experience</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Ways of Being (WoB) every day for three days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ashmolean Website</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>The Ashmolean Website every day for three days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>WofB</intervention_name>
    <description>Online experience designed to reduce anxiety and depression and support mental health and wellbeing</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ways of Being online Experience</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ashmolean Website</intervention_name>
    <description>A generic museum website owned by the Ashmolean Museum of Art and Archaeology at the University of Oxford.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ashmolean Website</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        People ages 16-24&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No access to a laptop or desktop computer&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>24 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rebecca Sheriff, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+ 44 (0)1865 618200</phone>
    <email>rebecca.sheriff@psych.ox.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Evgenia Riga</last_name>
    <email>jenny.riga@psych.ox.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ashmolean Museum Website</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oxford</city>
        <state>Oxfordshire</state>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rebecca Sheriff</last_name>
      <email>rebecca.sheriff@psych.ox.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sheriff</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 4, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

