<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2366">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04743011</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UPECLIN-MB-2</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04743011</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Enriched Heparin Anti COVID-19 Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>EnHanCed</acronym>
  <official_title>Nebulized Enriched Heparin to Treat no Critical Patients With Sars-Cov-2 - Triple Blind Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>UPECLIN HC FM Botucatu Unesp</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>UPECLIN HC FM Botucatu Unesp</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus 19 (COVID-19) is a viral respiratory disease that was identified in December 2019&#xD;
      after the first cases in China, spreading rapidly until reaching pandemic status, causing the&#xD;
      collapse of numerous health systems and strong economic and social impact. By the end of&#xD;
      April 2020, 3.08 million cases, and more than 214 thousand deaths were already recorded. The&#xD;
      treatment so far has not been established and there are several clinical trials testing known&#xD;
      drugs that have antiviral activity in vitro, due to the urgency that the global situation&#xD;
      imposes. Medicines with specific actions can take years to be discovered, while a vaccine&#xD;
      also takes a long time. Recently, it has been shown that the worsening of Coronavirus&#xD;
      infection may be related to the formation of micro clots in blood vessels and anticoagulants&#xD;
      have been used as adjuvants in the treatment. This study is justified by conducting a pilot&#xD;
      study that showed an in vitro antiviral action (anti-COVID-19) of high molecular weight&#xD;
      heparin. Methods: A phase I / II clinical trial will be conducted. 40 participants will be&#xD;
      included in two arms. Participants allocated to Group 1 (control) will receive inhalation&#xD;
      with 0.9% saline applied 4/4 hours, for 7 days. Participants allocated to Group 2&#xD;
      (intervention) will receive high molecular weight inhaled heparin (250ug / mL 0.9% SF), at a&#xD;
      4/4 hour dose, for 7 days. The outcomes of interest will be safety (absence of moderate or&#xD;
      serious adverse events) and effectiveness (measured in a score of 7 points, with 1 absence of&#xD;
      limitations and 7, death). Expected results: The development of a new therapeutic option for&#xD;
      COVID-19 is expected, with the possibility of use in other serious coronavirus diseases, to&#xD;
      be subsequently tested in phase III studies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In view of the enormous health, financial and social crisis resulting of the pandemic caused&#xD;
      by SARS-Cov-2, it is justified to urgently conduct tests with possible antiviral drugs. The&#xD;
      high molecular weight heparin (HMWH) (heparin enriched by ultrafiltration process) proposed&#xD;
      by this study, has a potential inhibition activity over viral replication, demonstrated by&#xD;
      preliminary in vitro tests, carried out in a model established in partnership with the&#xD;
      Laboratory of Clinical and Molecular Virology (LVCM) of the Institute of Biomedical Sciences&#xD;
      of the University of São Paulo (ICB-USP).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Along with the findings in the literature, such as the study carried out by Phelps, M.K. et&#xD;
      al (2020), among others, the use of inhaled heparin presents adequate levels of safety to be&#xD;
      used in a clinical trial. Taking into account that the dose of high molecular weight heparin&#xD;
      (enriched by this study team) with antiviral activity in vitro is much lower than the doses&#xD;
      currently presented in published clinical trials using inhaled UFH, we have the safety&#xD;
      premise to carry out this study. The intentions of this study differ from what has been&#xD;
      presented in the world literature so far, as it does not aim to induce anticoagulation, nor&#xD;
      to effectively inhibit the formation of pulmonary fibrin, but rather, to act as an inhibitor&#xD;
      of viral replication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Also, as characteristics of the product to be tested, this heparin (HMWH) is presented in a&#xD;
      buffered solution free of low-sulfated low-weight molecules, which is obtained in a sterile&#xD;
      environment through ultrafiltration of the unfractionated solution of porcine origin&#xD;
      available in Brazil (Hemofol - Cristália) using Centriprep-10kDa® centrifuge filter&#xD;
      (Millipore ™) used as recommended by the manufacturer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The high molecular weight heparin (HMWH) - enriched heparin - had two process patents filed,&#xD;
      one under the description &quot;HIGH MOLECULAR WEIGHT DEFINITION HEPARINE DEVELOPMENT PROCESS&quot;, BR&#xD;
      102014027804-4 A2 - granted by the Instituto Nacional de Propriedade Industrial (INPI) and&#xD;
      another with the description &quot;COMPOSITION OF HIGH MOLECULAR WEIGHT NON-FRACTIONAL HEPARINE&#xD;
      FOR ANTIVIRAL ACTION &quot;, BR 102020 011964-8 - deposited at INPI.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants allocated to Group 1 (control) will receive inhalation with 0.9% saline solution applied 4/4 hours, for 7 days. Participants allocated to Group 2 (intervention) will receive high molecular weight inhaled heparin (250ug / mL 0.9% SF), at a 4/4 hour dose, for 7 days.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The clinical trial will be triple-blind. Participants, researchers, and the data/statistical analysis team will not have access to the research data. Only one member of the team will produce the test product and assist a external physician (not part of the research team), with the adverse events that may occur with the participants during the execution of the research.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in activated partial thromboplastin time (APTT) &gt; 1.5</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Safety-related to the use of high molecular weight heparin inhaled in patients with SARS-COV-2 through the assessment of hemorrhagic events of any nature, alteration of the coagulogram that indicates an increase in APTT&gt; 1.5, heparin-induced thrombocytopenia.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Viral load in nasal swab RT-PCR.</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Effectiveness related to the proposed treatment, based on the analysis of the viral load of SARS-COV-2 virus in the participants through a sequential assessment of the viral load in nasal swab RT-PCR.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants needing supplemental oxygen therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of respiratory parameters measured by the need for supplemental oxygen therapy at greater doses than 5L/min;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants needing mechanical pulmonary ventilation</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of respiratory parameters measured by the need of definitive airway assisted pulmonary ventilation;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of hospitalization days</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of clinical parameters characterized by a prolonged hospital stay;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants that develop renal failure</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of clinical parameters characterized by renal failure through measurement of urea and creatinine;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants that develop major cardiovascular events</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of clinical parameters characterized by major cardiovascular events (pulmonary embolism, acute myocardial infarction)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants transfered to the intensive care unit (ICU)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of clinical parameters characterized by need for Intensive Care Unit (ICU) treatment;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants presenting secondary pulmonary bacterial infections</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of clinical parameters characterized by presentation of secondary pulmonary bacterial infections (pneumonia);</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants that develop deep vein thrombosis (DVT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of clinical parameters characterized by deep vein thrombosis (DVT);</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants that develop pancreatitis</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of clinical parameters characterized by pancreatitis through measurement of amilasis (&gt; 200 U/L);</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants that need corticosteroid therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of clinical parameters characterized by need for hydrocortisone, dexamethasone or orther corticosteroids due to inflamatory pulmonary disease;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of deaths among participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of clinical parameters characterized by death;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with increased white blood cell count</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of laboratory parameters measured by increased white blood cell count (&gt;10.000 cells/mm³);</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with increased C reactive protein test</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of laboratory parameters measured by increase in C reactive protein test (&gt;3.00mg/L);</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with deterioration of arterial blood gas paO2/pFiO2 ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of laboratory parameters measured by alterations in arterial blood gas measured by paO2/pFiO2 &lt; 200;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with altered sodium</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of laboratory parameters measured by alterations in sodium (&lt; 135mEq/L or &gt; 145mEq/L)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with altered potassium</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of laboratory parameters measured by alterations in potassium (&lt; 3,5mEq/L or &gt; 5,5mEq/L);</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with increased pulmonary area compromised (%)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately or up to 8 days after starting treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Worsening of tomographic parameters measured by the pulmonary area compromised by the infection and/or inflammation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive inhalation with 10mL 0.9% saline solution (placebo), 4/4h, only during the day period (5 doses).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Heparin sodium</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive inhalation with 10mL 0.9% saline solution + 250ug of hight molecular heparin - enriched heparin, 4/4h, only during the day period (5 doses).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Heparin sodium</intervention_name>
    <description>Nebulized inhalation of 10 mL of a solution containing high molecular weight heparin - enriched heparin - 250ug/mL and 0.9% saline solution, every 4 hours for 7 days, except during the night (5 doses/day)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Heparin sodium</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Hemofol, Cristália (Brazil)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Nebulized inhalation of 10 mL of 0.9% saline solution, every 4 hours for 7 days, except during the night (5 doses/day)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Saline solution 0.9%</other_name>
    <other_name>Physiological solution 0.9%</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signature and agreement to the Free Consent Form;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Both sexes, of any ethnic origin, aged between 18 and 90 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 infected patients diagnosed by RT-PCR (reverse-transcriptase polymerase chain&#xD;
             reaction) or with a strong suspicion of COVID-19 by clinical evaluation through&#xD;
             compatible clinical and radiological findings;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Time of disease evolution less than 10 days;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiological diagnosis of grade 2A pneumonia, with gas exchange ratio &gt; 200 on blood&#xD;
             gas analysis (paO2 / pFiO2), characterizing mild hypoxemia;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Indication of hospital treatment regime, provided that the period of hospitalization&#xD;
             before inclusion is not more than 24 hours;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Need for supplemental oxygen therapy (O2) less than 5L / min.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No agreement to the terms of this study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate or severe respiratory failure requiring admission to the ICU and the need for&#xD;
             invasive mechanical ventilation or non-invasive ventilation (NIV) with positive&#xD;
             pressure;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or puerperium;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with hematological diseases, coagulation disorders, use of anticoagulants,&#xD;
             previous heparin-induced allergy or thrombocytopenia, thrombocytopenia with a count of&#xD;
             fewer than 50,000 platelets / mm3;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 not confirmed by RT-PCR within 72 hours of inclusion in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Matheus Bertanha, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>São Paulo State University (Unesp)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Matheus Bertanha, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+55(14)3880-1444</phone>
    <email>matheusbertanha@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Carlos Magno CB Fortaleza, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+55(14)3880-1284</phone>
    <email>carlos.fortaleza@unesp.br</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>School of Medicine at Botucatu- Paulista State University- UNESP, São Paulo, Brazil</name>
      <address>
        <city>Botucatu</city>
        <state>SP</state>
        <zip>18607030</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Matheus Bertanha, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+55 14 3880-1444</phone>
      <email>matheusbertanha@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Carlos Magno CB Fortaleza, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+55 14 38801284</phone>
      <email>carlos.fortaleza@unesp.br</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Matheus Bertanha, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Phelps, M. K., Olson, L. M., Patel, M. A. V. B., Thompson, M. J., &amp; Murphy, C. V. (2020). Nebulized Heparin for Adult Patients With Smoke Inhalation Injury: A Review of the Literature. Journal of Pharmacy Technology. 2020; 36(4): 130-140.</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 3, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>UPECLIN HC FM Botucatu Unesp</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Matheus Bertanha, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Heparin</keyword>
  <keyword>Antiviral Agents</keyword>
  <keyword>Blood Coagulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Clinical Protocols</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heparin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Calcium heparin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>There is a plan to make IPD and related data dictionaries available</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The summary data will be published or made available 6 months after publication.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Epidemiological data, clinical data, and patient evolution will be shared during the study only for researchers who request access to the data. Access requests will be analyzed by the main researcher, and they will only be released for scientific purposes.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

