<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4718">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02656381</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>160046</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>16-EI-0046</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02656381</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Uveitis/Intraocular Inflammatory Disease Biobank (iBank)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Uveitis/Intraocular Inflammatory Disease Biobank (iBank)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Eye Institute (NEI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Uveitis is a serious eye disease that can cause vision loss. Treatment sometimes causes&#xD;
      serious side effects or does not work. Researchers want to learn more about uveitis and why&#xD;
      some people develop it.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To learn clinical and genetic factors that may make people develop uveitis and influence how&#xD;
      they respond to treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People ages 8 and older who have uveitis, scleritis, inflammatory eye disease, or a disease&#xD;
      related to eye inflammation&#xD;
&#xD;
      INCLUSION CRITERIA FOR COVID-19 COHORT:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants with COVID-19 will be eligible if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Have a diagnosis of COVID-19 confirmed by a nasaopharyngeal swab (or another&#xD;
           confirmative test) within less than or equal to 3 days prior, with symptoms of any&#xD;
           severity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Are able to give verbal consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Are 16 years of age or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXCLUSION CRITERIA FOR COVID-19 COHORT:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants with COVID-19 will not be eligible if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Use regular prescription eye drops on the day of sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Current use of antiviral medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical exam&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eye exam&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation lasts up to 10 years. The clinic visit schedule varies depending on&#xD;
      participants eye disease:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline visit with annual follow-ups&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline visit, visits at months 3 and 6, and annual follow-ups&#xD;
&#xD;
      Another schedule set by the researcher&#xD;
&#xD;
      Depending on participants eye disease, tests during each visit could include:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fluorescein angiography or indocyanine green angiography: Dye is injected through a needle in&#xD;
      the arm&#xD;
&#xD;
      and flows through the blood vessels in the eye. A camera takes pictures of the eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Electroretinography: Participants sit in the dark with their eyes patched.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After 30 minutes, numbing drops and contact lenses are put in the eyes. Then, the retina is&#xD;
      stimulated with flashing lights.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Perimetry: Participants look into a bowl or lens and press a button when they see a light.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Conjunctival or corneal biopsy, or skin biopsy: A small piece of tissue is removed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anterior chamber tap: A needle enters the eye to remove fluid.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood and urine tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      Saliva, stool, hair, or tear samples&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cotton swab of the inside of the cheek.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the study, participants may need immunosuppressive treatment, such as drugs or&#xD;
      injections in or around the eyes depending on their disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Uveitis refers to a large group of intraocular inflammatory diseases that can cause&#xD;
      devastating visual loss in adults and children. This study establishes a clinical database&#xD;
      and biospecimen repository for the identification of novel factors relevant to the&#xD;
      pathogenesis, progression, and response to treatment of a wide spectrum of uveitic&#xD;
      conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives: This study provides for standardized collection of longitudinal clinical data and&#xD;
      for serial collection, processing, and storage of a variety of biospecimens. The clinical&#xD;
      data set and biospecimen repository will be used to identify novel genetic factors,&#xD;
      biomarkers, and experimental models associated with pathogenesis, progression, and response&#xD;
      to treatment for various ocular and systemic conditions where inflammation of the uveal tract&#xD;
      is present.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population: The study plans to accrue 500 participants with uveitis or related&#xD;
      diseases. This will not be restricted by anatomical location or etiology with the inclusion&#xD;
      of both idiopathic cases, infectious uveitis, scleritis and those cases linked to a disease&#xD;
      known to be associated with an increased risk of intraocular inflammation (e.g., sarcoidosis,&#xD;
      Beh(SqrRoot)(Beta)et's disease, and multiple sclerosis (MS) and lymphoma). In addition, 100&#xD;
      participants without intraocular inflammatory disease will be enrolled as controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design: This is a prospective observational study of participants with intraocular&#xD;
      inflammatory diseases incorporating:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. A standardized follow-up and testing schedule with standard-of-care management of eye&#xD;
           diseases; and&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Collection of biospecimens for research purposes for which sampling does not incur more&#xD;
           than minimal risk to participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome Measures: Outcome measures include the interaction of key parameters of disease&#xD;
      phenotype (such as visual acuity and ocular imaging features) with genetic variants and other&#xD;
      biomarkers identified from biospecimens and the characterization of new experimental models&#xD;
      of eye health and disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 26, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2029</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2029</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The clinical data and samples from this study will be used to test for interaction of key parameters of phenotype with genetic variants and other biomarkers identified from biospecimens.</measure>
    <time_frame>ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>The intent is to collect data on a variety of phenotypic pararmeters and to store biospecimens in a manner that permits a broad array of potnential testing and experimentation in the future.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary outcomes will include the number and severity of systemic and ocular adverse events among participants who use systemic immunosuppression.</measure>
    <time_frame>ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>Events include but are not limited to structural ocular complications, hospitalizations, osteoporosis, renal and hepatic side effects, infections and myelosuppression from conventional immunosuppressives and biologics.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">650</enrollment>
  <condition>Uveitis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Anterior Uveitis</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants with AU at entry</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intermediate Uveitis</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants with IU at entry</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Other</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants not fitting above criteria</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Posterior/Pan Uveitis</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants with non-infectious posterior or pan-uveitis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study plans to accrue 500 participants with uveitis or related diseases. This will not&#xD;
        be restricted by anatomical location or etiology with the inclusion of both idiopathic&#xD;
        cases, infectious uveitis, scleritis and those cases linked to a disease known to be&#xD;
        associated with an increased risk of intraocular inflammation (e.g., sarcoidosis,&#xD;
        Beh(SqrRoot)(Beta)et's disease, multiple sclerosis (MS) and lymphoma). In addition, 100&#xD;
        participants without intraocular inflammatory disease will be enrolled as controls.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA (NOT APPLICABLE TO COVID COHORT):&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants will be eligible if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Have a diagnosis of uveitis, scleritis or a disease known to be associated with&#xD;
             intraocular inflammation, (e.g., sarcoidosis, Behcet's disease, multiple sclerosis&#xD;
             (MS) and lymphoma) OR could serve as an unaffected control.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Are eight years of age or older if an affected participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Are 18 years of age or older if serving as an unaffected control.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. For participants 18 years of age and older:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Are willing to give informed consent that includes collection and study of at&#xD;
                  least one peripheral blood sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA (NOT APPLICABLE TO COVID COHORT):&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants will not be eligible if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Are unable to understand and sign the informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Are unable or unwilling to give informed consent that includes use of medical records&#xD;
             and clinical samples for current and future research related to vision and diseases&#xD;
             affecting the eyes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have a systemic disease that compromises the ability to provide adequate&#xD;
             ophthalmologic examination or treatment as determined by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. For participants with uveitis:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Have inactive anterior uveitis or quiescent infectious uveitis not requiring such&#xD;
                  regimented and intensive standardized testing as determined by the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Have end stage or chronic quiescent changes in the setting of an established&#xD;
                  infectious etiology, such as an old ocular toxoplasma scar (participants with&#xD;
                  active intraocular inflammation due to infection will be recruited).&#xD;
&#xD;
        The eligibility requirements for this protocol are intended to be broadly inclusive, but&#xD;
        those individuals screened at the NEI and found to be ineligible may be evaluated under the&#xD;
        NEI Screening Protocol for potential participation in other studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA FOR COVID-19 COHORT:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants with COVID-19 will be eligible if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Have a diagnosis of COVID-19 confirmed by a nasaopharyngeal swab (or another&#xD;
             confirmative test) within less than or equal to 3 days prior, with symptoms of any&#xD;
             severity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Are able to give verbal consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Are 16 years of age or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA FOR COVID-19 COHORT:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants with COVID-19 will not be eligible if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Use regular prescription eye drops on the day of sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Current use of antiviral medications.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hatice N Sen, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Eye Institute (NEI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Dominic Obiyor, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 435-4556</phone>
    <email>dominic.obiyor@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2016-EI-0046.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 10, 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 13, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 13, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 14, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Sarcoidosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Behcet's Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Natural History Study</keyword>
  <keyword>Biological Specimens</keyword>
  <keyword>Immune System</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Uveitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

