<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1984">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04650035</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>The Impact of COVID-19 Jordan</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04650035</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Impact of COVID-19 on Surgical Practice in Jordan During the Second Outbreak</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Impact of COVID-19 on Surgical Practice in Jordan During the Second Outbreak : A Survey</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yarmouk University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yarmouk University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: COVID-19 is an acute respiratory pandemic with no available effective antiviral&#xD;
      treatment or widely available effective vaccine. Surgical practice has faced widespread&#xD;
      problems due to the pandemic including viral transmission risk and cross-infection, staffing&#xD;
      problems, prioritizations of surgical procedures and lack of beds due to occupancy of&#xD;
      hospitals and ICU beds with COVID-19 patients; Methods: A survey was conducted between&#xD;
      October 31 to November 4, 2020, through google forms. The questionnaire involved 16 questions&#xD;
      sent to consultants and specialists of all general and special surgical specialties and&#xD;
      subspecialties in Jordan;&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A survey was conducted between October 31 and November 4, 2020. The questionnaire was made&#xD;
      through google forms, and a consent was taken from the Jordan medical association to send the&#xD;
      link to surgeons in Jordan through the social media and the official WhatsApp groups. The&#xD;
      survey was introduced with the invitation to participate of surgeons of all general and&#xD;
      special surgical specialties and subspecialties. The aim of the survey was mentioned in the&#xD;
      introduction which was to evaluate the impact of COVID-19 on surgical practice in Jordan&#xD;
      during the second outbreak of COVID-19, and it was explained that the aim of the survey was&#xD;
      for research purposes only and that it was totally anonymous with privacy preserved, and no&#xD;
      identifying information required. Also, it was noted that we have added spaces for written&#xD;
      views and recommendations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The questionnaire involved 16 questions of the multiple-choice, the dropdown, the multiple&#xD;
      check, and the short answer questions. The first 2 questions were about the specialty and the&#xD;
      place of work whether it was the ministry of health, the royal medical services, the&#xD;
      university hospitals, or the non-governmental organizations. The 3rd and 4th questions were&#xD;
      about the hospital where the participant works whether it admits COVID-19 patients and/or&#xD;
      ordinary patients. The Questions from the 5th to the 8th were about the volume of work in&#xD;
      terms of the number of elective and emergency surgeries during the month of October 2020 in&#xD;
      comparison to the average monthly rate during the year 2019. The questions from the 9th to&#xD;
      the 15th were about the problems that might have been faced in managing elective and&#xD;
      emergency cases during the month of October 2020 in relation to COVID-19. The last question&#xD;
      was a multiple checkbox question with an added space for giving the possible recommendations&#xD;
      to manage the situation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 10, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 4, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of surgical operations performed whether elective or emergency</measure>
    <time_frame>October 2020</time_frame>
    <description>difference between the monthly rate of operations during 2019 and the month of October 2020.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Consultants and specialists of all general and special surgical specialties and&#xD;
        subspecialties in Jordan&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consultants and specialists of all general and special surgical specialties and&#xD;
             subspecialties in Jordan&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Raed M Ennab</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences, Faculty Of Medicine, Yarmouk University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yarmouk University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Irbid</city>
        <zip>21163</zip>
        <country>Jordan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Jordan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.who.int/director-general/speeches/detail/who-director-general-s-opening-remarks-at-the-media-briefing-on-covid-19---11-march-2020</url>
    <description>World health organization official website</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://dosweb.dos.gov.jo</url>
    <description>Department of Statistics Jordan. Population Count. (2020).</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://ncscm.gov.jo/index.php</url>
    <description>National Center for Security and Crises Management. COVID-19 in Jordan. (2020).</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.pm.gov.jo/</url>
    <description>Prime Ministry of Jordan. Official Reports. (2020).</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://corona.moh.gov.jo/ar</url>
    <description>Jordanian Ministry of Health. COVID-19 in Jordan. (2020).</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.absurgery.org/default.jsp?covid19_resources</url>
    <description>The American Board of Surgery official website, COVID-19 Guidelines and Resources</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Guo YR, Cao QD, Hong ZS, Tan YY, Chen SD, Jin HJ, Tan KS, Wang DY, Yan Y. The origin, transmission and clinical therapies on coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) outbreak - an update on the status. Mil Med Res. 2020 Mar 13;7(1):11. doi: 10.1186/s40779-020-00240-0. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32169119</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lam S, Lombardi A, Ouanounou A. COVID-19: A review of the proposed pharmacological treatments. Eur J Pharmacol. 2020 Nov 5;886:173451. doi: 10.1016/j.ejphar.2020.173451. Epub 2020 Aug 6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32768505</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Al-Jabir A, Kerwan A, Nicola M, Alsafi Z, Khan M, Sohrabi C, O'Neill N, Iosifidis C, Griffin M, Mathew G, Agha R. Impact of the Coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic on surgical practice - Part 1. Int J Surg. 2020 Jul;79:168-179. doi: 10.1016/j.ijsu.2020.05.022. Epub 2020 May 12. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32407799</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Coccolini F, Perrone G, Chiarugi M, Di Marzo F, Ansaloni L, Scandroglio I, Marini P, Zago M, De Paolis P, Forfori F, Agresta F, Puzziello A, D'Ugo D, Bignami E, Bellini V, Vitali P, Petrini F, Pifferi B, Corradi F, Tarasconi A, Pattonieri V, Bonati E, Tritapepe L, Agnoletti V, Corbella D, Sartelli M, Catena F. Surgery in COVID-19 patients: operational directives. World J Emerg Surg. 2020 Apr 7;15(1):25. doi: 10.1186/s13017-020-00307-2.</citation>
    <PMID>32264898</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Russell FM, Greenwood B. Who should be prioritised for COVID-19 vaccination? Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2020 Nov 3:1-5. doi: 10.1080/21645515.2020.1827882. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>33141000</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 1, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 1, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 2, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 1, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 1, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 3, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Yarmouk University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Raed M Ennab</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

