<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4874">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04405284</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>COVID2020_HelwanU_01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04405284</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Use of Disinfectants Among Women in Egypt and the Toxicity by Bleach During the Coronavirus Lock-down.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Disinfection Practices Among Women in Egypt During the Coronavirus Pandemic.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Helwan University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Nebraska</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Helwan University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study examines the use of disinfectants by Egyptian women during the coronavirus&#xD;
      lockdown. Data will be collected via an online self-administered questionnaire that will be&#xD;
      distributed to Egyptian women via social media channels. Questions in the questionnaire will&#xD;
      assess types of disinfectants frequently used and how often they have been used for household&#xD;
      disinfection during the 2020 coronavirus pandemic. The investigators hypothesized that the&#xD;
      frequent use of disinfectants in deep household cleaning during the lockdown has been&#xD;
      associated with increased incidents of toxicity by bleach and similar products. At the same&#xD;
      time, people were advised to stay home and refrain from seeking in-person medical care to&#xD;
      avoid catching the coronavirus. Therefore, many people used social media to receive medical&#xD;
      advice not necessarily from the right sources nor qualified experts.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study examines the use of disinfectants by Egyptian women during the coronavirus&#xD;
      lockdown. Data will be collected via an online self-administered questionnaire that will be&#xD;
      distributed to Egyptian women via social media channels such as (Facebook and WhatsApp).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Google Forms tool will be used to conduct the questionnaire as questions in the questionnaire&#xD;
      will assess types of disinfectants frequently used and how often they have been used for&#xD;
      household disinfection during the 2020 coronavirus pandemic. Questions will also assess the&#xD;
      occurrence of adverse effects related to the increased use of disinfectants during the&#xD;
      lockdown and how women reached out for medical care for their family members in cases of&#xD;
      accidental toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesized that the frequent use of disinfectants in deep household&#xD;
      cleaning during the lockdown has been associated with increased incidents of toxicity by&#xD;
      bleach and similar products. At the same time, people were advised to stay home and refrain&#xD;
      from seeking in-person medical care to avoid catching the coronavirus. Therefore, many people&#xD;
      used social media to receive medical advice not necessarily from the right sources nor&#xD;
      qualified experts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The questionnaire is designed by the primary investigator (Dr. Maha Farid) and was reviewed&#xD;
      by other experts in the field of forensic medicine and clinical toxicology. The questions&#xD;
      were developed in English and then translated in Arabic to be distributed to the target&#xD;
      population in Arabic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The inclusion criteria for women participating in this survey will include adult females&#xD;
      living in Egypt during the time of lockdown due to coronavirus pandemic that started in Egypt&#xD;
      in March 2020.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The questionnaire will be open for a month or till we reach the desired sample size,&#xD;
      whichever comes first.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data collected via this questionnaire will be then tabulated and analyzed using the&#xD;
      proper statistical analysis methods.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 4, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The use of disinfectants in deep house cleaning by women in Egypt.</measure>
    <time_frame>one month after the distribution of the questionnaire</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of disinfection practice among women in Egypt</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">425</enrollment>
  <condition>Toxicity by Bleach</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>use and exposure to disinfectants during the coronavirus pandemic</intervention_name>
    <description>The use of disinfecting products in deep house cleaning by women during the coronavirus lockdown.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Women aging 18 years old and above located in Egypt during the coronavirus lockdown in&#xD;
        March 2020.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult women living in Egypt the coronavirus lockdown started in March 2020&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men living in Egypt&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult women not living in Egypt during the coronavirus lockdown started in March 2020.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Maha M Farid, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Helwan University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Maha M Farid</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 26, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 26, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 19, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 19, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Helwan University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Maha Farid,MBBCh, MSc,PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Lecturer in the department of Forensic Medicine and Clinical Toxicology, Faculty of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>women</keyword>
  <keyword>Egypt</keyword>
  <keyword>disinfectatnts</keyword>
  <keyword>adverse reactions</keyword>
  <keyword>coronavirus</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Disinfectants</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The plan to make (IPD) viable has not been decided to maintain the confidentiality and privacy of the information collected in this research project.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

