<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1336">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04664010</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>XianInternationalMCH_HXJ</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04664010</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of High-dose Vitamin C Combined With Chinese Medicine Against Coronavirus Pneumonia (COVID-19)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy and Safety of High-dose Vitamin C Combined With Traditional Chinese Medicine in the Treatment of Moderate and Severe Coronavirus Pneumonia (COVID-19)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In December 2019, coronavirus pneumonia (COVID-19) was detected in many cases in Wuhan,&#xD;
      China. With the rapid spread of the coronavirus, cases of COVID-19 were also reported in&#xD;
      other cities of China and other countries. COVID-19 can cause amplification of the pulmonary&#xD;
      inflammatory responses, including the production of a large amount of free radicals and the&#xD;
      release of inflammatory factors, in a short time after infection, leading to lung tissue&#xD;
      damage and dysfunction, even resulting in life-threatening respiratory distress syndrome and&#xD;
      respiratory failure. At present, there are no effective drugs targeting COVID-19. Previous&#xD;
      studies have shown that Buzhong Yiqi Decoction has anti-bacterial, anti-viral, and&#xD;
      anti-allergy effects. High-dose vitamin C also has anti-oxidative and anti-toxin effects,&#xD;
      possibly exhibiting good effects in the treatment of viral infection and critical respiratory&#xD;
      diseases. The study objectives include (1) investigate whether Buzhong Yiqi Decoction can&#xD;
      improve the clinical symptoms of patients with mild and severe COVID-19 and accelerate&#xD;
      recovery and to further investigate the clinical efficacy of high-dose vitamin C combined&#xD;
      with traditional Chinese medicine in the treatment of mild and severe COVID-19; (2) to assess&#xD;
      the safety of high-dose vitamin C combined with Chinese medicine in the treatment of mild and&#xD;
      severe COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Preparation prior to treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Record of age, sex, race, height, body mass, body mass index, body temperature, blood&#xD;
           pressure, pulse, and respiratory rate;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Record of previous medical history, current medical history, treatment history,&#xD;
           concomitant disease/treatment history;&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Record of laboratory tests: routine blood test, routine stool and urine tests, fecal&#xD;
           occult blood test, C-reactive protein measurement, biochemical assay, PCR testing for&#xD;
           respiratory virus, tumor marker test, and ABO typing&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Cytokine detection: Serum levels of interleukin-6, interleukin-10, and tumor necrosis&#xD;
           factor-alpha (TNF-α)&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Auxiliary examination: Chest CT for assessment of lung infection&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chinese medicine treatments Chinese medicine treatments include oral administration of&#xD;
      concentrated Chinese herbal decoction, fumigation/inhalation of Chinese medicine and vitamin&#xD;
      C, and bolus administration of vitamin C.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Traditional Chinese and western medicine prescription details Traditional Chinese medicine&#xD;
      treatment details Prescription 1: Buzhong Yiqi plus and minus formula (recommended for&#xD;
      patients who had no fever and those who are in the convalescent period): This formula is&#xD;
      composed of Radix Astragali 30 g, Radix Ginseng 15 g, Radix Glycyrrhizae 15 g, Rhizoma&#xD;
      Atractylodis Macrocephalae 10 g, Pericarpium Citri Reticulatae 6 g, Radix Angelicae Sinensis&#xD;
      10 g, Fructus Jujubae 6, Rhizoma Zingiberis Recens 9 pieces, Radix Bupleuri 12 g, Rhizoma&#xD;
      Cimicifugae 6 g.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preparation method: The aforementioned herbs are decocted with water. After removal of&#xD;
      macromolecules, 50 g concentrate is left, and then packaged, 25 g/dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Suggested usage: 1 dose once, twice a day, taking with warm water.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prescription 2: Huhuang Detoxicity Paste (recommended for patients who have no fever): This&#xD;
      formula is composed of Rhizoma Coptidis 20 g, Radix Et Rhizoma Rhei 10 g, Rhizoma&#xD;
      Atractylodis 10 g, Radix Asteris 10 g, Herba Houttuyniae 10 g, Herba Taraxaci 10 g, Rhizoma&#xD;
      Polygoni Cuspidati 10 g, Radix Astragali 20 g.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preparation method: The aforementioned herbs are boiled with water. The extract was subjected&#xD;
      to high-speed centrifugation. After removal of impurities, 50 g concentrate is left, and then&#xD;
      packaged, 25 g/dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Suggested usage: One dose once, twice a day, taking with warm water.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prescription 3: Baimu Qingre Jiedu Paste This formula is composed of Radix Puerariae 15 g,&#xD;
      Radix Angelicae Dahuricae 12 g, Flos Magnoliae 9 g, Radix Isatidis 30 g, Fructus Forsythiae&#xD;
      15 g, Bulbus Fritillariae Thunbergii 12 g Preparation method: The aforementioned herbs are&#xD;
      boiled with water. The extract was subjected to high-speed centrifugation. After removal of&#xD;
      impurities, 50 g concentrate is left, and then packaged, 25 g/dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Suggested usage: One dose once, twice a day, taking with warm water.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prescription 4: Fumigation/inhalation of Chinese herbs and vitamin C The formula consists of&#xD;
      Rhizoma Coptidis 20 g, Radix Et Rhizoma Rhei 10 g, Rhizoma Atractylodis Macrocephalae 10 g,&#xD;
      Radix Astragali 10 g, Radix Asteris 10 g, Herba Houttuyniae 10 g, Herba Taraxaci 10 g,&#xD;
      Rhizoma Polygoni Cuspidati 10 g, Radix Astragali 20 g.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preparation method: The aforementioned herbs are boiled with water. The extract was subjected&#xD;
      to high-speed centrifugation. After removal of impurities, 50 g concentrate is left, and then&#xD;
      packaged, 25 g/dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fumigation/inhalation method: 3L of water is added to the intelligent rice cooker&#xD;
      (specification 5L), and then the aforementioned semifluid paste is also placed in the cooker.&#xD;
      After boiling, 10 g vitamin C is added. The oxygen tube is inserted into the bottom of the&#xD;
      traditional Chinese medicine solution (oxygen flow is about 3-4 L/min). The steam is sucked&#xD;
      with the mouth and nose alternately, 30-40 minutes once, 3-7 times a day. Patients take&#xD;
      vitamin E capsule and folic acid every day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Bolus administration of vitamin C 100 mL of 5% glucose containing vitamin C (10 g/60 kg body&#xD;
      mass) is intravenously administered twice a day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Western medicine treatment details Atomized inhalation of 5 million U α-interferon and 2 mL&#xD;
      sterilized water, twice a day; 0.2 g arbidol, three times a day, treatment course no more&#xD;
      than 10 days; intravenous administration of ribavirin 500 mg, once every 12 hours, treatment&#xD;
      course no more than 10 days; intravenous administration of 10 g immunoglobulin C, once a day,&#xD;
      3-5 days. Anti-bacterial infection treatment is given to the patients who have yellow sputum&#xD;
      and increased levels of procalcitonin and other bacterial infection specific indicators.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Notes for case and course record The medical record of integrated Chinese and western&#xD;
      medicine treatment for each case should be carefully filled. A summary of the medical record&#xD;
      is made every three days. The name and dosage of the traditional Chinese medicine and western&#xD;
      medicine used, the route of administration, curative effect, and side effects are recorded.&#xD;
      The record form of the curative effect should be filled every day.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 6, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 14, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>participants are assigned to one of two or more groups in parallel for the duration of the study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>Blinding and blinding maintenance&#xD;
(1)The biostatisticians and the personnel unrelated to the clinical trial complete the binding of the study drugs and emergency card preparation. The random coding table and corresponding parameters are recorded blindly. After drug designation, the personnel responsible for blinding of the study drugs will sign at the perforation of the blinding envelope.&#xD;
A two-level blinding design will be adopted. The first-level code corresponds to intervention A or intervention B, and the second-level code presents the corresponding group. The envelope containing two-level blinding file will be preserved in Tianjin Angsai Cell Gene Engineering Co., Ltd., China until unblinding. The unblinding will not be performed during the study period.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recovery time</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until the date of discharge, assessed up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The discharge criteria of Diagnosis and Treatment Protocol for Novel Coronavirus Pneumonia (Trial Version 7) are applied: a) body temperature is back to normal for more than three days; b) respiratory symptoms improve obviously; c) pulmonary imaging shows obvious resolution of inflammation; d) nuclei acid tests negative twice consecutively on respiratory tract samples such as sputum and nasopharyngeal swabs (sampling interval being at least 24 hours)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time of disappearance of fever symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until the date of discharge, assessed up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Time of disappearance of fever in degrees centigrade</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The rate of conversion from COVID-19 positive to COVID-19 negative</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until the date of discharge, assessed up to 6 months.</time_frame>
    <description>The rate of conversion from COVID-19 positive to COVID-19 negative</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time of disappearance of cough</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until the date of discharge, assessed up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Time of disappearance of cough in times per day</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Respiratory rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1-14 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Respiratory rate in times/minute with blood gas analysis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood oxygen saturation</measure>
    <time_frame>1-14 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Blood oxygen saturation in percent with blood gas analysis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PaO2</measure>
    <time_frame>1-14 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>PaO2 in kPa with blood gas analysis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PaCO2</measure>
    <time_frame>1-14 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>PaCO2 in kPa with blood gas analysis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The time of obvious improvement as shown on chest CT scans relative to admission</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until the date of discharge, assessed up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The time in days of patients of obvious improvement as shown on chest CT scans relative to admission</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The rate of obvious improvement as shown on chest CT scans relative to admission</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of randomization until the date of discharge, assessed up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The rate in percentages of patients of obvious improvement as shown on chest CT scans relative to admission</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of C-reactive protein</measure>
    <time_frame>1-14 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Levels of C-reactive protein measurement in mg/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Erythrocyte sedimentation rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1-14 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Erythrocyte sedimentation rate in mm/h</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of Procalcitonin</measure>
    <time_frame>1-14 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Levels of Procalcitonin in ng/mL</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of interleukin-6</measure>
    <time_frame>1-14 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Serum Levels of interleukin-6 in ng/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of interleukin-10</measure>
    <time_frame>1-14 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Levels of interleukin-10 in ng/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of tumor necrosis factor-alpha</measure>
    <time_frame>1-14 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Levels of tumor necrosis factor-alpha in ng/mL</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Ultrasound examination of the urinary system</measure>
    <time_frame>1-14 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Ultrasound examination of the kidney, ureter, and bladder after treatment to mainly check for urolithiasis</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>moderate COVID-19 group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients with moderate COVID-19 receiving western medicine treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>severe COVID-19 group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients with severe COVID-19 receiving western medicine treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>moderate COVID-19 with traditional Chinese medicine group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients with moderate COVID-19 receiving western medicine treatment + traditional Chinese medicine + intravenous administration of 5% glucose</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>moderate COVID-19 with combination therapy group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients with moderate COVID-19 receiving western medicine treatment + traditional Chinese medicine + intravenous administration of 5% glucose containing high-dose vitamin C</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>severe COVID-19 with traditional Chinese medicine group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients with severe COVID-19 receiving western medicine treatment + traditional Chinese medicine + intravenous administration of 5% glucose</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>severe COVID-19 with combination therapy group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients with severe COVID-19 receiving western medicine treatment + traditional Chinese medicine + intravenous administration of 5% glucose containing high-dose vitamin C</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Alpha-interferon alpha, abidol, ribavirin, Buzhong Yiqi plus and minus formula, Huhuang Detoxicity Paste, Baimu Qingre Jiedu Paste, fumigation/inhalation of vitamin C</intervention_name>
    <description>Atomized inhalation of 5 million U α-interferon and 2 mL sterilized water, twice a day; 0.2 g arbidol, three times a day, treatment course no more than 10 days; intravenous administration of ribavirin 500 mg, once every 12 hours, treatment course no more than 10 days; intravenous administration of 10 g immunoglobulin C, once a day, 3-5 days. Anti-bacterial infection treatment is given to the patients who have yellow sputum and increased levels of procalcitonin and other bacterial infection specific indicators.</description>
    <arm_group_label>moderate COVID-19 group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>severe COVID-19 group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Western medicine treatment</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Alpha-interferon, abidol, ribavirin, Buzhong Yiqi plus and minus formula, Huhuang Detoxicity Paste, Baimu Qingre Jiedu Paste and 5% glucose</intervention_name>
    <description>Buzhong Yiqi plus and minus formula: 1 dose once, twice a day, taking with warm water. Huhuang Detoxicity Paste: One dose once, twice a day, taking with warm water; Baimu Qingre Jiedu Paste: One dose once, twice a day, taking with warm water; Fumigation/inhalation of Chinese herbs and vitamin C: 30-40 minutes once, 3-7 times a day. Patients take vitamin E capsule and folic acid every day. plus invention 1</description>
    <arm_group_label>moderate COVID-19 with combination therapy group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>moderate COVID-19 with traditional Chinese medicine group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Traditional Chinese medicine treatment plus Western medicine treatment</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Alpha-interferon, abidol, ribavirin, Buzhong Yiqi plus and minus formula, Huhuang Detoxicity Paste, Baimu Qingre Jiedu Paste and high-dose vitamin C treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>invention 1 plus invention 2 plus 100 mL of 5% glucose containing vitamin C (10 g/60 kg body mass) is intravenously administered twice a day.</description>
    <arm_group_label>severe COVID-19 with combination therapy group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>severe COVID-19 with traditional Chinese medicine group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Traditional Chinese medicine treatment plus Western medicine treatment plus Bolus administration of vitamin C</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with mild and severe COVID-19 confirmed according to the Diagnosis and&#xD;
             Treatment Protocol for Novel Coronavirus Pneumonia (Trial Version 7) that was issued&#xD;
             by the National Health Commission &amp; State Administration of Traditional Chinese&#xD;
             Medicine;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with suspected COVID-19 who meet one of the following pathogenic or&#xD;
             serological evidence are also confirmed infected with the virus: a) COVID-19 nucleic&#xD;
             acid test positive, as confirmed by real-time fluorescence RT-PCR detection; b) viral&#xD;
             gene sequencing is highly homologous with the known COVID-19; c) serum test positive&#xD;
             for both COVID-19 specific IgM and IgG antibodies; d) serum IgG antibody turns&#xD;
             positive from negative or IgG antibody level in the recovering phase rises four times&#xD;
             or higher than in the acute phase&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with moderate COVID-19 have fever and respiratory symptoms and present with&#xD;
             the imaging features of coronavirus disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects will be considered developing severe COVID-19 if one of the following&#xD;
             conditions occur: a) dyspnea, respiratory ≥ 30 beats/minute, blood oxygen saturation ≤&#xD;
             93%, partial pressure of arterial oxygen (PaO2)/ fraction of inspired oxygen ratio&#xD;
             (FiO2) ≤ 300, and /or lung infiltrates &gt; 50% within 24 to 48 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Age &gt; 18 years, of either sex Provision of written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with critical COVID-19 presenting with shock, acute respiratory distress&#xD;
             syndrome, multiple organ failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with mild COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pregnant or lactating woman&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Upon the investigator's judgment, patients had the diseases that possibly influence&#xD;
             patient participation in this study or study outcomes (such as malignant disease,&#xD;
             autoimmune disease, severe malnutrition, liver and kidney disease, blood disease,&#xD;
             nervous system disease, endocrine diseases) or currently suffer from the diseases that&#xD;
             seriously affect the immune system (such as human immunodeficiency virus infection) or&#xD;
             blood system, or splenectomy/organ transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Upon the request of the investigators or sponsors, patients with other acute malignant&#xD;
             or chronic disease or mental disorder are not suitable for participation in this&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Xijing He, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yongping Liu</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Xudong Yang</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yali Wang</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yifan Feng</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kuiwei Zhang</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jiayue Shan</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lei Shang</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Zhijian Cheng</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Second Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rui Wang</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Second Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Guoyu Wang</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Second Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hui Gao</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Shanjiao Jiang</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Shenhao Liu</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Xi'an</city>
        <state>Shaanxi</state>
        <zip>710100</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 9, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 9, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Qiang Yin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>President</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>vitamin C</keyword>
  <keyword>traditional Chinese medicine</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vitamins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ascorbic Acid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferons</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ribavirin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Interferon-alpha</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

