<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1181">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04726137</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>17493/002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04726137</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>European Pregnancy and Paediatric Infections Cohort Collaboration (EPPICC) SARS-CoV-2 Antibody Study Protocol. Covid-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>SARS-Cov2</acronym>
  <official_title>European Pregnancy and Paediatric Infections Cohort Collaboration (EPPICC) SARS-CoV-2 Antibody Study Protocol</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>PENTA Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital st pierre, Belgium</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Athens</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Cape Town</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital General Universitario Gregorio Marañon</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital Sant Joan de Deu</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Karolinska Institutet</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Guy's and St Thomas' NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>North Manchester General Hospital (Northern Care Alliance NHS Group), Manchester</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital Birmingham NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Imperial College Healthcare NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>King's College Hospital NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>St George's University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>CHIPS+ cohort</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Medical Research Council</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>PENTA Foundation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Scientific knowledge about the COVID-19 pandemic and the virus that is causing it&#xD;
      (SARS-CoV-2) is developing rapidly, and the investigators have a clearer idea of the&#xD;
      population groups who are at higher risk of becoming infected, having serious illness, and&#xD;
      dying. However, less is known about COVID-19 in children, adolescents and young adults living&#xD;
      with HIV. It is not yet known whether, or how, HIV affects people's risk of being infected&#xD;
      with the virus or becoming ill. This study aims to find out whether children and adolescents&#xD;
      living with HIV have had the COVID-19 virus, even if they did not have symptoms and did not&#xD;
      realise it at the time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When a person is infected with a virus, their immune system fights the infection. As a&#xD;
      result, they produce proteins called antibodies, and it may take a few weeks for enough&#xD;
      antibodies to be made to be detected by a blood test. These antibodies may help protect the&#xD;
      person from getting the same infection again. This study wants to find out how many children&#xD;
      and adolescents living with HIV across Europe and South Africa have antibodies to the&#xD;
      COVID-19 virus. It wants to see if the proportion with antibodies is different in younger&#xD;
      children compared to older adolescents and young adults, and whether it varies between&#xD;
      different countries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Children and adolescents with HIV regularly attend hospital outpatient appointments, and&#xD;
      during these appointments blood samples may be taken to monitor their health. This study will&#xD;
      invite these patients to be tested for antibodies to the COVID-19 virus during their routine&#xD;
      visit. The participants will be asked a few short questions about COVID-19 diagnoses in their&#xD;
      household and other risk factors for exposure to the virus, and it will collect information&#xD;
      on their HIV, medications and any other illnesses they may have. At their next routine clinic&#xD;
      visit, approximately 6 months later, it will test them again for antibodies. Testing twice&#xD;
      will let see how the percentage of children, adolescents and young adults with antibodies to&#xD;
      the COVID-19 virus has changed over time. In South Africa, HIV-uninfected adolescents from a&#xD;
      similar socioeconomic background to those living with HIV and recruited to the study will be&#xD;
      invited to join this study, which will allow us to compare the prevalence of antibodies&#xD;
      across the two groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The information from this study will help scientists and healthcare workers care for&#xD;
      children, adolescents and young adults living with HIV during the ongoing COVID-19 epidemic&#xD;
      in the best possible way. Participants may be given their test results, together with&#xD;
      information about what the result means, depending on the usual practice within their clinic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study will be conducted within existing cohorts of children, adolescents and young adults&#xD;
      living with HIV being followed up in several European countries and South Africa: the&#xD;
      European Pregnancy and Paediatric Infections Cohort Collaboration (EPPICC) Paediatric Study&#xD;
      and the Cape Town Adolescent Antiretroviral Cohort (CTAAC). In CTAAC, adolescents without HIV&#xD;
      are also enrolled and will be included in this study. For all participants, two blood samples&#xD;
      will be taken at routine clinic visits approximately six months apart and tested for&#xD;
      antibodies to SARS-CoV-2; clinical data and data on potential COVID-19 exposures will also be&#xD;
      collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MAIN AIM OF THE STUDY The overall aim of this study is to describe the prevalence and&#xD;
      distribution of antibodies to SARS-CoV-2 in children and adolescents living with HIV in&#xD;
      Europe and South Africa.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      •To estimate prevalence of SARS-CoV-2 antibodies in the paediatric and adolescent HIV&#xD;
      population and how this changes over time, overall and by key age groups and regions&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess factors associated with presence of SARS-CoV-2 antibodies (including&#xD;
           demographic factors, antiretroviral treatment, HIV-associated factors or co-morbidities&#xD;
           and exposure to household members with COVID-19)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To estimate the incidence of changes in antibody status to SARS-CoV-2 and associated&#xD;
           factors&#xD;
&#xD;
      ENROLMENT Where feasible, all children and adolescents meeting the inclusion criteria and&#xD;
      attending the participating clinics during the study period will be invited to take part;&#xD;
      where this is not possible, a convenience sample of children and adolescents (e.g. those&#xD;
      attending clinic on a specified day of the week) should be invited. The invitation to&#xD;
      participate should be independent of the patient's probability of having been exposed to&#xD;
      COVID-19. Participants enrolled in the EPPICC Paediatric Study or CTAAC will continue to be&#xD;
      followed up as part of the ongoing study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DATA COLLECTION The study will use data collected in the main EPPICC Paediatric study for&#xD;
      participants attending clinics which participate in that study. This includes demographic&#xD;
      data and clinical, therapeutic, laboratory and outcome information relating to HIV, COVID-19&#xD;
      and multi-system inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C). These data are extracted from&#xD;
      clinic records and submitted as part of the main EPPICC study, and will be linked to data&#xD;
      collected through the serology study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sites which are not members of the EPPICC network will submit equivalent data relating to the&#xD;
      time of the two study visits for CLWHIV and HIV-uninfected adolescents.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additionally, a short questionnaire will be completed by the participant (or their parent /&#xD;
      carer) about potential exposures to COVID-19, including diagnoses in household members and&#xD;
      known contacts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For any participant with a record of a suspected or confirmed COVID-19 or MIS-C diagnosis,&#xD;
      the cohort will be asked to complete an additional case record form providing details of the&#xD;
      diagnosis (e.g. clinical features, hospital admissions, treatments and outcomes).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cohorts will send pseudonymised electronic datasets to the MRC CTU at UCL. Transfer of data&#xD;
      to the MRC CTU at UCL takes place using Galaxkey or an equivalent secure method such as UCL's&#xD;
      REDCap server. Data will then be uploaded into a customised database.&#xD;
&#xD;
      LABORATORY TESTING Where sites are conducting serological testing as part of standard care,&#xD;
      venous blood samples taken at each site will be transported to the laboratory(ies) routinely&#xD;
      carrying out antibody testing for that site. Samples will be analysed with the tests used by&#xD;
      each site in routine practice according to manufacturers' instructions or, if in-house tests&#xD;
      are used, local SOPs/protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At sites not offering routine serological testing, arrangements should be made with local&#xD;
      laboratories for testing. There is strong preference for tests for IgG against the viral&#xD;
      spike protein; however, it is recognised that there may be local considerations influencing&#xD;
      the range of tests available across settings and results from other tests will be considered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DISCONTINUATION OR EARLY WITHDRAWAL OF PARTICIPANTS Participants (or their parents/carers)&#xD;
      may withdraw from the study at any time without providing a reason.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants wishing to withdraw from the study will be offered two options:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Participants may withdraw from active follow-up (i.e. future study procedures) within&#xD;
           this study but allow the retention and use of data already collected, and further&#xD;
           linkage with other data sources as described in the Participant Information Sheet.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Participants may withdraw completely from the study, in which case all data and samples&#xD;
           collected (if not already tested) would be destroyed and no further follow-up or linkage&#xD;
           would take place as part of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Should a participant (or their parent / carer) lose the capacity to consent, they will be&#xD;
      withdrawn from active follow-up and their data / samples retained and included in data&#xD;
      linkages. Participants who withdraw for any reason will not be replaced.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All withdrawals will be recorded in the study database.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ANALYSIS PLAN Proportions with SARS-CoV-2 antibody at baseline and follow-up and the&#xD;
      number/incidence of changes in antibody status between baseline and subsequent test will be&#xD;
      estimated overall and by key patient characteristics, region, history of symptomatic&#xD;
      COVID-19, contact with COVID-19 cases. Factors associated with the presence of SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      antibody, changes in antibody status and any subsequent COVID-19 diagnosis (if numbers&#xD;
      allow), will be explored using univariable and multivariable logistic and Poisson regression.&#xD;
      Exposures of interest include age, sex, ART class and regimen (e.g. protease inhibitor- or&#xD;
      tenofovir-based versus other), CD4 count, viral load, ethnicity, BMI-for-age z-score,&#xD;
      co-infections (e.g. tuberculosis), co-morbidities and household size.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The association between HIV status and SARS-CoV-2 seropositivity, changes in antibody status&#xD;
      and subsequent COVID-19 diagnosis will be assessed in the South African cohort (which&#xD;
      includes HIV-uninfected children as well as CLWHIV) using similar methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If there is substantial variation in the type of antibody test used (anti-S versus anti-N),&#xD;
      analyses will be stratified by type of test. For participants with positive results at both&#xD;
      baseline and follow-up and if data allow, quantitative antibody results will be explored to&#xD;
      qualitatively describe the possible contribution of re-exposure boosting antibody responses&#xD;
      (versus persistence of an existing response).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In sensitivity analyses, we will investigate the implications of misclassification of results&#xD;
      due to imperfect sensitivity / specificity of the serological tests used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      COMPLIANCE The study will be conducted in compliance with the approved protocol, the&#xD;
      Declaration of Helsinki 1996, the principles of Good Clinical Practice as laid down by the&#xD;
      ICH topic E6 (R2), General Data Protection Regulation and the UK Data Protection Act 2018&#xD;
      (DPA number: Z6364106), and the UK Policy Framework for Health and Social Care Research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each cohort is responsible for ensuring compliance with local and national regulatory and&#xD;
      ethical processes, and data protection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with presence of SARS-CoV-2 antibodies assessed by serology tests</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with presence of SARS-CoV-2 antibodies assessed by serology tests</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1150</enrollment>
  <condition>Sars-Cov2 Antibodies in Children and Adolescents Living With HIV</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Paediatric infectious disease clinics across Europe and ongoing study in South Africa&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &lt; 18 years at HIV diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current age under 25 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Attending routine HIV care in a participating clinic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently in follow-up in CTAAC, a cohort which contributes to EPPICC, or another&#xD;
             collaborating cohort&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If aged ≥16 years (or local legal adult age), willing and able to give informed&#xD;
             consent to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If aged &lt;16 years (or local legal adult age), a parent/carer able to give informed&#xD;
             consent for participating in the study (and, depending on local requirements, those&#xD;
             aged ≥10 years, with capacity, to also provide assent).&#xD;
&#xD;
        In addition, in South Africa HIV-uninfected adolescents will be eligible to participate in&#xD;
        the study during planned study visits if they meet the following inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current age under 25 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In follow-up in the CTAAC study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If aged ≥18 years, willing and able to give informed consent to participate in the&#xD;
             study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If aged &lt;18 years, a parent/carer is able to give informed consent for participating&#xD;
             in the study and participant willing and able to provide assent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are taking part in a COVID-19 / SARS-CoV-2 vaccine study at enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have received a COVID-19 / SARS-CoV-2 vaccine through routine care or any other route&#xD;
             at enrollment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>24 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Intira J Collins, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>jeannie.collins@ucl.ac.uk</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Carlo Giaquinto, MD</last_name>
    <phone>0039049964</phone>
    <phone_ext>0122</phone_ext>
    <email>Carlo.Giaquinto@pentafoundation.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Gabija Morkunaite</last_name>
    <phone>0039049964</phone>
    <phone_ext>0122</phone_ext>
    <email>Gabija.Morkunaite@pentafoundation.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Sars-Cov2</keyword>
  <keyword>children</keyword>
  <keyword>adolescents</keyword>
  <keyword>paediatric</keyword>
  <keyword>cohort</keyword>
  <keyword>infectious diseases</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

