<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4028">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04712448</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20/33</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04712448</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Serum Prevalence of Dars-Cov-2 Antibodies in Pre-pandemic Blood Samples (SPARE)</brief_title>
  <acronym>SPARE</acronym>
  <official_title>Serum Prevalence of Antibodies Anti-SARS-2Cov in Healthy Subjects and in Patients With Chronic Diseases in Pre-pandemic Blood Samples</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>IRCCS San Raffaele</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Department of Transfusion Medicine Venice Area</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Istituto per lo Studio, la Prevenzione e la Rete Oncologica</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>IRCCS San Raffaele</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The first reports of infections caused by SARS-CoV-2 were released from Wuhan, China in&#xD;
      December 2019. From there, the infection quickly spread into a pandemic form. The clinical&#xD;
      manifestation of the infection varies enormously, from totally asymptomatic or mildly&#xD;
      symptomatic forms, with nonspecific and flu-like manifestations, to an acute respiratory&#xD;
      distress syndrome which, in patients requiring hospitalization in the ICU and mechanical&#xD;
      ventilation invasive, can lead to death, especially in elderly subjects and carriers of&#xD;
      co-morbidities. Recently, the association of blood groups ABO as possible biological markers&#xD;
      of susceptibility to COVID-19, has been evaluated, linking blood type O with a lower chance&#xD;
      of infection, blood type A with the highest risk, and blood group B with the greatest&#xD;
      complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Italy, the first non &quot;imported&quot; case dates back to February 2020, although new evidence on&#xD;
      subjects tested positive for the antibody assay on serum samples suggests that the virus&#xD;
      started to circulate before the official date.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Few are the data relating to asymptomatic infections or with mild non-specific and nuanced&#xD;
      symptoms that have been quantified in about 85% of the total number of infected. Moreover,&#xD;
      thanks to the availability of serological tests that identify the presence of anti-SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      antibodies, it emerged that a proportion of the population was infected by the virus and&#xD;
      developed an antibody response and that almost 30% of the people with antibodies were&#xD;
      asymptomatic. In order to evaluate the seroprevalence of COVID-19 infection among&#xD;
      asymptomatic subjects we will conduct specific serological tests (total antibodies) to&#xD;
      identify the prevalence of SARS-2-CoV antibodies among healthy blood donors who went to&#xD;
      transfusion facilities of the DIMT in Venice during the pandemic (about 2500 periodic donors&#xD;
      who referred to the Transfusion Center in the period between May and October 2019). Patients&#xD;
      afferent to the Interinstitutional Multidisciplinary Biobank (BioBIM) of the Research Center&#xD;
      of the IRCCS San Raffaele Pisana in Rome, with or without concomitant co-morbidities (about&#xD;
      1000 subject) will be also tested. All samples will be analyzed for any association with sex,&#xD;
      age group and blood group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. Title Serum prevalence of Sars-Cov-2 antibodies in pre-pandemic blood samples&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Background The first reports of infections caused by SARS-CoV-2, a Beta Corona virus,&#xD;
           single-stranded RNA, were released from Wuhan, China in December 2019 [1,2]. From there,&#xD;
           the infection quickly spread into a pandemic form.&#xD;
&#xD;
           The clinical manifestation of the infection varies enormously, from totally asymptomatic&#xD;
           or mildly symptomatic forms, with nonspecific and flu-like manifestations, to an acute&#xD;
           respiratory distress syndrome which, in patients requiring hospitalization in the ICU&#xD;
           and mechanical ventilation invasive, can lead to death [3]. The greater severity of the&#xD;
           course of the infection depends greatly on the general conditions of the patients, being&#xD;
           maximum in elderly subjects and carriers of co-morbidities [4]. Recent studies have also&#xD;
           evaluated the association of blood groups ABO as possible biological markers of&#xD;
           susceptibility to COVID-19, suggesting that people with blood type O have a lower chance&#xD;
           of infection while individuals with blood type A are most at risk, and people with blood&#xD;
           group B have the greatest complications in the event of infection [5,6].&#xD;
&#xD;
           In Italy, the first non &quot;imported&quot; case dates back to February 2020 in a person residing&#xD;
           in Lombardy, in the province of Lodi [7]. However, new evidence on subjects tested&#xD;
           positive for the antibody assay on serum samples suggests that the virus started to&#xD;
           circulate before the official date.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Initially, due to the sudden explosion of cases, epidemiological surveillance focused on&#xD;
           patients related to health facilities because they were symptomatic, suspicious and&#xD;
           high-risk contacts. Few are the data relating to asymptomatic infections or with mild&#xD;
           non-specific and nuanced symptoms that, data from China, would quantify in about 85% of&#xD;
           the total number of infected. Precisely on the role of person-to-person transmission in&#xD;
           the course of asymptomatic infection and in the subclinical phases of the disease,&#xD;
           epidemiological data are lacking despite they could prove to be very important. In fact,&#xD;
           thanks to the availability of serological tests that identify the presence of&#xD;
           anti-SARS-CoV-2 antibodies, it emerged that a proportion of the population was infected&#xD;
           by the virus and developed an antibody response [8] and that almost 30% of the people&#xD;
           with antibodies were asymptomatic. [9]. Therefore, the understanding of the prevalence&#xD;
           of the disease and the prevalence of the antibody response appear to be of considerable&#xD;
           interest, as it seems to be established that asymptomatic subjects can transmit the&#xD;
           SARS-CoV-2 infection for a period that in some cases has proved greater than 14 days&#xD;
           [10].&#xD;
&#xD;
           In order to evaluate the seroprevalence of COVID-19 infection among asymptomatic&#xD;
           subjects, thus obtaining a real estimate of the beginning of the circulation of the&#xD;
           virus in Italy, in our study we intend to conduct specific serological tests (total&#xD;
           antibodies) to identify the prevalence of SARS-2-CoV antibodies among healthy blood&#xD;
           donors who went to transfusion facilities of the DIMT in Venice during the pandemic&#xD;
           (about 2500 periodic donors who referred to the Transfusion Center in the period between&#xD;
           May and October 2019).&#xD;
&#xD;
           Samples belonging to healthy volunteers (about 500) who have agreed to donate their&#xD;
           blood will also be evaluated to establish a pool of control subjects belonging to the&#xD;
           Interinstitutional Multidisciplinary Biobank (BioBIM) of the Research Center of the&#xD;
           IRCCS San Raffaele Pisana in Rome. Finally, in order to evaluate the impact of&#xD;
           seroprevalence in subjects with chronic diseases (about 1000), such as cardiovascular,&#xD;
           oncological, respiratory and neurodegenerative ones, which represent settings of&#xD;
           COVID-19 positive patients with a poorer prognosis, patient samples with the listed&#xD;
           comorbidities, already present in BioBIM, will be analyzed. It has recently emerged that&#xD;
           seroprevalence increases with increasing age and that younger groups have a lower&#xD;
           susceptibility to infection [11]. Therefore, all samples will be analyzed for any&#xD;
           association with sex, age group and blood group.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Promoter Prof.ssa Fiorella Guadagni&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Sponsor/Promotor IRCCS San Raffaele Pisana&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Site IRCCS San Raffaele Pisana&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Study type Multicentric, retrospective, observational, non pharmacological, on&#xD;
           biological samples, conducted at the IRCCS San Raffaele Pisana, Rome, aimed at verifying&#xD;
           the seroprevalence of SARS-COV-2 antibodies in the population.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Objectives 7.1 PRIMARY Objective: The aim of the study is to determine the proportion of&#xD;
           people in the general population who developed an antibody response to antigenic&#xD;
           determinants of SARS-CoV-2 in the period preceding the spread of the virus in Italy.&#xD;
&#xD;
           7.2 SECONDARY Objective: Secondary objectives are represented by the possibility to&#xD;
           characterize the differences in prevalence between genders, age groups and blood groups,&#xD;
           also in relation to more unfavourable courses in subjects with other chronic diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Participants&#xD;
&#xD;
           The study protocol will involve a total of 3500 subjects (3000 healthy subjects and 1000&#xD;
           patients with chronic diseases) aged&gt; 18 years, of both sexes. The two groups will be&#xD;
           formed as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
           A- Healthy subjects among periodic blood donors of the Transfusion Center and volunteer&#xD;
           donors of BioBIM B- Patients with chronic diseases including cardiovascular,&#xD;
           respiratory, oncological and neurodegenerative diseases related to BioBIM&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Inclusion/exclusion Criteria 9.1 Inclusion criteria - Both sexes&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Age &gt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Signed informed consent for the donation / sample storage in the Biological Bank&#xD;
                9.2 Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  for healthy subjects, all those who have shown any symptoms, albeit mild, in the 28&#xD;
                days prior to the donation.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  patients who have not signed the informed consent for the conservation of their&#xD;
                samples in the Biological Bank.&#xD;
&#xD;
           9.3 Drop out Not applicable.&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Study design&#xD;
&#xD;
           The study will last 9 months, and includes 3 phases as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Phase 1: identification of samples Phase 2: sample analysis Phase 3: statistical&#xD;
           analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. Methods of contact with possible participants in the study Not applicable. The study&#xD;
           will be carried out only on samples stored in the Biobank.&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. Methods of acquisition, statistical analysis of data and storage of raw data, compliance&#xD;
           with privacy regulations Data collection will be carried out on a dedicated and&#xD;
           anonymized database by the Principal Investigator. Data will be stored on a dedicated&#xD;
           and protected server.&#xD;
&#xD;
       13. Statistical Methodology 13.1 Statistical analysis Statistical analysis of all parameters&#xD;
           will be conducted under the responsibility of the Biomarker Discovery and Advanced&#xD;
           Technologies (BioDAT) Unit of IRCCS San Raffaele Pisana.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data analysis will be carried out using frequency and percentage for the categorical&#xD;
      variables, and mean and standard deviation for the quantitative variables. The t-test will be&#xD;
      used to compare means and a p-value less than 0.05 will be considered statistically&#xD;
      significant. All analysis will be performed on the SPSS Statistical Package for Social&#xD;
      Sciences.&#xD;
&#xD;
      13.2 Sample size The SPARE study is a pilot study, designed to verify the adequacy and&#xD;
      feasibility of the project, and to obtain preliminary data that allow to determine the size&#xD;
      of the sample of the final study. The sample size is therefore represented by a consecutive&#xD;
      number of subjects who donated blood in the period May-October 2019 (about 2500) and all&#xD;
      subjects (healthy and with chronic diseases) who referred to BioBIM in 2019 (about 1500 ).&#xD;
&#xD;
      14) Requirements of originality and scientific soundness of the study The SPARE study aims to&#xD;
      evaluate the seroprevalence of COVID-19 infection among asymptomatic subjects and thus obtain&#xD;
      a real estimate of the beginning of the circulation of the virus in Italy. The evidence&#xD;
      currently present in the literature refers mainly to the period of the actual pandemic, but&#xD;
      there are no data relating to the months prior to autumn 2019. Same for the official data&#xD;
      released by the Ministry of Health in collaboration with the National Institute of Statistics&#xD;
      (ISTAT) [11]. This study will allow us to define the spread of the SARS-2-CoV virus in a&#xD;
      period long before the date to which the pandemic began in Italy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      15) Expected Results&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main expected results are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Identification of seroprevalence of anti-SARS-2-CoV antibodies in the population prior&#xD;
           to the date on which the beginning of the infection in Italy is officially traced;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Description of any associations with sex, age, blood group, outcomes of patients with&#xD;
           chronic diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      16) Progress report The proposers will submit a report on the progress of the study to the&#xD;
      Ethics Committee at the end of each year and at the end of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      17) Feasibility&#xD;
&#xD;
      - n. patient samples that may be included is consistent with the study design&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  presence of the necessary equipment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  adequacy of personnel 18) Concomitant treatments Not applicable. The SPARE study is a&#xD;
           study on biological samples only 19) Cost/benefit ratio The study is supported by the&#xD;
           IRCCS San Raffaele Pisana. The inclusion of samples belonging to healthy donors and&#xD;
           patients in this clinical study may provide benefits in terms of more accurate&#xD;
           management and acquisition of indications on the spread of the Sars-COV-2 virus in the&#xD;
           asymptomatic population. There are no risks.&#xD;
&#xD;
           20) Ethical relevance The study is conducted on patient samples stored in the Biological&#xD;
           Banks, therefore there are no problems of an ethical nature to its execution.&#xD;
&#xD;
           21) Insurance The procedures provided for the study in this centre do not directly&#xD;
           involve patients, but the analysis of samples taken in the centres they enrol. The&#xD;
           researcher assigned to the analysis of the samples is covered by an insurance policy&#xD;
           included in the contract stipulated with the IRCCS San Raffaele Pisana.&#xD;
&#xD;
           22) Result publication In compliance with the provisions in force regarding the&#xD;
           confidentiality of sensitive data and patent protection, the results of the study will&#xD;
           be submitted for publication within 6 months of after the closure of the database.&#xD;
&#xD;
           23) Informed Consent The submission of specific informed consent for this study on&#xD;
           anonymized samples from biological banks or large collections does not apply.&#xD;
&#xD;
           24) Ethical aspects This protocol will be conducted in accordance with the ethical&#xD;
           principles that draw their origin from the Declaration of Helsinki, respects the GCP and&#xD;
           applicable regulatory provisions.&#xD;
&#xD;
           25) References&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Zhu N, Zhang D, Wang W, Li X, Yang B, Song J, et al. China Novel Coronavirus&#xD;
                Investigating and Research Team A Novel Coronavirus from Patients with Pneumonia in&#xD;
                China, 2019. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(8):727-33. 10.1056/NEJMoa2001017&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. World Health Organization (WHO). Novel coronavirus - China. Geneva: WHO; 12 Jan&#xD;
                2020. [Accessed 09 Oct 2020]. Available from:&#xD;
                https://www.who.int/csr/don/12-january-2020-novel-coronavirus-china/en/&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Santos-Sánchez NF, Salas-Coronado R. Medwave. Origin, structural characteristics,&#xD;
                prevention measures, diagnosis and potential drugs to prevent and COVID-19. 2020&#xD;
                Sep 25;20(8):e8037. doi: 10.5867/medwave.2020.08.8037.&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. Luo L, Fu M, Li Y, Hu S, Luo J, Chen Z, Yu J, Li W, Dong R, Yang Y, Tu L, Xu X. The&#xD;
                potential association between common comorbidities and severity and mortality of&#xD;
                coronavirus disease 2019: A pooled analysis. Clin Cardiol. 2020 Oct 7. doi:&#xD;
                10.1002/clc.23465.&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. Zaho J, Yang Y, Huang H, Li D, Gu D., Lu X, et al. Relationship between the ABO&#xD;
                Blood Group and the COVID-19 susceptibility. 10.1101/2020.03.11.20031096&#xD;
&#xD;
             6. Zalba Marcos S, Luisa Antelo M, Galbete A, Etayo M, Ongay E, García-Erce JA.&#xD;
                Infection and thrombosis associated with COVID-19: Possible role of the ABO blood&#xD;
                group. Med Clin (Engl Ed). 2020 Sep 26. doi: 10.1016/j.medcle.2020.06.013.&#xD;
&#xD;
             7. Livingston E, Bucher K. Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) in Italy. JAMA.&#xD;
                2020;323(14):1335. 10.1001/jama.2020.4344&#xD;
&#xD;
             8. Mizumoto K, Kagaya K, Zarebski A, Chowell G. Estimating the asymptomatic proportion&#xD;
                of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) cases on board the Diamond Princess cruise&#xD;
                ship, Yokohama, Japan, 2020. Euro Surveill 2020;25(10):2000180.&#xD;
&#xD;
             9. ISTAT. Primi risultati dell'indagine di sieroprevalenza sul SARS-CoV-2. Accessible&#xD;
                presso https://www.istat.it/it/archivio/246156&#xD;
&#xD;
            10. Oran DP, et al. Prevalence of Asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 Infection - A Narrative&#xD;
                Review. Ann Int Med 2020; 173:362-376. doi.org/10.7326/M20-3012.&#xD;
&#xD;
            11. Pagani G, et al. Seroprevalence of SARS-CoV-2 significantly varies with age:&#xD;
                Preliminary results from a mass population screening. J Infect. 2020 Sep&#xD;
                19;S0163-4453(20)30629-0. doi: 10.1016/j.jinf.2020.09.021.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 30, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Seroprevalence of antibodies anti-COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>May-October 2019</time_frame>
    <description>Seroprevalence of antibodies anti-COVID-19</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation with blood group</measure>
    <time_frame>May-October 2019</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation with blood group</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation with co-morbidities</measure>
    <time_frame>May-October 2019</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation with co-morbidities</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">3500</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy subjects</arm_group_label>
    <description>Donors of the Transfusion Center of Venice Healthy volunteers afferent to BioBIM</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with chronic diseases afferent to BioBIM</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Anti-COVID test</intervention_name>
    <description>No intervention is foreseen by the protocol</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy subjects</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Serum and whole blood samples&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study protocol will involve a total of 3500 subjects (3000 healthy subjects and 1000&#xD;
        patients with chronic diseases) aged&gt; 18 years, of both sexes. The two groups will be&#xD;
        formed as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A- Healthy subjects among periodic blood donors of the Transfusion Center and volunteer&#xD;
        donors of BioBIM B- Patients with chronic diseases including cardiovascular, respiratory,&#xD;
        oncological and neurodegenerative diseases related to BioBIM&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Both sexes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent for the donation / sample storage in the Biological Bank&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  for healthy subjects: all those who have shown any symptoms, albeit mild, in the 28&#xD;
             days prior to the donation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  for patients: who have not signed the informed consent for the conservation of their&#xD;
             samples in the Biological Bank.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IRCCS San Raffaele</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rome</city>
        <zip>00166</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>IRCCS San Raffaele</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Fiorella Guadagni</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Full Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

