<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2168">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04659200</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>06122020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04659200</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Thyroid Function Tests and Status of Thyroid Autoantibodies in Covid-19 Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Thyroid Function Tests and the Status of Thyroid Autoantibodies in Hospitalized Covid-19 Patients and Their Relationship With White Blood Cells, Neutrophil / Lymphocyte Ratio, c Reactive Protein, Fibrinogen, Procalcitonin, Ferritin and D-dimer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bezmialem Vakif University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bezmialem Vakif University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      COVID-19 infection causes a hypersensitive immune reaction and widespread inflammation&#xD;
      through cytokines in various organs of the body, especially the lungs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This cytokine-mediated widespread inflammation can also affect the thyroid gland, causing&#xD;
      thyroiditis and impaired thyroid functions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The researchers evaluated thyroid function tests and thyroid autoantibodies in patients&#xD;
      hospitalized for COVID-19 infection. Researchers excluded patients on intensive care therapy&#xD;
      and patients with known thyroid disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The researchers examined the relationship of thyroid hormones and thyroid autoantibodies to&#xD;
      COVID-19 disease, white blood cells, neutrophil / lymphocyte ratio, c reactive protein,&#xD;
      fibrinogen, procalcitonin, ferritin, and D-dimer stages in these patients. Researchers&#xD;
      compared changes in thyroid hormones and autoantibodies in people without COVID-19 infection&#xD;
      and without thyroid disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The coronavirus-2 (SARS-COV-2) virus, which can cause severe acute respiratory syndrome&#xD;
      through droplet, has caused the global Coronavirus 19 (COVID-19) pandemic. COVID-19 infection&#xD;
      can be asymptomatic as well as lead to severe illness and even death. This virus causes a&#xD;
      hypersensitive immune reaction and varying degrees of widespread inflammation through&#xD;
      cytokines in various organs of the body, mainly the lungs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cytokine-mediated widespread inflammation caused by the virus may also affect the thyroid&#xD;
      gland and thyrocytes, causing thyroiditis and impairment of thyroid functions. Thus, it may&#xD;
      cause changes in thyroid hormones and thyroid autoantibodies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In study, the researchers found that in patients who were symptomatic with COVID-19 infection&#xD;
      and who were hospitalized, thyroid function tests such as serum thyrotropin (TSH), free&#xD;
      triiodothyronine (FT3), free thyroxine (FT4) and thyroid peroxidase antibodies (TPOAb),&#xD;
      anti-thyroglobulin evaluated antibodies (TGAb). The investigators did not recruit patients in&#xD;
      intensive care and patients with known thyroid disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Researchers looked at the association of patients' thyroid hormones and thyroid&#xD;
      autoantibodies with white blood cells, neutrophil / lymphocyte ratio, c reactive protein,&#xD;
      fibrinogen, procalcitonin, ferritin, D-dimer from hospital archives. The researchers&#xD;
      determined how the thyroid hormones and autoantibodies of patients with COVID-19 infection&#xD;
      were compared with healthy individuals without COVID-19 infection and thyroid disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 7, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 5, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of thyroid stimulating hormone (TSH) between groups</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum TSH results of the Covid patient group and non-Covid control groups were recorded and compared statistically.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of free triiodothyronine (fT3) between groups</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum fT3 results of the Covid patient group and non-Covid control groups were recorded and compared statistically.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of free thyroxine (fT4) between groups</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum fT4 results of the Covid patient group and non-Covid control groups were recorded and compared statistically.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of anti-thyroid peroxidase (Anti-TPO) between groups</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum anti-TPO results of the Covid patient group and non-Covid control groups were recorded and compared statistically.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of anti-thyroglobulin (Anti-Tg) between groups</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum anti-Tg results of the Covid patient group and non-Covid control groups were recorded and compared statistically.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>White blood cells (WBC) results of Covid 19 patient group</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum WBC results were recorded in Covid 19 patient groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Neutrophil / lymphocyte ratio (N/LO) results of Covid 19 patient group</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum N/LO results were recorded in Covid 19 patient groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>C-reactive protein (CRP) results of Covid 19 patient group</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum CRP results were recorded in Covid 19 patient groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fibrinogen results of Covid 19 patient group</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum fibrinogen results were recorded in Covid 19 patient groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Procalcitonin results of Covid 19 patient group</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum procalcitonin results were recorded in Covid 19 patient groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ferritin results of Covid 19 patient group</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum ferritin results were recorded in Covid 19 patient groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>D-dimer results of Covid 19 patient group</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum D-dimer results were recorded in Covid 19 patient groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19 Infection</condition>
  <condition>Thyroid Function Tests</condition>
  <condition>Inflammation; Thyroid</condition>
  <condition>Inflammatory Markers</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Covid Disease Patient Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Researchers evaluated serum thyrotropin, free triiodothyronine, free thyroxine hormones, thyroid peroxidase antibodies and anti-thyroglobulin antibodies in patients hospitalized for COVID-19 infection. The researchers evaluated the results of white blood cells, neutrophil / lymphocyte ratio, c reactive protein, fibrinogen, procalcitonin, ferritin, D-dimer in Covid-9 patients.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Covid-Free Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Researchers evaluated the results of serum thyrotropin, free triiodothyronine, free thyroxine hormones, thyroid peroxidase antibodies and anti-thyroglobulin antibodies, white blood cells, neutrophil / lymphocyte ratio, c reactive protein, fibrinogen, procalcitonin, ferritin, D-dimer in the non-patient control group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Venous blood was collected for biochemistry testing.</intervention_name>
    <description>For the measurement of blood tests, 10 ml of blood samples were taken from the right forearm veins with a syringe.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Covid Disease Patient Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Covid-Free Control Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The results of screening thyroid blood tests of healthy people without thyroid disease will&#xD;
        be compared with the records of the COVID 19 patient group who were hospitalized and&#xD;
        treated with no known thyroid disease.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  To accept research.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being over the age of 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID 19 test results to be positive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not taking thyroid disease medication before.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving inpatient treatment in the COVID service in the hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not accepting research.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be under the age of 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative COVID 19 test results for patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID patients treated as outpatient.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thyroid disease in the healthy control group.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sabahattin Destek</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fatih</city>
        <state>Istanbul</state>
        <zip>34093</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brancatella A, Ricci D, Viola N, Sgrò D, Santini F, Latrofa F. Subacute Thyroiditis After Sars-COV-2 Infection. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2020 Jul 1;105(7). pii: dgaa276. doi: 10.1210/clinem/dgaa276.</citation>
    <PMID>32436948</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Caron P. Thyroid disorders and SARS-CoV-2 infection: From pathophysiological mechanism to patient management. Ann Endocrinol (Paris). 2020 Oct;81(5):507-510. doi: 10.1016/j.ando.2020.09.001. Epub 2020 Sep 18. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32950466</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mattar SAM, Koh SJQ, Rama Chandran S, Cherng BPZ. Subacute thyroiditis associated with COVID-19. BMJ Case Rep. 2020 Aug 25;13(8). pii: e237336. doi: 10.1136/bcr-2020-237336.</citation>
    <PMID>32843467</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>van Gerwen M, Alsen M, Little C, Barlow J, Naymagon L, Tremblay D, Sinclair CF, Genden E. Outcomes of Patients With Hypothyroidism and COVID-19: A Retrospective Cohort Study. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2020 Aug 18;11:565. doi: 10.3389/fendo.2020.00565. eCollection 2020.</citation>
    <PMID>33013686</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 8, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Bezmialem Vakif University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sabahattin Destek</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Thyroid Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The study will be shared when it becomes an article.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

