<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4475">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04740489</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>005</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04740489</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Impact of Covid-19 on Cardiac Rehabilitation Participants and Staff</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pilot Study Examining Participants Psychosocial Health, Physical Activity and Staff Experiences: Is Adapted Home-based Phase 3 Cardiac Rehabilitation Feasible and Beneficial?</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ant Shepherd</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hampshire Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Portsmouth</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      What are the experiences of staff and participants in phase 3 cardiac rehabilitation during&#xD;
      the Covid-19 pandemic, and what impacts have adapted delivery had on participants' physical&#xD;
      activity levels, mental health and well-being?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiac rehabilitation (CR) is a vital service for individuals diagnosed and treated for&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease (e.g., heart attack, angina, valve disease). The service helps to&#xD;
      improve recovery rates through supporting patients with beneficial lifestyle changes (e.g.,&#xD;
      physical activity, healthy eating), and coping with emotional distress following a traumatic&#xD;
      cardiac event. The environment in which CR is being delivered has changed in response to the&#xD;
      Covid-19 pandemic, including remote working practices, and in some instances postponing of&#xD;
      rehabilitation. Despite the public health rationale for such measures, it is essential to&#xD;
      consider the impact of adapted services on patient's mental health and physical activity&#xD;
      participation, and to consider staff experiences in using remote working regimes. The current&#xD;
      study aims to recruit staff and patients from phase 3 cardiac rehabilitation across Hampshire&#xD;
      Hospitals Foundation Trust to explore their experiences of adapted services through a mixed&#xD;
      methods study design. Staff and patients will be interviewed over the phone to explore&#xD;
      experiences and impacts of Covid-19 with their rich in-depth viewpoints and stories. In&#xD;
      addition, during an 8 week period of rehabilitation, patients will be asked to report and&#xD;
      record their physical activity levels with diaries and accelerometers (a wrist worn device&#xD;
      measuring movement), record their resting blood pressure and heart rate, and complete&#xD;
      questionnaires to assess changes in mental health. This study could help to understand the&#xD;
      impact of the pandemic on cardiac patients recovery and on staff's experiences implementing&#xD;
      programme changes to assist in preparing for the future of CR post COVID 19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cardiovascular disease (CVD) causes 17.9 million deaths globally each year, an estimated 31%&#xD;
      of all deaths worldwide. Individuals diagnosed with CVD (e.g., acute coronary syndrome) are&#xD;
      typically referred to cardiac rehabilitation (CR) following acute treatment (e.g.&#xD;
      percutaneous coronary intervention) to facilitate both physical and psychological recovery,&#xD;
      as well as an absolute risk reduction in cardiovascular mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The timescale of CR can be divided into 4 interlinked phases. Phase 1 is marked by admission&#xD;
      to hospital and acute care (e.g., revascularisation). Phase 2 is considered as early&#xD;
      rehabilitation following patient discharge, usually a period of 2-6 weeks home-based support&#xD;
      (e.g., Heart Manual) depending on when a participant is considered fit enough to start a&#xD;
      structured exercise programme. Phase 3 CR is a comprehensive outpatient programme, considered&#xD;
      the core rehabilitation phase, in which participants receive structured exercise, health&#xD;
      education, risk factor modification and psychological support. Upon discharge from clinically&#xD;
      supervised phase 3 CR participants are generally signposted to long-term community based&#xD;
      exercise classes (phase 4).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current study will take place within a core phase 3 CR programme in the UK. According to&#xD;
      the National Audit of CR, 75.4% of participants receive group-based supervised programmes,&#xD;
      and only 8.8% of participants receive home-based services in the UK (BHF, 2019).&#xD;
      Nevertheless, the environment in which CR is being delivered has dramatically changed in&#xD;
      response to the COVID 19 pandemic. Staff have been redeployed to COVID units, limiting&#xD;
      operative capabilities, and in some instances postponed rehabilitation. In the midst of this&#xD;
      global crisis, The European Association of Preventive Cardiology recommended an increased&#xD;
      patient turnover in CR, adoption of precautions during programmes (e.g., avoiding group&#xD;
      exercises), shortening the programmes, and following participants with remote assessment.&#xD;
      Despite the public health rationale for such measures, it is essential to consider the impact&#xD;
      of adapted services on participant's psychosocial health and physical activity participation,&#xD;
      and to consider staff experiences of adaptation 'on the fly' through remote working&#xD;
      protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An integral characteristic of group-based CR settings is a positive, supporting and inclusive&#xD;
      climate that encourages participants to manage their emotions and illness perceptions to&#xD;
      improve coping and recovery following a cardiac event . Currently, these interpersonal&#xD;
      dynamics have dramatically altered with the shift to remote delivery of CR components (e.g.,&#xD;
      telephone, video, internet, and social media). Hence, some of the benefits of group and face&#xD;
      to face rehabilitation have arguably been removed. In addition, participants are now having&#xD;
      to cope with the added threat of catching COVID 19 and having to deal with some of the&#xD;
      potentially distressing consequences of quarantine, such as post-traumatic stress symptoms,&#xD;
      confusion and anger. Therefore, the CR work force needs to be resilient and innovative to&#xD;
      support participants throughout the pandemic with home-based programmes and telemedicine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fortunately, there is an evidence base to suggest that home-based programmes, such as the&#xD;
      &quot;Heart Manual&quot;, are as effective as centre-based CR in improving clinical and health-related&#xD;
      quality of life outcomes. Indeed, novel interventions, such as telehealth weight management,&#xD;
      Rehabilitation EnAblement in Chronic Heart Failure (REACH-HF), and cardiac telerehabilitation&#xD;
      interventions, such as REMOTE-CR, are effective alternatives to the 'gold standard'&#xD;
      centre-based provision. However, these findings are typically based upon randomised&#xD;
      controlled trials (RCT) and are rarely investigated within real-world clinical settings where&#xD;
      the research to practice gap needs to be negotiated. Scaling up RCT's and implementing novel&#xD;
      remote programmes into CR promptly and effectively during the current pandemic could be a&#xD;
      challenging process impacted by attitudes towards change, resources available, expertise,&#xD;
      time, and competing priorities. Hence, it is important to assess and understand the&#xD;
      real-world patient outcomes (e.g., physical activity participation, psychosocial and physical&#xD;
      health) and the complexity of employing adapted CR services during the Covid-19 pandemic,&#xD;
      including the barriers and facilitators to such implementation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this pilot study is to obtain quantitative and qualitative data to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Assess the impact of adapted CR modalities in the UK on participants' physiological&#xD;
           health, psychosocial health and physical activity behaviour&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Explore CR staff's experiences of adapted delivery&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Determine the feasibility of an adapted home-based CR programme for routine clinical&#xD;
           practice&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Psychosocial health and wellbeing</measure>
    <time_frame>During qualitative interviews (post week 5).</time_frame>
    <description>Semi structured interviews</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability to Participants</measure>
    <time_frame>During qualitative interviews after the intervention has ended (post week 5).</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative interviews</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasible to Participants</measure>
    <time_frame>During qualitative interviews after the intervention has ended (post week 5).</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative interviews</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical activity</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 1, 4 and 8 of rehabilitation</time_frame>
    <description>Accelerometer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Loneliness</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 1, 4 and 8 of rehabilitation</time_frame>
    <description>University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA) loneliness scale version 3 (minimum score 20 maximum of 80). Higher score signifies more loneliness</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Heart rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 1, 4 and 8 of rehabilitation</time_frame>
    <description>Beats per minute</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 1, 4 and 8 of rehabilitation</time_frame>
    <description>mmHg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease management</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 1, 4 and 8 of rehabilitation</time_frame>
    <description>Patient activation measure (Questionnaire)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease management</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 1, 4 and 8 of rehabilitation</time_frame>
    <description>The Cardiac Self-Efficacy (CSE) Scale. (minimum score 0 maximum of 52). Higher score indicates higher cardiac self-efficacy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Heart Diseases</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Phase 3 Cardiac rehabilitation</intervention_name>
    <description>Phase 3 CR is a comprehensive outpatient programme, considered the core rehabilitation phase, in which participants receive structured exercise, health education, risk factor modification and psychological support. Upon discharge from clinically supervised phase 3 CR participants are generally signposted to long-term community-based exercise classes (phase 4). The current study will take place within a core phase 3 CR programme in the UK.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Service user participants are individuals treated for acute coronary syndromes (e.g.,&#xD;
        NSTEMI, STEMI), heart failure, valve disease, and ICD's.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Staff participants will be recruited from members of a multidisciplinary team including; CR&#xD;
        professionals including CR specialist nurses, physiotherapists and exercise practitioners.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 18 years or over&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Staff and participants participating in Phase 3 CR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to undertake the interview, diary, questionnaire and accelerometer&#xD;
             processes&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged &lt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not participating in Phase 3 CR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any individuals who are unable to represent their own interests or are particularly&#xD;
             susceptible to coercion (vulnerable individuals), and are therefore unable to give&#xD;
             informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If individuals have difficulties in adequately understanding written or verbal&#xD;
             information in English, as the study doesn't have funding for a translator or&#xD;
             interpreter&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Samantha J Meredith, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0239284</phone>
    <phone_ext>5194</phone_ext>
    <email>samantha.meredith@port.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Chad SG Witcher, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0239284</phone>
    <phone_ext>5194</phone_ext>
    <email>chad.witcher@port.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Portsmouth</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ant Shepherd</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Senior Lecturer in Physical Activity, Exercise and Health</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Physical data will be made available. Interview transcripts will not as participants could be identified.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

