<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="379">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04589936</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>284061</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04589936</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prone Position to Improve Oxygenation in COVID-19 Patients Outside Critical Care</brief_title>
  <acronym>PRONE-COVID</acronym>
  <official_title>Prone Position to Improve Oxygenation in COVID-19 Patients Outside Critical Care (PRONE-COVID Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Prone positioning is known to improve the PaO2/FiO2 ratio and reduce mortality in patients&#xD;
      with ARDS managed in the critical care setting. Therefore, it is incorporated into regular&#xD;
      clinical practice of managing patients with ARDS in critical care and is being used as such&#xD;
      in the COVID-19 outbreak. Given that prone positioning is recommended by the Intensive Care&#xD;
      Society in non-ventilated patients with COVID-19, there is an urgent need to better&#xD;
      understand the physiological effects of prone positioning in such cases. Furthermore, the&#xD;
      translation and applicability of such a low-cost non-invasive intervention in a wider group&#xD;
      of patients with pneumonia not specific to covid-19 infection, is an important consideration&#xD;
      that merits investigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This single-centred observational study conducted at Cambridge University Hospitals NHS&#xD;
      Foundation Trust aims to improve understanding of physiological effects of prone positioning&#xD;
      in non-ventilated patients with COVID-19 and a control group of patients with non-COVID-19&#xD;
      related pneumonia. The study also aims to incorporate a small subset of patients, with an&#xD;
      approximately even spread of COVID-19 and non-COVID cases, which allows for an additional&#xD;
      exploratory descriptive report on prone positioning over a 24-hour period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study proposes that prone positioning improves oxygenation in non-ventilated patients&#xD;
      with pneumonia (COVID-19 related or not) requiring supplemental oxygen managed outside of the&#xD;
      critical care setting.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      COVID-19 (coronavirus disease 2019) caused by the infectious agent, SARS-CoV-2, was first&#xD;
      recognised in Wuhan, Hubei Province, China in December 2019. Whilst a large proportion of&#xD;
      COVID-19 illness within the community is mild, patients who are admitted to hospital with&#xD;
      COVID-19 often have more severe disease and have a higher risk of developing COVID-19&#xD;
      complications including ARDS. Patients with ARDS are often managed on intensive care units&#xD;
      that have evidence-based protocols for managing patients with ARDS. Prone positioning for&#xD;
      such patients is a well-recognised component of ARDS critical care management. It is known to&#xD;
      improve oxygenation and reduce oxygen requirements, as well as reduce mortality in patients&#xD;
      with moderate to severe ARDS managed in critical care. The benefits of prone positioning as a&#xD;
      technique to improve oxygenation in awake, non-intubated patients is less well-established. A&#xD;
      few studies have showed prone positioning to be well-tolerated and improved oxygenation&#xD;
      amongst non-intubated patients without respiratory support, as well as those requiring&#xD;
      high-flow nasal oxygen or non-invasive ventilation support.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It remains unknown whether prone positioning is beneficial in patients with COVID-19 earlier&#xD;
      in their disease, prior to requirement of non-invasive or invasive ventilation. This study&#xD;
      therefore aims to better understand the physiological effects of prone positioning in&#xD;
      patients with pneumonia with and without COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This will be a single-centred interventional case-control study, comparing physiological&#xD;
      effect of prone positioning in COVID-19 cases versus pneumonia unrelated to COVID-19. A&#xD;
      sub-study of a smaller number of enrolled patients, with approximately even spread of&#xD;
      COVID-19 and non-COVID cases, will allow an additional exploratory descriptive report on&#xD;
      prone positioning over a 24-hour period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant will be fitted with a Masimo monitoring device that enables continuous&#xD;
      monitoring, and subsequent data storage and download of SpO2, heart rate, end tidal CO2 and&#xD;
      respiratory rate. The sub-study investigating the effects of a longer duration of proning&#xD;
      will involve applying a non-invasive positional sensor to automatically detect the&#xD;
      participant's position, and correlate it with the patient's physiological parameters as well&#xD;
      as tolerability. Qualitative data on patient's tolerability of prone positioning will also be&#xD;
      collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is anticipated that each participant will be their own control, enabling comparison of&#xD;
      SpO2 in supine, lateral, prone and again supine positions. Summary statistics of mean,&#xD;
      median, range, interquartile range, and range for each position for participants will be&#xD;
      summarised. The data from the two arms will initially be analysed separately, then pooled to&#xD;
      determine if a larger sample size impacts results. A multilevel regression model with average&#xD;
      SpO2 as outcome will be fitted to assess the effect of lying position on SpO2. Additional&#xD;
      models such as mixed models incorporating multiple repeated measurements/endpoints may be&#xD;
      considered/fitted for exploratory analyses. Data from questionnaires will be reported by&#xD;
      summary statistics where possible. Free text responses may be grouped into themes, and&#xD;
      parametric or non-parametric tests will be used to analyse the VAS data further.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All data will be transferred into a Case Report Form (CRF) which will be anonymised. The&#xD;
      investigator will obtain written informed consent from each participant before any&#xD;
      study-specific activity is performed. Before the start of the study, or implementation of any&#xD;
      amendment, we will obtain approval of the protocol, protocol amendments, informed consent&#xD;
      forms and other relevant documents from the REC.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 3, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Case-control study design, with 1:1 for COVID-19 case versus pneumonia unrelated to COVID-19.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Peripheral Oxygen saturation</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year (June 2021)</time_frame>
    <description>Oxygenation measured by peripheral saturations in relation to inspired oxygen (FiO2) when patient is prone versus a supine or lateral position using a Masimo device</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PaO2 :FiO2 ratio calculated from formulae</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year (June 2021)</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate effects of prone position versus supine or lateral position on derived measures of oxygenation (Pa02:Fi02 ratio calculated from formulae) in relation to inspired oxygen.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Respiratory rate measured with Masimo device</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year (June 2021)</time_frame>
    <description>Effects of prone versus supine or lateral position on respiratory rate</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Heart rate measured with Masimo device</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year (June 2021)</time_frame>
    <description>Effects of prone versus supine or lateral position on heart rate</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood pressure measured with Masimo device</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year (June 2021)</time_frame>
    <description>Effects of prone versus supine or lateral position on blood pressure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient reported severity of breathlessness on a continuous linear scale of 0 to 10cm (10cm being the most severe)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year (June 2021)</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate whether prone position reduces patient reported severity of breathlessness assessed by visual assessment score.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient tolerability of prone position on a continuous linear scale of 0 to 10cm (10cm being the most unacceptable)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year (June 2021)</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate patient tolerability of prone position assessed by visual assessment score.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Investigator experience of delivering prone positioning</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year (June 2021)</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate investigator experience of delivering prone positioning in this study by free text question responses.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess patient's peripheral oxygen saturation</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year (June 2021)</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the natural position of patients (with the aid of position sensors) who are encouraged to position themselves prone over a 24-hour period (which include sleep) and relationship with oxygenation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">56</enrollment>
  <condition>Pneumonia</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Non-ventilated patients with COVID-19</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pneumonia control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with pneumonia unrelated to COVID-19 requiring supplemental O2.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prone positioning</intervention_name>
    <description>Patient will first lay supine for a given time period, followed by lateral position on either side, then prone position, lastly return to supine position. Participants are anticipated to stay in prone position for a minimum of 30min to a maximum of 2 hours depending on tolerability. Participants will be guided in how to independently position themselves and rotate through the cycle of positions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pneumonia control</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Proning</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Have confirmed or suspected COVID-19 or non-COVID pneumonia (confirmed with&#xD;
             radiological changes)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. FiO2 ≥24% or requiring basic respiratory support (supplementary oxygen via face mask,&#xD;
             nasal cannula, venturi, non-rebreathe bag) to achieve clinical target SpO2 (e.g. SpO2&#xD;
             92-96%), ensuring patient is on appropriately titrated oxygen to be within this range.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Be able to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Communicate and cooperate with the procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Rotate and adjust position independently&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. No anticipated airway issues&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The presence of any of the following will mean participants are ineligible:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Signs of respiratory distress (e.g. respiratory rate ≥35, accessory muscle use)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Immediate need for intubation&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Haemodynamic instability or new arrhythmia&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Unstable spine/thoracic injury/recent abdominal surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Pregnancy (2nd/3rd trimester)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. At risk of pressure sores/ulcers&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Neurological issues-frequent seizures&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Facial injury that would make prone position difficult&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Gastrointestinal issues-frequent vomiting or diarrhoea that would make prone position&#xD;
             difficult&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jonathan Fuld</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jonathan Fuld</last_name>
    <phone>01223 256 337</phone>
    <email>jonathan.fuld@addenbrookes.nhs.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cambridge</city>
        <state>Cambridgeshire</state>
        <zip>CB23 7PH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jonathan Fuld</last_name>
      <phone>01223 256 337</phone>
      <email>jonathan.fuld@addenbrookes.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Akhilesh Jha</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marie Fisk</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Iain Goodhart</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sam Mann</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Fangyue Chen</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Andrew Ying</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Celine Goh</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Chen Zhang</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kate Fitzpatrick</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Elharrar X, Trigui Y, Dols AM, Touchon F, Martinez S, Prud'homme E, Papazian L. Use of Prone Positioning in Nonintubated Patients With COVID-19 and Hypoxemic Acute Respiratory Failure. JAMA. 2020 Jun 9;323(22):2336-2338. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.8255.</citation>
    <PMID>32412581</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 6, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 15, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 15, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr Jonathan Fuld</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Consultant in Respiratory and Acute medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Prone positioning</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Pneumonia</keyword>
  <keyword>Oxygenation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

