<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4640">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04550351</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LKM-2020-NCV03</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04550351</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Recombinant New Coronavirus Vaccine (CHO Cells) to Prevent SARS-CoV-2 Phase I Clinical Trial (≥60 Years Old)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled Phase I Clinical Trial to Evaluate the Safety and Tolerability of Recombinant New Coronavirus Vaccines (CHO Cells) in Healthy People Aged 60 Years and Above</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Anhui Zhifei Longcom Biologic Pharmacy Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Anhui Zhifei Longcom Biologic Pharmacy Co., Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Popular topic: Phase I clinical trial of recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cell) (≥60&#xD;
      years old) Research purpose: Main purpose: To evaluate the safety and tolerability of&#xD;
      different doses of recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells) in healthy people aged 60&#xD;
      years and above. Secondary purpose: to initially explore the immunogenicity and durability of&#xD;
      different doses of recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Overall design: A single-center, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial design&#xD;
      was adopted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population: a healthy population of 60 years and above, a total of 50 cases, both men&#xD;
      and women.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Test groups: 20 cases in the low-dose group, 5 cases in the placebo group; 20 cases in the&#xD;
      high-dose group, 5 cases in the placebo group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Popular topic: Phase I clinical trial of recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cell) (≥60&#xD;
      years old) Product name: Recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cell),Each dose contains&#xD;
      25μg/0.5mL/bottle (low dose), 50μg/0.5mL/bottle (high dose) Indications: Prevention of&#xD;
      respiratory diseases caused by new coronavirus infection Research population: healthy people&#xD;
      ≥60 years old Research Unit: Hunan Provincial Center for Disease Control and Prevention&#xD;
      Research purpose: Main purpose: To evaluate the safety and tolerability of different doses of&#xD;
      recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells) in healthy people aged 60 years and above.&#xD;
      Secondary purpose: to initially explore the immunogenicity and durability of different doses&#xD;
      of recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Overall design: A single-center, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial design&#xD;
      was adopted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Immunization program: 0, 1, and 2 months. Dose: Divided into low-dose group (25μg/0.5mL) and&#xD;
      high-dose group (50μg/0.5mL).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population: a healthy population of 60 years and above, a total of 50 cases, both men&#xD;
      and women.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Test groups: 20 cases in the low-dose group, 5 cases in the placebo group; 20 cases in the&#xD;
      high-dose group, 5 cases in the placebo group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research plan and implementation:Volunteers aged 60 and above signed the informed consent&#xD;
      form and asked about medical history, residence history and other information and then&#xD;
      performed relevant examinations, including height, weight, vital signs, physical examination,&#xD;
      laboratory tests (blood routine, urine routine, blood biochemistry), urine Pregnancy (women&#xD;
      of childbearing age). After the study number is assigned, the subjects will collect throat&#xD;
      swabs for SARS-CoV-2 real-time fluorescent RT-PCR nucleic acid detection, and blood will be&#xD;
      collected for SARS-CoV-2 IgM and IgG antibody detection. Subjects will be in accordance with&#xD;
      0, 1, and 2 months Vaccination procedures are carried out. According to the order of the dose&#xD;
      from low to high, it is divided into two stages and inoculated sequentially. Among them,&#xD;
      placebo/five people per dose group, test vaccine/20 people per dose group, and qualified&#xD;
      subjects were randomly enrolled into the test vaccine group and the placebo control group. In&#xD;
      the first phase, subjects in the low-dose group (20 cases) and the placebo group (5 cases)&#xD;
      were randomly enrolled; the safety data of the first 7-day vaccination was evaluated by DSMB,&#xD;
      and if the suspension/termination criteria were not met, the first In the second-phase study,&#xD;
      subjects in the high-dose group (20 cases) and the placebo group (5 cases) were randomly&#xD;
      enrolled. Follow-up to 30 days after each dose, if the suspension/termination criteria is&#xD;
      reached, DSMB will decide whether to inoculate the follow-up doses; in other cases, the&#xD;
      investigator will decide whether to inoculate the follow-up doses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety endpoint:&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. The incidence of all AEs within 1 month after the first dose to the full course of&#xD;
      vaccination:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Total AE incidence;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. The incidence of AEs related to research vaccines;&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. The incidence of grade 3 and above AE;&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. The incidence of grade 3 and above AEs related to research vaccines;&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. The incidence of AEs leading to withdrawal;&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. The incidence of AEs related to research vaccines leading to withdrawal; 2. The&#xD;
           incidence of all serious adverse events (SAE) and the incidence of SAE related to the&#xD;
           vaccine within 12 months after the first dose to the full course of vaccination; 3.&#xD;
           Changes in the clinical significance of the laboratory test indicators after each dose&#xD;
           of inoculation compared to before the first dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Immunogenicity endpoint:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Humoral immunity: before the first dose of vaccination, 1 month and 6 months after the full&#xD;
      vaccination, neutralizing antibodies of novel coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2), S protein binding&#xD;
      antibody (IgG), RBD protein binding antibody (IgG) ) Positive rate; The levels of&#xD;
      neutralizing antibodies against SARS-CoV-2, S protein binding antibody (IgG) and RBD protein&#xD;
      binding antibody (IgG) and their relative immunity 1 month and 6 months after the full&#xD;
      vaccination of all subjects Increase the multiple before.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 19, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 18, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The number of adverse events after intramuscular injection</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months after full vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>The main observation methods of adverse reactions mainly include laboratory examination, local reactions and systemic reactions at the administration site.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenic end point</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 6 months after the last dose of vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>The positive rate of neutralizing antibody, S protein binding antibody (IgG), RBD protein binding antibody (IgG) of all subjects before the first dose, 1 month and 6 months after the full vaccination And titer levels and their fold increase before immunity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronavirus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Population I</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Population I has 20 subjects and is considered negative for SARS-COV-2 and fluorescent RT-PCR nucleic acids. Population I is intramuscular injection of deltoid muscle of upper arm with low dose of vaccine.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Population II</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Population II has 20 subjects and is considered negative for SARS-COV-2 and fluorescent RT-PCR nucleic acids. Population II is a high-dose vaccine intramuscular injection of deltoid muscle of the upper arm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Population Ⅲ</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Population Ⅲ has 10 subjects and is considered negative for SARS-COV-2 and fluorescent RT-PCR nucleic acids. Population Ⅲ is a placebo intramuscular injection of deltoid muscle of the upper arm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Biological/Vaccine: Recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cell) low-dose group</intervention_name>
    <description>Intramuscular injection of deltoid muscle of upper armof 25μg/0.5ml/person doseRecombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Population I</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Biological/Vaccine: Recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells) high-dose group</intervention_name>
    <description>Intramuscular injection of deltoid muscle of upper armof 50μg/0.5ml/person doseRecombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Population II</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Biological/Vaccine: Recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells) placebo group</intervention_name>
    <description>Intramuscular injection of deltoid muscle of upper armof 0.5ml/person doseRecombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Population Ⅲ</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        standard constrain：&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Persons with full capacity for civil conduct aged ≥60 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects voluntarily agree to participate in the research and sign an informed consent&#xD;
             form, and can provide valid identification; understand and comply with the&#xD;
             requirements of the trial protocol; have the ability to understand (non-illiterate)&#xD;
             research procedures and participate in the planned follow-up;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Axillary body temperature &lt;37.3℃;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Female subjects and male subjects of childbearing age agree to take effective&#xD;
             contraceptive measures during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria：&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The results of physical examination and laboratory examination before screening are&#xD;
             abnormal and clinically significant as judged by clinicians, or systolic blood&#xD;
             pressure ≥160mmHg and/or diastolic blood pressure ≥100mmHg before screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. A history of severe allergies to any component of the test vaccine, including aluminum&#xD;
             preparations, such as: anaphylactic shock, allergic laryngeal edema, allergic purpura,&#xD;
             thrombocytopenic purpura, local allergic necrosis (Arthus reaction), dyspnea, blood&#xD;
             vessels Neuroedema, etc.; or any previous history of serious side effects after the&#xD;
             use of any vaccine or drug;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. People with a history of SARS and SARS-CoV-2 (meet any of the following: ①Have a&#xD;
             history of SARS and SARS-CoV-2 infection or onset; ②During this SRAS-CoV-2 epidemic,&#xD;
             there are patients who have been diagnosed with the new crown/ Suspected patient&#xD;
             contact history);&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Have taken antipyretic or analgesic within 24 hours before the first dose of&#xD;
             vaccination;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Inoculate subunit vaccine and/or inactivated vaccine within 14 days before the first&#xD;
             dose of vaccine, and inoculate live attenuated vaccine within 30 days;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. People suffering from the following diseases:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acute (within 72 hours) feverish illness;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Suffering from digestive system diseases (such as diarrhea, abdominal pain,&#xD;
                       vomiting, etc.) in the past 7 days;&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  Suffering from congenital malformations or developmental disorders,&#xD;
                            genetic defects, severe malnutrition, etc.;&#xD;
&#xD;
                              -  Congenital or acquired immunodeficiency or autoimmune disease&#xD;
                                 history or receiving immunomodulator treatment within 6 months,&#xD;
                                 such as hormones; or monoclonal antibodies; or thymosin; or&#xD;
                                 interferon, etc.; but local medication (such as ointment, Eye&#xD;
                                 drops, inhalation or nasal spray);&#xD;
&#xD;
                                   -  Known to have been diagnosed with infectious diseases, such&#xD;
                                      as: tuberculosis, viral hepatitis and/or human&#xD;
                                      immunodeficiency virus HIV antibody positive or syphilis&#xD;
                                      specific antibody positive;&#xD;
&#xD;
                                        -  Neurological diseases or neurodevelopmental dysfunction&#xD;
                                           (for example, migraine, epilepsy, stroke, seizures in&#xD;
                                           the last three years, encephalopathy, focal neurological&#xD;
                                           deficits, Guillain-Barré syndrome, encephalomyelitis or&#xD;
                                           transverse myelitis; History of mental illness or family&#xD;
                                           history;&#xD;
&#xD;
                                           ⑦Functional asplenia, as well as any cause of aspleen or&#xD;
                                           splenectomy;&#xD;
&#xD;
                                           ⑧Severe chronic diseases or conditions that cannot be&#xD;
                                           controlled smoothly in the advanced stage, such as&#xD;
                                           diabetes and thyroid disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
                                           ⑨Severe liver and kidney diseases; respiratory diseases&#xD;
                                           that currently require daily drug treatment (for&#xD;
                                           example, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease [COPD],&#xD;
                                           asthma) or any treatment for exacerbation of respiratory&#xD;
                                           diseases (for example, asthma exacerbation) in the last&#xD;
                                           5 years; suffering from severe History of cardiovascular&#xD;
                                           disease (such as congestive heart failure,&#xD;
                                           cardiomyopathy, ischemic heart disease, arrhythmia,&#xD;
                                           conduction block, myocardial infarction, pulmonary heart&#xD;
                                           disease) or myocarditis or pericarditis;&#xD;
&#xD;
                                           ⑩Have thrombocytopenia, any coagulation dysfunction or&#xD;
                                           receive anticoagulant treatment, etc.;&#xD;
&#xD;
                                           ?Tumor patients;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Have received blood or blood-related products, including immunoglobulin, within 3&#xD;
             months; or plan to use it during the research period;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Those who are already pregnant (including a positive urine pregnancy test), or are&#xD;
             breastfeeding;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Any research or unregistered products (drugs, vaccines, biological products or&#xD;
             devices) other than research products have been used within 3 months, or planned to be&#xD;
             used during the research period;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. The investigator believes that any disease or condition in the subject may put the&#xD;
             subject at an unacceptable risk; the subject cannot meet the requirements of the&#xD;
             protocol; it interferes with the assessment of the vaccine response.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hunan Provincial Center for Disease Control and Prevention</name>
      <address>
        <city>Xiangtan</city>
        <state>Changsha</state>
        <zip>411228</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 14, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Recombinant Novel Coronavirus Vaccine</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

