<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3809">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04695704</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PENDING</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04695704</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Montelukast Clinical Trial in Mild-moderate Respiratory Symptoms in Patients With Long-COVID (ESPERANZA COVID)</brief_title>
  <acronym>ESPERANZACOVID</acronym>
  <official_title>Double-blind Randomized Clinical Trial, Placebo-controlled to Assess the Efficacy of Montelukast in Mild-moderate Respiratory Symptoms in Patients With Long-COVID: E-SPERANZA COVID PROJECT</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Jordi Gol i Gurina Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut Català de la Salut</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Jordi Gol i Gurina Foundation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Recently, a new clinical presentation called &quot;long covid&quot; has been reported, for patients&#xD;
      with symptoms lasting for more than 4 weeks from the onset of the disease. Typically, the&#xD;
      symptoms comprise dyspnea, cough, headache, arthralgia, fever, abdominal pain, asthenia and&#xD;
      skin manifestations This project aims to evaluate the efficacy of Montelukast in improving&#xD;
      the quality of life associated with respiratory symptoms in patients with persistent COVID-19&#xD;
      symptoms. The main objective is to compare the efficacy of low-dose Montelukast versus&#xD;
      placebo to improve respiratory symptoms in patients with persistent COVID-19 symptoms.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In December 2019, the first case of a new coronavirus causing pneumonia was described in&#xD;
      Wuhan (China), designated as SARS-CoV-2 by the World Health Organization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      From the start of the SARS-CoV-2 alert until May 21st, 2020, 250,287 cases of coronavirus&#xD;
      disease (COVID-19) were reported in Spain. The importance of the COVID-19 pandemic with its&#xD;
      high humanitarian and economic cost, urgently requires effective therapies to reduce the&#xD;
      severity, complications and mortality associated with this infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As the number of cases of COVID-19 increases, so does information regarding the management&#xD;
      and evolution of the disease. More recently, a new clinical presentation called &quot;long COVID&quot;&#xD;
      has been reported, for patients with symptoms lasting for more than 4 weeks from the onset of&#xD;
      the disease. Typically, the symptoms comprise dyspnea, cough, headache, arthralgia, fever,&#xD;
      abdominal pain, asthenia and skin manifestations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The inflammatory process produced at the pulmonary and extra pulmonary level, and the immune&#xD;
      response triggered have been identified as important mechanisms in the pathophysiology of&#xD;
      COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Coronavirus infection activates the cytokine cascade at the immune level, in which&#xD;
      leukotriene are possibly involved in the development of respiratory symptoms in patients with&#xD;
      persistent symptoms after infection by SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Leukotriene antagonists (LTRAs) have a bronchodilator action and inhibit inflammation of the&#xD;
      airways, resulting in a significant improvement in asthma symptoms and allergic rhinitis. In&#xD;
      asthma, they improve respiratory function, inhalation rate of inhaled β2 agonist, airway&#xD;
      inflammation, airway hyper responsiveness, inhaled corticosteroid dosage, and reduce&#xD;
      exacerbations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Regarding the treatment of acute SARS-CoV-2 infection, to date, the available evidence is&#xD;
      limited; there are few conclusive clinical trials that allow recommendations based on&#xD;
      scientific evidence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To date, no treatment has been evaluated in long COVID. The hypothesis of using Montelukast&#xD;
      would be based on the pathophysiological response of the disease mediated by the immune&#xD;
      system against the SARS-CoV-2 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Montelukast blocks the action of substances such as leukotriene C4, D4 and E4 by binding to&#xD;
      the CysLT1 receptor in the lungs and bronchi. This reduces the bronchoconstriction caused by&#xD;
      leukotriene and results in less inflammation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Montelukast effectively attenuated both lung inflammation induced by Lipopolysaccharides in a&#xD;
      mouse model with Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome, as in human neutrophils.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Individuals affected by long COVID have self-organized to gain visibility. They have made a&#xD;
      self-completed form to describe the characteristics of the disease. The &quot;Persistent COVID19&quot;&#xD;
      network in Catalonia currently gathers more than 3000 people.&#xD;
&#xD;
      From the contact with the &quot;Persistent COVID19 association&quot; in Catalonia, and in search of a&#xD;
      response to this symptomatology, which can be very disabling, a pilot study was carried out&#xD;
      in patients with persistent COVID-19 symptoms with off-label use of Montelukast.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Empirical treatment with Montelukast at a dose of 10 mg / day for 14 days was started in 13&#xD;
      patients with long COVID, some with symptoms of more than a month of evolution since the&#xD;
      beginning of the COVID-19 clinic. The patients were followed up to evaluate the improvement&#xD;
      of the symptoms with a numerical scale from 0 to 100 and COPD Assessment Test Scale (CAT), 3&#xD;
      weeks after starting treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An improvement in symptoms was observed a few days after treatment and a good evolution of&#xD;
      the sensation of dyspnea, chest pain, symptoms of discomfort, dry cough, and nasal symptoms.&#xD;
      Likewise, the incorporation of the patients to their work activity during that period was&#xD;
      observed. To date, the improvement continues to exist, without evidence of clinical&#xD;
      deterioration.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Double-blind randomized placebo-controlled clinical trial,.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator and Outcomes Assessor)</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COP Assessment Test Scale (CAT)</measure>
    <time_frame>7, 14, 21 and 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>The COPD Assessment Test (CAT) is a questionnaire for people with COPD, designed to measure the impact of COPD on a person's life, and how this changes over time.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1min sit-to-stand test</measure>
    <time_frame>14 and 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Exercise capacity: number of repetitions performed in the 1min sit-to-stand test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>O2 desaturation</measure>
    <time_frame>14 and 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>O2 desaturation ≥ 4% with effort (1min sit-to-stand test)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Analogical Scale (VAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>7, 14, 21 and 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Symptoms evaluated using numeric Visual Analogical Scale (VAS): asthenia, headache, ageusia, anosmia, and rhinitis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All-cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>7, 14, 21 and 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Mortality from any cause during the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of visits to primary care</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of visits of any kind to primary health care settings (phone visit or face to face visit) during the study period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of visits to the emergency room</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of visits to emergency room form primary health o hospital settings during the study period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of hospital admissions.</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of hospital admissions during the study period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Medication side effects</measure>
    <time_frame>7, 14, 21 and 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number and type of adverse reactions during the study period related to medication.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Days of sick leave</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days of incapacity for work (sick leave) during the study period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">284</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>SARS (Disease)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Montelukast</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>10mg oral montelukast once daily for 28 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>oral placebo once daily for 28 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Montelukast</intervention_name>
    <description>10 mg oral montelukast once daily for 28 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Montelukast</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>antileukotriene</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>10 mg oral placebo once daily for 28 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients 18 to 80 years old with SARS-CoV-2 infection (positive CRP &lt;10 days from the&#xD;
             onset of symptoms) treated in Primary Health Care.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persistent respiratory symptoms (more than 1 and &lt;3 months of evolution)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mild-moderate dyspnea: score at the beginning of the study according to the modified&#xD;
             Medical Research Council (mMRC) scale from 0 to 3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient must be competent to complement the follow-up evaluations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient agrees to participate in the study and take assigned medication during the&#xD;
             4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sign the informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severity criteria: fever&gt; 38ºC, or O2 saturation &lt;93%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with SARS-Cov-2 pneumonia in the acute / subacute phase.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have required hospital admission for SARS-Cov-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD), asthma, bronchiectasis, pulmonary&#xD;
             fibrosis, obstructive sleep apnea syndrome (OSAS), chronic respiratory failure from&#xD;
             any cause, home oxygen therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of montelukast or zafirlukast ≤ 30 days prior to inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any dose of systemic corticosteroids ≤ 30 days prior to inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of gemfibrocil.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypersensitivity to montelukast or to any of the excipients included (e.g. lactose.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition (including the inability to swallow pills) that, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             researcher, would prevent the completion of taking the medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active malignancy, current or recent chemotherapy treatment (&lt;6 months).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical history of infection by the Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) or any serious&#xD;
             immunocompromised state.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, planning to get pregnant or patients of childbearing age not undergoing&#xD;
             birth control methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Breastfeeding mother.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other condition for which, in the opinion of the principal investigator, it is&#xD;
             considered that the subject does not fit the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jesus Almeda Ortega, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Foundation Jordi GOL</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sara Bonet Monne, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Institut Català de la Salut</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Betlem Salvador Gonzalez, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Institut Català de la Salut</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Francisco Mera Cordero, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Institut Català de la Salut</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Francisco M Mera Cordero, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+34699942492</phone>
    <email>franmcor@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Rosa Morros Padro, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+34934824124</phone>
    <email>idiap@idiapjgol.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>Montelukast</keyword>
  <keyword>Leukotriene Antagonists</keyword>
  <keyword>Primary Health Care</keyword>
  <keyword>Clinical Trial</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
  <keyword>Long Term Covid</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Signs and Symptoms, Respiratory</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Montelukast</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

