<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4704">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04668820</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>09.2020.1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04668820</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Reliability and Acceptability of Real-time Virtual Video Pediatric Gait, Arms, Legs and Spine (V-pGALS)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Reliability and Acceptability of Real-time Virtual Video Pediatric Gait, Arms, Legs and Spine (V-pGALS) Assessment for Musculoskeletal Assessment of Children for Telemedicine Visits</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Marmara University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Marmara University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The use of telemedicine in musculoskeletal assessment has been historically low. The current&#xD;
      COVID 19 global pandemic has forced a paradigm shift with many centers rapidly adopting&#xD;
      virtual visits to conduct care resulting in rapid expansion of use of telemedicine amongst&#xD;
      practices. Mayoclinic has published The Telemedicine Musculoskeletal Examination for adults.&#xD;
      Paediatric Musculoskeletal Matters (PMM) has put video Pediatric Gait, Arms, Legs and Spine&#xD;
      (V-pGALS) assessment sheet on their website. However, there is a lack of the acceptability&#xD;
      and reliability of these tools. The aim of this study is to investigate acceptability and&#xD;
      reliability of real-time virtual video Pediatric Gait, Arms, Legs and Spine (V-pGALS)&#xD;
      assessment for musculoskeletal assessment of children for telemedicine visits.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The use of telemedicine in musculoskeletal assessment has been historically low. The current&#xD;
      COVID 19 global pandemic has forced a paradigm shift with many centers rapidly adopting&#xD;
      virtual visits to conduct care resulting in rapid expansion of the use of telemedicine&#xD;
      amongst practices. Mayoclinic has published The Telemedicine Musculoskeletal Examination for&#xD;
      adults. 'Paediatric Musculoskeletal Matters' (PMM- www.pmmonline.org, is a free,&#xD;
      evidence-based, and peer-reviewed open e-resource for pediatric musculoskeletal (MSK)&#xD;
      medicine targeting non-MSK specialists. They have also published video Pediatric Gait, Arms,&#xD;
      Legs and Spine (V-pGALS), an assessment sheet for telemedicine visits on their webpage.&#xD;
      However, there is a lack of the acceptability and reliability of these tools. The aim of this&#xD;
      study is to investigate acceptability and reliability of real-time virtual video Pediatric&#xD;
      Gait, Arms, Legs and Spine (V-pGALS) assessment for musculoskeletal assessment of children&#xD;
      for telemedicine visits. For this purpose, children at between the ages of 7-18 who admitted&#xD;
      the Pediatric Rehabilitation outpatient clinic of Department of Physical Medicine and&#xD;
      Rehabilitation of Marmara University School of Medicine will be recruited to the study. They&#xD;
      will be evaluated via V-pGALS face to face on the day of admission and the physiatrist will&#xD;
      record the diagnosis if there is. Within 24 hours the child will be reevaluated via V-pGALS&#xD;
      by using Zoom application virtually. The acceptability of V-pGALS examination to the child&#xD;
      and parents in terms of the duration and additional discomfort caused was evaluated using&#xD;
      visual analog scale with smiley faces (0-10, 0 for full acceptability).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Children between the ages of 7-18 who admit pediatric rehabilitation outpatient clinic</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Two phsyiatrist who will perform virtual video Pediatric Gait, Arms, Legs and Spine (V-pGALS) and the physiatrist who will perform face to face examination will be blinded to each other</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Face to face examination of video Pediatric Gait, Arms, Legs and Spine (V-pGALS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Face to face examination</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>real-time virtual video Pediatric Gait, Arms, Legs and Spine (V-pGALS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Video real-time examination via zoom application</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of V-pGALS examination to the child in terms of the duration</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>visual analog scale with smiley faces (0-10, 0 for full acceptability)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of V-pGALS examination to the child in terms of the additional discomfort caused</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>visual analog scale with smiley faces (0-10, 0 for full acceptability).&#xD;
visual analog scale with smiley faces (0-10, 0 for full acceptability).&#xD;
visual analog scale with smiley faces (0-10, 0 for full acceptability). visual analog scale with smiley faces (0-10, 0 for full acceptability).&#xD;
visual analog scale with smiley faces (0-10, 0 for full acceptability)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of V-pGALS examination to the parent who will be present during examination in terms of the duration</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>visual analog scale with smiley faces (0-10, 0 for full acceptability)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of V-pGALS examination to the parent who will be present during examination in terms of the additional discomfort caused</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>visual analog scale with smiley faces (0-10, 0 for full acceptability)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Musculoskeletal Abnormality</condition>
  <condition>Pediatric</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Children who admit to Pediatric Rehabilitation outpatient clinic</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Children who admit to Pediatric Rehabilitation outpatient clinic of the Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation will be evaluated by face to face and virtually by using zoom application via video Pediatric Gait, Arms, Legs and Spine (V-pGALS)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>video Pediatric Gait, Arms, Legs and Spine (V-pGALS)</intervention_name>
    <description>The Video-pGALS includes maneuvers from pediatric regional examination of the musculoskeletal system (pREMS) and derived from the pediatric gait arms legs spine examination assessment which is a validated simple basic musculoskeletal (MSK) examination for children. V-pGALS offers a structured approach to a cursory overview MSK exam with a focus on range of movement and symmetry. Utilizing the parent or caregiver to feel the joint in question for obvious warmth/ swelling or to palpate for point of maximal tenderness can add important information.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Children who admit to Pediatric Rehabilitation outpatient clinic</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children between the ages of 7-18 who admitted the Pediatric Rehabilitation outpatient&#xD;
             clinic of Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-ambulatory children&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children with poor cooperation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being severe ill and unable to tolerate examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children and parents who do not give oral and written permission for study enrollment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Evrim Karadag-Saygı, Prof</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Marmara University School of Medicine Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Esra Giray, assoc. prof</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Koc University School of Medicine Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Özden Ozyemisci Taskiran, Prof</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Koc University School of Medicine Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ozge Kenis-Coskun, assoc. prof</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Marmara University School of Medicine Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Esra Giray, Ass Prof</last_name>
    <phone>05558134394</phone>
    <email>girayesra@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Özge Kenis-Coskun, assoc. prof</last_name>
    <phone>05058294947</phone>
    <email>ozgekenis@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Marmara University School of Medicine Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <zip>34899</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.pmmonline.org/doctor/approach-to-clinical-assessment/examination/v-pgals</url>
    <description>video Pediatric Gait, Arms, Legs and Spine (V-pGALS)</description>
  </link>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Batu ED, Keniş Coşkun Ö, Sönmez HE, Karali D, Arslanoğlu Aydin E, Bilginer Y, Karadağ Saygi E, Özen S. Acceptability and Practicality of the Turkish Translation of Pediatric Gait Arm Legs and Spine in Turkish Children. J Clin Rheumatol. 2017 Dec;23(8):421-424. doi: 10.1097/RHU.0000000000000586.</citation>
    <PMID>28926470</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Pelaez F, de Haro C. Translational inhibition by eIF-2-phospholipid complex in mammalian cell-free systems. FEBS Lett. 1989 Jul 3;250(2):523-8.</citation>
    <PMID>2753146</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Shenoi S, Hayward K, Curran ML, Kessler E, Mehta JJ, Riebschleger MP, Foster HE. Telemedicine in pediatric rheumatology: this is the time for the community to embrace a new way of clinical practice. Pediatr Rheumatol Online J. 2020 Oct 31;18(1):85. doi: 10.1186/s12969-020-00476-z.</citation>
    <PMID>33129319</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 16, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 9, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 9, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>telemedicine</keyword>
  <keyword>pandemic</keyword>
  <keyword>video Pediatric Gait, Arms, Legs and Spine (V-pGALS)</keyword>
  <keyword>pediatric examination</keyword>
  <keyword>musculoskeletal examination</keyword>
  <keyword>reliability</keyword>
  <keyword>acceptability</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Abnormalities</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The data that support the findings of this study will be available on request from the corresponding author (EG). The data will not be publicly available due to their containing information that could compromise the privacy of research participants.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

