<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="254">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04590365</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>283187</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04590365</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Iota-carrageenan Nasal Spray COVID-19 Prophylaxis for Healthcare Professionals</brief_title>
  <acronym>ICE-COVID</acronym>
  <official_title>Efficacy of Iota-carrageenan Nasal Spray Prophylaxis for Healthcare Professionals Treating Patients During the COVID-19 Pandemic - A Double Blind Randomised Placebo-controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Swansea University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cardiff University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Marinomed Biotech AG</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Walgreens Boots Alliance</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Abertawe Bro Morgannwg University Health Board</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Swansea University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The current COVID-19 pandemic is the biggest global healthcare challenge in the last century,&#xD;
      and the number of cases in the next 12 months is likely to increase. There is currently no&#xD;
      proven treatment, chemoprophylaxis or vaccine against COVID-19, which exhibits a wide&#xD;
      clinical spectrum from asymptomatic carriage to mild upper respiratory tract infection,&#xD;
      severe viral pneumonia to acute respiratory distress syndrome and death. There has been a&#xD;
      disproportionate effect on healthcare workers due to their high exposure risk, highlighting&#xD;
      the need for effective preventative strategies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 is a positive-sense single-stranded enveloped RNA virus which transmits via&#xD;
      droplets, aerosols and direct contact, to reach their target naso- and oropharyngeal&#xD;
      epithelial cells through initial electrostatic interactions to cell surface heparan sulphate&#xD;
      (HS) proteoglycans. Carrageenan mimics cell surface HS, thereby trapping the virus to allow&#xD;
      mucociliary clearance and has demonstrated anti-viral activity in-vitro and in a number of&#xD;
      common cold clinical trials when administered as a nasal spray.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ICE-COVID a randomised, double blind, placebo-controlled phase III trial of the prophylactic&#xD;
      efficacy of iota-carrageenan nasal and throat spray in preventing COVID-19 illness in at risk&#xD;
      healthcare professionals. Participants (n=240) will be randomly allocated to either the&#xD;
      treatment arm (verum Coldamaris plus, 0.12% iota-carrageenan in 0.5% saline) or placebo&#xD;
      (Coldamaris sine, saline 0.5%) arm. The study's primary objective is the prevention of&#xD;
      COVID-19 infection, confirmed by PCR swab or documented seroconversion. Secondary objectives&#xD;
      are to determine if carrageenan sprays reduce the clinical severity of COVID-19 and&#xD;
      symptomatic acute respiratory infection of other aetiologies (non-SARS-CoV-2).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective is to determine whether carrageenan nasal and throat sprays reduce the&#xD;
      risk of COVID-19 infection in healthcare professionals. The secondary objective is to&#xD;
      determine whether carrageenan nasal sprays attenuate the severity and/or duration of symptoms&#xD;
      in COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To gain maximum value from this study, we will take the opportunity to address two additional&#xD;
      objectives where new knowledge could provide important insights into predictive factors for&#xD;
      infection and severity:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine whether any investigations or questionnaire findings in this trial offer a&#xD;
           predictive value for acquiring COVID-19 infection or determining severity and/or&#xD;
           duration of resultant infection&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine any associations between symptom severity and/or duration and prognosis in&#xD;
           healthcare professionals with COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study design consists of a double blind, randomised placebo-controlled trial. Of the 480&#xD;
      healthcare professionals recruited, 240 participants will be randomly allocated to each of&#xD;
      either the treatment arm (verum Coldamaris plus i.e. Iota-carrageenan 0.12% in 0.5% saline)&#xD;
      or placebo (Coldamaris sine i.e. 0.5% saline) arms. Participants will use the spray&#xD;
      prophylactically into each nostril and throat three times per day for 8 weeks, during which&#xD;
      time the participants will be invited to complete a daily symptom tracker questionnaire.&#xD;
      COVID-19 infection during the trial period will be confirmed using viral PCR swabs (if&#xD;
      symptomatic), SARS-CoV-2 serology at 14 days following onset of symptoms as well as trial&#xD;
      entry and exit serology to detect asymptomatic infection during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Allocation to each group, treatment or placebo administration and data analysis will be&#xD;
      blinded to both participant and investigator. The primary outcome measure will be acquisition&#xD;
      of COVID-19 infection as confirmed by positive PCR swab taken at the time of symptoms or&#xD;
      positive serology measured 2 weeks after symptom onset or seroconversion at the end of the&#xD;
      trial (via trial entry and exit serology) to detect asymptomatic infection during the study&#xD;
      period. COVID-19 Core Outcome Measures in Effectiveness Trials (COMET) core outcome sets&#xD;
      (COS) will be adhered to. Secondary outcome measured will include symptom types, severity and&#xD;
      duration (recorded by the daily symptom tracker questionnaire), hospital admission and length&#xD;
      of stay, oxygen saturation and radiological lung changes on admission, need for ventilatory&#xD;
      support (oxygen therapy, CPAP, intubation &amp; ventilation), haematological changes, intensive&#xD;
      care admission and length of stay, mortality, subsequent familial/household COVID-19&#xD;
      infection and acquisition of non-COVID-19 upper respiratory tract infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Deliverables:&#xD;
&#xD;
      5. This trial will help us to determine whether carrageenan nasal sprays significantly affect&#xD;
      the primary outcome measure of acquisition of COVID-19 infection as confirmed by positive PCR&#xD;
      swab taken at the time of symptoms or positive serology measured 2 weeks after symptom onset&#xD;
      or at the end of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      6. It will also determine the effect of carrageenan nasal sprays on secondary outcome&#xD;
      measures which include types, severity and duration of symptoms, hospital admission and&#xD;
      length of stay, need for ventilatory support and intensive care admission, mortality as well&#xD;
      as familial or household COVID-19 infection and acquisition of other respiratory tract&#xD;
      infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7. We will also investigate whether haematological changes (FBC, CRP, U&amp;E, Ferritin, LFT,&#xD;
      LDH, Clotting, D-dimer, FDP, Vitamin D level) and demographic questionnaire findings can&#xD;
      offer a predictive value for acquiring COVID-19 infection or determining severity and/or&#xD;
      duration of resultant infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      8. To determine any associations between symptom severity and/or duration and prognosis in&#xD;
      healthcare professionals with COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The study design consists of a double blind, randomised placebo-controlled trial. Of the 480 healthcare professionals recruited, 240 participants will be randomly allocated to each of either the treatment arm (verum Coldamaris plus i.e. Iota-carrageenan 0.12% in 0.5% saline) or placebo (Coldamaris sine i.e. 0.5% saline) arms.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Allocation to each group, treatment or placebo administration and data analysis will be blinded to both participant and investigator. The sprays will be blinded at the site of manufacture. Trial sealed envelopes will be available in case of any adverse reactions.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of COVID-19 infection in healthcare professionals</measure>
    <time_frame>6-9 months</time_frame>
    <description>Acquisition of COVID-19 infection as confirmed by positive PCR swab taken at the time of symptom onset or positive serology measured 2 weeks after symptom onset or seroconversion at the end of the trial (via trial entry and exit serology) to detect asymptomatic infection during the study period</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Severity of COVID-19 infection</measure>
    <time_frame>6-9 months</time_frame>
    <description>Time taken for all symptoms to resolve (days)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Severity of COVD-19 infection</measure>
    <time_frame>6-9 months</time_frame>
    <description>Length of hospital and intensive care stay (days)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Severity of COVID-19 infection</measure>
    <time_frame>6-9 months</time_frame>
    <description>Morality rate</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">480</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <condition>SARS-CoV 2</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Coldamaris plus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>verum Coldamaris plus i.e. Iota-carrageenan 0.12% in 0.5% saline</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Coldamaris sine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Coldamaris sine i.e. 0.5% saline</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Carrageenan nasal and throat spray</intervention_name>
    <description>Iota-carrageenan nasal and throat spray (verum Coldamaris plus i.e. Iota-carrageenan 0.12% in 0.5% saline)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Coldamaris plus</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Saline nasal and throat spray</intervention_name>
    <description>Saline nasal and throat spray (placebo Coldamaris sine i.e. 0.5% saline)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Coldamaris sine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥18 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Study participants who have given informed consent, and received a copy of signed&#xD;
             consent form prior to any study related procedures;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthcare professionals (nurses, doctors, allied health professionals, Health Care&#xD;
             Assistants, operating department practitioners) working in Swansea Bay University&#xD;
             Health Board;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects agree to refrain from taking over the counter products intended to prevent,&#xD;
             intervene in, or treat colds/flu, starting at study entry and continuing through week&#xD;
             8 of the study. Medications in Table 2 (section 4.3) are specifically disallowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Capacity, consent and conflicts of interest:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The person lacks capacity;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject is related to any study personnel or has any other close ties or conflicts&#xD;
             of interest with the research team or the study sponsor;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject has received any investigational drug or participated in a clinical trial&#xD;
             within 4 weeks of entry to this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to complete the daily symptom tracker&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to communicate in English or Welsh&#xD;
&#xD;
        Comorbidities:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity or allergy to any component of the test product;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe cardiovascular, endocrinological, neurological, respiratory, gastrointestinal&#xD;
             disease, immune deficiency, autoimmune disease or a history or any current disease&#xD;
             that is considered by the investigator as a reason for exclusion;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Proven hypersensitivity of allergy resulting in hay fever and rhinitis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe nasal septal deviation, nasal polyps or other non-infectious condition that&#xD;
             could cause nasal obstruction;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of any nasal or sinus surgery in the past that in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator may influence the symptoms;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An unrelated infection that in the opinion of the investigator may influence symptoms&#xD;
             (gastrointestinal infection, other viral diseases such as measles, mumps);&#xD;
&#xD;
        COVID-19 Status:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Participants with proven COVID-19 infection (positive serology and/or viral PCR swab)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Medications:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent treatment of common cold that in the opinion of the investigator may influence&#xD;
             symptoms (see Table 2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants taking any of the medications outlined in Table 2 during the trial period&#xD;
             will be excluded&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Zita M Jessop, MBBChir PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Swansea University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Zita M Jessop, MBBChir PhD</last_name>
    <phone>07743684868</phone>
    <email>z.m.jessop@swansea.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Iain S Whitaker, PhD FRCS</last_name>
    <phone>07525249048</phone>
    <email>iainwhitaker@fastmail.fm</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Buck CB, Thompson CD, Roberts JN, Müller M, Lowy DR, Schiller JT. Carrageenan is a potent inhibitor of papillomavirus infection. PLoS Pathog. 2006 Jul;2(7):e69.</citation>
    <PMID>16839203</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eccles R, Meier C, Jawad M, Weinmüllner R, Grassauer A, Prieschl-Grassauer E. Efficacy and safety of an antiviral Iota-Carrageenan nasal spray: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled exploratory study in volunteers with early symptoms of the common cold. Respir Res. 2010 Aug 10;11:108. doi: 10.1186/1465-9921-11-108.</citation>
    <PMID>20696083</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eccles R, Winther B, Johnston SL, Robinson P, Trampisch M, Koelsch S. Efficacy and safety of iota-carrageenan nasal spray versus placebo in early treatment of the common cold in adults: the ICICC trial. Respir Res. 2015 Oct 5;16:121. doi: 10.1186/s12931-015-0281-8.</citation>
    <PMID>26438038</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>González ME, Alarcón B, Carrasco L. Polysaccharides as antiviral agents: antiviral activity of carrageenan. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 1987 Sep;31(9):1388-93.</citation>
    <PMID>2823697</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Grassauer A, Weinmuellner R, Meier C, Pretsch A, Prieschl-Grassauer E, Unger H. Iota-Carrageenan is a potent inhibitor of rhinovirus infection. Virol J. 2008 Sep 26;5:107. doi: 10.1186/1743-422X-5-107.</citation>
    <PMID>18817582</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ludwig M, Enzenhofer E, Schneider S, Rauch M, Bodenteich A, Neumann K, Prieschl-Grassauer E, Grassauer A, Lion T, Mueller CA. Efficacy of a carrageenan nasal spray in patients with common cold: a randomized controlled trial. Respir Res. 2013 Nov 13;14:124. doi: 10.1186/1465-9921-14-124.</citation>
    <PMID>24219370</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Leibbrandt A, Meier C, König-Schuster M, Weinmüllner R, Kalthoff D, Pflugfelder B, Graf P, Frank-Gehrke B, Beer M, Fazekas T, Unger H, Prieschl-Grassauer E, Grassauer A. Iota-carrageenan is a potent inhibitor of influenza A virus infection. PLoS One. 2010 Dec 14;5(12):e14320. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0014320.</citation>
    <PMID>21179403</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shao Q, Guo Q, Xu Wp, Li Z, Zhao Tt. Specific Inhibitory Effect of κ-Carrageenan Polysaccharide on Swine Pandemic 2009 H1N1 Influenza Virus. PLoS One. 2015 May 13;10(5):e0126577. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0126577. eCollection 2015.</citation>
    <PMID>25969984</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>June 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Carrageenan</keyword>
  <keyword>Nasal spray</keyword>
  <keyword>Anti-viral</keyword>
  <keyword>Prevention</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

