<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2488">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04631536</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Lebanese American University</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04631536</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Managing Endothelial Dysfunction in COVID-19 : A Randomized Controlled Trial at LAUMC</brief_title>
  <acronym>MEDIC-LAUMC</acronym>
  <official_title>Managing Endothelial Dysfunction in Moderate COVID-19 : A Randomized Controlled Trial at the Lebanese American University Medical Center- Rizk Hospital</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Lebanese American University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Lebanese American University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      COVID-19 infection was shown to cause endothelial dysfunction .&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the level of the endothelium the pathophysiological mechanisms have been hypothesized and&#xD;
      were divided into pro-coagulant, pro-inflammatory, anti-fibrinolytics, impaired barrier&#xD;
      function, vasoconstrictor and pro-oxidant. So far, the pro-coagulant and pro-inflammatory&#xD;
      pathways have been studied and as a result dexamethasone and anticoagulation became part of&#xD;
      the standard therapies for the disease. However, so far, no RCT has been evaluated on&#xD;
      targeting the vasoconstrictive and antioxidant pathways with an aim of revealing clinical&#xD;
      benefit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      So, with this trial we intend to provide a regiment composed of several medications we&#xD;
      hypothesize will act on several downstream pathways that would improve endothelial function&#xD;
      primarily via the increase in NO production and release.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the time of this proposal there has been no randomized trials evaluating or testing the&#xD;
      use of cardiovascular drugs targeting endothelial dysfunction in COVID-19 patients. As&#xD;
      previously noted there has been a call to study these drugs and their effect after a strong&#xD;
      research regarding their theorized effectiveness. For evidence, there was a recently&#xD;
      published meta-analysis evaluating the role of statins in COVID-19 with preliminary findings&#xD;
      suggested a reduction in fatal or severe disease by 30% and discredited the suggestion of&#xD;
      harm, that emphasized on the need of well-designed randomized controlled trial to confirm the&#xD;
      role of statins in COVID-19 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our study would help determine the potential therapeutic effect of the endothelial protocol&#xD;
      as adjunct to mainstream management. This study seeks to further our knowledge in treating&#xD;
      COVID-19 to ultimately improve clinical outcomes and reduce complications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome-Coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) is the novel pathogen&#xD;
      responsible coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) first discovered in Wuhan, China. Since its&#xD;
      emergence in late December 2019, many pathophysiological mechanisms have been proposed with&#xD;
      multiple pathways that involve various organ systems . Although considered at its emergence&#xD;
      as a respiratory infection with manifestations ranging from lower respiratory tract infection&#xD;
      to pneumonia and advancing to acute respiratory disease syndrome (ARDS) in its final stages,&#xD;
      recent evidence has highlighted how disseminated the virus can be affecting almost every&#xD;
      organ be it the heart kidneys or blood vessels . Recent trends in research have focused on&#xD;
      elucidating the cardiovascular dysfunction in COVID-19 patients Especially following studies&#xD;
      showing that cardiovascular risk factors are among the most common presenting comorbidities&#xD;
      and that cardiovascular complications of SARS-CoV-2 are among the most lethal . Initial&#xD;
      research revealed that the virus makes use of the angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE-2)&#xD;
      receptor to infiltrate host cells. With the ACE-2 receptor being a widely expressed receptor&#xD;
      found in multiple cells lining the lung, heart, gastrointestinal tract, kidneys and&#xD;
      endothelial cells. Another prominent mechanism of infection is immune system dysregulation&#xD;
      manifesting as a cytokine storm and inflammatory response over-activation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Attempts at laying out a comprehensive or unifying pathogenesis of a COVID-19 infection have&#xD;
      singled out endothelial dysfunction as a core pathway. The endothelium in summary is&#xD;
      monolayer lining the arteries, veins and microvasculature. The endothelium hence plays a&#xD;
      major role in homeostasis with interactive roles in blood pressure regulation,&#xD;
      anti-coagulation and immune protection Moreover, it is thus relevant to note that the most&#xD;
      common comorbidities that present with COVID-19 such as hypertension, diabetes, obesity and&#xD;
      old age are all underlined by pre-existing endothelial damage or dysfunction. As such,&#xD;
      endothelial dysfunction and oxidative stress and their relation to the manifestation and&#xD;
      progression of COVID-19 infections has gain significant traction in recent publications. This&#xD;
      breakthrough exposes several causes of endothelial dysfunction which include direct lining&#xD;
      attack, hypoxia, cytokine storm and suppressed endothelial nitric oxide synthase (eNOS) with&#xD;
      concomitant nitric oxide deficiency. Several studies have emphasized the role of NO signaling&#xD;
      as a major regulator of vascular tone and its antioxidant, anti-inflammatory and&#xD;
      antithrombotic activity. For example, augmenting the production of NO and its bioavailability&#xD;
      by nicorandil has been proposed as a potential treatment in patients with COVID 19.&#xD;
      Nicorandil (a vasodilatory agent composed of N-[2-hydroxyethyl]-nicotinamide nitrate) used&#xD;
      among patients with acute heart failure emergencies However, it has never been tested in&#xD;
      patients with cardiovascular complications resulting from COVID 19 . Statins are&#xD;
      cardioprotective in nature with recent reports showing that they can be beneficial in&#xD;
      COVID-19 . An important mechanism via which Statins may improve endothelial function include&#xD;
      increasing the production of NO and subsequent vasodilation effect, along with its&#xD;
      established major anti-inflammatory and anti-oxidant properties . Nebivolol, a&#xD;
      cardio-selective beta blocker has also shown non-adrenergic vasodilating properties via the&#xD;
      release of NO along with antioxidative and anti-atherosclerotic activities. Furthermore, eNOS&#xD;
      overexpression leads to an increase in NO formation only when the BH4 synthase&#xD;
      GTP-cyclohydrolase 1 (GCH-1) is alsoup-regulated. So, Folic Acid and L-arginine will be given&#xD;
      to supplement our patients with BH4 . We hypothesize that its administration along with the&#xD;
      other previously mentioned agents would improve endothelial function in patients suffering&#xD;
      from COVID 19 via a cumulative increase in the bioavailability of Nitric Oxide (NO), and thus&#xD;
      improving patients' outcomes&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 10, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of intervention administration until the date of discharge from hospital or date of death from any cause, whichever came first, assessed up to 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical improvement was defined as improvement of at least two points from the baseline from date of intervention administration until the date of discharge from hospital or date of death from any cause, whichever came first, assessed up to 1-month status on the six-category ordinal scale. This scale contains the subsequent categories: (1) death (2) hospital admission requiring invasive mechanical ventilation (3) hospital admission, requiring non-invasive positive pressure ventilation (4) hospital admission, requiring oxygen (5) hospital admission, not requiring oxygen (6) discharge.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Need for invasive mechanical ventilation</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessment on daily basis for up to 1 month or until hospital discharge/death whichever came first</time_frame>
    <description>assess the patients in need of mechanical ventilation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of ICU stay</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessment on daily basis after the intervention is given for up to 1 month or until hospital discharge/death whichever came first</time_frame>
    <description>Length of ICU stay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of hospital Stay</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessment on daily basis after intervention given for up to 1 month or until hospital discharge/death whichever came first</time_frame>
    <description>Length of hospital Stay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of need of mechanical ventilation</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessment on daily basis after intervention given for up to 1 month or until hospital discharge/death whichever came first</time_frame>
    <description>Length of need of mechanical ventilation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>assessed for up to 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>All cause mortality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of side effects</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessment on daily basis after intervention given for up to 1 month or until hospital discharge/death whichever came first</time_frame>
    <description>Occurrence of side effects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Endothelial Dysfunction Protocol</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Our study will evaluate the impact of the endothelial treatment protocol (atorvastatin, nicorandil, l-arginine, folic acid and nebivolol) in patients already on optimal medical therapy for the treatment of COVID0-19 virus.&#xD;
Endothelial dysfunction protocol + Standard of Care (dexamethasone, anticoagulation, vitamin c, zinc).&#xD;
Atorvastatin Atorvastatin will be provided as a 40 mg tablet to be given PO once daily. This dose was suggested because high intensity statin has been associated with a better endothelial profile (Int J Cardiol 2017 Oct 1;244:112-118.-- Eur J Clin Pharmacol 2014 Oct;70(10):1181-93)&#xD;
Nicorandil Nicorandil 10 mg PO BID as the recommended dose for coronary vasodilatation by the manufacturer&#xD;
Nebivolol Nebivolol 5 mg PO ONCE daily while keeping Heart Rate (HR) between 50-90 bpm&#xD;
Folic Acid Folic Acid 5 mg po once daily&#xD;
L-Arginine L-Arginine 1 g po TID</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo + Standard of Care (dexamethasone, anticoagulation, vitamin c, zinc)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Atorvastatin + L-arginine + Folic acid + Nicorandil + Nebivolol</intervention_name>
    <description>active Comparator: Endothelial dysfunction protocol + Standard of Care (dexamethasone, anticoagulation, vitamin c, zinc). Treatment to be continued until 14 days or discharge/death whichever occurs first. It includes: Nebivolol 5 mg PO daily, Sigmart 10 mg PO twice daily, Atorvastatin 40 mg PO daily, Folic Acid 5 mg PO daily, L-arginine 1000 mg PO 3 times daily.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Endothelial Dysfunction Protocol</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Nicorandil</other_name>
    <other_name>L-arginine</other_name>
    <other_name>Folic acid</other_name>
    <other_name>Nebivolol</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo + Standard of Care (dexamethasone, anticoagulation, vitamin c, zinc)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults 18 years of age and above admitted for inpatient treatment of COVID-19&#xD;
             infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PCR-confirmed COVID-19 classified as mild, moderate or with severe disease as per the&#xD;
             FDA.&#xD;
&#xD;
        With mild being a positive testing by standard RT-PCR assay or equivalent test and symptoms&#xD;
        of mild illness with COVID-19 that could include fever, cough, sore throat, malaise,&#xD;
        headache, muscle pain, gastrointestinal symptoms, without shortness of breath or dyspnea.&#xD;
        No clinical signs indicative of Moderate, Severe, or Critical Severity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate defined as positive testing by standard RT-PCR assay or equivalent testing&#xD;
             and symptoms of moderate illness which could include any symptom of mild illness or&#xD;
             shortness of breath with exertion. Clinical signs suggestive of moderate illness with&#xD;
             COVID-19, such as respiratory rate ≥ 20 breaths per minute, saturation of oxygen&#xD;
             (SpO2) &gt; 93% on room air at sea level, heart rate ≥ 90 beats per minute. No clinical&#xD;
             signs indicative of Severe or Critical Illness Severity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe symptoms could include any symptom of moderate illness or shortness of breath&#xD;
             at rest, or respiratory distress. Clinical signs indicative of severe systemic illness&#xD;
             with COVID-19, such as respiratory 468 rate ≥ 30 per minute, heart rate ≥ 125 per&#xD;
             minute, SpO2 ≤ 93% on room air at sea level or 469 PaO2/FiO2 &lt; 300.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No criteria for Critical Severity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant in another RCT&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Myocarditis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are already on beta-blockers&#xD;
&#xD;
        .Patients already on Statins.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients already on Nicorandil.&#xD;
&#xD;
        . Patients taking PDE5 inhibitors or Riociguat&#xD;
&#xD;
        .Shock as defined by SBP&lt;90 for more than 30 minutes not responding to IV fluids with&#xD;
        evidence of end organ damage.&#xD;
&#xD;
        .Severe bradycardia (&lt;50 bpm).&#xD;
&#xD;
        .Heart block greater than first-degree (except in patients with a functioning artificial&#xD;
        pacemaker).&#xD;
&#xD;
        .Decompensated heart failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        .Sick sinus syndrome (unless a permanent pacemaker is in place).&#xD;
&#xD;
        .Severe hepatic impairment (Child-Pugh class C) or active liver disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        .Unexplained persistent elevations of serum transaminases.&#xD;
&#xD;
        .Pregnancy or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
        .Hypersensitivity to any of the medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Can't take medications orally&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient refuses to participate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Matli Kamal, MD</last_name>
    <phone>9613439675</phone>
    <email>matlikamal@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu YC, Chen CS, Chan YJ. The outbreak of COVID-19: An overview. J Chin Med Assoc. 2020 Mar;83(3):217-220. doi: 10.1097/JCMA.0000000000000270.</citation>
    <PMID>32134861</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yuki K, Fujiogi M, Koutsogiannaki S. COVID-19 pathophysiology: A review. Clin Immunol. 2020 Jun;215:108427. doi: 10.1016/j.clim.2020.108427. Epub 2020 Apr 20. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32325252</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mason RJ. Pathogenesis of COVID-19 from a cell biology perspective. Eur Respir J. 2020 Apr 16;55(4). pii: 2000607. doi: 10.1183/13993003.00607-2020. Print 2020 Apr.</citation>
    <PMID>32269085</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu Z, McGoogan JM. Characteristics of and Important Lessons From the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Outbreak in China: Summary of a Report of 72 314 Cases From the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention. JAMA. 2020 Apr 7;323(13):1239-1242. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.2648.</citation>
    <PMID>32091533</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Driggin E, Madhavan MV, Bikdeli B, Chuich T, Laracy J, Biondi-Zoccai G, Brown TS, Der Nigoghossian C, Zidar DA, Haythe J, Brodie D, Beckman JA, Kirtane AJ, Stone GW, Krumholz HM, Parikh SA. Cardiovascular Considerations for Patients, Health Care Workers, and Health Systems During the COVID-19 Pandemic. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020 May 12;75(18):2352-2371. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2020.03.031. Epub 2020 Mar 19. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32201335</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Murthy S, Gomersall CD, Fowler RA. Care for Critically Ill Patients With COVID-19. JAMA. 2020 Apr 21;323(15):1499-1500. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.3633.</citation>
    <PMID>32159735</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ruan Q, Yang K, Wang W, Jiang L, Song J. Clinical predictors of mortality due to COVID-19 based on an analysis of data of 150 patients from Wuhan, China. Intensive Care Med. 2020 May;46(5):846-848. doi: 10.1007/s00134-020-05991-x. Epub 2020 Mar 3. Erratum in: Intensive Care Med. 2020 Apr 6;:.</citation>
    <PMID>32125452</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hu Y, Sun J, Dai Z, Deng H, Li X, Huang Q, Wu Y, Sun L, Xu Y. Prevalence and severity of corona virus disease 2019 (COVID-19): A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Virol. 2020 Jun;127:104371. doi: 10.1016/j.jcv.2020.104371. Epub 2020 Apr 14.</citation>
    <PMID>32315817</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Guan WJ, Ni ZY, Hu Y, Liang WH, Ou CQ, He JX, Liu L, Shan H, Lei CL, Hui DSC, Du B, Li LJ, Zeng G, Yuen KY, Chen RC, Tang CL, Wang T, Chen PY, Xiang J, Li SY, Wang JL, Liang ZJ, Peng YX, Wei L, Liu Y, Hu YH, Peng P, Wang JM, Liu JY, Chen Z, Li G, Zheng ZJ, Qiu SQ, Luo J, Ye CJ, Zhu SY, Zhong NS; China Medical Treatment Expert Group for Covid-19. Clinical Characteristics of Coronavirus Disease 2019 in China. N Engl J Med. 2020 Apr 30;382(18):1708-1720. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2002032. Epub 2020 Feb 28.</citation>
    <PMID>32109013</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Guo T, Fan Y, Chen M, Wu X, Zhang L, He T, Wang H, Wan J, Wang X, Lu Z. Cardiovascular Implications of Fatal Outcomes of Patients With Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19). JAMA Cardiol. 2020 Jul 1;5(7):811-818. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2020.1017. Erratum in: JAMA Cardiol. 2020 Jul 1;5(7):848.</citation>
    <PMID>32219356</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhang H, Penninger JM, Li Y, Zhong N, Slutsky AS. Angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) as a SARS-CoV-2 receptor: molecular mechanisms and potential therapeutic target. Intensive Care Med. 2020 Apr;46(4):586-590. doi: 10.1007/s00134-020-05985-9. Epub 2020 Mar 3.</citation>
    <PMID>32125455</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Liu PP, Blet A, Smyth D, Li H. The Science Underlying COVID-19: Implications for the Cardiovascular System. Circulation. 2020 Jul 7;142(1):68-78. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.047549. Epub 2020 Apr 15.</citation>
    <PMID>32293910</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hamming I, Timens W, Bulthuis ML, Lely AT, Navis G, van Goor H. Tissue distribution of ACE2 protein, the functional receptor for SARS coronavirus. A first step in understanding SARS pathogenesis. J Pathol. 2004 Jun;203(2):631-7.</citation>
    <PMID>15141377</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jung F, Krüger-Genge A, Franke RP, Hufert F, Küpper JH. COVID-19 and the endothelium. Clin Hemorheol Microcirc. 2020;75(1):7-11. doi: 10.3233/CH-209007.</citation>
    <PMID>32568187</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Libby P, Lüscher T. COVID-19 is, in the end, an endothelial disease. Eur Heart J. 2020 Sep 1;41(32):3038-3044. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa623. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32882706</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ashour H, Elsayed MH, Elmorsy S, Harb IA. Hypothesis: The potential therapeutic role of nicorandil in COVID-19. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 2020 Nov;47(11):1791-1797. doi: 10.1111/1440-1681.13395. Epub 2020 Sep 9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32881062</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kunal S, Gupta K, Gupta S. Statins in COVID-19: A new ray of hope. Heart Lung. 2020 Nov - Dec;49(6):887-889. doi: 10.1016/j.hrtlng.2020.07.012. Epub 2020 Aug 11.</citation>
    <PMID>32861559</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gornik HL, Creager MA. Arginine and endothelial and vascular health. J Nutr. 2004 Oct;134(10 Suppl):2880S-2887S; discussion 2895S. doi: 10.1093/jn/134.10.2880S. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15465805</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 14, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Lebanese American University Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kamal Matli</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Cardiology Fellow</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Endothelial dysfunction</keyword>
  <keyword>Nicorandil</keyword>
  <keyword>Statin</keyword>
  <keyword>Nebivolol</keyword>
  <keyword>L-arginine</keyword>
  <keyword>Folic acid</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Folic Acid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vitamin B Complex</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nicorandil</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nebivolol</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Atorvastatin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

