<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="720">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04621071</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-3700</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04621071</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy of Probiotics in Reducing Duration and Symptoms of COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>PROVID-19</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Efficacy of Probiotics to Reduce the Duration and Symptoms of COVID-19 (PROVID-19 Study): a Randomized, Double-blind, Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre de recherche du Centre hospitalier universitaire de Sherbrooke</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Lallemand Health Solutions</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre de recherche du Centre hospitalier universitaire de Sherbrooke</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      COVID-19 disease caused by a new coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) has received worldwide attention.&#xD;
      No specific antiviral treatment is recommended for COVID-19 and no vaccine is currently&#xD;
      available. Probiotics may be considered as an option of treatment since they have anti-viral&#xD;
      effect, trigger immunomodulation and have low side-effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This randomized controlled trial aims to evaluate the efficacy of probiotics to reduce the&#xD;
      duration and symptoms of COVID-19 in a symptomatic population tested positive to SARS-CoV-2,&#xD;
      self-caring at home.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Rational: COVID-19 disease is caused by a new coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) and has received&#xD;
      worldwide attention. No specific antiviral treatment is recommended for COVID-19 and no&#xD;
      vaccine is currently available so far. Several strong arguments support the study of&#xD;
      probiotics for COVID-19: 1) probiotics act on viruses by various well described mechanisms&#xD;
      (reduction of absorption, cellular internalization of the virus, production of metabolites /&#xD;
      substances having a direct antiviral effect; and immunomodulation); 2) probiotics are&#xD;
      considered with a high level of evidence (meta-analysis) to reduce diarrhea (associated with&#xD;
      antibiotics and Clostridium difficile) and for respiratory tract infections; 3) probiotics&#xD;
      are affordable and available with low side-effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Evaluate the effect of probiotics on the duration of COVID-19 in symptomatic patients,&#xD;
           with moderate forms of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Evaluate the effect of probiotics on the severity of COVID-19 in symptomatic patients,&#xD;
           with moderate forms of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Evaluate the effect of probiotics on the evolution of oral and fecal microbiota in&#xD;
           symptomatic patients, with moderate forms of the COVID-19 disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Population: Men and women, 18 years or older, with a first positive test for COVID-19 in the&#xD;
      last 5 days, having symptoms of the COVID-19, self-caring at home, living in Quebec for the&#xD;
      next 60 days, able to take medication alone, with access to a phone or to the Internet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Material: After providing consent remotely (electronic or recorded by phone), patients will&#xD;
      receive by mail at home: : a leaflet explaining the study, the study product (probiotics or&#xD;
      placebo) for 25 days, a container of maple syrup and a cup, a thermometer, an oximeter, a&#xD;
      logbook, 2 saliva sample self-collection kits, 2 stool sample self-collection kits and&#xD;
      instruction sheets.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization: Patients will be randomized in one of the study groups (stratified by age and&#xD;
      gender). The randomization is double-blind and uses a ratio 1:1. Group A: will take&#xD;
      probiotics for up to 25 days / Group B: will take placebo for up to 25 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up: Upon inclusion in the study, the participant will complete a questionnaire that&#xD;
      will focus on socio-demographic (age, marital status), medical (weight, height, general&#xD;
      health, current medication, symptoms…), food intake and other relevant information. The&#xD;
      participants will fill a daily booklet evaluating their symptoms, compliance to treatment,&#xD;
      medication intake, temperature, oxygen saturation value, etc. For those who will be admitted&#xD;
      to hospital, data on their admission, complications and treatments will be collected. At 55&#xD;
      days after their enrollment, will fill an end of study questionnaire (symptoms, satisfaction,&#xD;
      well-being, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Samples: The study includes the optional collection of saliva and stool samples twice, on Day&#xD;
      1 (before the first product is taken) and on Day 10.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 5, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of symptoms of the COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>During the period of the treatment (from Day 1 to Day 25)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days before symptoms disappear</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Severity of the COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>During the period of the study, first day in (at randomization) to last day in (last follow-up 30 days after the end of treatment) (from Day 1 to Day 55)</time_frame>
    <description>Categorical distribution among: 1) at home without symptoms, 2) at home with symptoms, 3) hospitalized without O2 supplementation, 4) hospitalized with O2 supplementation, 5) admitted to intensive care unit, 6) deceased</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evolution of oral and fecal microbiota</measure>
    <time_frame>At Day 1 (baseline) and Day 10 of the treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Metagenomic sequencing</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">84</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Probiotics</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Two probiotic strains will constitute the experimental arm (Probiotics). Patients will take two capsules a day (one closed capsule to swallow and one open capsule mixed with maple syrup) from Day 1 to Day 10 and one closed capsule to swallow from Day 11 to Day 25.They will stop the treatment if they are admitted to the hospital. The treatment will last a maximum of 25 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Potato starch and magnesium stearate will constitute the comparator arm (Placebo). Patients will take two capsules a day (one closed capsule to swallow and one open capsule mixed with maple syrup) from Day 1 to Day 10 and one closed capsule to swallow from Day 11 to Day 25.They will stop the treatment if they are admitted to the hospital. The treatment will last a maximum of 25 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Probiotics (2 strains 10x10^9 UFC)</intervention_name>
    <description>Probiotic vs Placebo (1:1)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Probiotics</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo (potato starch and magnesium stearate)</intervention_name>
    <description>Probiotic vs Placebo (1:1)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  First positive test for COVID-19 in the last 5 days;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having symptoms of the COVID-19 at enrollment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-caring at home;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Living in Quebec for the next 60 days;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to take medication alone;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With access to a phone or to the Internet;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taking probiotic supplements at enrollment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taking antibiotics for a reason other than COVID-19 at enrollment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergies to soy, lactose, yeast, maltodextrin, vitamin C, potato starch, magnesium&#xD;
             stearate, hypromellose or titanium dioxide;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a chronically weakened immune system (AIDS, lymphoma, chemo-radio- corticosteroid&#xD;
             therapy, immunosuppressive pathology);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Was treated with chemo-radio-corticosteroid therapy in the last 6 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has active cancer;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taking immunosuppressive drugs (e.g. anti-rejection treatment after organ transplant);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Already participating in another clinical trial;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is pregnant, expects to become pregnant in the next few months or is breastfeeding;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has any other condition that would prevent safe participation in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jean-Charles Pasquier, Dr</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CIUSSSE-CHUS</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Audrey Hamel-Thibault, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>819-346-1110</phone>
    <phone_ext>12865</phone_ext>
    <email>audrey.hamel-thibault@usherbrooke.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Blanche Senicourt, PhD</last_name>
    <email>Blanche.Senicourt@USherbrooke.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CIUSSS de L'Estrie-CHUS Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sherbrooke</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>J1H 5N4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Audrey Hamel-Thibault, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>8193461110</phone>
      <phone_ext>12865</phone_ext>
      <email>Audrey.Hamel-Thibault@USherbrooke.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Blanche Senicourt, PhD</last_name>
      <email>Blanche.Senicourt@USherbrooke.ca</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jean-Charles Pasquier, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 6, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>covid</keyword>
  <keyword>sars-cov-2</keyword>
  <keyword>coronavirus</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

