<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="364">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04709302</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ENDOCOVID</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04709302</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of COVID-19 on Endothelium in HIV-Positive Patients in Sub-Saharan Africa</brief_title>
  <acronym>ENDOCOVID</acronym>
  <official_title>COVID-19 and Its Effects on Endothelium in HIV-Positive Patients in Sub-Saharan Africa: Cardiometabolic Risk, Thrombosis and Vascular Function</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical University of Graz</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Olso</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Kristiania University College</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Walter Sisulu University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Lagos State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Management Sciences for Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical University of Graz</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) has affected almost every country in the&#xD;
      world, especially in terms of health system capacity and economic burden. People from&#xD;
      sub-Saharan Africa (SSA) often face interaction between human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)&#xD;
      infection and non-communicable diseases such as cardiovascular disease. Role of HIV infection&#xD;
      and anti-retroviral treatment (ART) in altered cardiovascular risk is questionable and there&#xD;
      is still need to further carry out research in this field. However, thus far it is unclear,&#xD;
      what impact the COVID-19 co-infection in people living with HIV (PLHIV), with or without&#xD;
      therapy will have. The ENDOCOVID project aims to investigate whether and how HIV-infection in&#xD;
      COVID-19 patients modulates the time course of the disease, alters cardiovascular risk, and&#xD;
      changes vascular endothelial function and coagulation parameters/ thrombosis risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: In this long-term study, cardiovascular research on PLHIV with or without ART with&#xD;
      COVID-19 and HIV-negative with COVID-19 will be carried out via clinical and biochemical&#xD;
      measurements for cardiovascular risk factors and biomarkers of cardiovascular disease (CVD).&#xD;
      Vascular and endothelial function will be measured by brachial artery flow-mediated&#xD;
      dilatation (FMD), carotid intima-media thickness (IMT) assessments, and retinal blood vessel&#xD;
      analyses, along with vascular endothelial biomarkers and cogualation markers. The correlation&#xD;
      between HIV-infection in COVID-19 PLHIV with or without ART and its role in enhancement of&#xD;
      cardiovascular risk and endothelial dysfunction will be assessed. Potential changes in these&#xD;
      endpoints by COVID-19 will be followed for 4 weeks across the three groups (PLHIVwith or&#xD;
      without ART and HIV negatives).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Impact of project: The ENDOCOVID project aims to evaluate in the long-term the cardiovascular&#xD;
      risk and vascular endothelial function in PLHIV thus revealing an important transitional&#xD;
      cardiovascular phenotype in COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 has affected almost every country worldwide with regard to health system&#xD;
      capacities and economic burden, so far. The typical clinical presentations of COVID-19 are&#xD;
      fever, sore through, cough, dyspnea, abdominal pain and diarrhea. Approximately 15% of&#xD;
      patients with COVID-19 must be hospitalized and 5% are critically ill, and often develop&#xD;
      acute respiratory distress syndrome and need to be admitted to intensive care units. Risk of&#xD;
      severe disease increases with age, male sex, and with co-morbidities such as chronic lung&#xD;
      disease, CVDs, and diabetes. COVID-19 can also affect the nervous systems and cause loss of&#xD;
      smell or taste sensation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Populations in SSA are increasingly facing a double burden of disease involving the&#xD;
      interaction between HIV-AIDS and non-communicable diseases such as CVDs. In general, vascular&#xD;
      endothelial function can be regarded as a marker of the net harmful effects of cardiovascular&#xD;
      risk factors on the vascular wall. HIV- infected patients have premature atherosclerosis and&#xD;
      increased risk of ischemic heart disease. The cardiovascular risk represented by&#xD;
      HIV-infection is moreover affected by anti-retroviral treatment (ART). ART may, among other&#xD;
      effects, prompt dyslipidaemic and metabolic changes in patients over to systemic immune&#xD;
      activation, stimulation of endothelial inflammation and atherosclerosis. However, a recent&#xD;
      meta-analysis showed that evidence for - and against - a role for ART in the development of&#xD;
      CVDs remains unconvicing and that more research is necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With the current COVID-19 pandemic, which has also spread across Africa, another burden is&#xD;
      added. However, thus far it is unclear, what effect the additional COVID-19 co-infection in&#xD;
      people with HIV (PLHIV) will have as there are no data yet on how HIV/AIDS a prevalent&#xD;
      diseases SSA, will affect COVID-19 infection rates or outcomes. Currently, there is no proof&#xD;
      for a higher COVID -19 infection rate in PLHIV compared to HIV-negatives. However, there is a&#xD;
      possibility that HIV infection may have an influence on the course of infection. PLHIV who&#xD;
      are on ART with a normal CD4 T-cell count and suppressed viral load should not be at an&#xD;
      increased risk of severe disease. On the other hand, this theoretically positive situation&#xD;
      could be counterbalanced by recent evidence that ART could also have effects on COVID-19.&#xD;
      Furthermore, HIV-infected patients may additionally suffer from co-morbidities, which could&#xD;
      pose a greater risk of COVID-19 infection. Currently, there is no data available about&#xD;
      COVID-19 infection in PLHIV in SSA reflecting who in particular is at high risk for&#xD;
      infections, complications and fatal outcomes. As COVID-19 associated multisystem&#xD;
      inflammation, and the way organ damage caused by COVID-19 occurring in patients with COVID-19&#xD;
      is still incompletely understood, and current treatment options are limited. There is&#xD;
      therefore an urgent need to better understand the risk of severe and fatal COVID-19 outcomes,&#xD;
      especially in PLHIV (+/- ART).&#xD;
&#xD;
      A severe course of COVID-19 can cause the development of COVID-19-associated coagulopathy,&#xD;
      with features of both disseminated intravascular coagulation and thrombotic microangiopathy,&#xD;
      resulting in widespread microvascular thrombosis that may involve consumption of coagulation&#xD;
      factors and the liver. There seems to be a causal relationship with the inflammatory and&#xD;
      reparative processes involving diffuse alveolar damage (DAD), because thrombi are frequently&#xD;
      detected in small pulmonary arteries, most presumed secondary to endothelial damage. The&#xD;
      damage of endothelium could be due to the direct viral infection of the endothelial cells,&#xD;
      which express ACE-2 receptors, or to a host response. Besides, the alveolar fibrin deposition&#xD;
      in DAD may affect the local homeostasis between fibrinolysis and coagulation. Alveolar and&#xD;
      endothelial damage of smaller vessels may be followed by microvascular pulmonary thrombosis,&#xD;
      which could then extend to larger vessels. Additionally, elevated D-dimer has been observed&#xD;
      in patients with COVID-19. It is known that inceased D-dimer is associated with acute&#xD;
      pulmonary emboli (APE), deep venous thrombosis (DVT), cancer, peripheral vascular disease,&#xD;
      inflammatory diseases and pregnancy. It has been found that patients with COVID-19, including&#xD;
      those not on respirators but bedconfined, develop DVT and APE much earlier than expected.&#xD;
      Even with usage of prophylactic anticoagulation, autopsy has shown that deaths in COVID-19&#xD;
      may be caused by the thrombosis in segmental and subsegmental pulmonary arterial vessels.&#xD;
      ENDOCOVID project aims to evaluate the degree to which COVID-19 induced inflammation&#xD;
      contributes to endothelial function and coagulation changes and cardiometabolic risk in PLHIV&#xD;
      (+/-ART). Endothelial function will be evaluated non-invasively via FMD and blood asymmetric&#xD;
      dimethyl arginine (ADMA).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Problem statement HIV infection is a burden for the cardiovascular system but coinfection of&#xD;
      HIV and SARS-CoV-2 in SSA population could be a very big load and could lead to higher menace&#xD;
      of cardiovascular health. However, the potential of risk in this population, including early&#xD;
      vascular and endothelial changes, is yet unclear. Given the ongoing global pandemic,&#xD;
      epidemiological studies to address this knowledge gap is necessary. The aim of this study is&#xD;
      to evaluate cardiovascular risk in HIV and COVID-19 populations, which also would allow&#xD;
      assessment of current - and future - cardiovascular risk, via vascular endothelial function&#xD;
      measurements. The ENDOCOVID project has been designed to give an evaluation of cardiovascular&#xD;
      risk in PLHIV and COVID-19 living in SAA. ENDOCOVID builds up on the EndoAfrica study, which&#xD;
      is currently being carried out in SSA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim and objectives The general aim of the ENDOCOVID project is to identify whether and how&#xD;
      HIV-infection with or without ART in COVID-19 patients relates to the time course of the&#xD;
      disease, alters cardiovascular risk, and changes vascular endothelial structure and function&#xD;
      in adults living in the SSA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three groups of participants will take part in this project:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. PLHIV without ART but with COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. PLHIV with ART and COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. HIV-negative patients with COVID-19, sex- /age matched&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following objectives will be investigated:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Evaluation of the prevalence of COVID-19 in PLHIV (with or without ART) admitted to&#xD;
           clinics in South Africa and Nigeria because of COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Assessment of the incidence of acute respiratory distress syndrome, admission to ICU,&#xD;
           fatal course of disease (30-days mortality), and thromboembolic events in hospitalized&#xD;
           patients included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Evaluation of the influence of ART on severity of COVID-19 in PLHIV (with or without&#xD;
           ART) as well as clinical presentation, changes of endothelial/vascular function and&#xD;
           biomarkers.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Evaluation of the effects of COVID-19 on endothelial/vascular function, thrombotic&#xD;
           factors, and oro-naso sensory alterations over infection and after recovery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Correlation of hospitalization and mortality of COVID-19 infected PLHIV(with or without&#xD;
           ART) and HIV negatives with co-morbidity incidence;&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Assessment of the incidence of obesity and insulin resistance in the 3 groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>4 Weeks</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients developing Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of all three groups, recorded for each patient</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of ICU admissions</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of all three groups, recorded for each patient</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Deaths</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of all three groups</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiometabolic Status: ADMA</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Asymmetrisches Dimethylarginin (ADMA) as marker for endothelial function (from blood sample) measured via commercially available ELISA kits</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiometabolic Status: Cholesterol</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the lipid profile, cholesterol levels will be assessed via blood samples in a routine laboratory</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiometabolic Status: Triglycerides</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the lipid profile, triglyceride concentrations will be assessed via blood samples in a routine laboratory</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiometabolic Status: HDL cholesterol</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the lipid profile, HDL cholesterol concentrations will be assessed via blood samples in a routine laboratory</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiometabolic Status: LDL cholesterol</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the lipid profile, LDL cholesterole concentrations will be assessed via blood samples in a routine laboratory</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiometabolic Status: Glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed via blood samples in a routine laboratory</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiometabolic Status: Glycated Hemoglobin</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>HbA1c as marker for diabetes, assessed via blood samples in a routine laboratory</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiometabolic Status: hs-CRP</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>high sensitivity CRP as inflammatory marker, assessed via blood samples in a routine laboratory</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Endothelial function and vascular changes: FMD</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed non-invasively using ultrasound in the brachial artery (flow mediated dilatation)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Endothelial function and vascular changes: PWV</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>PWV, a marker of aortic stiffness, is most commonly measured as the time it takes a pulse wave to travel from the carotid to the femoral arteries divided by the distance multiplied by 0.8. PWV can be measured by several devices. The non-invasive Vicorder device has been shown to have good reproducibility - even when the assessor has limited experience in its usage - and the results obtained reflect those obtained via invasive central blood pressure measurements and those of SphygmoCor device.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Endothelial function and vascular changes: Retinal microvasculature analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>A non-mydriatic, hand-held, portable digital retinal camera (Optomed Aurora, Optomed Oy, Oulu, Finland) will be used for collecting retinal images. Dimensions of vessels and microvascular state will be analyzed offline with the semi-automated MONA REVA software (VITO, Belgium).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Endothelial function and vascular changes: IMT</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Intima media thickness is assessed via ultrasound in the carotid artery</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Coagulatory Parameters: D-dimer</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>increased D-Dimer as marker for pulmunary embolism in a routine laboratory</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Coagulatory Parameters: CAT</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Calibrated automated thrombography as thrombisis marker (Thrombinoscope BV)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Coagulatory Parameters: TF</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Tissue factor (TF) measured via triggered thromboelastometry (TEM) coagulation analyzer (ROTEM05)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">342</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Hiv</condition>
  <condition>ART</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 positive, HIV-positive with ART</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients tested positive for SARS-CoV-2 Patients tested positive for HIV who are on ART</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 positive, HIV-positive without ART</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients tested positive for SARS-CoV-2 Patients tested positive for HIV ART naive group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 positive, HIV-negative</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients tested positive for SARS-CoV-2 Patients tested positive for HIV ART naive group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>COVID-19</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients diagnosed with a COVID-19 infection</description>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 positive, HIV-negative</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 positive, HIV-positive with ART</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 positive, HIV-positive without ART</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SARS-CoV-2 positive</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HIV</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients diagnosed HIV-positive</description>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 positive, HIV-positive with ART</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 positive, HIV-positive without ART</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ART</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients on ART</description>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 positive, HIV-positive with ART</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Participants of the ENDOCOVID study population are patients with COVID-19, who at the same&#xD;
        time are infected with HIV (with or without ART), or are HIV negative. Some may be admitted&#xD;
        in the ICU. For inclusion into the study, participants must be positive for SARS-CoV-2 RNA&#xD;
        and 18 years or older. Participants will be excluded from the study if they are less than 3&#xD;
        months post-partum and those with other co-infections than HIV such as tuberculosis&#xD;
        Participants fulfilling the criteria will be invited into the study and asked to provide&#xD;
        written informed consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PLHIV without antiretroviral therapy but with COVID-19 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PLHIV with antiretroviral therapy and COVID-19 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV-negative patients, sex- and age matched, infected with COVID-19;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  older than 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with known co-infections such as hepatitis B and C&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  with a viral load of HIV RNA &gt;1000 copies/ml under ART or with advanced symptoms of&#xD;
             AIDS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  negative for SARS-CoV-2 RNA&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nandu Goswami, Dr PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Medical University of Graz</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Nandu Goswami, Dr PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+43 664 7924948</phone>
    <email>nandu.goswami@medunigraz.at</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Ilorin Teaching Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ilorin</city>
        <state>Kwara State</state>
        <country>Nigeria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Chidozie Agu</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lagos Stae University Teaching Hospital Ikeja</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lagos</city>
        <country>Nigeria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Simial Elias</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Walter Sisulu University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mthatha</city>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Benedicta Chungag</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Nigeria</country>
    <country>South Africa</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>HIV Seropositivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

