<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1410">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04427865</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CUKA-002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04427865</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Utility of Lactoferrin as a Preventive Agent for Healthcare Workers Exposed to COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy of Lactoferrin as a Preventive Agent for Healthcare Workers Exposed to COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      COVID 19, which probably started from zoonotic transmission related to crowded markets in&#xD;
      China was announced as a pandemic by the WHO on 11 March 2020.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is currently no clinically proven specific antiviral agents available for SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      infection. Supportive treatment, including oxygen therapy, fluid management, and&#xD;
      broad-spectrum antibiotics to cover secondary bacterial infection, remains the most important&#xD;
      management strategy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since its discovery, lactoferrin and its related peptides are considered non-specific host&#xD;
      defense molecules against a broad range of viruses including SARS-CoV, which is closely&#xD;
      related to SARS-CoV-2 that causes COVID-19. Besides reducing viral entry, lactoferrin can&#xD;
      also suppress virus replication after the viral entry and has an immunomodulatory effect that&#xD;
      can prevent the cytokine storm associated with COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of our study is to assess the safety and efficacy of lactoferrin within the context&#xD;
      of SARS-CoV-2 and propose the possibility of supplemental lactoferrin as a potential&#xD;
      preventive drug for healthcare workers exposed to SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In December, 2019, an outbreak of pneumonia with unknown cause occurred in Wuhan city, in&#xD;
      China. On January 7th, the scientists succeeded to isolate a novel coronavirus, severe acute&#xD;
      respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2). WHO nominated it as coronavirus disease 2019&#xD;
      (COVID-19) in February, 2020. COVID-19 has a wide clinical spectrum ranging between&#xD;
      asymptomatic infection, mild upper respiratory tract symptoms, and severe viral pneumonia&#xD;
      that may result in respiratory failure and finally death. There is currently no clinically&#xD;
      proven specific antiviral agent available for SARS-CoV-2 infection. Supportive treatment,&#xD;
      including oxygen therapy, conservation fluid management, and broad-spectrum antibiotics to&#xD;
      cover secondary bacterial infection, remains the most important management strategy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lactoferrin is a highly conserved pleiotropic iron-binding 80-kDa glycoprotein of the&#xD;
      transferrin family that is expressed and secreted by glandular cells and found in most body&#xD;
      fluids with especially high concentrations in mammalian milk. Since its discovery,&#xD;
      lactoferrin and its related peptides are mainly considered to be important non-specific host&#xD;
      defense molecules against a broad range of viruses including SARS-CoV, which is closely&#xD;
      related to SARS-CoV-2 that causes COVID-19. Lactoferrin has been found to experimentally&#xD;
      inhibit viral entry in murine coronavirus, and human coronaviruses hCOV-NL63 and pseudotyped&#xD;
      SARS-CoV. Given the homology of SARS-CoV and SARS-CoV-2 spike protein structures, as well as&#xD;
      both viruses depending on the same ACE2 receptor for cell entry, it is likely that&#xD;
      lactoferrin can inhibit SARS-CoV-2 invasion as in the case of SARS-CoV. Besides reducing&#xD;
      viral entry, lactoferrin can also suppress virus replication after the viral entry as in the&#xD;
      case of HIV.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Another major aspect of lactoferrin bioactivity relates to its immunomodulatory and&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory functions. Current thinking suggests that mortality from COVID-19 is not&#xD;
      simply due to viral infection but is a result of a cytokine storm associated with&#xD;
      hyper-inflammation leading to acute respiratory distress and subsequent mortality. A cytokine&#xD;
      profile in severe COVID-19 cases is characterized by increases in cytokines and acute phase&#xD;
      reactants such as interleukin IL-6, tumor necrosis factor-a (TNFa) and ferritin. In this&#xD;
      regard, lactoferrin was demonstrated to reduce IL-6, TNF a, and downregulate ferritin in&#xD;
      experimental settings simulating sepsis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, we aim to study the antiviral properties and immunomodulatory mechanisms of&#xD;
      lactoferrin within the context of its potential applications against SARS-CoV-2 and propose&#xD;
      the possibility of supplemental lactoferrin as a potential preventive agent for COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of SARS-CoV-2</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of confirmed infections of SARS-CoV-2 in healthcare workers</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Severity of disease in confirmed infected participants</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lactoferrin prophylaxis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>200 mg oral lactoferrin daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>prophylactic lactoferrin daily</intervention_name>
    <description>200 mg oral lactoferrin daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lactoferrin prophylaxis</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  health care workers at risk of SARS-CoV-2 transmission with no previous diagnosis of&#xD;
             SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No symptoms compatible with SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19) until the date of enrolment in the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy or hypersensitivity to the used medications&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>June 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 10, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 11, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 11, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Gamal Esmat</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Endemic Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lactoferrin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

