<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="16">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04407585</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Covid-19 Validation Study</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04407585</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Testing the Accuracy of a Digital Test to Diagnose Covid-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Validation of Machine Learning (ML) Models as Diagnostic Tools to Predict Infection With SARS-CoV-2</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>King's College London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Zoe Global Limited</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Department of Health, United Kingdom</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>King's College London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The Covid-19 viral pandemic has caused significant global losses and disruption to all&#xD;
      aspects of society. One of the major difficulties in controlling the spread of this&#xD;
      coronavirus has been the delayed and mild (or lack of) presentation of symptoms in infected&#xD;
      individuals, and the insufficient Covid-19 testing capacity in the UK. This warrants the&#xD;
      development of alternative diagnostic tools that reliably assess Covid-19 infection in the&#xD;
      early stages of infection, while also being low- cost, low-burden, and easily administered to&#xD;
      a wide proportion of the population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study aims to validate machine learning models as a diagnostic tool that predicts&#xD;
      infection with SARS-CoV-2 based on app-reported symptoms and phenotypic data, against the&#xD;
      'gold-standard' swab PCR-test. This study will take place within the Covid Symptom Study app,&#xD;
      the free symptom tracking mobile application launched in March 2020.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Covid-19 viral pandemic has caused significant global losses and disruption to all&#xD;
      aspects of society (including health, education, and business and economic security). One of&#xD;
      the major difficulties in controlling the spread of this coronavirus has been the delayed and&#xD;
      mild (or lack of) presentation of symptoms in infected individuals. Moreover, there is&#xD;
      insufficient Covid-19 testing capacity in the UK, and only moderate accuracy of such tests at&#xD;
      confirming coronavirus infection. Together, these obstacles have led to countless unknown&#xD;
      coronavirus cases going unobserved and fuelling the viral spread in the population, by&#xD;
      compromising the stringency of self- isolation measures undertaken by infected individuals&#xD;
      who may have otherwise curbed or prevented their transmission of the virus. The profound and&#xD;
      widespread cost of the continuing Covid-19 progression, coinciding with the lack of testing&#xD;
      capacity, warrants the development of alternative diagnostic tools that reliably assess&#xD;
      Covid-19 infection in the early stages of infection, while also being low- cost, low-burden,&#xD;
      and easily administered to a wide proportion of the population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The free symptom-monitoring app 'Covid Symptom Study' was launched in mid-March by health&#xD;
      technology start-up Zoe Global Ltd, and is currently being used in the UK, US and Sweden,&#xD;
      with more than 2.7 million users in the UK alone who use the app to self-report their&#xD;
      Covid-19 symptoms. Upon registering to use the app, users are asked to report demographic and&#xD;
      phenotypic data such as age, sex, BMI, ethnicity, contact with infected individuals (through&#xD;
      a healthcare professional capacity), smoking behaviour, existing health conditions, among&#xD;
      other information. From then on, users are asked to report, on a daily basis, their&#xD;
      presentation of symptoms attributable to Covid-19 (or lack thereof) through the use of&#xD;
      app-administered questionnaires, thus enabling real-time tracking of disease progression&#xD;
      across the UK. The app also allows users to report their Covid-19 test results, thus enabling&#xD;
      the development of prediction algorithms based solely on self-reported user data to predict&#xD;
      the presence of infection in untested users.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On behalf of Zoe Global Ltd, the UK Department of Health and Social Care with support from&#xD;
      the UK's Chief Scientific Advisor has committed to test up to 10,000 app-users per week for&#xD;
      infection with SARS-CoV-2 across England and Northern Ireland, for the purpose of rapidly&#xD;
      improving the accuracy of symptom-based predictions. Similar testing allowance may follow in&#xD;
      Scotland and Wales.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Symptomatic app-users will be asked to get tested for SARS-CoV-2 infection, using the popular&#xD;
      swab and qRT-PCR technique, and asked to report their test results in the app, while&#xD;
      continuing to log their symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This validation study, conducted at King's College London, aims to validate the sensitivity&#xD;
      and specificity of machine learning models as a diagnostic tool that predicts infection with&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 based on app-reported symptoms and phenotypic data, against the 'gold-standard'&#xD;
      swab PCR-test, by utilising the Covid Symptom Study app as a research platform.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is hypothesised that by training the symptom-based models using swab test results and&#xD;
      through multiple model iterations following continuous data input from reporting and tested&#xD;
      app users, predictions of infection will be made with considerable accuracy, thus enabling&#xD;
      the Covid Symptom Study app to be used as a diagnostic tool that alleviates the strain of&#xD;
      testing capacity in the UK while being easily accessible and posing low user burden.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to the rapidly developing and uncertain duration and intensity of the Covid-19 pandemic,&#xD;
      the present study design is prospective and one that enables regular iteration on prediction&#xD;
      models and continuous accumulation of validation data. The study consists of a series of&#xD;
      phases, each lasting 14 days. Before the start of each phase (day 0), a set of machine&#xD;
      learning models will be frozen and submitted for validation on data collected during this and&#xD;
      subsequent phases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Machine learning algorithms improve with increasing data. Therefore, validation phases will&#xD;
      continue as long as tests are available and app users consent to joining the study. Due to&#xD;
      the uncertainty around the progression of UK infection rates, the validation study will be&#xD;
      continue whilst it is of value to public health.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A detailed statistical analysis plan is described in the document attached to this record. A&#xD;
      record of all machine learning models used for validation will be regularly updated on GitHub&#xD;
      (https://github.com/zoe/covid-validation-study).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 10, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 10, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SARS-CoV-2 infection</measure>
    <time_frame>3 days</time_frame>
    <description>Likelihood of infection with Covid-19, based on app-reported symptoms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SARS-CoV-2 infection</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Active infection with Covid-19 as assessed by PCR swab test</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000000</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Covid-19 Symptom Study app-user</arm_group_label>
    <description>UK-based Covid-19 Symptom Study primary app-user completing self-reports in the app</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Covid-19 swab PCR test</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants satisfying machine learning test criteria will be asked to take a swab test for Covid-19.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Covid-19 Symptom Study app-user</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study population includes individuals are UK-based primary users of the Covid Symptom&#xD;
        Study app, who provide informed consent to participate.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Study Inclusion Criteria - app users will be eligible to join the study if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are based in the UK (are using the UK version of the Covid-19 Symptom Study app, and&#xD;
             have listed a UK postcode)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are the primary app user (are reporting directly for themselves)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are at least 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have not tested positive for a Covid-19 test before (but may have been tested)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study Exclusion Criteria - participants are ineligible for the study if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not meet inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not provide informed consent to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants will be subject to further screening to identify them as eligible for swab&#xD;
        testing during the course of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Swab inclusion criteria - participants will be eligible for swab testing if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have reported in the app at least once in the previous 3 days (days -2 to 0), and at&#xD;
             least two times in the previous 9 days (days -8 to 0). All reports must be healthy&#xD;
             (i.e. not experiencing any symptoms).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  On the previous day (day 1), have reported that they are experiencing at least one&#xD;
             symptom described in the app. Symptoms in the app are updated when deemed appropriate&#xD;
             by study investigators using evidence based reports in the scientific and medical&#xD;
             field.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have answered the phenotype fields required for the prediction model with&#xD;
             physiologically plausible values.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Swab exclusion criteria - participants are ineligible for swab testing if they:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are asymptomatic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not satisfy the inclusion criteria for testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Insufficient testing capacity:&#xD;
&#xD;
        If insufficient testing capacity is available for the study population as described, then&#xD;
        recruitment will be prioritised according to:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Firstly, most recent final healthy report before reporting symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Secondly, highest number of healthy reports during the previous 9 days before&#xD;
             reporting symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thirdly, randomised selection to stratify between participants of equal priority&#xD;
             according to the first two rules above.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Excess testing capacity:&#xD;
&#xD;
        If excess testing capacity is available beyond the study population as described, then&#xD;
        inclusion criteria will be expanded in order to adequately sample across under-represented&#xD;
        population groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Specifically, on day 7 of each validation phase, investigators will assess:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  What excess testing capacity is available, if any&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Which subgroups are under-represented compared to their proportion in the UK&#xD;
             population (as best as can be established given that some participants may not have&#xD;
             completed some phenotype fields):&#xD;
&#xD;
             (i) Age decade (ii) Sex (iii) Ethnicity (iv) BMI category&#xD;
&#xD;
        For underrepresented groups, investigators may additionally recruit participants with only&#xD;
        one report during the previous 3 days (days -2 to 0) and no other report during the&#xD;
        previous 9 days (days -8 to 0).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Inbar Linenberg, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>+447791871699</phone>
    <email>inbar.linenberg@kcl.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>King's College London</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>SE1 9NH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Inbar Linenberg, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>+447791871699</phone>
      <email>inbar.linenberg@kcl.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tim Spector</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sarah Berry</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Claire Steves</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sebastien Ourselin</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Peter Sasieni</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Andrew Chan</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 27, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 24, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Covid-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Machine learning</keyword>
  <keyword>Covid-19 diagnostic</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>May 26, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/85/NCT04407585/SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

