<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4931">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03013998</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BAML-16-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03013998</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Biomarker-Based Treatment of Acute Myeloid Leukemia</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Master Protocol for Biomarker-Based Treatment of AML (The Beat AML Trial)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Beat AML, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Beat AML, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This screening and multi-sub-study Phase 1b/2 trial will establish a method for genomic&#xD;
      screening followed by assigning and accruing simultaneously to a multi-study &quot;Master Protocol&#xD;
      (BAML-16-001-M1).&quot; The specific subtype of acute myeloid leukemia will determine which&#xD;
      sub-study, within this protocol, a participant will be assigned to evaluate investigational&#xD;
      therapies or combinations with the ultimate goal of advancing new targeted therapies for&#xD;
      approval. The study also includes a marker negative sub-study which will include all screened&#xD;
      patients not eligible for any of the biomarker-driven sub-studies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients for whom molecular, immunophenotypic, and/or biochemical studies are completed in &lt; 7 calendar days for assignment of treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>The feasibility of completing molecular, genetic, immunophenotypic, and biochemical testing for assignment of therapy will be assessed based on the proportion of patients for whom testing is completed within 7 days of the registration sample arriving at the laboratory</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients assigned to a novel therapeutic treatment group in 1 of several sub-studies in this Master Protocol, based on the result of the molecular, immunophenotypic, and/or biochemical studies</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>The feasibility of assigning patients to a treatment group will be assessed based on the proportion who are eligible for screening in this study who are assigned to treatment either on this study or an industry study relevant to the specific marker group and not unassignable due to insufficient material, laboratory error, or any other factors</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical response rate (rate of complete and partial responses) according to International Working Group criteria for treatment outcomes in therapeutic trials in acute myeloid leukemia</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients enrolled on this trial that ultimately will be assigned and go onto an assigned therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dynamic changes in clonal architecture over time in acute myeloid leukemia patients receiving targeted therapies</measure>
    <time_frame>time of diagnosis, remission (complete response or complete response with incomplete blood count recovery), 1 year of treatment, and relapse</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Relationships between baseline functional status and response rate or progression-free survival based on graphical comparison (eg, side-by-side boxplots or Kaplan-Meier plots)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Assessments of functional status will include Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status. Assessment of clinical response will be made according to International Working Group criteria. Relationships will be explored graphically (eg, side-by-side boxplots or Kaplan-Meier plots), where estimates with confidence intervals will be presented as the primary method of analysis due to the limited number of patients.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>13</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2000</enrollment>
  <condition>Previously Untreated Acute Myeloid Leukemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S1 (Closed)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is an open-label Phase 1b/2 clinical study of Samalizumab given in addition to standard induction chemotherapy/consolidation, followed by Samalizumab maintenance, in newly diagnosed acute myeloid leukemia. Patients that are marker negative, as defined based on the Beat AML Master Protocol assignment or with CBF karyotype/interphase cytogenetics/molecular testing defined by presence of t(8;21)(q22;q22) or the molecular equivalent RUNX1/RUNX1T1 fusion transcript or inv(16)(p13q22) or t(16;16)(p13;q22) or the molecular equivalent CBFB/MYH11 fusion transcript based on the Beat AML will receive Samalizumab in combination with induction therapy followed by Samalizumab maintenance.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is an open-label Phase 1b/2 clinical study of BI 836858 given in combination with azacitidine, followed by BI 836858 plus azacitidine maintenance, in newly diagnosed acute myeloid leukemia. The target population is assigned by the Beat AML Master Protocol (the &quot;umbrella&quot; study). Eligible patients will have previously untreated acute myeloid leukemia, age greater than or equal to 60, with any 1 of the following: mutated TET2, IDH1, IDH2, or WT1, or &quot;marker negative&quot; as defined by the overall Beat AML umbrella protocol.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is a phase 2 clinical trial to assess the feasibility and efficacy of a stepwise approach to the treatment of IDH2-mutant AML. On day 1 of the trial, all enrolled participants will be initiated on therapy with the IDH2 inhibitor AG-221 for IDH2 R140 and R172-mutant patients. The dosing will be based on phase 1 experience of AG-221, which has established 100 mg daily as a safe and tolerated dose, with preliminary suggestion of efficacy. These will be administered continuously in 28 day cycles. Hydroxyurea will be allowed for the purposes of cytoreduction.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S4 (Closed)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is a 2 cohort phase 1b/2 clinical trial to assess the feasibility and efficacy of entospletinib (ENTO) stepwise approach to the treatment of patients with balanced translocations of MLL identified cytogenetically (Cohort 1) and patients with MLL-partial tandem duplications identified molecularly (Cohort 2). All enrolled participants will be initiated on monotherapy with ENTO 400 mg PO BID. This dose will be administered continuously in 28 day cycles.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is a phase 2 clinical trial to assess the feasibility and efficacy of a stepwise approach to the treatment of patients with TP53 mutations (identified molecularly) with/without complex karyotype (Cohort A) or complex karyotype (3 or greater metaphase abnormalities without TP53) (Cohort B). All enrolled participants will be initiated on entospletinib 400 mg orally twice daily. This dose will be administered continuously in 28 day cycles.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S6</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The study is an open-label phase 2 study of entospletinib in younger and older AML patients with NPM1+/FLT3ITD-AML. It includes patients age ≥18 years who are able and willing to receive 7 + 3 intensive chemotherapy. Entospletinib is administered daily with IV daunorubicin (days 1-3 for Cycle 1) and cytarabine (days 1-7 for Cycle 1). If a second induction is required, it is given with IV daunorubicin (days 1-2 for Cycle 2) and cytarabine (days 1-5 for Cycle 2).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S9 (Closed)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is an open-label phase 2 clinical trial of a stepwise approach to the treatment of patients with TP53 mutation AML. On day 1, all enrolled participants will be initiated on therapy with pevonedistat (20 mg/m2) day 1, 3 and 5 together with azacitidine (75 mg/m2 days 1-7 or day 1-5 then day 8, 9) every 28 days. During cycle 1, patients with rapidly progressive disease or severe organ dysfunction, not correctable by hydroxyurea cytoreduction will not be eligible to continue. Those patients who achieved a response, defined as complete response or complete response with incomplete blood count recovery, by the end of cycle 4 will continue on pevonedistat and azacitidine until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, or 12 cycles of therapy. After 12 months of combined therapy, pevonedistat will be continued until progression of disease, unacceptable toxicity, or up to 2 years of total therapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S16</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is an open-label phase 2 clinical study to assess the feasibility and efficacy of a combination based approach to the treatment of IDH1 mutant AML. On day 1 of the trial, all enrolled participants will be initiated on therapy with the IDH1 inhibitor AG-120 given daily together with azacitidine (days 1-5 and 8-9 or 7 consecutive days 1-7) in 28 day cycles for IDH1 mutant patients. Those patients who have achieved a response, defined as complete response or complete response with incomplete blood count recovery, by the end of cycle 6, will continue on combination therapy for a total of 12 cycles and then patients will go onto receive monotherapy with AG-120 until disease progression or unacceptable side effects that mandate discontinuation of therapy. Patients who cannot complete 12 cycles of azacitidine may proceed onto monotherapy with AG-120.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S8</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is an open-label Phase 2/1b clinical study of gilteritinib as a single agent stratified into 2 cohorts in phase 2 portion based upon dominant versus non-dominant FLT3 mutation status. Cohort 1, Dominant FLT3, will include patients with either FLT3-ITD with allelic ratio of ≥0.5 stratified based upon the prioritization schema of the master trial; FLT3-TKD with highest variant allele frequency among mutations studied for stratification; or FLT3-TKD with second highest variant allele frequency in setting of DNMT3A, TET2, ASXL1, BCORL1, JAK2, and SF3B1 or other spliceosome family member. Cohort 2, non-dominant FLT3, will include the remainder of patients with FLT3-ITD or FLT3-TKD stratified based upon the master umbrella study protocol. For the phase 1b portion, gilteritinib will be given in combination with decitabine for non-responding patients to test the efficacy of gilteritinib in combination with decitabine in elderly AML with FLT3 mutation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-COV1 (Acalabrutinib)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is the treatment arm in a non-blinded Phase 2 sub-study trial of Acalabrutinib in patients with hematologic malignancies and hospitalization for confirmed PCR+ SARS-CoV-2 infection. Patients will be randomized in a 1:1 fashion to receive Acalabrutinib + standard therapy or standard therapy alone for COVID-19.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-COV1 (Standard Therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is the comparator arm in a non-blinded Phase 2 sub-study trial of Acalabrutinib in patients with hematologic malignancies and hospitalization for confirmed PCR+ SARS-CoV-2 infection. Patients will be randomized in a 1:1 fashion to receive Acalabrutinib + standard therapy or standard therapy alone for COVID-19.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S10</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is a phase 1b/2 clinical trial to assess the safety and efficacy of the combination of AZD5153 and venetoclax. In a phase 1b component, safety and tolerability of the combination will be assessed in relapsed/refractory AML patients ≥ 18 years of age. Following determination of the recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D), newly diagnosed, marker negative patients age ≥ 60 will be enrolled in the phase 2 component; these patients will be treated at the previously identified RP2D for the combination. The RP2D will be the highest dose level with ≤ 1 out of 6 patients with dose limiting toxicity and defined as the maximum tolerated dose.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S14</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The study is an open-label Phase 1b/2 clinical study of TP-0903 given in addition to decitabine in patients ≥ 60 years with newly diagnosed, previously untreated AML with TP53 mutations and/or complex karyotype. The Phase 1b portion of this study will use a standard 3 + 3 design with dose escalation based upon dose limiting toxicities. The maximum tolerated dose will be defined as the highest dose where at most 1 patient in 6 experiences dose-limiting toxicity, and this is generally the recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D). Once the RP2D is determined from Phase 1b, patients will be enrolled at this dose level to initiate the Phase 2 portion of the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Samalizumab (BAML-16-001-S1)</intervention_name>
    <description>300 mg/m2, IV, on days 1, 3, and 24; followed by 300 mg/m2, IV, every 21 days for 2 years in the absence of toxicity or disease progression. Dose may be de-escalated to 150 mg/m2 or escalated to 600 mg/m2 based on occurrence of dose-limiting toxicity.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S1 (Closed)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BI 836858 (BAML-16-001-S2)</intervention_name>
    <description>20 mg/m2, IV, on days 9, 16, and 23 of a 28-day cycle; followed 20 by mg/m2, IV, on days 1, 8, 15 and 22 of each 28-day cycle for 2 years in the absence of toxicity or disease progression (reduced to monthly administration in event of complete response or complete response with incomplete blood count recovery). Dose may be escalated to a maximum dose of 320 mg/m2 or de-escalated to 10 mg/m2 based on occurrence of dose-limiting toxicity.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Laboratory Biomarker Analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Molecular genomic assessment to assign patients to targeted therapy (sub-study) based on their specific subtype of acute myeloid leukemia</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S1 (Closed)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S16</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S4 (Closed)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S6</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S8</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S9 (Closed)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Daunorubicin (BAML-16-001-S1)</intervention_name>
    <description>60 mg/m2, IV, on days 4, 5, and 6 of the induction cycle</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S1 (Closed)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cytarabine (BAML-16-001-S1)</intervention_name>
    <description>100 mg/m2, IV, on days 4 through 10 of the 24-day induction cycle; 1000 mg/m2, IV, on days 2, 4, and 6 of the consolidation cycle 1 and days 1, 3, and 5 of consolidation cycles 2 through 4</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S1 (Closed)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Azacitidine (BAML-16-001-S2)</intervention_name>
    <description>75 mg/m2, IV, on days 1 through 7 of each 28-day cycle for 2 years in the absence of toxicity or disease progression</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AG-221 (BAML-16-001-S3)</intervention_name>
    <description>100 mg, oral, daily until time of intolerance or disease progression. Dose may be de-escalated to 50 mg based on occurrence of dose-limiting toxicity.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S3</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Enasidenib</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Azacitidine (BAML-16-001-S3)</intervention_name>
    <description>75 mg/m2, IV or SC, on days 1 through 7 of each 28-day cycle starting with cycle 6 and ending after 12 cycles for patients not attaining complete remission or complete remission with incomplete blood count recovery after 5 cycles of monotherapy with AG-221</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S3</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Entospletinib (BAML-16-001-S4)</intervention_name>
    <description>200 mg, oral, twice daily for 5 years until time of intolerance or disease progression. Dose may be escalated to 400 mg.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S4 (Closed)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>GS-9973, ENTO</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Azacitidine (BAML-16-001-S4)</intervention_name>
    <description>75 mg/m2, IV or SC, on days 1 through 7 of each 28-day cycle and continuing for 12 cycles. Treatment starts after 1 cycle of monotherapy with entospletinib for patients not attaining complete remission or complete remission with incomplete blood count recovery or after later cycles of monotherapy with entospletinib for patients with disease progression.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S4 (Closed)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Entospletinib (BAML-16-001-S5)</intervention_name>
    <description>400 mg, oral, twice daily for 2 years on study until time of intolerance or disease progression. Dose may be de-escalated to 200 mg twice daily or 200 mg once daily based on occurrence of dose-limiting toxicity.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S5</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>GS-9973, ENTO</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Decitabine (BAML-16-001-S5)</intervention_name>
    <description>20 mg/m2, IV, on days 1 through 5 or 10 of each 28-day cycle and continuing for up to 11 cycles. During the first induction cycle, and the 2nd and 3rd induction cycles if they are needed, administration occurs on days 1 through 10 of each 28-day cycle. During subsequent consolidation, decitabine is administered on days 1 through 5 of each 28-day cycle and continuing for up to 11 cycles. Duration may be reduced by 1 day based on occurrence of dose-limiting toxicity, and patients may switch to entospletinib monotherapy maintenance at any time if they develop toxicity or are unwilling to continue decitabine during consolidation therapy.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S5</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Entospletinib (BAML-16-001-S6)</intervention_name>
    <description>400 mg, oral, twice daily for 2 years until time of intolerance or disease progression.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S6</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>GS-9973, ENTO</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Daunorubicin (BAML-16-001-S6)</intervention_name>
    <description>60 mg/m2, IV, on days 1-3 or 1-2 of each 28-day cycle for the first and second induction cycle, respectively</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S6</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cytarabine (BAML-16-001-S6)</intervention_name>
    <description>100 mg/m2, IV, on days 1 through 7 or 1 through 5 of each 28-day cycle for the first and second induction cycle, respectively; then 1000 mg/m2 (patients ≥60 years) or 3000 mg/m2 (younger patients with creatinine clearance &gt;30 mL/min and &lt;50 mL/min), IV, every 12 hours on days 1, 3, and 5 of each 28-day cycle for up to 4 consolidation cycles</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S6</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pevonedistat (BAML-16-001-S9)</intervention_name>
    <description>20 mg/m2, IV, on days 1, 3, and 5 of each 28-day cycle and continuing for 24 cycles in the absence of toxicity or disease progression</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S9 (Closed)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>TAK-924, MLN4924</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Azacitidine (BAML-16-001-S9)</intervention_name>
    <description>75 mg/m2, IV or SC, on days 1 through 7 or days 1 through 5 and then 8 through 9 (based on institutional guidelines) of each 28-day cycle and continuing for 12 cycles in the absence of toxicity or disease progression</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S9 (Closed)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AG-120 (BAML-16-001-S16)</intervention_name>
    <description>500 mg, oral, daily until time of intolerance or disease progression. Dose may be de-escalated to 250 mg based on occurrence of dose-limiting toxicity.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S16</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Azacitidine (BAML-16-001-S16)</intervention_name>
    <description>75 mg/m2, IV or SC, on days 1 through 7 or days 1 through 5 and then 8 through 9 (based on institutional guidelines) of each 28-day cycle and continuing for 12 cycles in the absence of toxicity or disease progression</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S16</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Gilteritinib (BAML-16-001-S8)</intervention_name>
    <description>120 mg, oral, daily, with treatment continuing based on bone marrow results at 28 and 56 days. Patients with partial response at 28 days continue treatment for an additional 28 days. Patients with complete remission (CR) or complete remission with incomplete hematologic recovery (CRi) at 28 or 56 days continue treatment for 5 years until time of intolerance or disease progression. Patients with less than partial response at 28 days or partial response at 28 days followed by less than CR or CRi at 56 days proceed to combination treatment with decitabine or non-study alternative.&#xD;
The combination dose is 80 mg, oral, daily, for 5 years until time of intolerance or disease progression (patients who do not achieve CR or CRi after 3 cycles will discontinue study treatment). The combination dose may be escalated to 120 mg daily or de-escalated to 80 mg daily given after decitabine rather than in combination with decitabine based on absence or occurrence of dose-limiting toxicity.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S8</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Decitabine (BAML-16-001-S8)</intervention_name>
    <description>20 mg/m2, IV, on days 1 through 10 of each 28-day cycle and continuing for up to 3 cycles. Treatment starts after 1-2 cycles of monotherapy with gilteritinib if patients do not attain complete remission (CR) or complete remission with incomplete hematologic recovery (CRi) with monotherapy. Patients who do not achieve CR/CRi after 3 cycles of combination therapy will discontinue study treatment. If CR or CRi is obtained with combination therapy after 3 cycles, decitabine will be administered on days 1-5 of each subsequent 28-day cycle until progression, intolerance, or patient desire to discontinue therapy.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S8</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acalabrutinib (BAML-16-001-COV1)</intervention_name>
    <description>100 mg, oral, twice daily for 14 days or until unacceptable toxicities occur</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-COV1 (Acalabrutinib)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard Therapy (BAML-16-001-COV1)</intervention_name>
    <description>Standard therapy as required for COVID-19</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-COV1 (Acalabrutinib)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-COV1 (Standard Therapy)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AZD5153 (BAML-16-001-S10)</intervention_name>
    <description>20 mg, oral, once daily during 7-day lead-in and then on days 1 through 21 of each 28-day cycle for up to 2 years or until allogeneic stem cell transplantation, time of intolerance, or disease progression [if the continuous administration AZD5153 on Days 1-21 of a 28-day cycle is not tolerated, an alternative schedule of 2 weeks on and 2 weeks off (i.e. AZD5153 will be administered on Days 1-14 of a 28-day cycle) will be explored]. Dose may be de-escalated to 10 mg or escalated to 30 mg based on occurrence of dose-limiting toxicity during phase 1 dose escalation. Starting with Cycle 2, patients may receive concomitant fluconazole, isavuconazole, or posaconazole and doses adjusted to 2, 5, or 8 mg daily. The Phase 1b expansion pharmacokinetics cohort will allow for posaconazole starting at Cycle 1 with AZD5153 dose adjusted from 10, 20, or 30 mg daily to 2, 5, or 8 mg daily. Phase 2 dose will be based on Phase 1 results.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S10</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Venetoclax (BAML-16-001-S10)</intervention_name>
    <description>400 mg, oral, on days 1 through 21 of each 28-day cycle and continuing for up to 12 cycles (for Cycle 1, day 1 dose will be 100 mg, day 2 dose 200 mg, and days 3 onward 400 mg). Starting with Cycle 2, patients may receive concomitant fluconazole or isavuconazole and daily doses adjusted to 200 mg, or posaconazole and daily doses adjusted to 70 mg. The Phase 1b expansion pharmacokinetics cohort will allow for posaconazole starting at Cycle 1 with Venetoclax dose adjusted to 10 mg on day 1, 20 mg on day 2, 50 mg on day 3, and 70 mg on day 4 onward).</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S10</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TP-0903 (BAML-16-001-S14)</intervention_name>
    <description>37 mg, oral, once daily on days 1 through 21 of each 28-day cycle for up to 2 years to time of intolerance or disease progression. Dose may be de-escalated to as low as 12 mg or escalated to 50 mg based on occurrence of dose-limiting toxicity during Phase 1 dose escalation. Phase 2 dose will be based on Phase 1 results.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S14</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Decitabine (BAML-16-001-S14)</intervention_name>
    <description>20 mg/m2, IV, on days 1 through 5 or 10 of each 28-day cycle and continuing for up to 2 years to time of intolerance or disease progression. During the first induction cycle, and the 2nd and 3rd induction cycles if they are needed, administration occurs on days 1 through 10 of each 28-day cycle. During maintenance, decitabine is administered on days 1 through 5 of each 28-day cycle. Patients may switch to TP-0903 monotherapy maintenance if they develop toxicity or are unwilling to continue decitabine during maintenance therapy.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BAML-16-001-S14</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults, age 60 years or older at the time of diagnosis unless in a specific known&#xD;
             cytogenetic and genomic group for which treatment in Group A or B is allowed by the&#xD;
             sub-study where age 18 and older is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects or their legal representative must be able to understand and provide written&#xD;
             informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohort Inclusion Criteria - Group A: Subjects must have previously untreated acute&#xD;
             myeloid leukemia (AML) according to the WHO classification with no prior treatment&#xD;
             other than hydroxyurea. Prior therapy for myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS),&#xD;
             myeloproliferative syndromes (MPD), or aplastic anemia is permitted but not with&#xD;
             hypomethylating agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohort Inclusion Criteria - Group B: Subjects must have relapsed or refractory AML&#xD;
             according to the WHO classification. For study purposes, refractory AML is defined as&#xD;
             failure to ever achieve CR or recurrence of AML within 6 months of achieving CR;&#xD;
             relapsed AML is defined as all others with disease after prior remission.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Isolated myeloid sarcoma (meaning, patients must have blood or marrow involvement with&#xD;
             AML to enter the study)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute promyelocytic leukemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptomatic central nervous system (CNS) involvement by AML&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signs of leukostasis requiring urgent therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Disseminated intravascular coagulopathy with active bleeding or signs of thrombosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with psychological, familial, social, or geographic factors that otherwise&#xD;
             preclude them from giving informed consent, following the protocol, or potentially&#xD;
             hamper compliance with study treatment and follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other significant medical condition, including psychiatric illness or laboratory&#xD;
             abnormality, that would preclude the patient participating in the trial or would&#xD;
             confound the interpretation of the results of the trial&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>John C Byrd, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Beat AML</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Spencer Kalk</last_name>
    <phone>919-227-5843</phone>
    <email>spencer.kalk@syneoshealth.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic Arizona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Phoenix</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85054</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Completed</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCLA Ronald Reagan Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90095</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gary Schiller, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California, San Francisco</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94143</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rebecca Olin, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Colorado</name>
      <address>
        <city>Denver</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80203</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Completed</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Florida Health Shands Cancer Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32608</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christopher Cogle, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic Florida</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jacksonville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32224</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>James Foran, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emory University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30308</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>William Blum, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Chicago</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60637</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Wendy Stock, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Clinical Research Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fairway</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tara Lin, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Maryland Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Maria Baer, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic Minnesota</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mark R Litzow, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Eytan M Stein, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UNC Hospitals, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27514</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Matthew Foster, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ohio State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>John C Byrd, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alice Mims, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alison R Walker, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oregon Health &amp; Science University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97239</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Uma Borate, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UPMC Hillman Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael Boyiadzis, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas Southwestern</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75390</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Prapti Patel, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Huntsman Cancer Institute, University of Utah</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salt Lake City</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84112</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael Deininger, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.lls.org/beat-aml</url>
    <description>Click here for more information about this study: Study of Biomarker-Based Treatment of Acute Myeloid Leukemia</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 21, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 5, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 9, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 17, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 17, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 18, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cytarabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Azacitidine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Decitabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Daunorubicin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Venetoclax</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pevonedistat</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

