<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="534">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04733170</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>VATIC-0101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04733170</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Performance Evaluation of KnowNow SARS-CoV-2 Test for the Detection of COVID-19 Antigen</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Performance Evaluation of KnowNow SARS-CoV-2 Test for the Detection of COVID-19 Antigen</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vatic Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vatic Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an international, multicentre, non-interventional, observational study to assess the&#xD;
      clinical diagnostic performance of a rapid, point of care (POC) COVID-19 (SARS-CoV-2) antigen&#xD;
      In vitro diagnostic (IVD), The KnowNow SARS-CoV-2 Rapid Antigen Test, using saliva samples&#xD;
      when compared to reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) as the standard&#xD;
      detection of COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The KnowNow SARS-CoV-2 Rapid Antigen Test which uses saliva and is a lateral flow diagnostic&#xD;
      device that can detect the SARS-CoV-2 specific Antigens that are present on the surface of&#xD;
      the virus. The KnowNow test is an affordable, user friendly, and point of care device that&#xD;
      can be mass produced as part of a multipronged strategy to address the global COVID-19&#xD;
      pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A saliva sample is collected from someone with suspected COVID-19 and mixed with a running&#xD;
      buffer. The mixture is added to the sample pad of the KnowNow test, from where it migrates&#xD;
      through the lateral flow strip. If COVID-19 Antigens are present, they bind to capture&#xD;
      proteins on a test line and are made visible by secondary reagents within the device. The&#xD;
      test result is visually assessed after 15-30 minutes and provides a binary positive (two&#xD;
      lines) or negative (one line) result. Levels of COVID-19 Antigen differ dependent on disease&#xD;
      progression. A visible test line (marked T) indicates the presence of COVID-19 Antigen in&#xD;
      sufficient quantity in the collected sample to be detected. The appearance of the control&#xD;
      line (marked C) confirms that the test has been performed correctly.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess clinical diagnostic performance of the KnowNow SARS-CoV-2 Rapid Antigen Test</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>This includes determination of the sensitivity/positive percent agreement (PPA), specificity/negative percent agreement (NPA), positive predicted value (PPV) and negative predictive value (NPV).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy to assess the test compared to the reference test method</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Calculated Sensitivity/PPA, Specificity/NPA, PPV and NPV of the KnowNow SARS-CoV-2 Rapid Antigen Test compared to RT-PCR as SOT in individuals with and without COVID-19 symptoms.&#xD;
Calculated Sensitivity/PPA, Specificity/NPA, PPV and NPV of the KnowNow SARS-CoV-2 Rapid Antigen Test compared to RT-PCR as the reference method in individuals with and without COVID-19 symptoms.&#xD;
Calculated Sensitivity/PPA between the KnowNow SARS-CoV-2 Rapid Antigen Test and RT-PCR tests stratified using cycle threshold (CT) values.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and potential risks</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Collection of Adverse Device Events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Usability Questionnaire to evaluate the use of the test with 2 saliva collection methods</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the 2 saliva collection methods by a patient questionnaire and a healthcare provider questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>KnowNow SARS-CoV-2 Rapid Antigen Test</intervention_name>
    <description>KnowNow SARS-CoV-2 Rapid Antigen Test for the detection of Covid-19 in saliva, as compared to high sensitivity reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) of nasopharyngeal swabs as the reference test method</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Male or female aged 18 years or over (or age of adult consent in some states within the&#xD;
        United States) with suspected COVID -19 infection.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female aged 18 years or over (or age of adult consent in some states within&#xD;
             the United States).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Suspected COVID-19 infection and / or presenting with at least 1 recognised symptom&#xD;
             Fever or chills. ie: Cough. Shortness of breath or difficulty breathing, fatigue,&#xD;
             muscle or body aches, headache, new loss of taste or smell, sore throat&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Be willing and able to comply with study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Be able to give written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Inability to give written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Vaccinated against SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Adults unable to undertake the requirements of the nasopharyngeal or saliva sample&#xD;
             collection for physical or psychological reasons&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects with other significant disease, condition, or at the Clinician's discretion.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alex Sheppard, BA</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Vatic Ltd.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andrea Goodyer, BSc (Hons)</last_name>
    <phone>07930277125</phone>
    <email>andrea.goodyer@clinicallyconnected.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Laurie Comeau, BSc (Hons)</last_name>
    <email>Laurie Comeau &lt;laurie@my110.io&gt;</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

