<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4189">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04501445</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20071101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04501445</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Psychological Symptoms and Families of COVID-19 Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Relieving the Burden of Psychological Symptoms Among Families of Critically Ill Patients With COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rush University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Central Michigan University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rush University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Families of patients in Intensive Care Units (ICUs) are at increased risk for developing&#xD;
      psychological symptoms that can last for months after the patient is discharged. These&#xD;
      symptoms can have significant impact on both the patient and family member's quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators have found that families of patients admitted to the Rush University&#xD;
      Medical Center ICU during to the COVID-19 pandemic were more likely to develop clinically&#xD;
      significant psychological symptoms than families of patients admitted prior to the COVID-19&#xD;
      pandemic. The investigators suspect that this finding is due in part to the hospital-wide no&#xD;
      visitation policy that altered our standard communication practices and may have prevented&#xD;
      families from being active participants in the patient's medical care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goals of this project are 1) to determine the prevalence of psychological disorders among&#xD;
      families of COVID-19 patients after ICU discharge 2) to determine the characteristics of ICU&#xD;
      care that were associated with the development of psychological disorders among family&#xD;
      members and 3) to pilot a program in which families with psychological disorders after ICU&#xD;
      discharge receive therapy from mental health professionals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Part 1- Post-ICU discharge survey and Interview Upon enrollment in this post-ICU discharge&#xD;
      follow-up study, the subject (surrogate of the ICU patient) will complete a survey dealing&#xD;
      with the patient's course since Rush discharge&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Is the patient still alive?&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. If deceased, did the patient pass away at Rush or after discharge from Rush?&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. If alive, is the patient at home?&#xD;
&#xD;
           i. If at home, for how long? Is he/she receiving home health services?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. If the patient did not pass away at Rush, did the patient spend time in a rehabilitation&#xD;
           hospital, nursing home, or long-term acute care hospital after discharge from Rush?&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Is the patient currently having any of the following symptoms (check all that apply).&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Fatigue&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Trouble Breathing&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Difficulty speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. Difficulty eating&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. Difficulty thinking or paying attention&#xD;
&#xD;
             6. Pain or discomfort&#xD;
&#xD;
             7. Anxiety&#xD;
&#xD;
             8. Depressed mood&#xD;
&#xD;
             9. Difficulty moving or walking&#xD;
&#xD;
            10. Difficulty performing activities of daily living such as dressing or bathing&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Have the subject used mental health services since the time the patient was admitted?&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. What is the subject's overall impression of mental health services (choices ranging from&#xD;
           very unhelpful to very helpful)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be asked to complete the 1) Critical Care Family Needs Inventory (CCFNI)&#xD;
      questionnaire, 2) Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS), and 3) Impact of Events Scale&#xD;
      Revised (IES-R) questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will participate in a 30-minute phone interview with a member of the study team. The&#xD;
      interviewer will review the subject's responses to the above surveys and ask follow-up&#xD;
      questions. The interviewer will ask how the subject has been coping with any psychological&#xD;
      symptoms (i.e. anxiety, depression, post-traumatic stress)&#xD;
&#xD;
      The psychologist will describe different types of interventions for people coping&#xD;
      psychological symptoms and assess the subject's interest in pursuing any of them.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part 2 - Post-ICU psychological intervention Subjects with clinically significant&#xD;
      psychologist symptoms based on either their survey or interview responses will be invited to&#xD;
      participate in 6-week trauma-focused intervention with a psychologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The program will be brief and delivered online to test the acceptability and feasible of the&#xD;
      program, and to gather a preliminary estimate of effect size. We will pilot a group-based&#xD;
      intervention (n =3-5) online over Zoom and deliver the intervention across six sessions&#xD;
      outlined below. Sessions will last 60-75 minutes depending on participant questions and&#xD;
      discussion. Experiential exercises will be drawn from Acceptance and Commitment Therapy, a&#xD;
      related contemporary cognitive behavioral treatment (Hayes, Strosahl, &amp; Wilson, 2012). Some&#xD;
      commentary of Viktor Frankl's (1985) work on meaning making will be made in group discussion.&#xD;
      Activity scheduling worksheets from Martell, Dimijian and Herman-Dunn (2013) will be used for&#xD;
      out of session homework.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We plan two phases for the study. The first phase, sessions 1-3, focus on introducing the&#xD;
      model of behavioral activation and guide the participants to identify activities that will&#xD;
      being pleasant, meaningful, or offer a sense of accomplishment and mastery. The first session&#xD;
      aims to normalize diverse responses to health-related stress and loss by introducing the&#xD;
      behavioral model of depression, and the rationale for behavioral activation. In the second&#xD;
      session participants then clarify their values, so that they can begin scheduling pleasant&#xD;
      and/or meaningful activities in the third session. These activities are tailored based on&#xD;
      each participant's individuals goals, priorities and values. The second phase, sessions 4-6,&#xD;
      aims to reinforce and sustain positive gains made via behavioral activation and pleasant&#xD;
      activity scheduling. Session 4 offers suggestions for problem-solving ways to overcome&#xD;
      unhelpful avoidance, a transdiagnostic vulnerability that sustains a number of emotional and&#xD;
      psychiatric disorders. Session 5 offers suggestions for overcoming rumination including&#xD;
      instruction in mindfulness, and attentional techniques that help participants attend to the&#xD;
      outcomes and experiences of the pleasant activities they engage in. Session 6 concludes the&#xD;
      program, and guides participants to consider plans to maintain commitment to pleasant&#xD;
      activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Session 1 Psychoeducation Introductions. Question to group: Why are we here?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Normalize the grieving process and the challenges of COVID safety guidelines&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  grief, boredom, loneliness&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  1/3 of USA adults report depression and anxiety&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Discuss the behavioral model of depression - loss of reward and meaningful events as a&#xD;
           prelude to negative moods of all types&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Behavioral Activation as a strategy to enhance reward and meaning&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Experiential: Contemplate a time in life when you felt you were doing well. How were you&#xD;
           engaging the world around you?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Homework: Start Activity tracking. Worksheets will be provided, but we allow a more&#xD;
           feasible approach of jotting down 1-2 words about activity and providing a subjective&#xD;
           mood rating.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Session 2 Value Clarification Question to the group: How do we bring purpose into our living?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Consider values as the foundation of meaning and purpose&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Discuss meaning in life and Dr. Viktor Frankl's thesis that humans are driven to find&#xD;
           meaning&#xD;
&#xD;
           o &quot;We do not ask life what the meaning of life is. Life asks us, what is the meaning of&#xD;
           your life. And life demands our answer.&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  What gives/gave meaning to your loved one's life? What would make them smile? If you&#xD;
           share values with this person, how can you honor those values you share in your own&#xD;
           commitments and activities?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Experiential: Contemplate your 80th Birthday, Retirement Speech, family remembering you&#xD;
           far in the future, etc, Homework: Values Compass. Participants will complete the values&#xD;
           compass worksheet in which they rate their perceived importance and engagement in&#xD;
           various domains of living (e.g, family life, learning, spirituality).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Session 3 Scheduling Activities Question to group: What does it mean to be committed?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Discuss a role model or mentor who demonstrated commitment to something important. How&#xD;
           did they do it? Do they share values with the patient they care(d) for? How do these&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Selecting and scheduling pleasant events. Regardless of how you feel, take action to&#xD;
           experience:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Pleasure&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Mastery&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Purpose&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Health habits: steady sleep, diet, exercise&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Experiential: Participants visualize, write or discuss steps needed to engage a plan.&#xD;
           Visualize yourself overcoming a roadblock or barrier.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Homework: Activity Schedule. Participants will schedule several pleasant/meaningful&#xD;
           events for the coming week. They will rate their mood while engaged in these activities&#xD;
           and journal about their experiences.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Session 4 Overcoming Avoidance What do we do with fear?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Getting out of the TRAP (Trigger-Response-Avoidance Pattern) to get on Track (Trigger&#xD;
           Response Adaptive Coping)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Often we hurt when something that matters is threatened. We should protect what matters&#xD;
           not the momentary feeling. Discuss &quot;fear as an arrow&quot; that can be useful for pointing to&#xD;
           ones values (e.g., we typically do not fear losing things we do not care about).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Experiential: Flipping the coins of avoidance. Participants look to how fears, and&#xD;
           frustrations relate to other prosocial and personally valued events and experiences.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Homework: Activity Schedule. This repeats the homework from the prior week.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Session 5 Working with thoughts Question to the group: How do we prevent going on autopilot&#xD;
      so we stay focused on what matters?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Staying present to notice when actions are working. Being better at tracking outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Mindfulness versus rumination&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Experiential: Mindfulness of the present. Participants are guided in a mindfulness&#xD;
           exercise to attend to sense experiences in the present moment. The goal of the exercise&#xD;
           is to introduce a skill for re-orienting to the present moment. This is particularly&#xD;
           needed for attending to and noticing the pleasant and meaningful experiences that come&#xD;
           from behavioral activation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Homework: Activity Schedule Session 6 Recap and review Question to the group: How do we&#xD;
           carry these lessons with us? How do we share these lessons with others?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The goal of this session is to review and to provide additional practice with any of the&#xD;
           prior skills discussed in previous sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Relapse prevention concepts will be discussed. Participants will be encouraged to&#xD;
           continue to maintain pleasant activity scheduling, and to consider how these activities&#xD;
           can be reinforced through social commitments, and daily reflection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Consider making a symbol. Picture, photo, card, note to self to remind oneself of a&#xD;
           valued activity. This can be displayed in a prominent place (e.g., family photo on the&#xD;
           mantle, photo of exercise on bathroom mirror, religious text on coffee table). Should&#xD;
           evoke pleasant memory, and motivation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to beginning the intervention and at the completion of the intervention, surrogates&#xD;
      will complete the 1) Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS), and 2) Impact of Events&#xD;
      Scale Revised (IES-R) questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the completion of the intervention, subjects will participate in another 30-minute phone&#xD;
      interview with a study investigator. The study investigator will review the subject's&#xD;
      responses to the above surveys and ask follow-up questions. The study investigator will ask&#xD;
      how the subject has been coping with any psychological symptoms (i.e. anxiety, depression,&#xD;
      post-traumatic stress).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All interviews will be audio recorded and transcribed. Two members study staff will review&#xD;
      the transcriptions and use thematic content analysis to determine the types of psychological&#xD;
      symptoms that are present and the reason(s) they may be present.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When analyzing subject responses, the investigators will account for the following variables&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Whether the patient is deceased or not&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Length of time since hospital discharge&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Whether the subject received mental health services on their own or not&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Whether the subject received daily written summaries in the ICU or not&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analysis The investigators expect ~100 subjects to meet inclusion criteria. The&#xD;
      investigators expect ~70-100 to complete Part 1 (Post-ICU discharge survey and Interview).&#xD;
      The investigators will determine the prevalence of psychological symptoms and opinions on ICU&#xD;
      care by reviewing survey responses and interview recordings. The investigators expect ~30 to&#xD;
      complete Part 2 (Post-ICU discharge survey and Interview). The investigators compare pre- to&#xD;
      post-intervention survey responses for each subject using a paired t-test. Part 2 will be&#xD;
      considered a pilot study. The investigators will use the results to plan a future, adequately&#xD;
      powered study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 14, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptoms of Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) initial</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured once upon enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Score on Impact of Events Scale Revised (IES-R) questionnaire. 22 questions. Score 0-88 with higher scores indicating more stress.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptoms of Anxiety and Depression initial</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured once upon enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Score on Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS). Total score 0-21 for anxiety (7 questions) and 0-21 for depression (7 questions). Higher scores indicate greater symptom burden.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Surrogate Satisfaction with the Patient's ICU Care:</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured once upon enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Score on the Critical Care Family Needs Inventory (CCFNI) questionnaire. 14 questions. Total score range 14-56 with lower scores indicating better satisfaction.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptoms of Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) final</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured before behavioral intervention (6-12 weeks after enrollment)</time_frame>
    <description>Score on Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS). Total score 0-21 for anxiety (7 questions) and 0-21 for depression (7 questions). Higher scores indicate greater symptom burden.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptoms of Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) final</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured after behavioral intervention (12-24 weeks after enrollment)</time_frame>
    <description>Score on Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS). Total score 0-21 for anxiety (7 questions) and 0-21 for depression (7 questions). Higher scores indicate greater symptom burden.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptoms of Anxiety and Depression final</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured before behavioral intervention (6-12 weeks after enrollment)</time_frame>
    <description>Score on Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS). Total score 0-21 for anxiety (7 questions) and 0-21 for depression (7 questions). Higher scores indicate greater symptom burden.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptoms of Anxiety and Depression final</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured after behavioral intervention (12-24 weeks after enrollment)</time_frame>
    <description>Score on Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS). Total score 0-21 for anxiety (7 questions) and 0-21 for depression (7 questions). Higher scores indicate greater symptom burden.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Interview initial</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured once upon enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative analysis of phone interview to determine the presence and reason(s) for psychological symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Interview final</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured after behavioral intervention (12-24 weeks after enrollment)</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative analysis of phone interview to determine the presence and reason(s) for psychological symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Family Members</condition>
  <condition>Post Intensive Care Unit Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Post Traumatic Stress Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Rounding Summary</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Surrogates who were assigned to the intervention group received a written rounding summary every day or every other day that the patient is in the ICU.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Written Summary of Rounds</intervention_name>
    <description>The summary was organized as follows for each of the most important ICU problems: 1) Description of the problem, 2) Ways the ICU team is addressing the problem i.e. consultations, diagnostic tests, and treatments. 3) An assessment of whether the problem is improving or worsening.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Rounding Summary</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient's surrogate was enrolled in &quot;ICU Rounding Summaries for Families of&#xD;
             Critically Ill Patients&quot; (NCT03969810) and the patient had COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has been discharged from the hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jared A Greenberg</last_name>
    <phone>312-942-7871</phone>
    <email>jared_greenberg@rush.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rush University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jared A Greenberg, MD</last_name>
      <phone>312-942-6744</phone>
      <email>jared_greenberg@rush.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Davidson JE, Jones C, Bienvenu OJ. Family response to critical illness: postintensive care syndrome-family. Crit Care Med. 2012 Feb;40(2):618-24. doi: 10.1097/CCM.0b013e318236ebf9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22080636</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nelson JE, Hanson LC, Keller KL, Carson SS, Cox CE, Tulsky JA, White DB, Chai EJ, Weiss SP, Danis M. The Voice of Surrogate Decision-Makers. Family Responses to Prognostic Information in Chronic Critical Illness. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2017 Oct 1;196(7):864-872. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201701-0201OC.</citation>
    <PMID>28387538</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Davidson JE, Aslakson RA, Long AC, Puntillo KA, Kross EK, Hart J, Cox CE, Wunsch H, Wickline MA, Nunnally ME, Netzer G, Kentish-Barnes N, Sprung CL, Hartog CS, Coombs M, Gerritsen RT, Hopkins RO, Franck LS, Skrobik Y, Kon AA, Scruth EA, Harvey MA, Lewis-Newby M, White DB, Swoboda SM, Cooke CR, Levy MM, Azoulay E, Curtis JR. Guidelines for Family-Centered Care in the Neonatal, Pediatric, and Adult ICU. Crit Care Med. 2017 Jan;45(1):103-128. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27984278</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 5, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

