<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4833">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04545424</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>W81XWH2010432</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04545424</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Trial of Therapeutic Hypothermia in Patients With ARDS</brief_title>
  <acronym>CHILL</acronym>
  <official_title>Cooling to Help Injured Lungs (CHILL) Phase IIB Randomized Control Trial of Therapeutic Hypothermia in Patients With ARDS</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Maryland, Baltimore</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>US Department of Veterans Affairs Cooperative Studies Program</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>KAI Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>United States Department of Defense</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Maryland, Baltimore</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome (ARDS) is a serious condition that occurs as a&#xD;
      complication of medical and surgical diseases, has a mortality of ~40%, and has no known&#xD;
      treatment other than optimization of support. Data from basic research, animal models, and&#xD;
      retrospective studies, case series, and small prospective studies suggest that therapeutic&#xD;
      hypothermia (TH) similar to that used for cardiac arrest may be lung protective in patients&#xD;
      with ARDS; however, shivering is a major complication of TH, often requiring paralysis with&#xD;
      neuromuscular blocking agents (NMBA) to control. Since the recently completed NHLBI PETAL&#xD;
      ROSE trial showed that NMBA had no effect (good or bad) in patients with moderate to severe&#xD;
      ARDS, the CHILL trial is designed to evaluate whether TH combined with NMBA is beneficial in&#xD;
      patients with ARDS. This Phase IIb randomized clinical trial is funded by the Department of&#xD;
      Defense to compare TH (core temperature 34-35°C) + NMBA for 48h vs. usual temperature&#xD;
      management in patients in 14 clinical centers with the Clinical Coordination Center and Data&#xD;
      Coordinating Center at University of Maryland Baltimore. Planned enrollment is 340 over ~3.5&#xD;
      years of the 4-year contract. Since COVID-19 is currently the most common cause of ARDS,&#xD;
      randomization will be stratified on COVID-19 status and patients with COVID-19 limited to no&#xD;
      more than one-third of budgeted enrollment per year. Primary outcome is 28-day&#xD;
      ventilator-free days. Secondary outcomes include safety, physiologic measures, mortality,&#xD;
      hospital and ICU length of stay, and serum biomarkers collected at baseline and on days 1, 2,&#xD;
      3, 4, and 7.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Despite recent advances in supportive care for patients with acute respiratory distress&#xD;
      syndrome (ARDS), mortality remains &gt;40%. Fever worsens and hypothermia mitigates animal&#xD;
      models of ALI and in small non-randomized in patients with ARDS. Since hypothermia reduces&#xD;
      oxygen utilization as long as shivering is blocked, TH may reduce injury in part by allowing&#xD;
      lower levels of assisted ventilation. TH likely exerts additional lung protective effects by&#xD;
      directly modifying temperature-dependent cellular processes in endothelium, epithelium, and&#xD;
      leukocytes. Neuromuscular blockade (NMB) is the ultimate treatment to block shivering and is&#xD;
      frequently used in patients with ARDS to facilitate ventilator management. Since the recently&#xD;
      completed NHLBI PETAL ROSE trial showed that NMB caused conferred neither benefit nor harm in&#xD;
      patients with moderate to severe ARDS, the investigators have bundled TH with NMB to reduce&#xD;
      shivering. An open-label study of 8 ARDS patients showed that studying TH + NMB in patients&#xD;
      with moderate to severe ARDS was feasible. Moreover, the patients treated with TH +NMB had&#xD;
      more 28-day ventilator-free days (VFDs), ICU-free days (ICU-FDs) and greater hospital&#xD;
      survival (75% vs. 25%; p = 0.027) than historical controls with ARDS and NMB but without TH.&#xD;
      Within the limits of historical comparisons, these results support further study of TH in&#xD;
      ARDS. COVID-19 is currently the most common cause of ARDS and will likely remain so for at&#xD;
      least the first year of enrollment. Since patients with COVID-19 may respond differently to&#xD;
      TH than those with ARDS from other causes, a randomization strategy that limits COVID-19&#xD;
      patients will be used. Our overall hypothesis is that TH is lung protective in ARDS. The&#xD;
      hypothesis to be tested is that induced hypothermia (core temperature 34°-35°C) with NMB to&#xD;
      prevent shivering is safe and beneficial in patients with moderate to severe ARDS (PaO2/FIO2&#xD;
      (P/F) ratio&lt;200) who are receiving NMB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Focus of Study: We will conduct a multicenter RCT pilot of TH+NMB for 48h vs. usual&#xD;
      temperature management in 340 patients with ARDS in 14 clinical sites.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary and secondary objectives: The primary objective is to assess the safety and efficacy&#xD;
      of 48h TH+NMB in patients with ARDS compared with a control arm receiving usual temperature&#xD;
      management. Secondary objectives include: (1) generating data to inform a decision about&#xD;
      whether to proceed with a subsequent civilian population Phase III clinical trial of TH to&#xD;
      reduce mortality in ARDS and to direct its study design; (2) analyzing biomarker and&#xD;
      physiologic data to determine the mechanism(s) through which TH+NMB might exert benefit in&#xD;
      ARDS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design: The CHILL trial is a multi-center RCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention: The study intervention is TH to core temperature 34°-35°C + NMB for 48h.&#xD;
      Patients in the TH+NMB arm will receive deep sedation, treatment with a neuromuscular&#xD;
      blocking agent, and mechanical ventilation for at least 48h. Decisions about transition to&#xD;
      unassisted breathing, extubation, and transfer from ICU will be based on criteria in the&#xD;
      CHILL study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TH+NMB: Once sedation and NMB are confirmed, TH to 34°-35°C will be initiated using surface&#xD;
      cooling. Temperature will be measured from a central probe. Once target temperature is&#xD;
      reached, TH will be maintained for 48h. Patients will then be rewarmed to 35.5°C by 0.3°C/h&#xD;
      and the cooling devices removed. Post-TH fever suppression is not part of the CHILL protocol&#xD;
      and will be performed at the discretion of the primary ICU team. TH+NMB will be aborted for&#xD;
      persistent severe bradycardia, uncontrolled bleeding, and intractable arrhythmias.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Usual temperature management: Patients will receive light sedation (RASS 0 to -1). During the&#xD;
      54h post-randomization treatment period, acetaminophen will be given for core temperature&#xD;
      &gt;38°C and surface cooling will be initiated if core temperature remains &gt;38°C within ≥45&#xD;
      minutes of receiving acetaminophen and adjusted to maintain core temperature ≤38°C. If core&#xD;
      temperature ≤36°C, patients in this arm will receive surface warming to core temperature&#xD;
      37°C. Following the 54h treatment period, temperature will be managed at the discretion of&#xD;
      the primary ICU team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Concomitant Treatment: Since prone positioning independently improves survival in ARDS,&#xD;
      starting and stopping rules for prone positioning have been protocolized.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary and Secondary Endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary endpoint: 28-day Ventilator-free days (VFDs). Decisions about ventilator weaning and&#xD;
      extubation will be made based on criteria in the CHILL protocol. The 28-day VFDs will be&#xD;
      calculated at day 28.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intermediate endpoint: The low and high core temperatures in each 2-hour period will be&#xD;
      recorded for each of the first four study days. The time required to reach the target&#xD;
      temperature and the percent of readings within the target range in the TH+NMB arm will be&#xD;
      determined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical: (a) 28-day ICU-FDs: The 28-day ICU-FDs will be calculated at day 28; (b) baseline&#xD;
      and day 1, 2, 3, 4, and 7 non-neurologic SOFA score; (c) Glasgow coma score at hospital&#xD;
      discharge; (d) 60- and 90-day survival; (e) 60- and 90-day functional status. The Montreal&#xD;
      Cognitive Assessment Tool (MOCA) will be administered at ICU and hospital discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physiologic: (a) day-3 and -7 driving pressure; (b) day-3 and day-7 oxygen saturation index&#xD;
      (OSI).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Plasma Biomarker: Day 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, and 7 plasma IL-1ß, IL-6, IL-8, IL-18, soluble-RAGE,&#xD;
      surfactant protein-D, soluble ICAM-1, MMP8, and soluble TNFRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. For the first 54h: (a) continuous cardiac monitoring for bradycardia with associated&#xD;
           hypotension requiring i.v. fluid or vasopressors; (b) every 6h blood glucose&#xD;
           measurement; (c) every 12 h potassium, magnesium and phosphate; (d) significant bleeding&#xD;
           event (requiring ≥3u packed red blood cells or surgical or interventional radiologic&#xD;
           intervention)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. For the first 7 days: (a) Ventilator-associated pneumonia (VAP); (b) other secondary&#xD;
           infections; (c) monitor for SAEs&#xD;
&#xD;
      Schedule of Clinical and Laboratory Evaluations:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Definitions:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Baseline period: 24h prior to randomization&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Comprehensive metabolic panel (CMP): includes basic electrolytes, BUN, creatinine,&#xD;
                ALT, AST, alkaline phosphatase, bilirubin, calcium, magnesium, phosphate,&#xD;
                C-reactive protein (CRP)&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. CBC: complete blood count&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. Driving Pressure = Plateau Pressure - PEEP with patient NOT making inspiratory&#xD;
                effort (on NMB or post-NMB and observed RR at set ventilator rate)&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. OSI = Mean airway pressure x 100 x FIO2/SpO2&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Clinical and Research laboratory testing: Two purple top (EDTA; 24 ml blood) tubes will&#xD;
           be collected for biomarker analysis just prior to randomization and as close to 0800 as&#xD;
           possible on study days 1, 2, 3, 4, and 7 . Clinical laboratory testing required for&#xD;
           secondary clinical outcomes at baseline and on study days 1, 2, 3, 4, and will be&#xD;
           performed as part of usual clinical care whenever possible).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Day -7 to 0 (Screening and enrollment): To facilitate randomization within the inclusion&#xD;
           window, we will consent and enroll based on partial fulfillment of randomization&#xD;
           criteria and randomize once all criteria are met. Patients between 18 and 65 years old&#xD;
           receiving mechanical ventilation for ≤7 days will be screened and those who have&#xD;
           bilateral pulmonary opacities not fully explained by pleural effusions, atelectasis, or&#xD;
           hydrostatic pulmonary edema for &lt;48h will be offered enrollment even if they do not yet&#xD;
           meet the P/F ratio criterion for randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Pregnancy testing in women of child-bearing years&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Obtain informed consent from patient or Legally Authorized Representative (LAR)&#xD;
                depending on capacity&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Complete the screening and enrollment portion of the Screening, Enrollment and&#xD;
                Randomization CRF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3. Randomization:&#xD;
&#xD;
      a. If P/F&lt;200 at enrollment, proceed with randomization, otherwise follow until P/F &lt; 200 or&#xD;
      patient exits the 48h ARDS or 7 day mechanical ventilation windows.&#xD;
&#xD;
      b. Once patient meets criterion for randomization: i. Obtain baseline plasma for research&#xD;
      testing. If &gt;8h since last CBC and CMP or &gt;24 since last CRP, send new samples to lab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ii. Obtain treatment assignment will be made by the automated, web-based randomization&#xD;
      service provided by Cooperative Studies Program Coordinating Center (CSPCC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      iii. If patient does not have a central temperature probe, place esophageal probe.&#xD;
&#xD;
      iv. For TH+NMB arm, confirm adequate sedation (RASS -4) and NMB (Train of four ≤2 twitch) and&#xD;
      initiate TH protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      v. Complete the randomization section of the Screening, Enrollment, and Randomization CRF vi.&#xD;
      Complete Baseline CRF&#xD;
&#xD;
      4.Day 1-4:&#xD;
&#xD;
      a. Fill out Daily CRFs b. Collect plasma for research testing. c. Measure Driving Pressure&#xD;
      and OSI d. Make sure CBC and CMP sent every 12h e. Rewarming starts 48h after initially&#xD;
      reaching target temperature (34°-35°C) on day 3 f. Complete Unassisted Breathing Checklist&#xD;
      form if applicable g. Assess for adverse events&#xD;
&#xD;
      5. Days 5-6:&#xD;
&#xD;
      a. Follow for ventilator status, ICU status, survival, SAEs b. Follow CRP daily c. Complete&#xD;
      Unassisted Breathing Checklist form if applicable d. Assess for adverse events&#xD;
&#xD;
      6. Day 7:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Fill out Day 7 CRF&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Collect plasma for research testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Measure Driving Pressure and OSI&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Make sure CBC, CMP, and CRP sent&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Complete Unassisted Breathing Checklist form if applicable&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Assess for adverse events&#xD;
&#xD;
           7. Day 8-27:&#xD;
&#xD;
      a. Follow for ventilator status, ICU status, survival, SAEs b. Complete Unassisted Breathing&#xD;
      Checklist form if applicable&#xD;
&#xD;
      8. Day 28:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Complete Day 28 CRF&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Calculate 28 day VFDs and ICU-FDs&#xD;
&#xD;
           9. When patient is discharged from the ICU, complete ICU discharge CRF&#xD;
&#xD;
           10. When patient is discharged from the hospital, complete Hospital discharge CRF.&#xD;
&#xD;
           11. Day 60 and 90: Follow up about patient status. Complete phone follow-up CRF.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Study population: Adult patients with moderate to severe ARDS based on Berlin criteria&#xD;
           (P/F &lt; 200 while on PEEP ≥8 cm H2O) &lt;48h in duration.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Data Analysis: This is a pilot trial to determine whether patients with&#xD;
           COVID-19-associated patients with ARDS should be included in a multicenter trial of&#xD;
           TH+NMB in patients with ARDS from all causes. The data from this pilot will not be&#xD;
           merged with data from the planned multicenter trial. The primary analysis of this pilot&#xD;
           study will be to determine the effectiveness of the TH+NMB protocol in maintaining&#xD;
           targeted temperature and to determine whether there are any safety issues with the&#xD;
           TH+NMB protocol in this patient population.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Data Management: Data for this pilot RCT will be recorded on paper CRFs. Completion of&#xD;
           all fields will be checked in real-time. The forms have been designed to be compatible&#xD;
           with the electronic versions developed for the multicenter trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Randomization Plan: Patients with moderate to severe ARDS for ≤48h based on the Berlin&#xD;
           criteria 1 will be randomized. Because prone positioning improves survival in ARDS 37&#xD;
           and patients with COVID-19 may respond differently to TH than other ARDS patients,&#xD;
           randomization will be stratified by proning status, COVID-19 status, and clinical site&#xD;
           and patients will be randomized within each stratum using a 1:1 assignment ratio in&#xD;
           small blocks of randomly varying size. Patients without ABG data may be randomized based&#xD;
           on a P/F ratio imputed from SpO2 data as described by Brown et al. 135. To facilitate&#xD;
           randomization within the inclusion window, patients who meet all Berlin criteria but&#xD;
           have not yet met the P/F &lt;200 criterion will be consented, enrolled, and followed until&#xD;
           the P/F ratio &lt; 200 criterion is documented or they exit the 48 hr ARDS window. Just&#xD;
           prior to randomization, a research blood sample will be drawn, an esophageal temperature&#xD;
           probe will be placed if no other central temperature probe is present, and patients will&#xD;
           be randomized to TH+NMB or usual temperature management. The web-based randomization&#xD;
           system provided by CSPCC.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Subject Participation Duration: The duration of intervention, TH + NMB vs. usual&#xD;
           temperature management, is 48h, followed by rewarming for 3-6h in the TH group. NMB will&#xD;
           be discontinued and sedation reduced when subjects are rewarmed to core temperature&#xD;
           ≥35.5°C. In the control group fever and hypothermia during continuous renal replacement&#xD;
           therapy (CRRT) will be treated by protocol for 54h post-randomization. Physiologic and&#xD;
           clinical parameters will be collected through study day 7. In hospital follow-up up to&#xD;
           90 days will include determination of 28-day VFDs and ICU-FDs, and day of hospital&#xD;
           discharge. When the patient regains competence, consent for continued participation will&#xD;
           be obtained&#xD;
&#xD;
           Study Duration: Completion of enrollment is anticipated by December 1, 2023 and study&#xD;
           completion by May 31, 2024.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized (1:1) control (non-blinded) multicenter trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Since it will be obvious to observers of the subjects whether they are in the treatment (TH+NMB) or control groups, the study is not masked but all treatments that determine outcome are protocolized.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>28-day ventilator-free days (VFDs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Calculated at study day 28 or death (whichever occurs first)</time_frame>
    <description>Total number of days alive and not on a ventilator in the first 28 days after enrollment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>28-day ICU-free days</measure>
    <time_frame>Calculated at study day 28 or death (whichever occurs first)</time_frame>
    <description>Total number of days alive and not admitted to the ICU in the first 28 days after</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>calculated at 28, 60, and 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>28-day, 60-day, and 90-day mortality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>non neurologic Sequential Organ Failure (SOFA) scores</measure>
    <time_frame>At enrollment and study days 1, 2, 3, 4, 7, and 28</time_frame>
    <description>SOFA score excluding neurologic component - based on PaO2/FiO2 (0-4), BP and pressor requirement (0-4), bilirubin level (0-4), platelet count (0-4), and creatinine (0-14) with total composite score 0-20</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oxygen saturation (SpO2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at enrollment, every 2 hours on enrollment day, then once on day 2, 3, 4, 7 and 28</time_frame>
    <description>Pulse ox reading</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plateau airway pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at randomization and daily as close to 0800 as possible on study days 1 2, 3, 4, and 7 or until extubation whichever occurs first</time_frame>
    <description>On ventilator-imitated breath; measured at enrollment, every 4 hours on enrollment day, then Measured at randomization and daily on study days 1, 2, 3, 4, and 7 or until extubation whichever occurs firstinitiated breath</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean airway pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at randomization and daily as close to 0800 as possible on study days 1 2, 3, 4, and 7 or until extubation whichever occurs first</time_frame>
    <description>Measured from ventilator during machine initiated breath</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Airway driving pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at randomization and daily as close to 0800 as possible on study days 1 2, 3, 4, and 7 or until extubation whichever occurs first</time_frame>
    <description>Plateau pressure - PEEP (machine initiated breath)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oxygen saturation index</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at randomization and daily as close to 0800 as possible on study days 1 2, 3, 4, and 7 or until extubation whichever occurs first</time_frame>
    <description>Mean airway pressure x 100 x FiO2/SpO2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Core temperature</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured continuously and recorded at randomization and then every 2 hours through study day 4</time_frame>
    <description>Measured continuously from iv catheter, urinary catheter, or esophageal probe.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Urine output</measure>
    <time_frame>Daily on study day 1, 2, 3, 4, and 7</time_frame>
    <description>24 hour urine volume</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>comprehensive metabolic panel blood test (includes sodium, potassium, chloride, bicarb, BUN, creatinine, glucose, albumin, total protein, AST, SLT, alkaline phosphatase, and bilirubin)</measure>
    <time_frame>At randomization and each morning on study days 1, 2, 3, 4, and 7</time_frame>
    <description>7 ml of blood collected in serum separator tubes; assay preformed in clinical lab</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete blood count with differential count and platelet count</measure>
    <time_frame>At randomization and each morning on study days 1, 2, 3, 4, and 7</time_frame>
    <description>7 ml of blood collected in purple top tube; assay preformed in clinical lab</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma biomarkers measured by immunoassay and including IL-1ß, IL-6, IL-8, IL-18, surfactant protein D, soluble ICAM-1, MMP8, and soluble TNF receptor-I)</measure>
    <time_frame>Collected at randomization and as close to 0800 as possible on study days 1 2, 3, 4, and 7 or until extubation whichever occurs first</time_frame>
    <description>12 ml blood draw in two green top tubes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum electrolytes</measure>
    <time_frame>Performed each evening on study days 1, 2, and 3</time_frame>
    <description>performed in clinical lab</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fingerstick blood glucose level</measure>
    <time_frame>every 6 hour from randomization through study day 3</time_frame>
    <description>POC blood glucose testing performed at bedside</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">340</enrollment>
  <condition>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Adult</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hypothermia + Neuromuscular blockade</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Deep sedation and Neuromuscular blockade (NMB) and surface temperature management to maintain core temperature between 34 and 35°C for 48h, then rewarm to 36°C at 0.33°C per h and NMB discontinued when core temp reaches 35.5°C.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Temperature Management</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Acetaminophen and surface temperature management to maintain core temperature between 37°C and 38°C. Rewarming to 37°C for hypothermia ≤36°C with continuous renal replacement therapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hypothermia</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will be cooled using either cooling blankets or gel-pad systems to maintain core temperature 34-35°C.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hypothermia + Neuromuscular blockade</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>targeted temperature management</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Neuromuscular Blocking Agents</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects in the TH + NMB arm will be deeply sedated using agents at the discretion of the primary ICU team, then start continuous iv infusion of either cisatracurium, atracurium, or vecuronium titrated to 2 twitches on train of four monitoring and further titrated to ablate visible shivering.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hypothermia + Neuromuscular blockade</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Paralytics</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard of care</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects who are hypothermic (≤36°C) during CRRT will receive surface warming to restore core temperature to 37°C. Patients with core temperature &gt;38°C will receive 650 mg acetaminophen and, if temperature remains &gt;38°C, surface cooling will be initiated to return core temperature to 37-38°C.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Temperature Management</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Usual temperature managementl</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. endotracheal tube or tracheostomy in place and mechanically ventilated for ≤7 days;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. admitted to a participating ICU&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. radiologic evidence of bilateral pulmonary infiltrates not fully explained by pleural&#xD;
             effusions, atelectasis, or hydrostatic pulmonary edema&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. P/F ratio &lt;200 with PEEP ≥8 cm H2O; If ABG values are not available, the P/F ratio may&#xD;
             be inferred from SpO2 values based on Table 3 from Brown et al as long as following&#xD;
             conditions are met:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. SpO2 values are 80-96%&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. SpO2 is measured ≥10 min after any change in FIO2&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. PEEP is ≥ 8 cm H2O&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. the pulse oximeter waveform tracing is adequate&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. the qualifying inferred P/F ratio is confirmed 1-6h after initial determination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. access to an LAR to provide consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Criteria 3 AND 4 must be met within 48h of enrollment and randomization, not be fully&#xD;
             explained by hydrostatic pulmonary edema, and must have occurred within 7 days onset&#xD;
             of a condition associated with ARDS.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients may be enrolled and decision about randomization delayed if all criteria&#xD;
                  other than P/F ratio &lt; 200 are met and then randomized if and when the P/F ratio&#xD;
                  &lt; 200 (as long as this occurs within 48h of randomization).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Missed ARDS window (&gt;48hrs)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Missed NMB window: (&gt;12 hrs)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Missed mechanical ventilation window (&gt;7 days)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Refractory hypotension (&gt; 0.2 mcg/kg/min of norepinephrine or equivalent dose for 6 h&#xD;
             or longer)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Core temperature &lt;35.5°C while not receiving CRRT&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patient is unable to give consent and no Legally authorized representative is&#xD;
             available&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Significant, active bleeding (&gt;3u blood products and/or surgical/IR intervention)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Platelets &lt;10K/mm3 (uncorrected)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Active hematologic malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Skin process that precludes cooling device&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Moribund, not likely to survive 72h&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Pre-morbid condition makes it unlikely that patient will survive 28 days&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Do Not Resuscitate status&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Not likely to remain intubated for ≥48h&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Physician of record unwilling to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Severe underlying lung disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. On home O2&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. On BIPAP (except for OSA)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Prior lung transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. BMI &gt;50 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Known NYHA class IV heart disease&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Acute Coronary Syndrome past 30 days (MI, unstable angina)&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Cardiac arrest within 30 days of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Burns over &gt;20% of the body surface&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Severe chronic liver disease (Child-Pugh score 12-15)&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Previously randomized in CHILL study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jeffrey D Hasday, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Maryland, Baltimore</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Carl B Shanholtz, MD</last_name>
    <phone>410-328-8141</phone>
    <email>cshanhol@som.umaryland.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Michael L Terrin, MD/MPH</last_name>
    <phone>410-706-6139</phone>
    <email>mterrin@som.umaryland.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Christiana Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Newark</city>
        <state>Delaware</state>
        <zip>19718</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Matthew Barrett, DO</last_name>
      <phone>302-668-5823</phone>
      <email>MBarrett@Christianacare.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Luis Cardenas, DO/PhD</last_name>
      <email>LCardenas@ChristianaCare.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Matthew Barrett, DO</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Luis Cardenas, DO/PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emory University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jonathan Sevransky, MD</last_name>
      <email>jonathan.sevransky@emoryhealthcare.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jonathan Sevransky, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rush University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jared Greenberg, MD</last_name>
      <email>Jared_Greenberg@rush.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Mark Yoder, MD</last_name>
      <email>Mark_A_Yoder@rush.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jared Greenberg, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mark Yoder, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Illinois at Chicago</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sunit Singla, MD</last_name>
      <email>ssingl6@uic.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sunit singla, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Chicago</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60637</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Bhakti Patel, MD</last_name>
      <email>bpatel@medicine.bsd.uchicago.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bhakti Patel, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Loyola University Chicago</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60660</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sean Forsythe, MD</last_name>
      <email>SFORSY1@lumc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sean Forsythe, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Maryland Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Samuel A Tisherman, MD</last_name>
      <phone>410-328-9781</phone>
      <email>STisherman@som.umaryland.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Samuel A Tisherman, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Robert S Stephens, MD</last_name>
      <email>rsteph13@jhmi.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Robert S Stephens, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic Rochester Minnesota</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55902</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lioudmila Karnatovskaia, MD</last_name>
      <email>Karnatovskaia.Lioudmila@mayo.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lioudmilla Karnatovskaia, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Richard Oekler, MD/PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cleveland Clinc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44195</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rachel Scheraga, MD</last_name>
      <phone>216-296-4921</phone>
      <email>scherar@ccf.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Abhijit Duggal, MD/MSc/MPH</last_name>
      <email>duggala2@ccf.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rachel Scheraga, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Abhijit Duggal, MD/MSc/MPH</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pennsylavia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>John Reilly, MD</last_name>
      <email>John.Reilly@pennmedicine.upenn.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>John Reillt, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Thomas Jefferson University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19107</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michael Baram, MD</last_name>
      <email>Michael.Baram@jefferson.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael Baram, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Temple University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19140</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gerard Criner, MD</last_name>
      <phone>215-510-6570</phone>
      <email>Gerard.Criner@tuhs.temple.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Nathaniel Marchetti, DO</last_name>
      <email>Nathaniel.Marchetti@tuhs.temple.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gerarad Criner, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nathaniel Marchetti, DO</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brooke Army Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Sam Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78234</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Whittney Warren, DO</last_name>
      <email>whittney.a.warren.mil@mail.mil</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Robert Walter, MD</last_name>
      <email>robert.j.walter26.mil@mail.mil</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Whittney Warren, DO</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Robert Walter, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome Network, Brower RG, Matthay MA, Morris A, Schoenfeld D, Thompson BT, Wheeler A. Ventilation with lower tidal volumes as compared with traditional tidal volumes for acute lung injury and the acute respiratory distress syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2000 May 4;342(18):1301-8.</citation>
    <PMID>10793162</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Papazian L, Forel JM, Gacouin A, Penot-Ragon C, Perrin G, Loundou A, Jaber S, Arnal JM, Perez D, Seghboyan JM, Constantin JM, Courant P, Lefrant JY, Guérin C, Prat G, Morange S, Roch A; ACURASYS Study Investigators. Neuromuscular blockers in early acute respiratory distress syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2010 Sep 16;363(12):1107-16. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1005372.</citation>
    <PMID>20843245</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute PETAL Clinical Trials Network, Moss M, Huang DT, Brower RG, Ferguson ND, Ginde AA, Gong MN, Grissom CK, Gundel S, Hayden D, Hite RD, Hou PC, Hough CL, Iwashyna TJ, Khan A, Liu KD, Talmor D, Thompson BT, Ulysse CA, Yealy DM, Angus DC. Early Neuromuscular Blockade in the Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2019 May 23;380(21):1997-2008. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1901686. Epub 2019 May 19.</citation>
    <PMID>31112383</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Guérin C, Reignier J, Richard JC, Beuret P, Gacouin A, Boulain T, Mercier E, Badet M, Mercat A, Baudin O, Clavel M, Chatellier D, Jaber S, Rosselli S, Mancebo J, Sirodot M, Hilbert G, Bengler C, Richecoeur J, Gainnier M, Bayle F, Bourdin G, Leray V, Girard R, Baboi L, Ayzac L; PROSEVA Study Group. Prone positioning in severe acute respiratory distress syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2013 Jun 6;368(23):2159-68. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1214103. Epub 2013 May 20.</citation>
    <PMID>23688302</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Villar J, Blanco J, Kacmarek RM. Current incidence and outcome of the acute respiratory distress syndrome. Curr Opin Crit Care. 2016 Feb;22(1):1-6. doi: 10.1097/MCC.0000000000000266. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26645551</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hasday JD, Garrison A, Singh IS, Standiford T, Ellis GS, Rao S, He JR, Rice P, Frank M, Goldblum SE, Viscardi RM. Febrile-range hyperthermia augments pulmonary neutrophil recruitment and amplifies pulmonary oxygen toxicity. Am J Pathol. 2003 Jun;162(6):2005-17.</citation>
    <PMID>12759256</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lipke AB, Matute-Bello G, Herrero R, Kurahashi K, Wong VA, Mongovin SM, Martin TR. Febrile-range hyperthermia augments lipopolysaccharide-induced lung injury by a mechanism of enhanced alveolar epithelial apoptosis. J Immunol. 2010 Apr 1;184(7):3801-13. doi: 10.4049/jimmunol.0903191. Epub 2010 Mar 3.</citation>
    <PMID>20200273</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lipke AB, Matute-Bello G, Herrero R, Wong VA, Mongovin SM, Martin TR. Death receptors mediate the adverse effects of febrile-range hyperthermia on the outcome of lipopolysaccharide-induced lung injury. Am J Physiol Lung Cell Mol Physiol. 2011 Jul;301(1):L60-70. doi: 10.1152/ajplung.00314.2010. Epub 2011 Apr 22.</citation>
    <PMID>21515659</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rice P, Martin E, He JR, Frank M, DeTolla L, Hester L, O'Neill T, Manka C, Benjamin I, Nagarsekar A, Singh I, Hasday JD. Febrile-range hyperthermia augments neutrophil accumulation and enhances lung injury in experimental gram-negative bacterial pneumonia. J Immunol. 2005 Mar 15;174(6):3676-85.</citation>
    <PMID>15749906</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shah NG, Tulapurkar ME, Damarla M, Singh IS, Goldblum SE, Shapiro P, Hasday JD. Febrile-range hyperthermia augments reversible TNF-α-induced hyperpermeability in human microvascular lung endothelial cells. Int J Hyperthermia. 2012;28(7):627-35. doi: 10.3109/02656736.2012.690547. Epub 2012 Jul 26.</citation>
    <PMID>22834633</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tulapurkar ME, Almutairy EA, Shah NG, He JR, Puche AC, Shapiro P, Singh IS, Hasday JD. Febrile-range hyperthermia modifies endothelial and neutrophilic functions to promote extravasation. Am J Respir Cell Mol Biol. 2012 Jun;46(6):807-14. doi: 10.1165/rcmb.2011-0378OC. Epub 2012 Jan 26.</citation>
    <PMID>22281986</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ball MK, Hillman NH, Kallapur SG, Polglase GR, Jobe AH, Pillow JJ. Body temperature effects on lung injury in ventilated preterm lambs. Resuscitation. 2010 Jun;81(6):749-54. doi: 10.1016/j.resuscitation.2009.12.007. Epub 2010 Mar 17.</citation>
    <PMID>20299144</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Beurskens CJ, Aslami H, Kuipers MT, Horn J, Vroom MB, van Kuilenburg AB, Roelofs JJ, Schultz MJ, Juffermans NP. Induced hypothermia is protective in a rat model of pneumococcal pneumonia associated with increased adenosine triphosphate availability and turnover*. Crit Care Med. 2012 Mar;40(3):919-26. doi: 10.1097/CCM.0b013e3182373174.</citation>
    <PMID>22036856</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chang H, Huang KL, Li MH, Hsu CW, Tsai SH, Chu SJ. Manipulations of core temperatures in ischemia-reperfusion lung injury in rabbits. Pulm Pharmacol Ther. 2008;21(2):285-91. Epub 2007 Jun 14.</citation>
    <PMID>17629529</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chin JY, Koh Y, Kim MJ, Kim HS, Kim WS, Kim DS, Kim WD, Lim CM. The effects of hypothermia on endotoxin-primed lung. Anesth Analg. 2007 May;104(5):1171-8, tables of contents.</citation>
    <PMID>17456669</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cruces P, Erranz B, Donoso A, Carvajal C, Salomón T, Torres MF, Díaz F. Mild hypothermia increases pulmonary anti-inflammatory response during protective mechanical ventilation in a piglet model of acute lung injury. Paediatr Anaesth. 2013 Nov;23(11):1069-77. doi: 10.1111/pan.12209. Epub 2013 Jun 3.</citation>
    <PMID>23731357</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Huang PS, Tang GJ, Chen CH, Kou YR. Whole-body moderate hypothermia confers protection from wood smoke-induced acute lung injury in rats: the therapeutic window. Crit Care Med. 2006 Apr;34(4):1160-7.</citation>
    <PMID>16484924</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jo YH, Kim K, Rhee JE, Suh GJ, Kwon WY, Na SH, Alam HB. Therapeutic hypothermia attenuates acute lung injury in paraquat intoxication in rats. Resuscitation. 2011 Apr;82(4):487-91. doi: 10.1016/j.resuscitation.2010.11.028. Epub 2011 Jan 14.</citation>
    <PMID>21236547</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kim K, Kim W, Rhee JE, Jo YH, Lee JH, Kim KS, Kwon WY, Suh GJ, Lee CC, Singer AJ. Induced hypothermia attenuates the acute lung injury in hemorrhagic shock. J Trauma. 2010 Feb;68(2):373-81. doi: 10.1097/TA.0b013e3181a73eea.</citation>
    <PMID>19996791</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kira S, Daa T, Kashima K, Mori M, Noguchi T, Yokoyama S. Mild hypothermia reduces expression of intercellular adhesion molecule-1 (ICAM-1) and the accumulation of neutrophils after acid-induced lung injury in the rat. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2005 Mar;49(3):351-9.</citation>
    <PMID>15752401</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lim CM, Hong SB, Koh Y, Lee SD, Kim WS, Kim DS, Kim WD. Hypothermia attenuates vascular manifestations of ventilator-induced lung injury in rats. Lung. 2003;181(1):23-34.</citation>
    <PMID>12879337</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lim CM, Kim MS, Ahn JJ, Kim MJ, Kwon Y, Lee I, Koh Y, Kim DS, Kim WD. Hypothermia protects against endotoxin-induced acute lung injury in rats. Intensive Care Med. 2003 Mar;29(3):453-9. Epub 2002 Nov 22.</citation>
    <PMID>12624664</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Peng CK, Huang KL, Wu CP, Li MH, Lin HI, Hsu CW, Tsai SH, Chu SJ. The role of mild hypothermia in air embolism-induced acute lung injury. Anesth Analg. 2010 May 1;110(5):1336-42. doi: 10.1213/ANE.0b013e3181d27e90.</citation>
    <PMID>20418297</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tang ZH, Hu JT, Lu ZC, Ji XF, Chen XF, Jiang LY, Zhang C, Jiang JS, Pang YP, Li CQ. Effect of mild hypothermia on the expression of toll-like receptor 2 in lung tissues with experimental acute lung injury. Heart Lung Circ. 2014 Dec;23(12):1202-7. doi: 10.1016/j.hlc.2014.05.016. Epub 2014 Jun 24.</citation>
    <PMID>25224460</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Villar J, Slutsky AS. Effects of induced hypothermia in patients with septic adult respiratory distress syndrome. Resuscitation. 1993 Oct;26(2):183-92.</citation>
    <PMID>8290813</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Karnatovskaia LV, Festic E, Freeman WD, Lee AS. Effect of therapeutic hypothermia on gas exchange and respiratory mechanics: a retrospective cohort study. Ther Hypothermia Temp Manag. 2014 Jun;4(2):88-95. doi: 10.1089/ther.2014.0004. Epub 2014 May 19.</citation>
    <PMID>24840620</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Manthous CA, Hall JB, Olson D, Singh M, Chatila W, Pohlman A, Kushner R, Schmidt GA, Wood LD. Effect of cooling on oxygen consumption in febrile critically ill patients. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 1995 Jan;151(1):10-4.</citation>
    <PMID>7812538</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gattinoni L, Tonetti T, Cressoni M, Cadringher P, Herrmann P, Moerer O, Protti A, Gotti M, Chiurazzi C, Carlesso E, Chiumello D, Quintel M. Ventilator-related causes of lung injury: the mechanical power. Intensive Care Med. 2016 Oct;42(10):1567-1575. doi: 10.1007/s00134-016-4505-2. Epub 2016 Sep 12.</citation>
    <PMID>27620287</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nagarsekar A, Tulapurkar ME, Singh IS, Atamas SP, Shah NG, Hasday JD. Hyperthermia promotes and prevents respiratory epithelial apoptosis through distinct mechanisms. Am J Respir Cell Mol Biol. 2012 Dec;47(6):824-33. doi: 10.1165/rcmb.2012-0105OC. Epub 2012 Sep 6.</citation>
    <PMID>22962066</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Potla R, Singh IS, Atamas SP, Hasday JD. Shifts in temperature within the physiologic range modify strand-specific expression of select human microRNAs. RNA. 2015 Jul;21(7):1261-73. doi: 10.1261/rna.049122.114. Epub 2015 May 27.</citation>
    <PMID>26018549</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shah NG, Cowan MJ, Pickering E, Sareh H, Afshar M, Fox D, Marron J, Davis J, Herold K, Shanholtz CB, Hasday JD. Nonpharmacologic approach to minimizing shivering during surface cooling: a proof of principle study. J Crit Care. 2012 Dec;27(6):746.e1-8. doi: 10.1016/j.jcrc.2012.04.016. Epub 2012 Jul 2.</citation>
    <PMID>22762936</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Beitler JR, Sands SA, Loring SH, Owens RL, Malhotra A, Spragg RG, Matthay MA, Thompson BT, Talmor D. Quantifying unintended exposure to high tidal volumes from breath stacking dyssynchrony in ARDS: the BREATHE criteria. Intensive Care Med. 2016 Sep;42(9):1427-36. doi: 10.1007/s00134-016-4423-3. Epub 2016 Jun 24.</citation>
    <PMID>27342819</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Slack DF, Corwin DS, Shah NG, Shanholtz CB, Verceles AC, Netzer G, Jones KM, Brown CH, Terrin ML, Hasday JD. Pilot Feasibility Study of Therapeutic Hypothermia for Moderate to Severe Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome. Crit Care Med. 2017 Jul;45(7):1152-1159. doi: 10.1097/CCM.0000000000002338.</citation>
    <PMID>28406814</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Calfee CS, Ware LB, Eisner MD, Parsons PE, Thompson BT, Wickersham N, Matthay MA; NHLBI ARDS Network. Plasma receptor for advanced glycation end products and clinical outcomes in acute lung injury. Thorax. 2008 Dec;63(12):1083-9. doi: 10.1136/thx.2008.095588. Epub 2008 Jun 19.</citation>
    <PMID>18566109</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Greene KE, Wright JR, Steinberg KP, Ruzinski JT, Caldwell E, Wong WB, Hull W, Whitsett JA, Akino T, Kuroki Y, Nagae H, Hudson LD, Martin TR. Serial changes in surfactant-associated proteins in lung and serum before and after onset of ARDS. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 1999 Dec;160(6):1843-50.</citation>
    <PMID>10588595</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Calfee CS, Eisner MD, Parsons PE, Thompson BT, Conner ER Jr, Matthay MA, Ware LB; NHLBI Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome Clinical Trials Network. Soluble intercellular adhesion molecule-1 and clinical outcomes in patients with acute lung injury. Intensive Care Med. 2009 Feb;35(2):248-57. doi: 10.1007/s00134-008-1235-0. Epub 2008 Aug 1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18670758</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kimura D, Saravia J, Rovnaghi CR, Meduri GU, Schwingshackl A, Cormier SA, Anand KJ. Plasma Biomarker Analysis in Pediatric ARDS: Generating Future Framework from a Pilot Randomized Control Trial of Methylprednisolone: A Framework for Identifying Plasma Biomarkers Related to Clinical Outcomes in Pediatric ARDS. Front Pediatr. 2016 Mar 31;4:31. doi: 10.3389/fped.2016.00031. eCollection 2016.</citation>
    <PMID>27066464</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ferguson ND, Fan E, Camporota L, Antonelli M, Anzueto A, Beale R, Brochard L, Brower R, Esteban A, Gattinoni L, Rhodes A, Slutsky AS, Vincent JL, Rubenfeld GD, Thompson BT, Ranieri VM. The Berlin definition of ARDS: an expanded rationale, justification, and supplementary material. Intensive Care Med. 2012 Oct;38(10):1573-82. Epub 2012 Aug 25. Erratum in: Intensive Care Med. 2012 Oct;38(10):1731-2.</citation>
    <PMID>22926653</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brown SM, Grissom CK, Moss M, Rice TW, Schoenfeld D, Hou PC, Thompson BT, Brower RG; NIH/NHLBI PETAL Network Collaborators. Nonlinear Imputation of Pao2/Fio2 From Spo2/Fio2 Among Patients With Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome. Chest. 2016 Aug;150(2):307-13. doi: 10.1016/j.chest.2016.01.003. Epub 2016 Jan 19.</citation>
    <PMID>26836924</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Deredge D, Wintrode PL, Tulapurkar ME, Nagarsekar A, Zhang Y, Weber DJ, Shapiro P, Hasday JD. A temperature-dependent conformational shift in p38α MAPK substrate-binding region associated with changes in substrate phosphorylation profile. J Biol Chem. 2019 Aug 23;294(34):12624-12637. doi: 10.1074/jbc.RA119.007525. Epub 2019 Jun 18.</citation>
    <PMID>31213525</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 3, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Maryland, Baltimore</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jeffrey Hasday</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>ards</keyword>
  <keyword>targeted temperature management</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Adult</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acute Lung Injury</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypothermia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neuromuscular Blocking Agents</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The CHILL trial will be registered with clinicaltrials.gov. Within the first year of the study, Dr. Hasday and colleagues will publish the rationale for and description of the CHILL trial in a peer-reviewed journal. At the completion of the study, Dr. Hasday and colleagues will present the results of the long-term outcomes at national meetings and publish them in peer-reviewed journals. Within two years of the end of the award period or one year of the publication of the main trial data (whichever occurs first, Drs. Hasday and colleagues will make available for sharing with qualified investigators and consumer advocacy communities the de-identified study data. Plasma samples will be stored for at least 2 years after study closure and be made available to qualified investigators based on the rationale of their intended use. Requests for the limited plasma samples will be prioritized by the CHILL Executive Committee.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan will be included in a peer-reviewed article about the CHILL trial.&#xD;
The informed consent form will be available from the CHILL trial website currently under construction and planned to be operational by August, 2020&#xD;
The Clinical Study Report will be published within the first year of the CHILL trial.&#xD;
De-identified data will be made available within two years of the end of the award period or one year of the publication of the main trial data (whichever occurs first,</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>The consent form will be publicly available through the public accessible CHILL website portal.&#xD;
The Study Protocol, Statistical Analysis Plan, and Clinical study Report will be publicly available in a peer-review publication and will also be available on the CHILL website.&#xD;
-Access to de-identified data will be evaluated by the CHILL Executive Committee and made available to qualified investigators and consumer advocacy communities.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>July 30, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/24/NCT04545424/SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>July 30, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/24/NCT04545424/ICF_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>July 24, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/24/NCT04545424/Prot_002.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

