<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3391">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04646642</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FWH20200203E</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04646642</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Psychological Health, Coping Strategies and Preferences of Military COVID-19 Deployers</brief_title>
  <official_title>Psychological Health, Coping Strategies and Preferences of David Grant USAF Medical Center COVID-19 Deployers: A Critical Needs Assessment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>David Grant U.S. Air Force Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>David Grant U.S. Air Force Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The proposed research study aims to better understand COVID deployer needs. The study,&#xD;
      informally referred to as Project COPE, asks David Grant U.S. Air Force Medical Center (DGMC)&#xD;
      members who deployed in support of COVID-19 operations to complete a needs assessment&#xD;
      questionnaire. The purpose of this study is to understand the stressful experiences of our&#xD;
      COVID Theater Hospital (CTH) deployers, the typical coping strategies used and their&#xD;
      recommended preferences for support so that we can provide the best evidence-based resources&#xD;
      for post-deployment and to aid future CTH deployers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This prospective cohort needs assessment includes a psychological screening, potential&#xD;
      sources of stressor inventory, and a coping strategies and resource preference needs&#xD;
      assessment of eligible participants (n=160) upon return from COVID Theater Hospital (CTH)&#xD;
      deployment (est. Oct 2020). Study participation will occur through collection of anonymous&#xD;
      self-report measures using paper pencil which will be completed and returned to DGMC locked&#xD;
      drop-boxes (strategically placed in convenient high traffic areas).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: This study focuses on exploring our David Grant USAF Medical deployer&#xD;
      psychological status and the coping skills utilized during deployment as well as a needs&#xD;
      assessment of preferred coping resources.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
      AIM 1: Describe the post-deployment state of psychological health for COVID-19 Theater&#xD;
      Hospital (CTH) deployers AIM 2: Identify the frequencies/percentages and severities of&#xD;
      COVID-19-related stressors experienced by medics during deployment AIM 3: Identify coping and&#xD;
      cognition regulating strategies used by deployers in response to COVID-19 deployment&#xD;
      stressors AIM 4: Identify deployer coping resource preferences for future deployment support&#xD;
      packages&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: This prospective descriptive cohort study includes a psychological screening (PHQ-2,&#xD;
      GAD-2, PSQI-A), self-identified sources of stress, and a coping strategies (Brief COPE) and&#xD;
      resource preference needs assessment (Migliore's Coping Strategy and Resource Inventory) of&#xD;
      eligible participants (n=160) upon return from COVID Theater Hospital (CTH) deployment (est.&#xD;
      Oct 2020). Study participation will occur through a single collection of anonymous&#xD;
      self-report measures using paper pencil which will be completed and returned to locked&#xD;
      drop-boxes strategically placed on four inpatient/outpatient areas.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Results: Findings will inform the development of a DGMC COVID-19 healthcare worker&#xD;
      psychological coping and well-being toolkit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Health Questionnaire-2 (PHQ-2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Dec 2020 - Feb 2021</time_frame>
    <description>2-item screening tool for depression that uses first 2 items from PHQ-9. Total scores exceeding 2 suggest a positive depression screening. This tool provides a brief, practical, valid, and reliable screening instrument.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Generalized Anxiety Disorder-2 (GAD-2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Dec 2020 - Feb 2021</time_frame>
    <description>2-item screening tool for Generalized Anxiety Disorder. A total score of 3 points or greater identifies a positive screen and warrants further diagnostic evaluation with GAD-7 for Generalized Anxiety Disorder criteria. This tool provides a brief, practical, valid, and reliable screening instrument.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index-Addendum for PTSD (PSQI-A)</measure>
    <time_frame>Dec 2020 - Feb 2021</time_frame>
    <description>7-item questionnaire used to examine disruptive nocturnal behaviors common in adults with PTSD. Response items are endorsed for frequency. The PSQI-A is a valid instrument for PTSD applicable to both clinical and research settings.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Deployer Identified COVID-19 Stressors</measure>
    <time_frame>Dec 2020 - Feb 2021</time_frame>
    <description>Currently there are no valid and reliable instruments specific to COVID-19 distress. Given this is a novel pandemic, we requested deployers to list top 3 stressors experienced during deployment. Participants rated listed items as: 1-no distress, 2-mildly distressing, 3-distressing, 4- very distressing, and 5-extremely distressing.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Brief Coping Orientation to Problems Experienced (Brief COPE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Dec 2020 - Feb 2021</time_frame>
    <description>28-item multidimensional measure of 14 strategies (humor, positive reframing, acceptance, active coping,planning, behavioral disengagement, self-distraction, substance use, denial, self-blame, venting, emotional support, instrumental support, religion) used for coping or regulating cognitions in response to stressors. This abbreviated inventory (based on the complete 60-item COPE Inventory) is comprised of items that assess the frequency with which a person uses different coping strategies rated on a scale from 0-&quot;I haven't been doing this at all&quot; to 4-&quot;I've been doing this a lot.&quot; (Amoyal et al., 2011). We have eliminated two items that deal with drugs and alcohol to maintain the eligibility of exempt protocol status</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 Coping Strategy and Resource Inventory</measure>
    <time_frame>Dec 2020 - Feb 2021</time_frame>
    <description>18-item resource inventory developed by our DGMC research team to assess preferred strategic resources to manage COVID-19-related stressors. The inventory includes 5 categories of coping resources: 1) interactive [exercise, spiritual, social, mental health visit], 2) self-help videos/webinars, 3) mobile applications, 4) electronic toolkits, 5) podcasts</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Demographic questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Dec 2020 - Feb 2021</time_frame>
    <description>10 questions regarding individual deployer sex, COVID-19 risk status, mental health risk status, COVID-19 risk status of any family members at home, years of experience in current occupation and specific healthcare role, typical work setting at DGMC, any recent deployments.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">160</enrollment>
  <condition>Coping Skills</condition>
  <condition>Healthcare Workers</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Active duty healthcare workers assigned to David Grant U.S. Air Force Medical Center (DGMC)&#xD;
        who deployed in July 2020, under the command of Col Justin Nast and the COVID Theater&#xD;
        Hospital (CTH), in support of 8 civilian California hospitals.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The eligible participant group includes David Grant USAF Medical Center Active Duty&#xD;
             personnel, 4N medical technicians, Liaison officers (LNO's), nurses, physician&#xD;
             assistants, advanced practice nurses, respiratory therapists, psychologists, social&#xD;
             workers, chaplains, and physicians who deployed in July 2020, under the command of Col&#xD;
             Justin Nast and the COVID Theater Hospital (CTH) in support of the following civilian&#xD;
             facilities: Adventist Health Lodi Memorial Hospital, Lodi, CA Eisenhower Medical&#xD;
             Center, Rancho Mirage, CA Community Regional Medical Center, Fresno, CA Kaweah Delta&#xD;
             Health Care, Visalia, CA Adventist Health Dameron Hospital, Stockton, CA Adventist&#xD;
             Health Hanford, Hanford, CA LA County-USC Medical Center, Los Angeles, CA Harbor-UCLA&#xD;
             Medical Center, Torrance, CA&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Activated guard, reserve, or civilian healthcare deployers in support of COVID-19;&#xD;
             active duty healthcare deployers from MTF's other than DGMC in support of California&#xD;
             civilian hospitals other than the eight facilities named in the above inclusion&#xD;
             criteria.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <reference>
    <citation>Amoyal NR, Mason ST, Gould NF, Corry N, Mahfouz S, Barkey A, Fauerbach JA. Measuring coping behavior in patients with major burn injuries: a psychometric evaluation of the BCOPE. J Burn Care Res. 2011 May-Jun;32(3):392-8. doi: 10.1097/BCR.0b013e318217f97a.</citation>
    <PMID>21562462</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Braquehais MD, Vargas-Cáceres S, Gómez-Durán E, Nieva G, Valero S, Casas M, Bruguera E. The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the mental health of healthcare professionals. QJM. 2020 Jun 22. pii: hcaa207. doi: 10.1093/qjmed/hcaa207. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>32569374</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cacioppo JT, Reis HT, Zautra AJ. Social resilience: the value of social fitness with an application to the military. Am Psychol. 2011 Jan;66(1):43-51. doi: 10.1037/a0021419.</citation>
    <PMID>21219047</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cullen W, Gulati G, Kelly BD. Mental health in the COVID-19 pandemic. QJM. 2020 May 1;113(5):311-312. doi: 10.1093/qjmed/hcaa110.</citation>
    <PMID>32227218</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>The Depressed Project: Living Systematic Review of Mental Health in COVID-19 Retrieved August 27, 2020, https://www.depressd.ca/covid-19-mental-health</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Folkman S. Personal control and stress and coping processes: a theoretical analysis. J Pers Soc Psychol. 1984 Apr;46(4):839-52.</citation>
    <PMID>6737195</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Greenberg N. Mental health of health-care workers in the COVID-19 era. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2020 Aug;16(8):425-426. doi: 10.1038/s41581-020-0314-5.</citation>
    <PMID>32561871</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hawkley LC, Thisted RA, Masi CM, Cacioppo JT. Loneliness predicts increased blood pressure: 5-year cross-lagged analyses in middle-aged and older adults. Psychol Aging. 2010 Mar;25(1):132-41. doi: 10.1037/a0017805.</citation>
    <PMID>20230134</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hawkley L, Preacher K, Cacioppo J. As We Said, Loneliness (Not Living Alone) Explains Individual Differences in Sleep Quality: Reply. Health Psychol. 2011 Mar;30(2):136.</citation>
    <PMID>25067871</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hobfoll, S. E. (1998). The Plenum series on stress and coping.Stress, culture, and community: The psychology and philosophy of stress. Plenum Press. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4899- 0115-6</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Holmes EA, O'Connor RC, Perry VH, Tracey I, Wessely S, Arseneault L, Ballard C, Christensen H, Cohen Silver R, Everall I, Ford T, John A, Kabir T, King K, Madan I, Michie S, Przybylski AK, Shafran R, Sweeney A, Worthman CM, Yardley L, Cowan K, Cope C, Hotopf M, Bullmore E. Multidisciplinary research priorities for the COVID-19 pandemic: a call for action for mental health science. Lancet Psychiatry. 2020 Jun;7(6):547-560. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(20)30168-1. Epub 2020 Apr 15. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32304649</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hulley, S. B., Cummings, S. R., Browner, W. S., Grady, D., Hearst, N., &amp; Newman, T. B. (2007). Designing clinical research. Philadelphia.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Insana SP, Hall M, Buysse DJ, Germain A. Validation of the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index Addendum for posttraumatic stress disorder (PSQI-A) in U.S. male military veterans. J Trauma Stress. 2013 Apr;26(2):192-200. doi: 10.1002/jts.21793. Epub 2013 Mar 19.</citation>
    <PMID>23512653</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jansoon, M., &amp; Rello, J. (2020). Mental Health in Healthcare Workers and the Covid-19 Pandemic Era: Novel Challenge for Critical Care Abstract. Journal of Intensive and Critical Care, 6(26), 1-3. https://doi.org/10.36648/2471-8505.6.2.6</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lazarus, R. S., &amp; Folkman, S. (1984). Stress, appraisal, and coping. Springer publishing company.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JB. The Patient Health Questionnaire-2: validity of a two-item depression screener. Med Care. 2003 Nov;41(11):1284-92.</citation>
    <PMID>14583691</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JB, Monahan PO, Löwe B. Anxiety disorders in primary care: prevalence, impairment, comorbidity, and detection. Ann Intern Med. 2007 Mar 6;146(5):317-25.</citation>
    <PMID>17339617</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kurina LM, Knutson KL, Hawkley LC, Cacioppo JT, Lauderdale DS, Ober C. Loneliness is associated with sleep fragmentation in a communal society. Sleep. 2011 Nov 1;34(11):1519-26. doi: 10.5665/sleep.1390.</citation>
    <PMID>22043123</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Muller AE, Hafstad EV, Himmels JPW, Smedslund G, Flottorp S, Stensland SØ, Stroobants S, Van de Velde S, Vist GE. The mental health impact of the covid-19 pandemic on healthcare workers, and interventions to help them: A rapid systematic review. Psychiatry Res. 2020 Nov;293:113441. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113441. Epub 2020 Sep 1.</citation>
    <PMID>32898840</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pfefferbaum, B., &amp; North, C. S. (2020). Mental health and the COVID-19 pandemic. The New England Journal of Medicine, 383(6), 508-510. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMp2013466</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Poonian J, Walsham N, Kilner T, Bradbury E, Brooks K, West E. Managing healthcare worker well-being in an Australian emergency department during the COVID-19 pandemic. Emerg Med Australas. 2020 Aug;32(4):700-702. doi: 10.1111/1742-6723.13547. Epub 2020 Jun 25.</citation>
    <PMID>32386263</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rajkumar RP. COVID-19 and mental health: A review of the existing literature. Asian J Psychiatr. 2020 Aug;52:102066. doi: 10.1016/j.ajp.2020.102066. Epub 2020 Apr 10.</citation>
    <PMID>32302935</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rossi R, Socci V, Pacitti F, Di Lorenzo G, Di Marco A, Siracusano A, Rossi A. Mental Health Outcomes Among Frontline and Second-Line Health Care Workers During the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Pandemic in Italy. JAMA Netw Open. 2020 May 1;3(5):e2010185. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.10185.</citation>
    <PMID>32463467</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shah K, Kamrai D, Mekala H, Mann B, Desai K, Patel RS. Focus on Mental Health During the Coronavirus (COVID-19) Pandemic: Applying Learnings from the Past Outbreaks. Cureus. 2020 Mar 25;12(3):e7405. doi: 10.7759/cureus.7405. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32337131</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shaukat N, Ali DM, Razzak J. Physical and mental health impacts of COVID-19 on healthcare workers: a scoping review. Int J Emerg Med. 2020 Jul 20;13(1):40. doi: 10.1186/s12245-020-00299-5. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32689925</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shechter A, Diaz F, Moise N, Anstey DE, Ye S, Agarwal S, Birk JL, Brodie D, Cannone DE, Chang B, Claassen J, Cornelius T, Derby L, Dong M, Givens RC, Hochman B, Homma S, Kronish IM, Lee SAJ, Manzano W, Mayer LES, McMurry CL, Moitra V, Pham P, Rabbani L, Rivera RR, Schwartz A, Schwartz JE, Shapiro PA, Shaw K, Sullivan AM, Vose C, Wasson L, Edmondson D, Abdalla M. Psychological distress, coping behaviors, and preferences for support among New York healthcare workers during the COVID-19 pandemic. Gen Hosp Psychiatry. 2020 Sep - Oct;66:1-8. doi: 10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2020.06.007. Epub 2020 Jun 16.</citation>
    <PMID>32590254</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Skinner EA, Zimmer-Gembeck MJ. The development of coping. Annu Rev Psychol. 2007;58:119-44.</citation>
    <PMID>16903804</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Spoorthy MS, Pratapa SK, Mahant S. Mental health problems faced by healthcare workers due to the COVID-19 pandemic-A review. Asian J Psychiatr. 2020 Jun;51:102119. doi: 10.1016/j.ajp.2020.102119. Epub 2020 Apr 22. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32339895</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Worldometer. (n.d.). Coronavirus Cases. Retrieved August 22, 2020, https://www.worldometers.info /coronavirus/.</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 25, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 25, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 30, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>David Grant U.S. Air Force Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Amanda Fox</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Inquiry in Nursing Readiness Fellow</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

