<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3917">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04498247</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>V591-001</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-003493-46</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>V591-001</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04498247</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Assess Safety, Tolerability, and Immunogenicity of V591 (COVID-19 Vaccine) in Healthy Participants (V591-001)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1/Phase 2, Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Dose-Ranging Trial to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability and Immunogenicity of V591 (COVID-19 Vaccine) in Healthy Younger and Older Participants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this early Phase 1 study is to identify the V591 dose that achieves&#xD;
      the target immune response in humans based on preclinical or early clinical data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 27, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 26, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 26, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with at Least 1 Solicited Injection Site Adverse Event</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~5 days after vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>An adverse event (AE) is any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical study participant, temporally associated with the use of study intervention, whether or not considered related to the study intervention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with at Least 1 Solicited Systemic Adverse Event</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~14 days after vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical study participant, temporally associated with the use of study intervention, whether or not considered related to the study intervention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with at Least 1 Unsolicited Adverse Event</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~28 days after vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical study participant, temporally associated with the use of study intervention, whether or not considered related to the study intervention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with at Least 1 Serious Adverse Event</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~365 days (±14 days) after vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>A serious adverse event is &quot;life threatening,&quot; requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of existing hospitalization, results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity and is a congenital anomaly/birth defect.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants who Discontinued Study Treatment due to an Adverse Event</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~365 days (±7 days) after vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical study participant, temporally associated with the use of study intervention, whether or not considered related to the study intervention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants with at Least 1 Medically Attended Adverse Event</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to ~365 days (±14 days) after vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>A medically attended adverse event (MAAE) is an AE in which medical attention is received during an unscheduled, non-routine outpatient visit, such as an emergency room visit, office visit, or an urgent care visit with any medical personnel for any reason.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Titers for Serum Neutralizing Antibodies (nAb) as Measured by Plaque Reduction Neutralization Test (PRNT): All Panels</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 29</time_frame>
    <description>Serum samples will be collected and the presence of serum neutralization antibodies will be assessed using PRNT.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Concentration of Total Anti-Spike Immunoglobulin G (IgG) Antibodies as Measured by Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay (ELISA): All Panels</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 29</time_frame>
    <description>Serum samples will be collected and the total anti-spike IgG antibodies will be assessed using ELISA.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Titers for Serum Neutralizing Antibodies as Measured by PRNT: Panels A,B, I and J</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>Serum samples will be collected and the presence of serum neutralization antibodies will be assessed using PRNT.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Concentration of Total Anti-Spike IgG Antibodies as Measured by ELISA: Panels A,B, I and J</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>Serum samples will be collected and the total anti-spike IgG antibodies will be assessed using ELISA.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Titers for Serum Neutralizing Antibodies as Measured by PRNT: Panels K and L</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 197</time_frame>
    <description>Serum samples will be collected and the presence of serum neutralization antibodies will be assessed using PRNT.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Concentration of Total Anti-Spike IgG Antibodies as Measured by ELISA: Panels K and L</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 197</time_frame>
    <description>Serum samples will be collected and the total anti-spike IgG antibodies will be assessed using ELISA.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Titers for Serum nAb as Measured by PRNT</measure>
    <time_frame>Panels C-E and G-H: Days 1, 15, 29, 57, 85, 115, 211, and 365; Panels A,B, I and J: Days 1, 15, 29, 57, 71, 85, 115, 211, and 422; Panels F, K and L: Days 1, 15, 29, 85, 169, 197, 365 and 534</time_frame>
    <description>Serum samples will be collected and the presence of serum neutralization antibodies will be assessed using PRNT.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Concentration of Total Anti-Spike IgG Antibodies as Measured by ELISA</measure>
    <time_frame>Panels C-E and G-H: Days 1, 15, 29, 57, 85, 115, 211, and 365; Panels A,B, I and J: Days 1, 15, 29, 57, 71, 85, 115, 211, and 422; Panels F, K and L: Days 1, 15, 29, 85, 169, 197, 365 and 534</time_frame>
    <description>Serum samples will be collected and the total anti-spike IgG antibodies will be assessed using ELISA.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">260</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1: Panels A, B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this 18 to 55 year old sentinel cohort will receive 2 doses (Day 1 and Day 57) of V591 or placebo.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2A: Panels C-E</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this 18 to 55 year old cohort will receive 1 dose (Day 1) of V591 or placebo.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2A: Panel F</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this 18 to 55 year old cohort will receive 2 doses (Day 1 and Day 169) of V591 or placebo.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2B: Panels G, H</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this &gt;55 year old cohort will receive 1 dose (Day 1) of V591 or placebo.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2B: Panels I, J</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this &gt;55 year old cohort will receive 2 doses (Day 1 and Day 57) of V591 or placebo.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2B: Panels K, L</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this &gt;55 year old cohort will receive 2 doses (Day 1 and Day 169) of V591 or placebo.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>V591</intervention_name>
    <description>1 or 2 ascending doses of V591 will be administered via intramuscular (IM) injection.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1: Panels A, B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2A: Panel F</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2A: Panels C-E</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2B: Panels G, H</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2B: Panels I, J</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2B: Panels K, L</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo (0.9% sodium chloride) administered via IM injection.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1: Panels A, B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2A: Panel F</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2A: Panels C-E</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2B: Panels G, H</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2B: Panels I, J</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2B: Panels K, L</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is in overall good health based on medical history, physical examination,&#xD;
             electrocardiogram (ECG) and vital sign (VS) measurements performed prior to&#xD;
             randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is in overall good health based on laboratory safety tests obtained at the screening&#xD;
             visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a body mass index (BMI) &lt;30 kg/m2 inclusive. On this basis a rounded BMI of 29.9&#xD;
             is acceptable to satisfy the inclusion criteria. BMI = weight (kg)/height (m)2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has been practicing social distancing for at least two weeks prior to planned Day 1&#xD;
             vaccination and has no close contacts with known active severe acute respiratory&#xD;
             syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV)-2 infection in that time period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sentinel trial participants ONLY (Panel A, Panel B, and the first 5 participants of&#xD;
             Panel E): Seronegative for SARS-COV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is male or female, from 18 years to 55 years of age (inclusive) (Parts 1 and 2A) or&#xD;
             &gt;55 years of age (Part 2B), at the time of providing documented informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male participants are eligible to participate if they agree to refrain from donating&#xD;
             sperm during the intervention period and for at least 6 months after the last dose of&#xD;
             study intervention, be abstinent from heterosexual intercourse as their preferred and&#xD;
             usual lifestyle and agree to remain abstinent OR agree to use contraception unless&#xD;
             confirmed to be azoospermic .&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraceptive use by men and women should be consistent with local regulations&#xD;
             regarding the methods of contraception for those participating in clinical studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A female participant is eligible to participate if she is not pregnant or&#xD;
             breastfeeding, is not a woman of childbearing potential (WOCBP) or Is a WOCBP and&#xD;
             using an acceptable contraceptive method or be abstinent from heterosexual intercourse&#xD;
             as their preferred and usual lifestyle.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A WOCBP must have a negative highly sensitive pregnancy test (urine or serum as&#xD;
             required by local regulations) before the first dose of study intervention. If a urine&#xD;
             test cannot be confirmed as negative (e.g., an ambiguous result), a serum pregnancy&#xD;
             test is required. In such cases, the participant must be excluded from participation&#xD;
             if the serum pregnancy result is positive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refrain from donating oocyte during the intervention period and for at least 6 months&#xD;
             after the last dose of study intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The investigator is responsible for review of medical history, menstrual history, and&#xD;
             recent sexual activity to decrease the risk for inclusion of a woman with an early&#xD;
             undetected pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant (or legally acceptable representative) has provided documented&#xD;
             informed consent/assent for the study, including for future biomedical research.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is willing to comply with the study restrictions, including social distancing between&#xD;
             screening and randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is willing to abstain from donating whole blood or blood derivatives, tissue or organ&#xD;
             all along the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees to provide study personnel with a primary telephone number as well as an&#xD;
             alternate means of contact, if available (such as an alternate telephone number or&#xD;
             email) for follow-up purposes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Can read, understand, and complete the Vaccination Report Card.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently actively infected with SARS-CoV-2 (confirmed by polymerase chain&#xD;
             reaction;[PCR]).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has prior medical history of confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection or known exposure to an&#xD;
             individual with confirmed coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) disease or SARS CoV-2&#xD;
             infection within the past 2 weeks. With the exception of the sentinel participants&#xD;
             (Panel A, Panel B, and the first 5 participants of Panel E), study participants will&#xD;
             not be screened for enrollment by SARS-CoV-2 serology, allowing those who may have had&#xD;
             a prior asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection to be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of severe adverse reactions to vaccine administration, including&#xD;
             anaphylaxis and related symptoms, such as urticaria, respiratory difficulty,&#xD;
             angioedema and abdominal pain to vaccines, or history of known or suspected allergic&#xD;
             reaction likely to be exacerbated by any component of the COVID-19 vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently (or highly suspected to be) immunocompromised, including anticipating the&#xD;
             need for systemic immunosuppressive treatment within the next 6 months or 12 months&#xD;
             for 2-dose Day 1, Day 169 panels or has been diagnosed or highly suspected as having a&#xD;
             congenital or acquired immunodeficiency, HIV infection, lymphoma, leukemia, systemic&#xD;
             lupus erythematosus (SLE), rheumatoid arthritis, juvenile rheumatoid arthritis (JRA),&#xD;
             inflammatory bowel disease, or other autoimmune condition that could impact the immune&#xD;
             response or the safety of the study vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has clinically significant thrombocytopenia or other coagulation disorder&#xD;
             contraindicating intramuscular vaccination or repeated venipuncture.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has history or current evidence of any condition, therapy, laboratory abnormality, or&#xD;
             other circumstance that might expose the participant to risk by participating in the&#xD;
             study, confound the results of the study or interfere with the participant's&#xD;
             participation for the full duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history or presence of clinically significant pulmonary disorders (e.g. chronic&#xD;
             obstructive pulmonary disease [COPD], etc.), or asthma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of confirmed SARS-CoV-1 or Middle Eastern respiratory syndrome (MERS)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of or current clinically significant medical condition that puts or may&#xD;
             put a participant at increased risk for severe SARS-CoV-2 disease, such as conditions&#xD;
             associated with increased risk of severe illness from COVID-19, cancer, chronic kidney&#xD;
             disease, COPD, immunocompromised state (weakened immune system) from solid organ&#xD;
             transplant, obesity (BMI of 30 or higher), serious heart conditions, such as heart&#xD;
             failure, coronary artery disease, or cardiomyopathies, sickle cell disease, Type 2&#xD;
             diabetes mellitus, asthma, cerebrovascular disease, cystic fibrosis, hypertension or&#xD;
             high blood pressure, an immunocompromised state (weakened immune system), neurologic&#xD;
             conditions, such as dementia, liver disease, pregnancy, pulmonary fibrosis (having&#xD;
             damaged or scarred lung tissues), smoking, thalassemia (a type of blood disorder), or&#xD;
             Type 1 diabetes mellitus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Part 2B ONLY: Older adult participants having mild, well controlled hypertension as is&#xD;
             widely characteristic of aging are allowed if their medication regimens have not&#xD;
             substantively changed for the past 6 months, hypertension has not led to&#xD;
             hospitalization or currently increased rate of clinic visits over the past year, and&#xD;
             hypertension has not been confirmed as putting subjects at increased risk of severe&#xD;
             illness from COVID-19 by the CDC&#xD;
             (https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/need-extra-precautions/groups-at-higher-ris&#xD;
             k.html).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is mentally or legally incapacitated, has significant emotional problems at the time&#xD;
             of pre-study (screening) visit or expected during the conduct of the study or has a&#xD;
             history of clinically significant psychiatric disorder of the last 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of any clinically significant major neurological disorders or seizures&#xD;
             (including Guillain-Barré syndrome), with the exception of febrile seizures during&#xD;
             childhood.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of cancer (malignancy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known or suspected history of significant multiple and/or severe allergies&#xD;
             (e.g., food, drug, latex allergy), or has had an anaphylactic reaction or significant&#xD;
             intolerability (i.e., systemic allergic reaction) to prescription or non-prescription&#xD;
             drugs or food.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is positive for hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg), hepatitis C antibodies or human&#xD;
             immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-1 or 2 antibodies. Individuals with antibodies to&#xD;
             hepatitis C may be enrolled if hepatitis C viral load is undetectable and there is no&#xD;
             evidence of or history of liver disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had major surgery, donated or lost 1 unit of blood (approximately 500 mL) within 4&#xD;
             weeks prior to the pre-study (screening) visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received immunosuppressive drugs (like e.g. systemic corticosteroids, excluding&#xD;
             topical preparations and inhalers) within 3 months prior to the first vaccination or 6&#xD;
             months for chemotherapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  *Has received vaccination within 4 weeks prior to first vaccination or is planning to&#xD;
             receive a licensed vaccine 4 weeks before or after each study vaccination (e.g.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inactivated influenza vaccine).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  *Has received measles-containing vaccine within 3 months prior to the first&#xD;
             vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received a blood transfusion or blood products, including immunoglobulin, starting&#xD;
             from 3 months before the first study vaccination or is scheduled to receive a blood&#xD;
             transfusion or blood product through study completion. Autologous blood transfusions&#xD;
             are not considered an exclusion criterion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is unable to meet the concomitant medication restrictions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is using antiviral medications or any investigational agents for prophylaxis of&#xD;
             SARSCoV-2 within 4 weeks prior to the first vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has ever participated in an investigational study of a SARS-CoV-2 vaccine, or an&#xD;
             antiviral or other biologic product intended for the treatment of COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently participating in any study of a vaccine or investigational medicinal&#xD;
             product (IMP) or has recently completed participation in another study of a vaccine or&#xD;
             IMP and received a vaccine within 3 months prior to screening or an IMP within 4 weeks&#xD;
             (or 5 half-lives of the IMP, whichever is longer) prior to the pre-study (screening)&#xD;
             visit. The window will be derived from the date of the last study intervention (e.g.,&#xD;
             receiving a vaccine or IMP) in the previous study to the date of the pre-study&#xD;
             (screening) visit for this study. In addition, a participant cannot participate in&#xD;
             another investigational trial up to the post-trial visit of this study (approximately&#xD;
             12 months after the last study vaccination).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has glycated hemoglobin (A1C) ≥ 6.5% at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of alcohol, cocaine, or opioid abuse during the previous 3 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who currently smoke or used nicotine or nicotine-containing products&#xD;
             (e.g. nicotine patch) within last 3 months. Former smokers that have less than a 10&#xD;
             pack-year history of smoking and have not smoked in the last 12 months are eligible to&#xD;
             be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a tattoo, scar or other physical finding at the area of the vaccination site that&#xD;
             would interfere with intramuscular injection or a local tolerability assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presents any concern by the investigator regarding safe participation in the study or&#xD;
             for any other reason the investigator considers the participant inappropriate for&#xD;
             participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lives in a nursing home or long-term care facility.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently working in occupations with high risk of exposure to SARS-CoV-2 (e.g.,&#xD;
             health care worker with direct patient contact, emergency response personnel), or, at&#xD;
             the investigator's discretion to be at increased risk to acquire SARS-CoV-2 for any&#xD;
             other reason.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are living and/or working with severely immunocompromised people,&#xD;
             pregnant women, lactating women, children under 12 months old, or any other individual&#xD;
             that, in the judgment of the investigator, might be at increased risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is or has an immediate family member (e.g., spouse, parent/legal guardian, sibling, or&#xD;
             child) who is investigatively involved with this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  if the participant meets these exclusion criteria, the Day 1 Visit may be&#xD;
                  rescheduled for a time when these criteria are not met.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Centers of America, LLC ( Site 0014)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hollywood</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33024</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alliance for Multispecialty Research, LLC ( Site 0013)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wichita</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>67205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Central Kentucky Research Associates, Inc. ( Site 0011)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lexington</city>
        <state>Kentucky</state>
        <zip>40509</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Center for Pharmaceutical Research PC ( Site 0012)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>64114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>SCRI-CCCIT GesmbH ( Site 0006)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salzburg</city>
        <zip>5020</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medizinische Universitaet Wien ( Site 0007)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wien</city>
        <zip>1090</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitair Ziekenhuis Gent ( Site 0003)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gent</city>
        <state>Oost-Vlaanderen</state>
        <zip>9000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>SGS Life Science Services ( Site 0001)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Antwerpen</city>
        <zip>2060</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>ATC - Clinical Pharmacology Unit ( Site 0002)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Liege</city>
        <zip>4000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
    <country>Belgium</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 3, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 3, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 4, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 4, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 7, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>http://engagezone.msd.com/doc/ProcedureAccessClinicalTrialData.pdf</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>http://engagezone.msd.com/ds_documentation.php</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

