<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3167">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04354272</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>APHP200464</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04354272</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of Dental Emergency Treatments During COVID19 Crisis</brief_title>
  <acronym>URGDENTCOVID</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Management of Dental Emergencies During COVID 19 Crisis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      &quot;For 12 years, the odontology service of the Pitié-Salpêtrière hospital group (GHPS) has been&#xD;
      responsible for day and night dental emergency care. Several surveys have been conducted in&#xD;
      order to analyze the sociological characteristics of the patients and the typology of the&#xD;
      acts performed. These studies indicate that pain is the main reason for consultations, cited&#xD;
      by 60 to 80% of patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      So far, very few studies have been done in the context of emergencies. Very recently, a study&#xD;
      was undertaken on the satisfaction of patients consulting the odontological emergencies of&#xD;
      the GHPS, during a thesis work.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study, carried out in collaboration with the URC Pitié Salpêtrière, under analysis,&#xD;
      relates to the satisfaction of patients consulting the odontological emergencies of the GHPS&#xD;
      during the day and week, Monday to Friday, excluding night and week emergencies -end (WE). An&#xD;
      additional study (URGDENT-NW) aiming at completing this study by focusing on patients&#xD;
      consulting the emergency room at night and during the weekend is also in progress.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The COVID19 Crisis changed the organization and the venue of patients at the emergency dental&#xD;
      service.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore this project, based on the same protocol as URGENT and URGDENT-WE, aims at&#xD;
      evaluating the Odontology Emergency Reception Service (SAUO) during the COVID 19 epidemy. It&#xD;
      will be carried out in the form of a survey whose objective is to assess: on the one hand,&#xD;
      the effectiveness of the care provided in this emergency functional unit, and on the other&#xD;
      hand the satisfaction of the patients after their passage to the emergency room .&quot;&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      &quot;I. Research progress Two investigators will take turns in the service for the search&#xD;
      duration. They will be responsible for informing patients of the research upon their arrival&#xD;
      in the service and for the data collection and telephone follow-ups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The course of the research will take place as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Day of consultation (D0):&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Patient information on the search when he arrives in the service; explanation of its&#xD;
           objectives, its modalities and constraints.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Verification of eligibility criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Collection of the patient's non-opposition by the dentist during the consultation&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Consultation according to the usual care. During this procedure, the practitioner&#xD;
           performs a medical history and, according to the patient's answers, completes the&#xD;
           &quot;&quot;General Information Questionnaire&quot;&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
           He carries out the emergency care and explains the postoperative consequences.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Patient filling in the satisfaction questionnaire immediately after consultation.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Telephone follow-up:&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Telephone follow-up by the interviewer and fill in the questionnaire - in case of&#xD;
           non-availability of the patient on day 1, the patient will be recalled on day 2 and the&#xD;
           extrapolated data on the slope of the curve between D1 and D2&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Telephone follow-up by the interviewer on the day and filling in the questionnaire - if&#xD;
           the patient is not available on day 3, the patient will be recalled on day 4 and the&#xD;
           data extrapolated according to the slope of the curve between D1 and D4; if the patient&#xD;
           is not available at D4, he will be recalled to D5 and the extrapolated data between D1&#xD;
           and D5.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Telephone follow-up on the interviewer's day and fill in the questionnaire in case of&#xD;
           non-availability of the patient on day 7, the patient will be recalled to D8 and the&#xD;
           data extrapolated according to the slope of the curve between D3 and D8; if the patient&#xD;
           is still not available on D8, he will be recalled to D9 and the extrapolated data&#xD;
           between D3 and D9.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the night sample : from 6:30 pm to 8 am Recall should be 24 hours after the care, but it&#xD;
      seems not ethical or efficient to recall patients the night following ; an extension of 12&#xD;
      hours will be instaured, taking then the recalls to 36h (D1), 84h (D3), and 180h (D7) after&#xD;
      the care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the Day sample : from 8 am to 6:30 pm D1: 24 hours after the care D3: 72 hours after the&#xD;
      care D7 :168 hours after the care&#xD;
&#xD;
      II.1.STATISTICAL ASPECTS&#xD;
&#xD;
      II.1. Statistical justification for the sample size The investigators want to assess the&#xD;
      activity of the service over 4 weeks during the COVID crisis by taking two readings per week&#xD;
      during the day and one during the night. The 1st figures of the service (week of March 16 to&#xD;
      22) indicate an average attendance of 80 patients day and 50 per night.&#xD;
&#xD;
      So the investigators will have 8 x 80 = 640 patients during the day period and 4x 50 = 200&#xD;
      patients per night According to a previous study in the department (15), 50% of patients in&#xD;
      care could not be included in the study or were lost to follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This leads to a number of 420 analysable patients per week.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II.2. Description of statistical methods A descriptive analysis of the characteristics of the&#xD;
      sample will be performed (age, sex, reason for consultation, diagnosis, prior appointment&#xD;
      test, average score of anxiety and pain scores on D0, D1, D3, D7, compliance with&#xD;
      instructions and making follow-up appointments,), satisfaction rating, appreciation of the&#xD;
      quality of medical care, politeness of staff, waiting time, assessment of the quality of the&#xD;
      care setting, the information received, the treatment received, and the recommendation of the&#xD;
      service to third parties will be made.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An analysis of the evolution of pain and anxiety scores between D0, D1, D3 and D7 will be&#xD;
      performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Correlations between the type of treatment and the perceived pain as well as the type of&#xD;
      treatment and the perceived anxiety will be made.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II.3. Method of taking into account missing or invalid data Patients unreachable during the&#xD;
      telephone follow-up period will be contacted the next day; the pain and anxiety scores will&#xD;
      then be extrapolated from the previous data and the new data collected, by calculating the&#xD;
      nearest point on the curve connecting these two data. If they are new unreachable, the data&#xD;
      will be considered missing. Data from patients with missing data will be analyzed separately.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. DATA MANAGEMENT&#xD;
&#xD;
      III.1. Terms of data collection The research does not foresee the use of data extracted from&#xD;
      existing information systems or from previously completed studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      No nominative data will be collected as part of this research. The data will be rendered&#xD;
      non-identifying. They must not in any case show in clear the names of the persons concerned&#xD;
      or their address.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As part of this research, topics will be identified as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      N or W (depending on the Night or Week-end sample) - Chronological order of the person (3&#xD;
      digits) - first letter of the first name - first letter of last name&#xD;
&#xD;
      The answers to the different questionnaires (completed by the patients and the interviewers)&#xD;
      will be entered into an EXCEL file. This file will be protected by a password.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The seizure will be carried out by the coordinating investigator or one of those&#xD;
      collaborators (dentist or student) declared in the center and trained in research at the end&#xD;
      of each session.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III.2. Data circuit The investigators will collect the data directly from the patient during&#xD;
      the consultation or during telephone interviews on paper forms (CRF).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This data will then be entered into an Excel database specifically created for the search.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The database will be kept on the computer of the odontology service at the Pitié-Salpêtrière&#xD;
      hospital and will be protected by a password known only to research stakeholders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data analysis will be done by the principal investigator and the research stakeholders&quot;&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 13, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 20, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 20, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain score evolution measured by a 0-10 numeric scale (NS) where 0 is no pain and 10 the worst pain imaginable</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>&quot;Self report measure of pain on the numeric scale 24h after the visit &quot;</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain scores evolution 3 days and 7 days after first visit measured by a numeric scale where 0 is no pain and 10 the worst pain imaginable</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 3 and Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>the pain is measured with the numeric scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>welcoming quality from hospital staff</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Perception of welcoming, waiting time will be measured with a 0-10 numeric scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>anxiety score</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0, Day 1, Day 3, Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>The patient anxiety will be measured by numeric scale at Day 0, Day 1, Day 3, Day 7</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>perception of the technical quality of the emergency treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>The perception is measured just after care with a 0-10 numeric scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">840</enrollment>
  <condition>Orofacial Pain</condition>
  <condition>Orofacial Edema</condition>
  <condition>Dental Trauma</condition>
  <condition>Oral Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Questionnaire</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaire</intervention_name>
    <description>Questionnaire for the satisfaction of patients consulting the odontological emergencies of the GHPS during COVID 19.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Questionnaire</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        patients seeking care at the dental emergency serviceduring COVID 198 crisis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient reachable by telephone during the week following his / her care in the service&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Collection of the consent of the patient for his participation in research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Good understanding of the French language&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -Patient with communication difficulties or difficulties in understanding the French&#xD;
        language&quot;&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yves Boucher, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>01 42 16 14 51</phone>
    <email>yves.boucher@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Isabelle Rodriguez</last_name>
    <email>iba.rodriguez@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>April 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 10, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 21, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 16, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 16, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 21, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Facial Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

