<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3287">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04708340</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RPI015</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04708340</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Tolerability and Efficacy of RJX in Patients With COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>RJX</acronym>
  <official_title>A Two-part, Two-cohort, Double-blind, Randomized, Placebo-controlled, Multicenter Phase 1/2 Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability and Efficacy of REJUVEINIX (RJX) in Patients With COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Reven Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Reven Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is designed as a 2-part, 2-cohort, double-blind, randomized, placebo controlled,&#xD;
      multicenter Phase 1/2 study to evaluate the safety, tolerability and efficacy of RJX in&#xD;
      patients with COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      For each cohort, there will be an open label Safety Lead-in (Part 1) and a placebo&#xD;
      controlled, randomized, double-blind portion (Part 2). In Part 1, RJX will be administered&#xD;
      daily for 7 days. In the active treatment arm of Part 2 for both cohorts, RJX will be&#xD;
      administered daily for 7 days per cycle and patients may receive up to 2 cycles. As detailed&#xD;
      below, patients will be allowed to receive a second 7 day cycle of therapy based on the&#xD;
      medical judgment of the Investigator. The total RJX exposure during Part 2 could therefore be&#xD;
      up to 14 days. Both cohorts will start and enroll in parallel and independently. A safety&#xD;
      follow-up period will begin at Day 14/Discharge, or when treatment is discontinued, and will&#xD;
      continue for approximately 60 days post discharge. Part 1 will be conducted at a single site&#xD;
      and Part 2 will be conducted at multiple sites. The 2 cohorts in this study are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort 1:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Hospitalized COVID-19 patients ≥18 years without hypoxemia who are either not&#xD;
                receiving any oxygen therapy OR are receiving supplemental oxygen via mask or nasal&#xD;
                prongs (namely, clinical status score 4 or 5 on an 8-point ordinal scale).&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Patients are required to have the following high-risk characteristics&#xD;
&#xD;
                  1. Age ≥65 years AND type 2 diabetes or hypertension OR&#xD;
&#xD;
                  2. Age ≥18 years with abnormal blood tests AND CRP &gt;50 mg/L PLUS at least 1 of&#xD;
                     the following biomarkers:&#xD;
&#xD;
                       1. D-dimer &gt;1,000 ng/mL,&#xD;
&#xD;
                       2. Ferritin &gt;500 µg/L,&#xD;
&#xD;
                       3. High sensitivity cardiac troponin &gt;2 × upper limit of normal (ULN),&#xD;
&#xD;
                       4. LDH &gt;245 U/L.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cohort 2:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Hospitalized COVID-19 patients with hypoxemia without ARDS who are receiving either&#xD;
                non-invasive positive pressure ventilation (NIPPV) OR high flow oxygen (namely,&#xD;
                clinical status score 3 on an 8-point ordinal scale).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>In Part 1, RJX will be administered daily for 7 days (1 cycle). In Part 2, Placebo or RJX will be administered daily for 7 days for 1 cycle but may receive 2 cycles.&#xD;
Each Cohort is comprised of Part 1, a single site, and Part 2, multiple sites. The 2 Cohorts are:&#xD;
Cohort 1:&#xD;
Hospitalized COVID-19 patients ≥18 years without hypoxemia and either not receiving any oxygen therapy OR are receiving supplemental oxygen via mask or nasal prongs (clinical status score 4 or 5 on 8-point ordinal scale).&#xD;
Patients are required to have the following high-risk characteristics&#xD;
Age ≥65 years AND type 2 diabetes or hypertension OR&#xD;
Age ≥18 years with abnormal blood tests AND CRP &gt;50 mg/L PLUS at least 1 of the following biomarkers abnormal: a. D-dimer, b. Ferritin, c. High sensitivity cardiac troponin, d. LDH&#xD;
Cohort 2:&#xD;
• Hospitalized COVID-19 patients with hypoxemia and without ARDS who are receiving either non-invasive positive pressure ventilation (NIPPV) OR high flow oxygen</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Masking the dose administered</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety as measured by DLTs and drug related SAE's</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 60 days post-enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>• Part 1, Cohorts 1 and 2: Cumulative incidence of DLTs and drug-related SAEs (viz., sum of DLT + SAEs) reported within 14 days of first dose of RJX (Part 1) or reported within 60 days of first dose of study drug (Part 2)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Tolerability and Efficacy measured by progression of disease through an ordinal scale.</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 2 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>• Part 2, Cohort 1: Progression to severe disease on an 8-point ordinal scale from a clinical status score of 4 or 5 to a clinical status score of 3, 2, or 1 within 2 weeks of first dose of study drug</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy measured by time to resolution of respiratory failure</measure>
    <time_frame>60-days post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>• Part 2, Cohort 2: Time to resolution of respiratory failure (TTRRF), with status change on an 8-point ordinal scale from a clinical status score of 3 to a clinical status score of ≥4</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy as measured by day of ICU care.</measure>
    <time_frame>60-days post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>The key secondary endpoints for Parts 1 and 2, Cohorts 1 and 2 are:&#xD;
• Mean number of days of ICU care</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety, Tolerability, Efficacy measured by mortality over 28 Days.</measure>
    <time_frame>28-days post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>The key secondary endpoints for Parts 1 and 2, Cohorts 1 and 2 are:&#xD;
• Proportion of patients that die (any cause) by Day 28 post randomization (patient may be inpatient or outpatient in follow up)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy measured by mean change in baseline clinical status on Days 7 and 14.</measure>
    <time_frame>14-days post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Additional secondary endpoint for Parts 1 and 2, Cohorts 1 and 2 are:&#xD;
• Mean change from baseline of clinical status using an 8-point ordinal scale (with 8 being &quot;Not hospitalized, no limitations on activities&quot;, and 1 being &quot;Death&quot;) at Days 7 and 14</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy measured by mean change in hospitalization days on Days 7 and 14.</measure>
    <time_frame>14-days post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Additional secondary endpoint for Parts 1 and 2, Cohorts 1 and 2 are:&#xD;
• Mean number of hospitalization days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy measured by time to coming off supplemental oxygen on Days 7 and 14.</measure>
    <time_frame>14-days post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Additional secondary endpoint for Parts 1 and 2, Cohorts 1 and 2 are:&#xD;
• Time to coming off supplemental oxygen (defined as a score of ≥5 on an 8-point ordinal scale; Cohort 1 only)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and Efficacy measured by time from first dose to renal therapy.</measure>
    <time_frame>60-days post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Additional secondary endpoint for Cohort 2, Part 2 is:&#xD;
• Time to initiation of renal replacement therapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Change in Serum CRP Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28-days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The exploratory endpoint for Parts 1 and 2 is:&#xD;
Kinetic of response of CRP (comparison of baseline to Day 7, Day 14, and Day 28 post-randomization). These laboratory measures will be obtained either as an inpatient or an outpatient follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Change in Serum Ferritin Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28-days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The exploratory endpoint for Parts 1 and 2 is:&#xD;
Kinetic of response of ferritin (comparison of baseline to Day 7, Day 14, and Day 28 post-randomization). These laboratory measures will be obtained either as an inpatient or an outpatient follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Change in Serum D-dimer Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28-days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The exploratory endpoint for Parts 1 and 2 is:&#xD;
Kinetic of response of D-dimer (comparison of baseline to Day 7, Day 14, and Day 28 post-randomization). These laboratory measures will be obtained either as an inpatient or an outpatient follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Change in Serum LDH Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28-days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The exploratory endpoint for Parts 1 and 2 is:&#xD;
Kinetic of response of LDH (comparison of baseline to Day 7, Day 14, and Day 28 post-randomization). These laboratory measures will be obtained either as an inpatient or an outpatient follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Change in Serum IL-6 Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28-days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The exploratory endpoint for Parts 1 and 2 is:&#xD;
Kinetic of response of IL-6 (comparison of baseline to Day 7, Day 14, and Day 28 post-randomization). These laboratory measures will be obtained either as an inpatient or an outpatient follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Change in Serum IL-10 Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28-days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The exploratory endpoint for Parts 1 and 2 is:&#xD;
Kinetic of response of IL-10 (comparison of baseline to Day 7, Day 14, and Day 28 post-randomization). These laboratory measures will be obtained either as an inpatient or an outpatient follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Change in Serum TNF-α Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28-days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The exploratory endpoint for Parts 1 and 2 is:&#xD;
Kinetic of response of TNF-α (comparison of baseline to Day 7, Day 14, and Day 28 post-randomization). These laboratory measures will be obtained either as an inpatient or an outpatient follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Change in Serum TGF-β Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28-days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The exploratory endpoint for Parts 1 and 2 is:&#xD;
Kinetic of response of TGF-β (comparison of baseline to Day 7, Day 14, and Day 28 post-randomization). These laboratory measures will be obtained either as an inpatient or an outpatient follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Change in Serum C3 Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28-days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The exploratory endpoint for Parts 1 and 2 is:&#xD;
Kinetic of response of C3 (comparison of baseline to Day 7, Day 14, and Day 28 post-randomization). These laboratory measures will be obtained either as an inpatient or an outpatient follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Change in Serum C5 Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28-days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The exploratory endpoint for Parts 1 and 2 is:&#xD;
Kinetic of response of C5 (comparison of baseline to Day 7, Day 14, and Day 28 post-randomization). These laboratory measures will be obtained either as an inpatient or an outpatient follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Change in Plasma ascorbic acid Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28-days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The exploratory endpoint for Parts 1 and 2 is:&#xD;
Kinetic of response of ascorbic acid (comparison of baseline to Day 7, Day 14, and Day 28 post-randomization). These laboratory measures will be obtained either as an inpatient or an outpatient follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Change in plasma niacinamide Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28-days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The exploratory endpoint for Parts 1 and 2 is:&#xD;
Kinetic of response of niacinamide (comparison of baseline to Day 7, Day 14, and Day 28 post-randomization). These laboratory measures will be obtained either as an inpatient or an outpatient follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Change in plasma thiamine Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28-days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The exploratory endpoint for Parts 1 and 2 is:&#xD;
Kinetic of response of thiamine (comparison of baseline to Day 7, Day 14, and Day 28 post-randomization). These laboratory measures will be obtained either as an inpatient or an outpatient follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate Change in plasma cyanocobalamin Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28-days post randomization</time_frame>
    <description>The exploratory endpoint for Parts 1 and 2 is:&#xD;
Kinetic of response of cyanocobalamin (comparison of baseline to Day 7, Day 14, and Day 28 post-randomization). These laboratory measures will be obtained either as an inpatient or an outpatient follow-up.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">237</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <condition>Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>SARS-CoV-2</condition>
  <condition>Hypoxemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: RJX</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>RJX 20 mL (10 mL of Vial A plus 10 mL of Vial B) mixed in normal saline, total volume 120 mL, administered by IV infusion over a period of 40 minutes +/- 10 minutes once daily.&#xD;
Standard of care (current antiviral and/or supportive care treatment currently in place at the institution for COVID-19 treatment).&#xD;
Patients in Part 1 are allowed to receive only one 7-day cycle of RJX while patients in Part 2 may be treated daily for up to 14 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B: Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo (total of 20 mL normal saline) mixed in normal saline IV, total volume 120 mL of normal saline IV, administered by IV infusion over a period of 40 minutes +/- 10 minutes once daily.&#xD;
Standard of care (current antiviral and/or supportive care treatment currently in place at the institution for COVID-19 treatment).&#xD;
Patients in Part 1 will not receive placebo.&#xD;
Patients in Part 2 may be treated daily for up to 14 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rejuveinix (RJX) Active Comparator</intervention_name>
    <description>Active drug comprised of: ascorbic acid, magnesium sulfate heptahydrate, cyanocobalamin, thiamine, riboflavin 5' phosphate, niacinamide, pyridoxine, calcium d-pantothenate, and sodium bicarbonate.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: RJX</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>RJX</other_name>
    <other_name>Rejuveinix</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo Comparator</intervention_name>
    <description>0.9% Sodium Chloride in Water for Injection a.k.a. Normal Saline for injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B: Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>0.9% Sodium Chloride in Water for Injection, USP.</other_name>
    <other_name>Normal Saline for Injection, USP</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Cohort 1 (Part 1 and Part 2):&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Hospitalized COVID-19 patients ≥18 years without hypoxemia who are either not&#xD;
             receiving any oxygen therapy OR are receiving supplemental oxygen via mask or nasal&#xD;
             prongs (namely, clinical status score 4 or 5 on an 8-point ordinal scale)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Hospitalized COVID-19 patients age ≥65 years AND type 2 diabetes or hypertension, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Hospitalized COVID-19 patients ≥18 years AND abnormal blood tests with CRP &gt;50 mg/L&#xD;
             PLUS at least 1 of the following biomarkers:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. D-dimer &gt;1,000 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Ferritin &gt;500 µg/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. High sensitivity cardiac troponin &gt;2 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. LDH &gt;245 U/L&#xD;
&#xD;
             Cohort 2 (Part 1 and Part 2):&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Hospitalized COVID-19 patients with hypoxemia who are either receiving NIPPV OR&#xD;
             high-flow oxygen (namely, clinical status score 3 on an 8-point ordinal scale).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Bilateral opacities on a chest x-ray OR chest CT scan. Cohort 1 and Cohort 2 (Parts 1&#xD;
             and 2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Male and non-pregnant, non-lactating female patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection that is&#xD;
             documented by a Food and Drug Administration (FDA)-authorized diagnostic reverse&#xD;
             transcription polymerase chain reaction test at/or within 4 days of Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. ≥18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Body weight ≥40 kg at Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of COVID-19 within the last 2 weeks prior to study enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. The patient OR a legally authorized representative has provided written informed&#xD;
             consent&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Females of childbearing potential must have a negative beta human chorionic&#xD;
             gonadotropin pregnancy test at Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Females of childbearing potential must agree to be abstinent or else use a medically&#xD;
             acceptable form of contraception from the Screening period through Day 28. Medically&#xD;
             acceptable forms of contraception including implants, injectables, combined oral&#xD;
             contraceptives, some intrauterine devices, sexual abstinence or vasectomy, and&#xD;
             double-barrier method [condom and occlusive cap (diaphragm or cervical/vault caps)]&#xD;
             with spermicidal foam/gel/film/suppository&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria Cohort 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Receiving high-flow oxygen OR NIPPV. Cohort 1 and Cohort 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ARDS by Berlin definition (Appendix 16.2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. On extracorporeal membrane oxygenation&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Uncontrolled hypertension (systolic blood pressure [BP] &gt;150 mmHg and/or diastolic BP&#xD;
             &gt;100 mmHg), unstable angina, congestive heart failure of New York Heart Association&#xD;
             Classification Class III or IV (i.e., Class III: marked limitation in activity due to&#xD;
             symptoms, even during less-than-ordinary activity, e.g., walking short distances [20&#xD;
             100 m], comfortable only at rest; Class IV: severe limitations, experiences symptoms&#xD;
             even while at rest, mostly bedbound patients), serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring&#xD;
             treatment (exceptions: atrial fibrillation, paroxysmal supraventricular tachycardia),&#xD;
             history of myocardial infarction within 12 months prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects with a history of congenital long QT syndrome or of Torsades de pointes;&#xD;
             subjects with bradycardia (&lt;60 bpm), heart block (excluding 1st degree block, being PR&#xD;
             interval prolongation only); subjects with any of the following findings on&#xD;
             electrocardiogram (ECG): QTc interval &gt;470 msec in women OR &gt;450 msec in men; subjects&#xD;
             requiring any drugs known to prolong the QTc interval, including antiarrhythmic&#xD;
             medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Shock or hypotension requiring vasoactive peptides, such as dopamine, norepinephrine,&#xD;
             epinephrine, or dobutamine&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Renal function impairment with creatinine ≥2 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Liver function impairment with total bilirubin ≥2 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Platelet count &lt;50,000/µL&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Multi-organ failure&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of an allergic reaction or hypersensitivity to the study drug or any component&#xD;
             of the study drug formulation&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Use of systemic corticosteroids, nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs, antibiotics,&#xD;
             and antiviral drugs that are not part of the standard of care&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Presence of any uncontrolled concomitant illness (e.g., bacterial sepsis or invasive&#xD;
             fungal infection), or other serious illness and medical conditions, or other medical&#xD;
             history, including laboratory results, which, in the Investigator's opinion, would be&#xD;
             likely to interfere with their participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Pregnancy or breast-feeding (for women)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Fatih M Uckun, M.D., PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Reven Pharmaceutical</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>James D Carlson, Pharm.D.</last_name>
    <phone>701-429-4092</phone>
    <email>james.carlson@reven.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Natalie M Pizzimenti, M.S.</last_name>
    <phone>586-242-9590</phone>
    <email>natalie.pizzmenti@reven.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Adult</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acute Lung Injury</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypoxia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

