<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4614">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04355754</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Ventil-COVID-19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04355754</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ventil Device Usefulness in Mechanically Ventilated ICU Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Assesment of Usefulness of Ventil Device for Mechanical Ventilation in ICU Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical University of Gdansk</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ministry of Science and Higher Education, Poland</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical University of Gdansk</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      During Covid-19 pandemic many patients require mechanical ventilation due to disastrous&#xD;
      impact of SARS-CoV-2 on lungs. In several countries there is a shortage of ICU beds and&#xD;
      ventilators. Critically ill patients are treated outside ICUs. Doctors are facing ethical&#xD;
      dilemmas who they should treat with ventilation, who should receive ventilator and who should&#xD;
      but will not. In ICUs or step down units or in nursery homes there are also patients beyond&#xD;
      hope treated - very often they are dependent on mechanical ventilation. Some attempts to&#xD;
      invent a device that could replace complex machines in patients with anticipated poor outcome&#xD;
      have been made. Ventil was used in clinical scenarios for separate lung ventilation with good&#xD;
      effect. As a flow divider it has a potential to ventilate 2 patients at the same time. In the&#xD;
      study Ventil will ventilate one patient and instead of the second there will be an artificial&#xD;
      lung. Tidal volumes, minute ventilation, PEEP set and final will be checked. Ppeak, Pmean,&#xD;
      Pplat, Cdyn, airway resistance, EtCO2, Sat O2, HR, SAP, DAP will be monitored every 2 hrs, as&#xD;
      well as blood-gas analysis (every 8 hrs).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      During Covid-19 pandemic many patients require mechanical ventilation due to disastrous&#xD;
      impact of SARS-CoV-2 on lungs. In several countries there is a shortage of ICU beds and&#xD;
      ventilators. Critically ill patients are treated outside ICUs. Doctors are facing ethical&#xD;
      dilemmas who they should treat with ventilation, who should receive ventilator and who should&#xD;
      but will not.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before pandemic in ICUs there had always been patients who required mechanical ventilation&#xD;
      because of extrapulmonary reasons as well as palliative cases or those in vegetative&#xD;
      condition. Most of these patients require just a simple ventilator, not a sophisticated mode&#xD;
      of ventilation. Some attempts to invent a device that could replace complex machines in&#xD;
      patients with anticipated poor outcome have been made. Ventil was used in clinical scenarios&#xD;
      for separate lung ventilation with good effect. VENTIL device, a flow divider, theoretically&#xD;
      allows for independent, fully automated synchronous ventilation of 2 patients with use of&#xD;
      only one respirator. In the shortage of respirators (ex. terrorist attack, natural disasters)&#xD;
      device allows also to ventilate in classical system two patients using single respirator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ventil - independent lung ventilation system was constructed by engineers from Nalecz&#xD;
      Institute of Biocybernetics and Biomedical Engineering of Polish Academy of Science. Ventil&#xD;
      was tested in the clinical scenario - it's safety had been confirmed. Several years ago the&#xD;
      working prototypes of the device, after approval of Ethical Committee, was tested in about&#xD;
      150 patients, who were ventilated with independent synchronous lung ventilation and had been&#xD;
      found useful.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The idea of the study is to check the usefulness of the device (modern version) in ICU&#xD;
      patients who can be ventilated with volume -controlled mode of ventilation as an attempt to&#xD;
      use single device for ventilation of 2 patients. At this moment, according to several&#xD;
      scientific societies, sharing mechanical ventilators should not be attempted because it&#xD;
      cannot be done safely with current equipment. However, it is possible that using a designed&#xD;
      flow divider will allow safe ventilation in patients without needs for complicated modes of&#xD;
      ventilation. Then maybe it will be possible to release some ventilators and to use them in&#xD;
      patients in severe condition, mainly in the era of extreme ventilator shortage. In the study&#xD;
      Ventil will ventilate one patient and instead of the second, there will be an artificial&#xD;
      lung. Tidal volumes, minute ventilation, PEEP set and final will be checked. Ppeak, Pmean,&#xD;
      Pplat, Cdyn, airway resistance, EtCO2, Sat O2, HR, SAP, DAP will be monitored (every 2 hrs),&#xD;
      as well as blood-gas analysis (every 8 hrs)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The flow divider is connected to the ventilator. Half of the fresh gas flows to the patient, hallf to the artificial lung ( 1:1 ratio). For adequate ventilation tidal volume set on the ventilator is then doubled. Chosen respiratory and circulatory parameters are beeing noted.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of cases in which it was necessary to stop using Ventil and to step- back to ventilation without this flow divider</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Ventil will be removed from the patient-ventilator circiuit in case of episodes of desaturation &lt;90% (in pts without COPD) without reversibel reason; need for FiO2 increase by 10%; need for switch to other than CMV mode of ventillation need for neuromucular blockade or for deepen sedation because of assynchrony between patient and venilator cummulation of CO2&gt;45 mm Hg (in pts without COPD) not responding to the increase of minute ventilation for 30 minutes; if Pplat &gt;30 cmH2O; in case of new haemodynamic disturbances that cannot be explaned by other reasons; in case of increase or decrease of BP by 20%; increase or decrease of HR by 20%; in case of occurence of clinically important heart rhythm disturbances</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Respiratory Insufficiency</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>mechanically ventilated patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adult ICU patients who are mechanically ventilated and who do not require complex modes of ventilation.&#xD;
A designated flow divider (Ventil) will be used to divide inspiratory gas flow from ventilator in two separate streams - one to the patient and the second to the artificial lung</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ventil - a gas flow divider</intervention_name>
    <description>Checking ventilation parameters set and obtained and clinical parameters while ventilating the patient and an artificial lung simultaneously, using inspiratory flow divider.</description>
    <arm_group_label>mechanically ventilated patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ICU patients who require mechanical ventilation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who require complex modes of ventilation will not be recruited&#xD;
&#xD;
        The sudy in an individual patient be discontinued if case of:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Respiratory Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  episodes of desaturation &lt;90% (in pts without COPD) without reversibel reason&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  need for FiO2 increase by 10%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  need for switch to other than CMV mode of ventillation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  need for neuromucular blockade or for deepen sedation because of assynchrony between&#xD;
             patient and venilator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  cummulation of CO2&gt;45 mm Hg (in pts without COPD) not responding to the increase of&#xD;
             minute ventilation for 30 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pplat &gt;30 cmH2O&#xD;
&#xD;
        Circulatory criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  New haemodynamic disturbances that cannot be explaned by other reasons&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ↑ or ↓of BP by 20%&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ↑ or ↓of HR by 20%&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  clinically important heart rhythm disturbances&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Radoslaw Owczuk, prof</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Medical University of Gdansk</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Radoslaw Owczuk, prof</last_name>
    <phone>+48583493270</phone>
    <email>r.owczuk@gumed.edu.pl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Magdalena A Wujtewicz, dr</last_name>
    <phone>+48583493270</phone>
    <email>magwuj@gumed.edu.pl</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical University of Gdansk</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gdansk</city>
        <zip>80-214</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Magdalena A Wujtewicz</last_name>
      <phone>+48583493357</phone>
      <email>magwuj@gumed.edu.pl</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Radoslaw Owczuk</last_name>
      <phone>605408140</phone>
      <email>r.owczuk@gumed.edu.pl</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 21, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 27, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Medical University of Gdansk</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Radoslaw Owczuk</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>full professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>critically ill patient</keyword>
  <keyword>intensive care unit</keyword>
  <keyword>mechanical ventilation</keyword>
  <keyword>pandemic</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Insufficiency</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Valve Insufficiency</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

