<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="917">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04649515</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SCT-301</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04649515</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of TY027, a Treatment for COVID-19, in Humans</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase 3 Multi-Site, Randomised, Placebo Controlled, Double Blind, Single Dose Study of TY027 for Early Treatment of COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tychan Pte Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tychan Pte Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The emergence &amp; rapid spread of the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) since December 2019&#xD;
      across 188 countries globally has become a major public health crisis. COVID-19 was declared&#xD;
      a pandemic by the World Health Organisation on 11 March 2020. To date, tens of millions of&#xD;
      cases have been reported and over 3% of these cases have died. COVID-19 is an acute&#xD;
      respiratory disease caused by the novel SARS-CoV-2 virus from the Betacoronavirus genus, just&#xD;
      like SARS-CoV and MERS-CoV. SARS-CoV-2 is primarily transmitted person-to-person through&#xD;
      respiratory droplets/close contact. Fomite transmission has also been shown as a transmission&#xD;
      route. Common respiratory symptoms such as fever, sore throat, cough &amp; shortness of breath,&#xD;
      may appear 2 - 14 days after exposure. About 20% of infected cases progress to severe disease&#xD;
      resulting in an estimated 2 - 5% mortality rate. With the unrelenting increase in cases being&#xD;
      reported worldwide, there is thus an urgent need for therapeutics to be developed to treat&#xD;
      disease &amp; reduce further transmission in order to disrupt the ongoing pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To date, there are no specific proven antiviral treatment to prevent disease progression from&#xD;
      mild to severe respiratory dysfunction among COVID-19 patients. Supportive care is&#xD;
      recommended for symptom relief &amp; for severe cases. Numerous vaccine candidates against&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 are under development. Tychan's TY027, a fully engineered human IgG, is one of the&#xD;
      first few biologics in the world, specifically targeting SARS-CoV-2, to enter human clinical&#xD;
      trials. Preliminary data from our phase 1 healthy volunteer trial (SCT-001;&#xD;
      ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier NCT04429529) reveals that TY027 is safe &amp; well-tolerated up to&#xD;
      20 mg/kg tested. A total of 10 adverse events (AEs) were observed, all were of mild in&#xD;
      intensity with none resulting in subject withdrawal from the study. There were no serious&#xD;
      adverse events &amp; no clinically relevant trends in mean clinical laboratory, physical&#xD;
      examinations, vital signs or ECG results were observed. Pharmacokinetic profile of subjects&#xD;
      across dose cohorts 1 - 4, up to Day 14, were comparable to those typical of human IgG1&#xD;
      antibody with serum concentrations declining in a biphasic manner. Exposure of TY027, based&#xD;
      on Cmax, increased in a linear &amp; generally dose proportional manner. It is anticipated that&#xD;
      TY027, when administered to acutely infected COVID-19 patients, could reduce disease&#xD;
      severity. It may potentially also be used as a prophylaxis against COVID-19 amongst high risk&#xD;
      contacts.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 3 Multi-Site, Randomised, Placebo Controlled, Double Blind, Single Dose Study&#xD;
      of TY027 for Early Treatment of COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Efficacy and safety of single dose IV infusion of TY027 in COVID-19 patients will be&#xD;
      assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of 1,305 COVID-19 patients will be enrolled. The first 15 patients will be randomised&#xD;
      1:1:1 to receive either (i) a single fixed dose of 1,500 mg TY027, (ii) a single fixed dose&#xD;
      of 2,000 mg TY027 or (iii) Placebo (N = 5 per group) for initial safety assessment. This&#xD;
      safety assessment will comprise the safety review of clinical signs, adverse events (AEs) and&#xD;
      laboratory test results up to Day 3 post-dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subsequent patients will be randomised 1:1 to receive either a single fixed dose of 2,000 mg&#xD;
      TY027 (2,000 mg TY027 group) or Placebo (Placebo group) (N = 645 per group).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will be inpatient for up to 7 days post-dosing and followed up on Days 14 and&#xD;
      28.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If a patient becomes clinically well enough for discharge before Day 7, at the discretion of&#xD;
      attending physician, collection of subsequent events/parameters such as abbreviated physical&#xD;
      examinations, vital signs, clinical laboratory assessments, pharmacodynamic assessment,&#xD;
      biomarker assessment, disseminated intravascular coagulation assessment scheduled after&#xD;
      discharge will no longer be feasbile. Conversely, if a patient was to be hospitalised beyond&#xD;
      7 days for medically indicated reasons, daily monitoring and medical assessment will&#xD;
      continue, with any additional ad hoc sampling to be recorded as unscheduled visit(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Remote monitoring through a telephone or video call will be performed on days post-discharge&#xD;
      as per originally scheduled in schedule of events, as well as on Day 14 while patients are&#xD;
      serving their quarantine order or has been discharged home.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All discharged patients are to contact the Principal Investigator or the study team as soon&#xD;
      as possible should they experience a worsening of their condition, or if they are admitted to&#xD;
      hospital for COVID-19-related symptoms, before their Day 28 visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Final safety and efficacy analysis of all patients will be assessed at the end of the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 4, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants are assigned to either treatment or placebo</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the efficacy of a single dose intravenous (IV) infusion of TY027 in reducing disease progression, defined as progression to score 4 and below on COVID scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Within the first 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of COVID-19 patients with disease progression, defined as progression to score 4 and below on the COVID Scale, within the first 14 days after a single dose IV infusion of TY027 as compared to placebo</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of AEs (grade 3 and above) and SAEs in COVID-19 patients</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of AEs (grade 3 and above) and SAEs in COVID-19 patients after a single dose IV infusion of TY027 as compared to placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All cause mortality rate</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>All cause mortality rate by Day 28 in COVID-19 patients who receive a single dose IV infusion of TY027 as compared to placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects in categories 4, 3, 2 and 1 of the COVID scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of subjects in categories 4, 3, 2 and 1 of the COVID scale at Day 7, Day 14 and Day 28</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of days COVID-19 patients require supplemental oxygen, high flow oxygen, non-invasive and invasive mechanical ventilation (if applicable)</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days COVID-19 patients require supplemental oxygen, high flow oxygen, non-invasive and invasive mechanical ventilation (if applicable) after a single dose IV infusion of TY027 as compared to placebo up to Day 28</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of COVID-19 patients tested negative for SARS-CoV-2 via reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of COVID-19 patients tested negative for SARS-CoV-2 via reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) at Day 3, Day 5, Day 7, Day 14 and Day 28 after a single dose IV infusion of TY027 as compared to placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of COVID-19 patients with a minimum of 0.5 log time-weighted viral load reduction from saliva samples, via sub-genomic qRT-PCR</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7 post-dose or day of discharge, whichever is earlier</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of COVID-19 patients with a minimum of 0.5 log time-weighted viral load reduction from saliva samples, via sub-genomic qRT-PCR, at Day 7 post-dose or day of discharge, whichever is earlier, as compared to baseline between study groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1305</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronavirus Disease-2019 (COVID-19)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TY027 1,500 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>1,500 mg of TY027 will be administered via IV infusion over a period of 30 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TY027 2,000 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>2,000 mg of TY027 will be administered via IV infusion over a period of 30 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo will be administered via IV infusion over a period of 30 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TY027</intervention_name>
    <description>TY027 Injection, (100 mg/5 mL/Vial), SARS-CoV-2 Monoclonal Antibody (mAb) - 1,500 mg of TY027</description>
    <arm_group_label>TY027 1,500 mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TY027</intervention_name>
    <description>TY027 Injection, (100 mg/5 mL/Vial), SARS-CoV-2 Monoclonal Antibody (mAb) - 2,000 mg of TY027</description>
    <arm_group_label>TY027 2,000 mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>0.9% saline</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Symptomatic and RT-PCR confirmed COVID-19 within 6 days from symptom onset.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Has any one of the following factors associated with disease progression:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Elevated lactate dehydrogenase (LDH)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Elevated C reactive protein (CRP)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Lymphocyte count below normal limit&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Age 40 and above&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. History of well-controlled diabetes, hypertension, chronic obstructive lung&#xD;
                  disease or ischemic heart diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Stable chronic renal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. History of asthma&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Disease outcome score of 6, 7 or 8 based on the COVID Scale&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Willing to comply with the requirements of the study protocol and attend scheduled&#xD;
             study visits&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Can give written informed consent approved by the Ethical Review Board governing the&#xD;
             site&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Aged below 21 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Female who is pregnant or breast-feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. With the following conditions, but not limited to:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Known or suspected congenital or acquired immunodeficiency; or receipt of&#xD;
                  immunomodulation therapy such as anti-cancer chemotherapy or radiation therapy;&#xD;
                  or long-term systemic corticosteroid therapy defined as prednisone or equivalent&#xD;
                  for more than 2 consecutive weeks within the past 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Child-Pugh Class C chronic liver disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Renal insufficiency with an estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) &lt; 30&#xD;
                  mL/min/1.73m2 calculated by the CKD-EPI formula&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Suspected or confirmed active bacterial, fungal or mycobacterial infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of any allergic reaction to monoclonal antibodies&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Currently enrolled in another COVID-19 investigational drug study&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Previously enrolled in a COVID-19 investigational vaccine study&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any medical condition, which in the opinion of the Investigator, will compromise the&#xD;
             safety of the patient&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jenny Low, MBBS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Singapore General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Justin Ng, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+65 69046055</phone>
    <email>justin@tychanltd.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Anjali Baglody, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>+65 69046055</phone>
    <email>anjalib@tychanltd.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Singapore General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Singapore</city>
        <zip>169856</zip>
        <country>Singapore</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Singapore</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 26, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 2, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Coronavirus Disease-2019</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>Monoclonal Antibody</keyword>
  <keyword>Infectious diseases</keyword>
  <keyword>Phase 3 study</keyword>
  <keyword>Singapore</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

