<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1524">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04595240</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Semen analysis post covid-19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04595240</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Semen Analysis Changes in Covid-19 Positivepatients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Semen Analysis Changes in Covid-19 Positive Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The viral pandemic of the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), generated by a novel mutated&#xD;
      severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2), has become a serious worldwide&#xD;
      public health emergency, evolving exponentially. While the main organ targeted in this&#xD;
      disease is the lungs, other vital organs, such as the heart and kidney, may be implicated.&#xD;
      The main host receptor of the SARS-CoV-2 is angiotensin converting enzyme 2 (ACE2), a major&#xD;
      component of the renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system (RAAS). The ACE2 is also involved in&#xD;
      testicular male regulation of steroidogenesis and spermatogenesis. As the SARS-CoV-2 may have&#xD;
      the potential to infect the testis via ACE2 and adversely affect male reproductive system.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A recent report published in JAMA Network Open revealed that in an analysis 38 semen samples&#xD;
      from COVID-19 patients, 6 (four at the acute stage of infection and, alarmingly, two who were&#xD;
      recovering) tested positive for the virus by RT-PCR.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Importantly, at this point, the investigators have no idea whether the actual virus was&#xD;
      viable and infectious. Nevertheless, the possibility that this coronavirus could have a&#xD;
      pathophysiological impact on the testes was suggested by additional data indicating that&#xD;
      active COVID-19 infection dramatically reduced the testosterone-to-LH ratio, suggesting a&#xD;
      significant impact on the responsiveness of Leydig cells to LH stimulation In many ways, the&#xD;
      investigators should not be surprised by these observations because the blood-testes barrier&#xD;
      is known to offer little defense against viral invasion, given the wide range of pathogenic&#xD;
      viruses (HIV, hepatitis, mumps, papilloma) that are known to be capable of damaging the&#xD;
      testes and rendering the host infertile.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The angiotensin system plays a critical role in the survival and functionality of human&#xD;
      spermatozoa but also creates a vulnerability to COVID-19 attack. Angiotensin 1 is a&#xD;
      biologically inactive decapeptide that is cleaved by ACE1 to create angiotensin II, which in&#xD;
      turn activates the AT1R and AG2R receptors, both of which are present in these cells.&#xD;
      Angiotensin II is further processed by ACE2 to generate angiotensin 1-7 which binds the MAS&#xD;
      receptor activating PI3K. The latter then phosphorylates AKT, which maintains cell viability&#xD;
      by phosphorylating key regulators of sperm apoptosis such as BAD. As long as BAD is&#xD;
      phosphorylated, it is held in abeyance by a 14-3-3 keeper protein. However, if the PI3/AKT&#xD;
      pathway becomes compromised, BAD dephosphorylates, is released from its association with&#xD;
      14-3-3, and moves to the mitochondria where it inactivates anti-apoptotic factors and&#xD;
      promotes the intrinsic apoptotic cascade. The spike protein on COVID-19 specifically targets&#xD;
      ACE2 and in so doing removes an important stimulus for PI3K/AKT, thereby compromising sperm&#xD;
      viability. Subsequent to COVID-19 binding, the ectodomain of ACE2 may be removed by ADAM&#xD;
      proteases and shed from the sperm surface. Alternatively proteases from the TMPRSS-family,&#xD;
      either as intrinsic components of the sperm plasma membrane or delivered by seminal&#xD;
      prostasomes, can facilitate fusion between the virus and the sperm surface by cleaving ACE2&#xD;
      and the viral spike proteins (S1 and S2) at the sites indicated by dashed lines, thereby&#xD;
      completing the transformation of this cell from procreating gamete to viral vector.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An additional concern of the COVID-19 pandemic that might impact male fertility is fever.&#xD;
      Particularly high and sustained elevation in body temperature is a major manifestation of the&#xD;
      COVID-19 pandemic, which complicates more than 80% of patients. The concept that fever and&#xD;
      elevation of testicular temperature result in impairment of spermatogenesis is widely&#xD;
      accepted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      More importantly, emerging evidence indicates that a subgroup of patients with severe&#xD;
      COVID-19 might have a secondary cytokine storm syndrome (hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis).&#xD;
      This is an underrecognized, hyperinflammatory syndrome characterized by sustained fever, with&#xD;
      fulminant and fatal hypercytokinemia with multiorgan failure. These patients have a&#xD;
      particular serum blood cytokine profile with cytopenia and hyperferritinemia. These findings&#xD;
      also suggest that immunomodulatory therapy (IL-6 antagonist) may improve mortality rate&#xD;
      considerably in these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As cytokines contribute to testicular function and maintenance of male reproductive health,&#xD;
      and to the pathologies associated with their abnormal activity in this organ,&#xD;
      COVID-19-induced changes in cytokines profile may have further implications to male&#xD;
      fertility. In addition, immunomodulatory therapies may provoke potential long-term effects on&#xD;
      male fertility and are a matter of concern. Furthermore, cytokine microenvironment deviations&#xD;
      within the testis may have tumorigenic adverse effects on the cellular level, leading&#xD;
      eventually to testicular cancer, a second long-term matter of concern.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim of the study :&#xD;
&#xD;
      Know the Effect of covid-19 on spermatogenesis&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 15, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 15, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>changes of semen volume in (ML)by covid-19 from normal values.</measure>
    <time_frame>72days after infection</time_frame>
    <description>semen analysis taken by 72day of infection to see the effect on the new cycle of spermatogenesis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>changes of sperm concentration in (million/ml) by covid-19 from normal values.</measure>
    <time_frame>72days after infection</time_frame>
    <description>semen analysis taken by 72day of infection to see the effect on the new cycle of spermatogenesis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>changes of sperm morphology in (percentage of normal forms) by covid-19 from normal values.</measure>
    <time_frame>72days after infection</time_frame>
    <description>semen analysis taken by 72day of infection to see the effect on the new cycle of spermatogenesis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>changes of sperm motility in percentage of (A+B) by covid-19 from normal values.</measure>
    <time_frame>72days after infection</time_frame>
    <description>semen analysis taken by 72day of infection to see the effect on the new cycle of spermatogenesis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>changes of semen volume in (ML) by covid-19 from from the first sample</measure>
    <time_frame>after 72 days of the first sample</time_frame>
    <description>semen analysis taken by 72day of the first negative swab of covid-19 to see the effect on the new cycle of spermatogenesisand to compare with the first sample which done during infection.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>changes of sperm concentration in (million /ML) by covid-19 from from the first sample</measure>
    <time_frame>after 72 days of the first sample</time_frame>
    <description>semen analysis taken by 72day of the first negative swab of covid-19 to see the effect on the new cycle of spermatogenesisand to compare with the first sample which done during infection.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>changes of sperm morphology in percentage of normal form by covid-19 from from the first sample</measure>
    <time_frame>after 72 days of the first sample</time_frame>
    <description>semen analysis taken by 72day of the first negative swab of covid-19 to see the effect on the new cycle of spermatogenesisand to compare with the first sample which done during infection.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>changes of sperm motility in percentage of (A+B) by covid-19 from from the first sample</measure>
    <time_frame>after 72 days of the first sample</time_frame>
    <description>semen analysis taken by 72day of the first negative swab of covid-19 to see the effect on the new cycle of spermatogenesisand to compare with the first sample which done during infection.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>semen analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>semen analysis</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        men with th mentioned criteria&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  adult male patient age younger than 45 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no history of fertility disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  good body built and secondary sexual charcter .&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  congenital anomalies of the testis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronically ill patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  proplems of male fertility&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  males with varicocele&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  sexual performance disorders .&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>ahmed a abdel moniem, md</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mostafa Kamel</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assiut</city>
        <zip>71511</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 19, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 19, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 19, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>mostafa kamel abdel rahman abdel aal</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

