<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1801">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04669990</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>749-2020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04669990</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Remdesivir and Convalescent Plasma Therapy for Treatment of COVID-19 Infection in Nepal : A Registry Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Remdesivir and Convalescent Plasma Therapy for Treatment of COVID-19 Infection in Nepal : A Registry Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nepal Health Research Council</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Nepal Health Research Council</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The pandemic COVID-19 does not have an established treatment. Clinical trials of antiviral&#xD;
      drugs against SARS CoV-2 are currently in progress. Clinical study done by NIH which included&#xD;
      1059 patients indicated that those who received Remdesivir had a median recovery time of 11&#xD;
      days as compared with 15 days in those who received placebo. Remdesivir has recently received&#xD;
      full approval for COVID-19 by US FDA, and emergency use authorization (EUA) by multiple&#xD;
      countries including European Commission and Indian Health Service. Remdesivir appears to&#xD;
      demonstrate the most benefit in those with severe COVID-19 on supplemental oxygen. The NIH&#xD;
      Panel recommends using Remdesivir for 5 days or until hospital discharge, whichever comes&#xD;
      first. The interim analysis of WHO's SOLIDARITY trial, however, failed to show mortality&#xD;
      benefit with Remdesivir. Review of literature suggests the transfusion of convalescent plasma&#xD;
      has been used successfully in observational and retrospective studies. A recent metanalysis&#xD;
      showed that convalescent plasma reduced mortality by 57% compared to matched-patients&#xD;
      receiving standard treatments. The objective of NHRC sponsored initial clinical study&#xD;
      protocol (Convalescent Plasma study) was to provide a coordinated approach for collection and&#xD;
      preparation, distribution and guidance for safe and effective administration of convalescent&#xD;
      plasma with antibodies against SAR CoV-2 for treatment of patients with COVID-19 infection&#xD;
      who are most likely to benefit from this investigational treatment. On August 9th, 2020, the&#xD;
      Government of Nepal gave permission to use Remdesivir in COVID-19 patients of Nepal only as a&#xD;
      study drug when the original protocol was amended to add a second study arm to use Remdesivir&#xD;
      for treatment of patients with moderate to severe COVID-19. The enrollment goal of these two&#xD;
      protocols have been reached and collection of study data will be completed by the end of&#xD;
      October 2020. On October 18th, the GoN MoHP also announced and directed to provide access for&#xD;
      Remdesivir directly through the pharmacies. Therefore, this registry study has been designed&#xD;
      to replace the compassionate use study of Remdesivir and Convalescent plasma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The pandemic COVID-19 does not have an established treatment. Although small studies have&#xD;
      demonstrated some successes of few antiviral and immunomodulatory agents, either their data&#xD;
      so far are not very encouraging (e.g. Hydroxychloroquine and Antiretroviral Protease&#xD;
      Inhibitors) or clinical trials of newly introduced drugs are currently in progress and not&#xD;
      available in Nepal. Review of literature suggests the transfusion of convalescent plasma has&#xD;
      been used successfully in small observational and retrospective studies. A recent metanalysis&#xD;
      showed that convalescent plasma reduced mortality by 57% compared to matched-patients&#xD;
      receiving standard treatments. While multiple antiviral drugs are undergoing clinical trials&#xD;
      and there is no established antiviral agents against COVID-19, the infectious diseases&#xD;
      guidelines suggest use of Remdesivir among hospitalized patients with severe COVID-19&#xD;
      patients (Conditional recommendation, moderate certainty of evidence). Clinical study done by&#xD;
      NIH which included 1059 patients indicated that those who received Remdesivir had a median&#xD;
      recovery time of 11 days as compared with 15 days in those who received placebo. Remdesivir&#xD;
      has received emergency use authorization for COVID-19 by US FDA, European Commission, and&#xD;
      Indian Health Service. Remdesivir appears to demonstrate the most benefit in those with&#xD;
      severe COVID-19 on supplemental oxygen. The NIH Panel recommends using Remdesivir for 5 days&#xD;
      or until hospital discharge, whichever comes first. The interim analysis of WHO's SOLIDARITY&#xD;
      trial, however, failed to show mortality benefit with Remdesivir.The objective of initial&#xD;
      clinical protocol (Convalescent Plasma study) was to provide a coordinated approach for&#xD;
      collection and preparation, distribution and guidance for safe and effective administration&#xD;
      of convalescent plasma with antibodies against SAR CoV-2 for treatment of patients with&#xD;
      COVID-19 infection who are most likely to benefit from this investigational treatment. On&#xD;
      August 9th, 2020, the Government of Nepal gave permission to use Remdesivir in COVID-19&#xD;
      patients of Nepal only as a study drug when the original protocol was been amended to add a&#xD;
      second study arm for use of Remdesivir for treatment of patients with moderate to severe&#xD;
      COVID-19. The enrollment goal of these two protocols have been reached and collection of&#xD;
      study data will be completed by the end of October 2020. On October 18th, the GoN MoHP also&#xD;
      announced and directed to provide access for Remdesivir directly through the pharmacies.&#xD;
      Therefore, this registry study has been designed to replace the compassionate use study of&#xD;
      Remdesivir and Convalescent plasma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 19, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 19, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Demographics of recipients</measure>
    <time_frame>9 Months</time_frame>
    <description>- type of patients receiving plasma therapy : Age in Years, Sex: M/F</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Co-morbidity of recipient</measure>
    <time_frame>9 Months</time_frame>
    <description>- recipient comorbidities: Smoking, Diabetes, Heart disease, Chronic lung disease, chronic liver disease, cancer, organ transplant, HIV infection, TB. HIV, HBV, HCV, Syphillis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events of convalescent COVID-19 plasma and Remdesivir Therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>9 Months</time_frame>
    <description>any expected and unexpected adverse events during or after treatment (upto 7 days)&#xD;
any other complications related or unrelated to plasma transfusion and Remdesivir during hospital stay</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital and ICU length of stay</measure>
    <time_frame>9 Months</time_frame>
    <description>- number of days of hospital stay and ICU stay</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Disposition of patients including survival</measure>
    <time_frame>9 Months</time_frame>
    <description>- condition at discharge: complete recovery, partial recovery with complications, death</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2000</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Remdesivir</intervention_name>
    <description>The objective of this Registry study is to continue to collect safety and outcome data for COVID-19 patients who are treated with Remdesivir and convalescent plasma therapy (CPT).</description>
    <other_name>Convalescent Plasma</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients will be recruited from all COVID-19 treating hospitals of Nepal which are&#xD;
        participating in this clinical study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients who receive treatment with CPT or Remdesivir will be eligible for the&#xD;
             study. Treatment decision will be based on decision of the treating physicians.&#xD;
             However, following guidelines for treatment are provided based on current standard of&#xD;
             care: For Remdesivir: Patients with severe COVID-19 infection who require to be on&#xD;
             oxygen supplementation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For convalescent plasma therapy: Patients who meet one of the following criteria are likely&#xD;
        to benefit from convalescent plasma therapy:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients on life-threatening COVID-19 infection when combined with Remdesivir.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who progress to life-threatening infection despite being on remdesivir for 48&#xD;
             hours or longer. The following definitions are used to define severe and life&#xD;
             threatening COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Severe COVID-19 infection is defined by one or more of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Shortness of breath (dyspnea)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Respiratory frequency ≥ 30/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Blood oxygen saturation ≤ 93%&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Partial pressure of arterial oxygen to fraction of inspired oxygen ratio &lt; 300&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Lung infiltrates increased more than 50% within 24 to 48 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
        Life-threatening COVID-19 infection is defined as one or more of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Respiratory failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Septic shock&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Multiple organ dysfunction or failure&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. If the diagnosis is not confirmed with PCR or similar alternative tests for COVID-19&#xD;
             infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Any patient with contraindications for receiving plasma transfusion should not receive&#xD;
             plasma&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any patient with contraindications for receiving Remdesivir should not receive&#xD;
             Remdesivir&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Janak Koirala, MD,MPH</last_name>
    <phone>9818762117</phone>
    <phone_ext>+977</phone_ext>
    <email>clinicaltrialsnepal@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Saroj Bhattarai, M.Sc</last_name>
    <phone>9840388970</phone>
    <phone_ext>+977</phone_ext>
    <email>bhattaraisaroj23@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Narayani Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birgunj</city>
        <country>Nepal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Uday N Singh, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seti Provincial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dhangadi</city>
        <country>Nepal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sher B Kamar, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>BP Koirala Institute of Health Sciences (BPKIHS)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dharān Bāzār</city>
        <country>Nepal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Krishna Pokhrel, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bheri Provincial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nepalgunj</city>
        <country>Nepal</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rajan Pandey, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Nepal</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 15, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 15, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Nepal Health Research Council</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. Pradip Gyanwali,MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Member-Secretary</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

