<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="929">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04408456</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IEC-04/2020-1624</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04408456</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy of Hydroxychloroquine (HCQ) as Post Exposure Prophylaxis (PEP) for Prevention of COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>PEP-CQ</acronym>
  <official_title>Efficacy of Hydroxychloroquine (HCQ) as Post Exposure Prophylaxis (PEP) for Prevention of COVID-19 in Asymptomatic Individual at Risk for SARS-CoV-2 Infection-A Open Level Control Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Novel corona virus (SARS-CoV-2) epidemic which stared from Wuhan in China is now a well&#xD;
      established pandemic worldwide. After Italy, Spain, Germany, United Kingdom and USA, India is&#xD;
      at the edge of becoming the next epicentre of this Pandemic. If adequate preventive and&#xD;
      therapeutic measures are not taken, India has very high risk of affecting million of people&#xD;
      with high mortality because of the large population along with very high population density.&#xD;
      At present there are no definitive therapeutic drugs or vaccine are available for the&#xD;
      treatment and prevention of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Symptomatic and supportive care are being&#xD;
      given to COVID-19 cases along with isolation and quarantine measure are being taken for the&#xD;
      suspected individual at risk for COVID-19 to limit the spread of the SARS-CoV-2 infection .&#xD;
      Among the all the drugs being used for the treatment of COVID-19, hydroxychloroquine (HCQ),&#xD;
      has given some rays of hope to battle against this deadly pandemic. HCQ has some anti viral&#xD;
      effect against SARS-CoV in vitro. HCQ is quite safe and being used in rheumatology patients&#xD;
      for lifelong without much side effect, so it allow for higher dose without any significant&#xD;
      side effects and drug-drug interaction. Recently published clinical trial suggested HCQ can&#xD;
      be used for the therapeutic purpose of the SARS-CoV-2 infection. Indian council of medical&#xD;
      research (ICMR) has advised for HCQ prophylaxis for all asymptomatic health care workers&#xD;
      involved in taking care of suspected or confirmed COVID-19 cases and all asymptomatic&#xD;
      household contacts of labarotory confirmed COVID-19 cases. But there is still lack of&#xD;
      significant scientific data to prove or disprove the efficacy of HCQ for the treatment and&#xD;
      post exposure chemo-prophylaxis for SARS-CoV-2 infection. Being a tertiary care centre we are&#xD;
      catering many states which include Punjab, hariyana, himachal Pradesh, Uttara khand, Uttar&#xD;
      Pradesh. Among this Punjab have highest population of non residential Indian (NRI) and most&#xD;
      of them have returned home. This put our institute to handle highest burden of suspected&#xD;
      cases of SARS-CoV-2 in northern India. So we have planned this open level control clinical&#xD;
      trial to evaluate the efficacy of post exposure prophylaxis (PEP) with HCQ for the prevention&#xD;
      of COVID-19 in asymptomatic individuals who are at risk for SARS-CoV-2 infection. All&#xD;
      asymptomatic individuals who have undertaken international travel in last 2 weeks and all&#xD;
      asymptomatic individual with direct contact with laboratory confirmed cases will be advised&#xD;
      for home quarantine for 2 weeks along with social distancing and personal hygiene. They will&#xD;
      be given the option for taking HCQ prophylaxis. These quarantined asymptomatic individuals&#xD;
      will be assigned into one post exposure prophylaxis (PEP) group and one control group as per&#xD;
      inclusion and exclusion criteria. Individual who will not give consent for HCQ prophylaxis&#xD;
      and those with contraindication for HCQ therapy like, hypersensitivity to HCQ or&#xD;
      4-aminoquinolone derivatives, patients with known retionopathy, cardiac arrhythmia, G6PD&#xD;
      deficiency, psoriasis and pregnancy will be directly included in the control group. All&#xD;
      symptomatic individual, and all health care workers related to suspected or proven COVID-19&#xD;
      will be excluded from the study. The PEP group will receive tablet HCQ 400 mg q 12 hourly on&#xD;
      day one followed by 400 mg once weekly for 3 weeks (total cumulative dose of 2000 mg). The&#xD;
      control group will not receive HCQ. Both the groups will receive standard care of therapy in&#xD;
      the form of home quarantine for 2 weeks along with social distancing and personal hygiene.&#xD;
      They will be followed up for 4 weeks telephonically or physically as and when required and&#xD;
      will be enquired regarding development of any COVID-19 symptoms like fever, cough, sore&#xD;
      throat, shortness of breath, diarrhoea, myalgia.During follow up nasopharyngeal and or throat&#xD;
      swab of the participants will be taken for processing reverse transcription polymerase chain&#xD;
      reaction (RTPCR) for the detection SARS-Cov-2 RNA to confirm CoVID-19. Samples for RTPCR will&#xD;
      be taken when any asymptomatic participants become symptomatic and by the 5-14 days of&#xD;
      contact in asymptomatic participants through in-hospital visit at the institute's&#xD;
      communicable disease ward isolation. The participant with RTPCR positive and with or without&#xD;
      symptoms will be defined as definite COVID-19 case and the RTPCR negative symptomatic&#xD;
      participant will be defined as probable COVID-19 case. Asymptomatic participants with&#xD;
      negative RTPCR will be defined as non-COVID case. Incidence of COVID-19 or probable COVID-19&#xD;
      or non-COVID case in previously asymptomatic participants will be compared between the PEP&#xD;
      and control groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background and rational of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Novel corona virus (SARS-CoV-2) epidemic which stared from Wuhan in China is now a well&#xD;
      established pandemic worldwide affecting more than 3 lakh people with more than 15000&#xD;
      mortality. As Italy, Spain, Germany, United Kingdom and USA have taken over from China in&#xD;
      term of highest burden of mortality, India is at the edge of becoming the next epicentre of&#xD;
      this Pandemic. Presently there are around 500 active cases of corona virus disease-19&#xD;
      (COVID-19) in India with unfortunate mortality of 8 patients as on 24th March 2020. The&#xD;
      clinical presentation of the COVID-19 varies from asymptomatic cases and mild symptoms of&#xD;
      fever, cough, sore throat, headache, myalgia, nasal congestion, diarrhea to severe pneumonia,&#xD;
      acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) requiring mechanical ventilation and even&#xD;
      multi-organ dysfunction syndrome (MODS), sepsis leading to death. If adequate preventive and&#xD;
      therapeutic measures are not taken, India has very high risk of affecting million of people&#xD;
      with high mortality because of the large population along with very high population density.&#xD;
      At present there are no definitive therapeutic drugs or vaccine are available for the&#xD;
      treatment and prevention of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Symptomatic and supportive care are being&#xD;
      given to COVID-19 cases along with isolation and quarantine measure are being taken for the&#xD;
      suspected individual at risk for COVID-19 to limit the spread of the SARS-CoV-2 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Presently many scientist and doctors are recommending many existing available drugs&#xD;
      (Ribavirin, lopinavir, Remdesivir, chloroquine, hydroxychloroquine) for SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
      for therapeutic and as well as prophylactic purpose . Among which hydroxychloroquine sulphate&#xD;
      (HCQ), a chloroquine analogue has given some rays of hope to battle against this deadly&#xD;
      pandemic. In a in vitro study researchers have found that HCQ has some anti viral effect&#xD;
      against SARS-CoV through mechanism targeted at the host cell. HCQ is quite safe drugs as it&#xD;
      is being used in rheumatology patients for lifelong therapy without much side effect, so it&#xD;
      allow for higher dose without any significant side effects and drug-drug interaction.&#xD;
      Recently published clinical trial suggested HCQ can be used for the therapeutic purpose of&#xD;
      the SARS-CoV-2 infection and many governments including USA and India have already endorse&#xD;
      that due to lack of any other better alternative drugs. ICMR has advised for HCQ prophylaxis&#xD;
      for the people who are at risk for developing SARS-CoV-2 infection, all asymptomatic health&#xD;
      care workers involved in taking care of suspected or confirmed COVID-19 cases and all&#xD;
      asymptomatic household contacts of labarotory confirmed COVID-19 cases. But there is still&#xD;
      lack of significant scientific data to prove or disprove the efficacy of HCQ for the&#xD;
      treatment and post exposure chemo-prophylaxis for SARS-CoV-2 infection management. Being a&#xD;
      tertiary care centre we are catering many states which include Punjab, hariyana, himachal&#xD;
      Pradesh, Uttara khand, Uttar Pradesh. Among this Punjab have highest population of non&#xD;
      residential Indian (NRI) and most of them have returned home. This put our institute to&#xD;
      handle highest burden of suspected cases of SARS-CoV-2 in northern India. So we have planned&#xD;
      this randomised control clinical trial to evaluate the efficacy of post exposure prophylaxis&#xD;
      (PEP) with HCQ for the prevention of COVID-19 in asymptomatic population who are at risk for&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 infection. As a research institute of national as well as international interest,&#xD;
      it is a great opportunity for us to produce such a robust data which can be utilized in&#xD;
      reforming national and international guidelines for the battle against of COVID-19 pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Details of method:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims of the study: To evaluate the efficacy of post exposure prophylaxis (PEP) with HCQ for&#xD;
      the prevention of COVID-19 in asymptomatic individual who are at risk for SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Site of Study: The study will be conducted in the special screening OPD for the SARS-CoV-2 at&#xD;
      Emergency and medical outpatient department (EMOPD &amp; MOPD) and Communicable disease ward of&#xD;
      the Post Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research (PGIMER), Chandigarh, India.&#xD;
      The study will be done under the collaboration of the department of Internal Medicine,&#xD;
      Virology and Pharmacology of the institute, PGIMER,Chandigarh.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design: It is an open label controlled clinical trial. The study will be done in two&#xD;
      groups. After screening of the suspected SARS-CoV-2 infected individuals, asymptomatic&#xD;
      quarantined individuals will be assigned into two study groups. Post exposure prophylaxis&#xD;
      (PPE) group will receive tablet HCQ 400 mg q 12 hourly on day one followed by 400 mg once&#xD;
      weekly for 3 weeks (total cumulative dose of 2000 mg). The control group will not receive&#xD;
      HCQ. Both the groups will receive standard care of therapy. Individual who will not give&#xD;
      consent for HCQ prophylaxis and those with contraindication for HCQ therapy will be directly&#xD;
      included in the control group. They will be followed up for 4 weeks telephonically or&#xD;
      physically as and when required.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Screening and Enrolment of Patients: All the suspected cases of COVID-19 will be screened as&#xD;
      per ICMR guideline at special screening OPD for the SARS-CoV-2 at Emergency and medical&#xD;
      outpatient department (EMOPD &amp; MOPD. All asymptomatic individuals who have undertaken&#xD;
      international travel in last 2 weeks and all asymptomatic individual with direct contact with&#xD;
      laboratory confirmed cases will be advised for home quarantine for 2 weeks along with social&#xD;
      distancing and personal hygiene. They will be given the option for taking HCQ prophylaxis.&#xD;
      They will be assigned into one post exposure prophylaxis (PEP) group and one control croup as&#xD;
      per inclusion and exclusion criteria after getting informed consent.Individual who will not&#xD;
      give consent for HCQ prophylaxis and patients with contraindication for HCQ therapy like,&#xD;
      hypersensitivity to HCQ or 4-aminoquinolone derivatives, patients with known retionopathy,&#xD;
      cardiac arrhythmia, G6PD deficiency, psoriasis and pregnancy will be directly included in the&#xD;
      control groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence confirmed case of COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Participant with RTPCR positive for SARS-CoV-2 and with or without symptoms will be defined as definite COVID-19 case.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of probable case of COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The participant with new onset symptoms, but RTPCR negative for SARS-CoV-2 or could not be performed for any reason will be defined as probable COVID-19 case.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse drug reaction (ADR)</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Any adverse reaction related to Hydroxychloroquine</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">325</enrollment>
  <condition>CoVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Post Exposure Prophylaxis (PEP) Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard therapy in the form of home quarantine for 2 weeks along with social distancing and personal hygiene Plus Tablet HCQ 400 mg q 12 hourly on day one followed by 400 mg once weekly for 3 weeks (total cumulative dose of 2000 mg)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard therapy in the form of home quarantine for 2 weeks along with social distancing and personal hygiene</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HCQ</intervention_name>
    <description>Tablet HCQ 400 mg q 12 hourly on day one followed by 400 mg once weekly for 3 weeks (total cumulative dose of 2000 mg)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Post Exposure Prophylaxis (PEP) Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Home quarantine for 2 weeks plus social distancing plus personal hygiene</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Post Exposure Prophylaxis (PEP) Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Asymptomatic individuals who have undertaken International travel in last 2 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Asymptomatic individual with direct contact with laboratory confirmed cases&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Symptomatic individual&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Health care worker&#xD;
&#xD;
        Individual who will not give consent for HCQ prophylaxis and patients with contraindication&#xD;
        for HCQ therapy like, hypersensitivity to HCQ or 4-aminoquinolone derivatives, patients&#xD;
        with known retionopathy, cardiac arrhythmia, G6PD deficiency, psoriasis and pregnancy will&#xD;
        be directly included in the control groups.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Deba P Dhibar, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>PGIMER, Chandigarh, India</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Post Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research (PGIMER)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chandigarh</city>
        <zip>160012</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Post Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chandigarh</city>
        <zip>160012</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 1, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 1, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 4, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Deba Prasad Dhibar</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CoVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>Hydroxychloroquine (HCQ)</keyword>
  <keyword>post exposure prophylaxis (PEP)</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data will be shared with the concerned authority and Institutional Ethics committee as and when required.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

