<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="353">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04706156</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>OSECV</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04706156</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Oral Side Effects of COVID-19 Vaccine</brief_title>
  <official_title>Oral Side Effects of COVID-19 Vaccine: A Multicenter Cross-sectional Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Masaryk University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>F.D. Roosevelt Teaching Hospital with Policlinic Banska Bystrica</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Giessen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Kiel</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Yeditepe University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Masaryk University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a multicenter cross-sectional survey-based study conducted in four European&#xD;
      countries (Czech Republic, Germany, Slovak Republic, and Turkey). An online questionnaire&#xD;
      will be utilized to collect data from volunteer subjects following the STROBE reporting&#xD;
      guidelines of cross-sectional studies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this multicentre cross-sectional survey-based study is to estimate&#xD;
      the prevalence of oral side effects of COVID-19 vaccine in the short term.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  to identify the risk factors of COVID-19 vaccine oral side effects in the short term.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  to evaluate the relationship between oral side effects and other inflammatory side&#xD;
           effects of COVID-19 vaccine in the short term.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The target population is healthcare workers as they are identified among the priority groups&#xD;
      of COVID-19 vaccine deployment plans in the EU/EEA and the UK. One more reason to select the&#xD;
      healthcare workers among different groups of the population, their higher awareness about the&#xD;
      possible vaccine-related oral side-effects so that more accurate and reliable results can be&#xD;
      obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A self-administered questionnaire will be developed, and its content validity will be tested&#xD;
      using a panel of experts. The test re-test reliability of the questionnaire will be tested by&#xD;
      30 volunteers (10 Czech, 10 Turkish, 10 German) to achieve at least a Cronbach's alpha of&#xD;
      0.70. The questionnaire will be available in five languages; Czech, English, German, Slovak&#xD;
      and Turkish. Dual forward translation and expert panels will produce equivalent Czech,&#xD;
      German, Slovak and Turkish versions of the questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The questionnaire will be composed of multiple-choice items divided into four main&#xD;
      categories; a) demographic data including gender, age, location of practice, profession, and&#xD;
      experience, b) medical anamnesis including medical comorbidities, medications, and recent&#xD;
      oral symptoms, c) COVID-19 related anamnesis including vaccination date, previous infection,&#xD;
      and exposure to infected cases, and d) vaccine side effects including inflammatory symptoms,&#xD;
      cutaneous symptoms, and oral symptoms. (Annex 1)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Ecologic or Community</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Oral Side Effects</measure>
    <time_frame>0-30 days after the COVID-19 vaccine shot</time_frame>
    <description>Dichotomous outcome for the emergence of oral side effects (e.g. ulcers, vesicles, blisters, plaque, mouth odour, bleeding gum, burning gingiva, etc) following receiving the COVID-19 vaccine.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dermatologic Side Effects</measure>
    <time_frame>0-30 days after the COVID-19 vaccine shot</time_frame>
    <description>Dichotomous outcome for the emergence of dermatologic side effects (e.g. injection site swelling, or redness, rash, urticaria, angioedema, etc) following receiving the COVID-19 vaccine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>General (common) Side Effects</measure>
    <time_frame>0-30 days after the COVID-19 vaccine shot</time_frame>
    <description>Dichotomous outcome for the emergence of typical side effects (e.g. injection site pain, injection site swelling, injection site redness, tiredness, headache, nausea, muscle pain, joint pain, fever, swollen lymph nodes (lymphadenopathy), etc) following receiving the COVID-19 vaccine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1540</enrollment>
  <condition>Oral Manifestations</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Vaccine Adverse Reaction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vaccinated Healthcare Workers (CZ)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Czech healthcare workers who received COVID-19 vaccine during the last 30 days (n=385)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vaccinated Healthcare Workers (DE)</arm_group_label>
    <description>German healthcare workers who received COVID-19 vaccine during the last 30 days (n=385)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vaccinated Healthcare Workers (SK)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Slovak healthcare workers who received COVID-19 vaccine during the last 30 days (n=385)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vaccinated Healthcare Workers (TR)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Turkish healthcare workers who received COVID-19 vaccine during the last 30 days (n=385)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>COVID-19 Vaccine</intervention_name>
    <description>Receiving coronavirus disease (COVID-19) vaccine e.g. Pfizer-BioNTech or Moderna COVID-19 Vaccine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vaccinated Healthcare Workers (CZ)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Vaccinated Healthcare Workers (DE)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Vaccinated Healthcare Workers (SK)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Vaccinated Healthcare Workers (TR)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The target population is healthcare workers as they are identified among the priority&#xD;
        groups of COVID-19 vaccine deployment plans in the EU/EEA and the UK. One more reason to&#xD;
        select the healthcare workers among different groups of the population, their higher&#xD;
        awareness about the possible vaccine-related oral side-effects so that more accurate and&#xD;
        reliable results can be obtained.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthcare workers who received COVID-19 vaccine during the last 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participating subjects should be at least 18-year-old and able to give their informed&#xD;
             consent independently.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The healthcare workers who did not receive the COVID-19 vaccine recently.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-healthcare workers who received the COVID-19 vaccine recently.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Abanoub Riad, DDS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Masaryk University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Abanoub Riad, DDS</last_name>
    <phone>+420721046024</phone>
    <email>abanoub.riad@med.muni.cz</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <link>
    <url>https://stars.library.ucf.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1306&amp;context=honorstheses</url>
    <description>Effects of the Influenza Vaccine on the Oral Cavity</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://muni.cz/go/osecv</url>
    <description>Annex 1</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Riad A, Klugar M, Krsek M. COVID-19-Related Oral Manifestations: Early Disease Features? Oral Dis. 2020 Jun 30. doi: 10.1111/odi.13516. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>32603497</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Riad A, Gad A, Hockova B, Klugar M. Oral Candidiasis in Non-Severe COVID-19 Patients: Call for Antibiotic Stewardship. Oral Surg. 2020 Sep 21. doi: 10.1111/ors.12561. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>33042219</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Riad A, Kassem I, Stanek J, Badrah M, Klugarova J, Klugar M. Aphthous stomatitis in COVID-19 patients: Case-series and literature review. Dermatol Ther. 2021 Jan 3:e14735. doi: 10.1111/dth.14735. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>33389769</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Riad A, Kassem I, Hockova B, Badrah M, Klugar M. Halitosis in COVID-19 patients. Spec Care Dentist. 2020 Nov 29. doi: 10.1111/scd.12547. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>33249615</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Riad A, Kassem I, Badrah M, Klugar M. The manifestation of oral mucositis in COVID-19 patients: A case-series. Dermatol Ther. 2020 Nov;33(6):e14479. doi: 10.1111/dth.14479. Epub 2020 Nov 8.</citation>
    <PMID>33125803</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Riad A, Kassem I, Issa J, Badrah M, Klugar M. Angular cheilitis of COVID-19 patients: A case-series and literature review. Oral Dis. 2020 Oct 11. doi: 10.1111/odi.13675. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>33043573</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Riad A, Kassem I, Hockova B, Badrah M, Klugar M. Tongue ulcers associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection: A case series. Oral Dis. 2020 Sep 5. doi: 10.1111/odi.13635. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>32889763</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Riad A, Kassem I, Badrah M, Klugar M. Acute parotitis as a presentation of COVID-19? Oral Dis. 2020 Jul 25. doi: 10.1111/odi.13571. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>32713097</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Riad A, Kassem I, Badrah M, Klugar M. COVID-19 Transient Snoring (CVTS): Clinical and Laboratory Description. J Med Virol. 2020 Dec 2. doi: 10.1002/jmv.26705. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>33289127</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID19</keyword>
  <keyword>Oral Manifestations</keyword>
  <keyword>Vaccine Adverse Reaction</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Oral Manifestations</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>In accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), the data controller is Masaryk University (MUNI) and will be used solely by MUNI for the purpose of research in area of public health. The collected data will not be accessed or used by other institutions or for any other purposes. The data will be processed and analysed during the duration of the project (approximately one year). After the project is finished, the data will be encrypted and safely stored by MU as a measure to secure the integrity of the research.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

