<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4811">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04690517</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-11-115</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04690517</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of Tracheal Ultrasound With Capnography for Intubation Confirmation During CPR Wearing PPE</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparison of Tracheal Ultrasound With Capnography for Intubation Confirmation During CPR (Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation) Wearing PPE (Personnel Protective Equipment): A Prospective Comparative Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Samsung Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Samsung Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      It is very important to ensure the tube placement in patients with cardiac arrest and&#xD;
      unrecognized misplacement of endo-tracheal tube can lead to morbidity and mortality. In&#xD;
      recent pandemic situations such as COVID-19 (Coronavirus disease-19), the number of cases of&#xD;
      cardiopulmonary resuscitation with personal protective equipment (PPE) have increased. In&#xD;
      those cases, existing methods such as auscultation and chest uprising have to be limited.&#xD;
      Quantitative waveform capnography is recommended as the gold standard for confirming correct&#xD;
      endotracheal tube placement in the 2010 American HeartAssociation (AHA) Guidelines for CPR&#xD;
      and Emergency Cardiovascular Care (ECC), but it has some well-known limitations in cardiac&#xD;
      arrest patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ultrasonography is a non-invasive, real-time diagnostic tool commonly used during&#xD;
      resuscitation. Especially, tracheal ultrasonography can be performed in real-time when the&#xD;
      tube is passed through the trachea or esophagus. Previous prospective studies revealed that&#xD;
      tracheal ultrasonography could feasibly and rapidly confirm tracheal intubation during&#xD;
      emergency intubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There have already been several studies comparing the accuracy of tracheal ultrasound and&#xD;
      capnography, but there was no study comparing the two tools under the constraints of PPE that&#xD;
      is essential in pandemic situations as in this study. This study aimed to determine the&#xD;
      accuracy of tracheal ultrasonography in assessing endotracheal tube position during CPR with&#xD;
      PPE.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      When patients in cardiopulmonary arrest enter a emergency room (ER) or patients staying in a&#xD;
      ER have a cardiopulmonary arrest, participants perform intubation and CPR. When it is judged&#xD;
      as a high-risk group with a high probability of droplet infection, all participants in&#xD;
      resuscitation team should wear personal protective equipment. Tracheal ultrasound and&#xD;
      end-tidal carbon dioxide are used to confirm the placement of tube. The gold standard is the&#xD;
      direct visualization using laryngoscope. The time it takes to confirm the placement of tube&#xD;
      is also measured.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compared with the gold standard, the accuracy of tracheal ultrasonography in assessing tube position</measure>
    <time_frame>during intubation procedure</time_frame>
    <description>The gold standard is direct visualization using laryngoscopy. Tracheal ultrasound is performed regardless of whether it is in real-time or not.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">34</enrollment>
  <condition>Cardiopulmonary Arrest</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Tracheal ultrasound</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>The patients in cardiopulmonary arrest should be performed tracheal ultrasound when tube is passed through the trachea or esophagus.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>tracheal ultrasound</intervention_name>
    <description>When checking tracheal ultrasound, several signs are used in judgements. Direct signs include reverberation artifact and double ring sign. Indirect sign means checking the bilateral lung sliding.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Tracheal ultrasound</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. cardiopulmonary arrest patients receiving emergency intubation and CPR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  2. patients judged to need to wear PPE according to the judgement of the clinician&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. sign for DNR (do not resuscitate)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  2. patients unable to perform tracheal ultrasound due to trauma of the site&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  3. patients unable to perform tracheal ultrasound due to oropharynx cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  4. patients unable to perform tracheal ultrasound due to placement of tracheal cannula&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  5. patients not used tracheal ultrasound for checking tube placement&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hi Yoon, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Samsung Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hi Yoon, Professor</last_name>
    <phone>82-10-9933-5581</phone>
    <email>wildhi.yoon@samsung.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sooyeon Kang, fellow</last_name>
    <phone>82-10-3157-4718</phone>
    <email>syrei3.kang@samsung.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Samsung Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>06351</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hee Yoon, Professor</last_name>
      <phone>82-10-9933-5581</phone>
      <email>wildhi.yoon@samsung.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Sooyeon Kang, fellow</last_name>
      <phone>82-10-3157-4718</phone>
      <email>syrei3.kang@samsung.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chou HC, Chong KM, Sim SS, Ma MH, Liu SH, Chen NC, Wu MC, Fu CM, Wang CH, Lee CC, Lien WC, Chen SC. Real-time tracheal ultrasonography for confirmation of endotracheal tube placement during cardiopulmonary resuscitation. Resuscitation. 2013 Dec;84(12):1708-12. doi: 10.1016/j.resuscitation.2013.06.018. Epub 2013 Jul 9.</citation>
    <PMID>23851048</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 21, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 27, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 27, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 27, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 30, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Arrest</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

