<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="343">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04607928</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-002518-42</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04607928</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pirfenidone Compared to Placebo in Post-COVID19 Pulmonary Fibrosis COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>FIBRO-COVID</acronym>
  <official_title>Phase-II Randomized Clinical Trial to Evaluate the Effect of Pirfenidone Compared to Placebo in Post-COVID19 Pulmonary Fibrosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Institut d'Investigació Biomèdica de Bellvitge</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institut d'Investigació Biomèdica de Bellvitge</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Study population: Patients with fibrotic lung sequelae after recovery from acute phase of&#xD;
      severe COVID19 pneumonia Objectives: To evaluate the effect of pirfenidone administered for&#xD;
      24 weeks in patients who have pulmonary fibrotic changes after suffering severe COVID19&#xD;
      pneumonia, analysed by&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  % change in forced vital capacity (FVC)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  % fibrosis in high resolution computed tomography (HRCT) of the lung&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Has been designed a clinical trial with an experimental and a control arm, with 2&#xD;
      experimental subjects per control (2:1), we will have to study 98 experimental subjects and&#xD;
      50 control subjects, in total 148 patients. Randomization will be performed using a&#xD;
      centralized electronic system (IVRS) with 2: 1 randomized concealed assignment. This&#xD;
      randomization will be done by permuted blocks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study population will be patients with fibrosing lung sequelae after recovery from severe&#xD;
      COVID19 pneumonia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a double-blind, masked, placebo-controlled clinical trial: the patient and the&#xD;
      investigator are unaware of the assigned treatment the patient receives.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will follow a total of 5 clinic visits; V0 (screening, -1 days - +42 days from&#xD;
      signing the Informed Consent), V1 (randomization), V2 (week 12), V3 (week 24 or end of&#xD;
      treatment), V4 (week 28 or follow-up).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visits Plan&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  V0 - Screening: Initially, the informed consent will be collected. Subsequently, we will&#xD;
           proceed to collect clinical variables, blood tests and radiological characteristics&#xD;
           (chest CT scan; radiological signs of fibrosis such as tractional bronchiolectasis,&#xD;
           honeycombing, loss of lung volume and reticulation).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  V1 - Randomization: Before starting the drug:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control analytics Serum pregnancy test for all women of childbearing age KBILD quality of&#xD;
      life test. This validated questionnaire will be completed by the patient following the&#xD;
      instructions of the staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Spirometry (CVF) and plethysmography (DLCO) TM6m. Extraction of blood for DNA isolation (in&#xD;
      those cases that have specifically signed the IC for genetics) and proteins (serum).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once the screening evaluation has been completed, eligibility will depend on meeting the&#xD;
      inclusion criteria and not presenting any exclusion criteria. Those cases that are not&#xD;
      eligible will be informed and an adequate explanation will be provided.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  V2 - 12 weeks after starting medication. The patient's clinical status will be collected&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  V3 - 24 weeks (end of treatment period). Clinical data and quality of life test (KBILD)&#xD;
           will be collected, and chest CT scan, spirometry-plethysmography and TM6m will be&#xD;
           performed. Blood will be drawn for protein isolation (serum).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  V4 - 28 weeks (follow-up). Clinical and analytical variables will be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will have the telephone number of the main researcher or someone from the team where&#xD;
      they can call 24 hours, which will be specified on the patient's card (where it will be&#xD;
      identified that the patient participates in this study). In case of presenting any problem or&#xD;
      side effect in the period between visits, the patient will go to the center and an additional&#xD;
      visit will be made.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pirfenidone Name: Esbriet 267 mg hard capsules Dosage: 267 mg (capsules) Manufacturer: Roche&#xD;
      Pharma AG&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study drug administration schedule: The study medication will be started at incremental&#xD;
      doses, starting with 1602 mg / day (divided into three doses every 8 hours, 267 mg capsules&#xD;
      with each meal) and, if there is no liver or associated serious events, will be increased on&#xD;
      the 7th day to full doses of 2403 mg / day. The dose increase can be extended for one more&#xD;
      week if the investigator considers it safer (slight elevation of liver enzymes, digestive&#xD;
      discomfort or clear anorexia). Subsequently, 2403 mg / day will be maintained (3 capsules in&#xD;
      each meal during the day) except if it is necessary to reduce the dose or suspend the drug&#xD;
      due to adverse effects or associated problems (at the discretion of the researcher).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Concomitant treatments prohibited:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The use of the following therapies is prohibited during study treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cytotoxic, immunosuppressant, cytokine modulators, including but not limited to&#xD;
           azathioprine, bosentan, ambrisentan, cyclophosphamide, cyclosporine, etanercept,&#xD;
           iloprost, infliximab, leukotriene antagonists, methotrexate, high doses of&#xD;
           corticosteroids (more than 15 mg / day of prednisone or equivalent for more than 20&#xD;
           days), mycophenolate mofetil, tacrolimus, montelukast, tetrathiomolybdate, TNF-α&#xD;
           inhibitors, imatinib mesylate, interferon gamma-1b, and tyrosine kinase inhibitors.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Strong CYP1A2 inhibitors (eg, Fluvoxamine, Enoxacin), P-glycoprotein inhibitors (eg,&#xD;
           Ketoconazole, erythromycin) or CYP3A4 (eg, Ketoconazole, erythromycin), or their&#xD;
           inducers (eg. Eg, rifampicin, carbamazepine, phenytoin).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Any investigational therapy in an active clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Because moderate CYP1A2 inhibitors (eg, Ciprofloxacin) increase the systemic exposure of&#xD;
           pirfenidone (Esbriet® US label 2014), if ciprofloxacin is administered, it should be&#xD;
           limited to 250 or 500 mg daily (QD), and the patient should be closely monitored.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prohibited foods: The consumption of grapefruit juice will be prohibited during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additional restriction: The use of any form of tobacco consumption will be prohibited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Criteria for patient withdrawal from the study Participation in the study is voluntary and&#xD;
      the subjects can withdraw at any time without having to give explanations and without this&#xD;
      implying a detriment to the healthcare they receive in the future.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For her part, the researcher must withdraw a subject from the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adverse event or clinical situation of the patient that, in the clinical opinion, makes&#xD;
           it necessary to withdraw from the study. Patients can interrupt the medication for up to&#xD;
           14 days, returning to the previous dose without requiring titration. If they interrupt&#xD;
           for more than 14 days, they have to gradually increase the dose. If the patient cannot&#xD;
           tolerate the minimum dose, then the treatment will be withdrawn, allowing study visits&#xD;
           to be completed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Request for withdrawal by the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Serious violation of protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Loss of follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pregnancy during the study. When a subject withdraws from the study, the investigator&#xD;
           will record the reason or reasons for withdrawal in the original documents in the&#xD;
           Medical Record.&#xD;
&#xD;
      End of clinical trial is defined as the date the last recruited patient completes the last&#xD;
      visit (LPLV). The last patient is expected to complete the last visit 4 weeks after the last&#xD;
      patient has completed treatment, which is expected to happen 14 months after the start of the&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>2:1 (treatment:placebo)</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>doble blinded, IVRSystem</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate the effect of pirfenidone on fibrotic signs induced by COVID19 infection</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To investigate the effect of pirfenidone administered for 24 weeks measuring the number of patients who have pulmonary fibrotic changes from baseline after suffering severe COVID19 pneumonia, analysed by&#xD;
Change From Baseline in % in forced vital capacity (FVC)&#xD;
Change From Baseline % fibrosis in high resolution computed tomography (HRCT) of the lung</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maintenance of stability or functional improvement FVC</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients who show maintenance of stability or functional improvement: stability will be considered when the FVC does not increase more than 10% or does not decrease more than 10% and the DLCO does not increase more than 15% or decreases more than 15%. An increase in% FVC greater than 10% or in DLCO greater than 15% will be considered significant improvement.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Decreased oxygen requirement for physical activity</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of decreased oxygen requirement for physical activity in patients</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Improved exercise capacity (&gt; 50 meter improvement or less decrease in% oxygen saturation) in the TM6m</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients who have improved exercise capacity (&gt; 50 meter improvement or less decrease in% oxygen saturation) in the TM6m</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospitalizations (general and due to respiratory problems)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of Hospitalizations (general and due to respiratory problems)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visits to the Emergency or Day Hospital for respiratory causes</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of Visits to the Emergency or Day Hospital for respiratory causes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lung transplantation</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients who need Lung transplantation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Death</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients who die</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">148</enrollment>
  <condition>Fibrotic Pulmonary Sequelae Post-COVID19 Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>No anti-fibrotic treatment. Patients in placebo and treatment arm may be on corticosteroid treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pirfenidone</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pirfenidone</intervention_name>
    <description>Comparing the effect of pirfenidone in avoiding establishing or progression of fibrosis induced after COVID19 infection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Comparing the effect of pirfenidone in avoiding establishing or progression of fibrosis induced after COVID19 infection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed Informed Consent Form&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to comply with the study protocol in the opinion of the Investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmation of SARS-COV2 infection in previous weeks (Confirmation of negativity or&#xD;
             no activity of SARS-COV2 before randomization using the usual tests performed in the&#xD;
             hospital), which induced severe pneumonia and ARDS, with subsequent torpid recovery&#xD;
             and/or incipient clinical-radiological signs of pulmonary fibrosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HRCT with fibrotic radiological changes of at least 5% after recovery from the acute&#xD;
             process (HRCT chest during the screening period, performed minimum after 1 month of&#xD;
             the acute phase and maximum 90 days after hospital discharge)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be able to understand the information given and sign the informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For women or men of childbearing age who are not sterile, a commitment to use&#xD;
             non-hormonal contraception during the 24-week treatment period will be required.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of systemic steroids (oral or intravenous) at doses greater than 15 mg/day one&#xD;
             month prior to randomisation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe or moderate myopathy that may associate a decrease of FVC.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe or life-limiting chronic disease prior to COVID19 infection, including severe&#xD;
             asthma, cancer, clinical dementia, IPF, or uncontrolled ischemic cardiomyopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with pirfenidone or nintedanib prior to Covid19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant treatment with significant interactions with pirfenidone (such as&#xD;
             fluvoxamine).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in any other investigational trial throughout the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active smoking.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Relevant blood alterations in the analysis made during the screening period:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin &gt; 2 ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST/SGOT or ALT/SGPT &gt; 2.5 ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alkaline phosphatase &gt;3.0 ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine Clearance &lt;40 mL/min, calculated by the Cockcroft-Gault formula&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant treatments that can cause severe digestive problems.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gastric surgery in the last 3 months or similar procedures that may increase gastric&#xD;
             intolerance.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to complete required visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous intolerance or allergy to pirfenidone or hypersensitivity to any of its&#xD;
             excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of angioedema&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Maria Molina-Molina, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Institut d'Investigació Biomèdica de Bellvitge</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Guadalupe Bermudo, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>00342607689</phone>
    <email>ufip@bellvitgehospital.cat</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital of Bellvitge</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hospitalet de Llobregat</city>
        <state>Barcelona</state>
        <zip>08907</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Guadalupe Bermudo, PI</last_name>
      <phone>0034 932607689</phone>
      <email>lupebermudope@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Claudia Valenzuela, PI</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rosalia Laporta, PI</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Juan Rigual, PI</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Diego Castillo, PI</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jacobo Sellarés, PI</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Karina Portillo, PI</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Eva Balcells, PI</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Germans Trias i Pujol</name>
      <address>
        <city>Badalona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clínic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital del Mar</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Sant Pau</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Diego Castillo, PI</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital La Princes</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Puerta de Hierro</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Piedad Usetti, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Ramón y Cajal</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>David Jimenez, MD, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Institut d'Investigació Biomèdica de Bellvitge</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Maria Molina</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Coordinating Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Fibrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pirfenidone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

