<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="276">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04666116</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HdeSagunto</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04666116</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Changes in Viral Load in COVID-19 After Probiotics</brief_title>
  <official_title>Changes in Viral Load in Patients With COVID-19 Disease After Dietary Supplementation With Probiotics: A Randomized Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital de Sagunto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Biopolis S.L.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Laboratorios Heel España</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital de Sagunto</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main objective of the study is to evaluate the capacity of a novel nutritional supplement&#xD;
      intervention including strains from the species Bifidobacterium longum, Bifidobacterium&#xD;
      animalis subsp. Lactis and Lactobacillus rhamnosus, plus vitamin D, zinc and seleniumt)&#xD;
      (immune system enhancer, antioxidant and anti-inflammatory capacity) to decrease the viral&#xD;
      load by nasopharyngeal smear in patients admitted for COVID-19 coronavirus disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. Study hypothesis: Through the administration of specific probiotics, the immune response&#xD;
           against the coronavirus COVID-19 could be stimulated, being able to decrease its viral&#xD;
           load and secondary symptomatology.&#xD;
&#xD;
           There is a different way to attack a harmful microorganism. It is based on the existence&#xD;
           in its habitat of a whole complex network of other microorganisms, our microbiota, which&#xD;
           prevents the development, growth and feeding of that microorganism, either by&#xD;
           competition of space, food, or immune effects. In COVID-19 patients, intestinal&#xD;
           dysbiosis has been described, specifically observing the decrease of species considered&#xD;
           as probiotics of the genera Lactobacillus and Bifidobacterium. The current study&#xD;
           proposes the testing of the novel nutritional supplement to potential the patient's&#xD;
           immune system and balances the damaged microbiota. This product contains species from&#xD;
           the genera described as affected in the COVID-19 infection. Moreover, the strains&#xD;
           selected showed an anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effect, and capacity for&#xD;
           stimulation of the immune system in previous assays. All three strains have the GRAS&#xD;
           status recognized by the FDA and are on the EFSA QPS list. The product also contains&#xD;
           vitamin D, zinc and selenium, three powerful inducers of the immune response. It is a&#xD;
           safe product according to WHO criteria. In addition, it can be effective despite the&#xD;
           administration of antibiotics, due to postbiotic activity, reducing the risk of sepsis&#xD;
           described in this type of patient. In order to monitor the effects of treatment with the&#xD;
           functional product, a follow-up will be made by means of consultation regarding the&#xD;
           evolution of the patient's condition. On the other hand, we will try to correlate this&#xD;
           state with the viral load present in serum and pharyngeal-nasal scraping.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. PRIMARY AND SECONDARY OBJECTIVES&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main objective: The main objective of the study is to evaluate the capacity of the novel&#xD;
      nutritional supplement (immune system enhancer, antioxidant and anti-inflammatory capacity)&#xD;
      to decrease the viral load by nasopharyngeal smear in patients admitted for COVID-19&#xD;
      coronavirus disease. The Patient will follow the medication agreed by the Hospital committee&#xD;
      during all the process.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives: Monitoring of changes, in patients admitted by COVID-19+, of the&#xD;
      following parameters at admission and prior to discharge:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hospital stay (days). Stay in Intensive Care Unit (days)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Clinical indicators: Respiratory rate, body temperature, number of bowel movements and&#xD;
           consistency. Abdominal pain. Nausea and vomiting. Sat02.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Type of respiratory support on day 5 of admission: ambient air (none), nasal mask,&#xD;
           ventimask, reservoir, non-invasive mechanical ventilation (NIV), orotracheal intubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Analytical parameters at admission and discharge: Total lymphocytes, Hemoglobin,&#xD;
           Ferritin, Neutrophils, Urea/Creatinine, C-reactive protein, LDH, D-dimer, AST/ALT,&#xD;
           Platelets.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determination of the incidence of mortality in the patient cohort and comparison with&#xD;
           that described in the literature.&#xD;
&#xD;
           3. PRIMARY AND SECONDARY STUDY VARIABLES&#xD;
&#xD;
           3. 1. Primary study variable&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Viral load during the period of admission to the nasopharyngeal smear.&#xD;
&#xD;
           3. 2. Secondary study variables&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hospital stay (days). Stay in Intensive Care Unit (days).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Clinical indicators on admission and every 48 hours thereafter: Respiratory rate, oxygen&#xD;
           saturation, body temperature, number of bowel movements and consistency. Abdominal pain.&#xD;
           Nausea and vomiting.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Type of respiratory support on the 5th day of admission: ambient air (none), nasal&#xD;
           glasses, ventimask, reservoir, non-invasive mechanical ventilation (NIV), orotracheal&#xD;
           intubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Analytical parameters at day 0 and at hospital discharge: Total lymphocytes, ferritin,&#xD;
           hemoglobin, neutrophils, urea/creatinine, C-reactive protein, IL-6, LDH, D-dimer,&#xD;
           AST/ALT, platelets&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Appearance of side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
           4. MATERIAL AND METHODS&#xD;
&#xD;
      4.1. Study design Randomized clinical trial with a clinical intervention of prescription of&#xD;
      functional novel nutritional supplement. The expected duration is 3 months in all patients&#xD;
      presenting symptoms of infection by COVID-19 or COVID+.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Serum viral load will be analyzed by rt-qPCR (reverse transcriptase quantitative Polymerase&#xD;
      Chain Reaction) at the beginning of the patient's admission and every 48 hours until&#xD;
      remission of the infection and pharyngeal-nasal exudate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patient medicated according to hospital protocol will also be given a daily dose (one&#xD;
      sachet) until remission of the illness or for one month.&#xD;
&#xD;
      4.2. Sample size of the study According to GRANMO Sample Size Calculator (Version 7.12 April&#xD;
      2012) Accepting an alpha risk of 0.15 and a beta risk of 0.3 in a bilateral contrast, 48&#xD;
      subjects in the first group and 48 in the second are required to detect the difference&#xD;
      between two proportions as statistically significant, than for group 1 (intervention group)&#xD;
      it is expected to be 0.5 and group 2 0.7. A follow-up loss rate of 5% has been estimated. The&#xD;
      ARCOSENE approach has been used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      4.3. Statistical plan Quantitative variables will be expressed as mean and standard deviation&#xD;
      assuming normal distribution based on the central limit theorem.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Qualitative variables will be expressed as frequencies with their 95% confidence intervals.&#xD;
      Qualitative variables will be compared using the Chi-square test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Quantitative variables will be compared using the Student T test. In order to evaluate the&#xD;
      impact of the intervention on the evolution of the disease by COVID-19, on average stay,&#xD;
      clinical variables and qualitative and quantitative analyses, a multivariate analysis will be&#xD;
      carried out, in which it will be controlled by different variables that could act as factors&#xD;
      of confusion (age, sex, type of disease, severity of the disease on admission, other diseases&#xD;
      that could affect the evolution, medical treatment, previous surgeries, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
      4.4. Planning the physical-sample drawing Main evaluation criteria: These patients will have&#xD;
      their surgery performed pharyngeal-nasal smear on day 0 and day 5 of hospital admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Viral load testing and cytokines: In the samples, the viral load will be determined by&#xD;
      rt-qPCR, in hospital services. Cytokines shall be measured at the indication of the physician&#xD;
      when deemed appropriate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      5. ETHICAL ASPECTS TAKEN INTO ACCOUNT IN THE STUDY PROTOCOL&#xD;
&#xD;
      5.1 Ethical conduct of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be carried out in accordance with the following guidelines:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Local ethical standards.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  European directives on the protection of human subjects in research.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Declaration of Helsinki.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The study will be conducted in strict accordance with the international ethical&#xD;
           recommendations for human research and clinical trials set out in the Declaration of&#xD;
           Helsinki, and in accordance with the recommendations of the Ministry of Health on&#xD;
           clinical trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Recommendations of the European Network of Pharmacoepidemiology and Pharmacovigilance&#xD;
           Centres&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  GMP recommendations.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Other relevant guidelines, laws or regulations applicable in each country and in the&#xD;
           Valencian Community As it is a research project with a nutritional supplement, it is not&#xD;
           considered a medicine or a health product, and therefore the Biomedical Research Law&#xD;
           applies to it and not the EECC RD 1090/2015. Therefore, there is no need for&#xD;
           authorization by the AEMPS (State Agency for Medicines) or by the Conselleria de&#xD;
           Sanitat.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study protocol will be submitted for prior approval to the Hospital de Sagunto IRB.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized, single blind clinical trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Computerized randomization based on a single sequence based on the latest issue in the patient's medical history</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Viral load during the period of admission to the nasopharyngeal smear.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The main objective of the study is to evaluate the capacity of the nutritional supplement (immune system enhancer, antioxidant and anti-inflammatory capacity) to decrease the viral load by nasopharyngeal smear in patients admitted for COVID-19 coronavirus disease</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical indicators on admission and every 48 hours thereafter</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>non-invasive mechanical ventilation (NIV) intervention, (yes or not)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Analytical parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>IL-6 initial point. (pg/mL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mobility</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Hospital stay (days) and Stay in Intensive Care Unit (days).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbiome analysis in feces</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Generation of a collection of PCRs products individually labelled from the hypervariable region of the 16s rRNA. After QC, each sample will be PCR amplified using a specific combination of primers specially designed and adapted for massive sequencing to capture the hypervariable region V3-V4 of the bacterial 16s rRNA (Klindworth et al. 2013). Sequencing in a illumina Miseq equipment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">96</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 patients no dietary administration</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Only medication agreed by the hospital committee</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 patients with dietary administration</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Medication agreed by the hospital committee and nutritional supplement.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dietary supplementation in patients with covid disease admitted to hospital</intervention_name>
    <description>Dietary supplementation in patients with covid disease admitted to hospital</description>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 patients with dietary administration</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients over 18 years of age admitted to the Internal Medicine Unit of Sagunto&#xD;
             Hospital, for illness due to infection secondary to COVID-19 during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  To be willing and able to sign the informed consent to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not meeting any of the inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Present allergy to any of the components of the nutritional supplement Gasteel Plus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not being able to ingest anything by mouth, either by dysphagia or by prescription.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>xavier cortés</last_name>
    <phone>0034962339300</phone>
    <email>xacori@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Laura Sanchis</last_name>
    <phone>0034962339300</phone>
    <email>lausanar@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital de Sagunto</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sagunto</city>
        <state>Valencia</state>
        <zip>46520</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Completed</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital de Sagunto</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <zip>46520</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Xavier Cortés</last_name>
      <phone>0034 962 33 93 00</phone>
      <email>xacori@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Laura Sanchis</last_name>
      <phone>0034 962 33 93 00</phone>
      <email>lausanar@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 11, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hospital de Sagunto</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Xavier Cortés</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Digestive specialist from the Internal Medicine Service</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>probiotic supplementation</keyword>
  <keyword>GASTEEL PLUS</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

