<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4964">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01087333</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>100066</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>10-C-0066</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01087333</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Collection of Human Samples to Study Hairy Cell and Other Leukemias, and to Develop Recombinant Immunotoxins for Cancer Treatment</brief_title>
  <official_title>Collection of Human Samples to Study Hairy Cell and Other Leukemias and to Develop Recombinant Immunotoxins for Cancer Treatment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Researchers who are studying hairy cell leukemia, and how the disease compares with other&#xD;
      disorders, are interested in obtaining additional samples from leukemia patients and healthy&#xD;
      volunteers. The investigators are particularly interested in samples from individuals who&#xD;
      have diseases that can be treated with a new type of drug called immunotoxin, in which an&#xD;
      antibody carrying a toxin binds to a cancer cell and allows the toxin to kill the cell.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To collect a variety of clinical samples, including blood, urine, lymph samples, and other&#xD;
      tissues, in order to study the samples and develop new treatments for leukemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Individuals 18 years of age and older who have been diagnosed with leukemia or other kinds&#xD;
      of blood and lymphatic system cancers, or who are healthy volunteers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Individuals who have leukemia will be asked to provide blood, bone marrow, urine, and&#xD;
           tumor tissue samples as requested by the researchers. Healthy volunteers will provide&#xD;
           only blood and urine samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  No treatment will be given as part of this protocol.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hairy cell leukemia (HCL) is highly responsive to but not curable by standard&#xD;
           chemotherapy, and also responds well to investigational agents called recombinant&#xD;
           immunotoxins which are being developed by the Laboratory of Molecular Biology (LMB).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The investigators on this protocol are studying molecular and clinical aspects of HCL,&#xD;
           and how they compare to normal or to other disorders, including chronic lymphocytic&#xD;
           leukemia (CLL) non-Hodgkin s lymphoma (NHL), and acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Recombinant immunotoxins are fusion proteins containing a bacterial toxin connected to a&#xD;
           targeting ligand, like a single-chain antibody or a growth factor. Recombinant&#xD;
           immunotoxins currently under clinical development in the LMB include BL22 and a high&#xD;
           affinity variant, HA22, targeting CD22, LMB-2, targeting CD25, and SS1P, targeting&#xD;
           Mesothelin.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  LMB-2, BL22 and HA22 are being tested in purine analog resistant HCL.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Other LMB trials include LMB-2 for cutaneous T-cell lymphoma, chronic lymphocytic&#xD;
           leukemia (CLL), and adult T-cell leukemia, and HA22 for non-Hodgkin s lymphoma and CLL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To allow the collection of a variety of clinical samples, including blood, urine,&#xD;
      lymphopheresis samples, and other tissues, to better understand the disease processes which&#xD;
      are being studied, or to determine eligibility and/or optimal timing for clinical testing.&#xD;
      Specific projects planned may include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  studying antibodies made against immunotoxins&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  quantifying tumor antigens by flow cytometry and other methods&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  testing how well recombinant immunotoxins and other agents kill tumor cells ex vivo&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  molecularly characterizing malignant B-cells by sequencing their immunoglobulin&#xD;
           rearrangements and other genes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Samples which are easily obtained, including blood and urine, may be obtained from&#xD;
           patients and normal volunteers.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Samples requiring procedures, including bone marrow biopsy/aspiration, leukopheresis,&#xD;
           and any procedure done because of medical need, may be obtained from patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients or normal donors are consented for the protocol and samples are obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  This protocol does not involve treatment, although patients may also be on therapy or&#xD;
           protocol treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 2, 2010</start_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Tissue Acquisition</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Collection of a variety of clinical samples, including blood, urine, lymphopheresis samples, and other tissues and associated data</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>every year</time_frame>
    <description>Time from the start of treatment that patients are still alive</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>assessment of tumor burden</measure>
    <time_frame>when also needed for medical purposes</time_frame>
    <description>obtain imaging data for assessment of tumor burden</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>correlate tumor burden with lab measurements</measure>
    <time_frame>when also needed for medical purposes</time_frame>
    <description>correlate tumor burden with lab measurements using imaging data</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>define immune response in patients with current or past viral infections</measure>
    <time_frame>when also needed for medical purposes</time_frame>
    <description>Define the T- and B-cell repertoire in patients with active or past viral infections, particularly for COVID-19 pandemic</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1263</enrollment>
  <condition>Hairy Cell Leukemia (HCL)</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL)</condition>
  <condition>Non-Hodgkins Lymphoma (NHL)</condition>
  <condition>Cutaneous T Cell Lymphoma (CTCL)</condition>
  <condition>Adult T Cell Lymphoma (ATL)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with hematologic malignancy, including HCL, CLL, CTCL, ATL, NHL, ALL, or solid tumor, including mesothelioma.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <description>Normal Donors who are defined as individuals without a diagnosis of or history of any cancer.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>3</arm_group_label>
    <description>Samples transferred from protocols 07-C-0130 and 08-CN-013</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Primary clinical population; normal donors&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients may have a diagnosis of hematologic malignancy, including HCL, CLL, CTCL,&#xD;
             ATL, NHL, ALL, or solid tumor, including mesothelioma. These patients would not be&#xD;
             excluded if they were in complete remission or thought to be cured of their&#xD;
             malignancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients and normal volunteer donors must be at least 18 years of age and able to give&#xD;
             informed consent. Informed consent will be waived for patient samples transferred from&#xD;
             other protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For patients undergoing leukapheresis for research purposes, the hematocrit must be at&#xD;
             least 28% and the platelet count at least 50,000/mm(3).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inclusion of Women and Minorities-Both men and women and members of all races and&#xD;
             ethnic groups are eligible for this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Desire of the patient or normal donor not to submit samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA FOR NORMAL DONORS:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Heart, lung, kidney disease, or bleeding disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hepatitis since age 11.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of HIV infection or AIDS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of high-risk activities for exposure to the AIDS virus, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Receipt of money or drugs in exchange for sex in the past 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Use of needles to take drugs, steroids, or anything not prescribed by a physician&#xD;
                  in the past 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Sexual contact in past 12 months with anyone having these high-risk activities or&#xD;
                  anyone whose status is unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptoms of AIDS or other infection in past 12 months including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unexplained weight loss or night sweats&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Blue or purple spots in the mouth or skin&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  White spots or unusual sores in the mouth&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Persistent cough or shortness of breath&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chronic diarrhea&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fever of more than 100.5 degrees F for more than 10 days&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Robert J Kreitman, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Julie C Feurtado, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 480-6186</phone>
    <email>julie.feurtado@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Robert J Kreitman, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 480-6187</phone>
    <email>kreitmar@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact National Cancer Institute Referral Office</last_name>
      <phone>(888) NCI-1937</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2010-C-0066.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>December 21, 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 13, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 13, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 16, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cytotoxicity Assay</keyword>
  <keyword>Neutralizing Antibodies</keyword>
  <keyword>Apheresis</keyword>
  <keyword>Flow Cytometry</keyword>
  <keyword>Hemolytic Uremic Syndrome (HUS)</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Hairy Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell, Cutaneous</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia-Lymphoma, Adult T-Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

