<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4380">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04617262</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-91-PM+</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04617262</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pilot Feasibility Study of Remote Problem Management Plus for Adults Affected by COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>PM+</acronym>
  <official_title>Pilot Feasibility Study of Remote Problem Management Plus to Improve Well-being and Functioning of Adults Affected by COVID-</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The New School</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>George Washington University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The New School</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a pilot feasibility study of remotely delivered Problem Management Plus, a&#xD;
      low-intensity psychological intervention, delivered in five sessions to adults affected by&#xD;
      crisis. The current study will evaluate the feasibility and acceptability of the intervention&#xD;
      when delivered remotely via Zoom to community members in New York City impacted by the&#xD;
      COVID-19 pandemic. The investigator's goal is to use qualitative and quantitative approaches&#xD;
      to inform procedures for a subsequent cluster randomized control trial of Problem Management&#xD;
      Plus versus enhanced usual care. A mixed-methods design will be used to evaluate the&#xD;
      feasibility, acceptability, perceived utility, and impact of the remotely delivered PM+&#xD;
      intervention, to determine recruitment and retention rates, to assess ethics and safety of&#xD;
      trial procedures. Additionally, the study will evaluate the acceptability, feasibility and&#xD;
      fidelity of the remote training and supervision of helpers trained to deliver the&#xD;
      intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Problem Management Plus (PM+) is recommended as part of the World Health Organization Mental&#xD;
      Health Gap Action Program for communities affected by adversity. It is a low-intensity,&#xD;
      scalable manualized intervention that was designed according to a task-sharing model of care.&#xD;
      PM+ has four core features that make the intervention suitable for populations exposed to&#xD;
      adversities in low-resource settings. First, it is a brief intervention (five sessions);&#xD;
      second, it can be delivered by paraprofessionals (trained, non-specialist workers, lay or&#xD;
      peer providers under the supervision of a mental health professional), using the principle of&#xD;
      task shifting/task sharing; third, it is designed as a trans-diagnostic intervention to&#xD;
      address a range of client-identified emotional (e.g. depression, anxiety, traumatic stress,&#xD;
      general stress) and practical problems; and, fourth, it is designed for communities affected&#xD;
      by any kind of adversity (e.g. violence, disasters) in low-income countries. The intervention&#xD;
      was originally developed for adults affected by humanitarian crises and tested in low-income&#xD;
      countries. A number of randomized controlled trials in Kenya, Pakistan, Nepal, as well as the&#xD;
      Netherlands have indicated that PM+ delivered by non-specialist helpers is effective in&#xD;
      decreasing symptoms of psychological distress (including depression, anxiety and&#xD;
      post-traumatic stress disorder symptoms) and improving functioning; however, empirical&#xD;
      evidence of the feasibility and efficacy of the remote training and delivery of PM+ is&#xD;
      limited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In May 2020, the United Nations released a policy brief emphasizing inclusion of mental&#xD;
      health and psychosocial support (MHPSS) in national response plans including scaling up&#xD;
      access to remote support (UN, 2020). The brief was released in response to emerging concerns&#xD;
      of the negative mental health and psychosocial impacts arising from the health and societal&#xD;
      consequences of COVID-19. Extant population-based research is showing high rates of anxiety,&#xD;
      depression, and general distress in the US, while at the same time MHPSS provision has been&#xD;
      disrupted or halted due to social distancing measures. Remote delivery forms of PM+ may serve&#xD;
      as an important mechanism to facilitate access to care during the ongoing pandemic and into&#xD;
      the future. Furthermore, there is very limited research with PM+ in high-income countries&#xD;
      where specialized mental health interventions are available, but where access for certain&#xD;
      populations or during periods of public health crisis is limited due to systemic and&#xD;
      practical barriers. Even in high income countries, only 22.4% of those with depression&#xD;
      receive minimally adequate care; however, 64.9% of those with depression perceive a need for&#xD;
      treatment. The treatment gap may be considerably higher among marginalized groups and&#xD;
      economically disadvantaged communities. COVID-19 continues to bring on widespread mental&#xD;
      health disparities, particularly among vulnerable and underserved communities that are&#xD;
      disproportionately affected by COVID-19. Brief, low-intensity interventions designed to be&#xD;
      implemented by non-specialists represent a promising and scalable approach to minimize this&#xD;
      treatment gap in under-served US populations by partnering with community-based organizations&#xD;
      (CBO) to train and supervise staff already involved in social and public health services. An&#xD;
      important first step before investing resources in training and implementation with CBOs is&#xD;
      to evaluate the feasibility, acceptability and effectiveness of remotely delivered PM+ with&#xD;
      relevant community samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is the first study to evaluate remotely delivered PM+ implemented by helpers whose&#xD;
      training and supervision was conducted entirely online, as well as one of the first trials&#xD;
      evaluating PM+ with community samples in the US. The aims of this pilot feasibility study are&#xD;
      to a) assess interest from perspective beneficiaries by partnering with community-based&#xD;
      organizations in New York City to recruit participants; b) to gather and evaluate information&#xD;
      about the feasibility, acceptability and safety of the intervention, in particular when&#xD;
      implemented via remote delivery; c) to identify whether the clinical and content adaptations&#xD;
      that were made during the remote training, adaptation and conduct of initial practice cases&#xD;
      are appropriate for the setting; and d) to assess possible problems of recruitment, delivery&#xD;
      of the intervention and retention to ensure that procedures are adequate for a cluster&#xD;
      randomized control trial. Additionally, the investigators will employ a single-arm,&#xD;
      uncontrolled design in order to begin to examine the effectiveness and impact of remotely&#xD;
      delivered PM+ among community members in New York City who are experiencing symptoms of&#xD;
      common mental health problems. Lastly, trainees' knowledge and perceived self-efficacy in a)&#xD;
      foundational helping skills based on common therapeutic factors and b) intervention-specific&#xD;
      competencies will be evaluated pre-training, post-training and post-supervision.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Psychological Outcomes Profile; Unabbreviated scale title &quot;Psychological Outcomes Profile&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>4-item measure of personalized distress and client-generated problems, function and wellbeing; minimum value = 0, maximum value = 20; higher scores mean greater distress</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Health Questionnaire; Unabbreviated scale title &quot;Patient Health Questionnaire&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>9-item measure of depression symptoms; minimum value = 0, maximum value = 27; higher scores mean more severe depression symptoms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Generalized Anxiety Disorder Scale; Unabbreviated scale title &quot;Generalized Anxiety Disorder 7-item Scale&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>7-item measure of anxiety symptoms; minimum value = 0 and maximum value = 21; higher scores mean more severe anxiety symptoms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>World Health Organization Disability Assessment Scale 2.0; Unabbreviated scale title &quot;World Health Organization Disability Assessment Scale 2.0&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>12-item measure of ability to engage in daily activities and functioning; minimum value = 0, maximum value = 48; higher scores mean worse disability outcomes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>World Health Organization Quality of Life Questionnaire-BREF; Unabbreviated scale title &quot;World Health Organization Quality of Life Questionnaire-BREF&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>26-item quality of life assessment of physical health, psychological health, social, relationships and environment; minimum value = 26 and maximum value = 130; higher scores mean better quality of life</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EuroQoL 5-dimension 5-level; Unabbreviated scale title &quot;EuroQoL 5-dimension 5-level&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>5-item assessment of dimensions of health status: mobility, self-care, usual activities, pain and discomfort, and anxiety and depression; minimum= 5, maximum = 25; higher score mean worse health outcomes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index; Unabbreviated scale title &quot;Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>19-item measure of sleep quality and disturbance; 19 items combined to form 7 &quot;component&quot; scores, each of which has a range of 0-3 points, 7 component scores are added to yield one global global score; minimum value = 0 and maximum value = 21; higher score means greater difficulty sleeping</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Somatic Symptom Scale-8; Unabbreviated scale title &quot;Somatic Symptom Scale-8&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>8-item assessment of the presence and severity of common somatic symptoms; minimum value = 0, maximum value = 32; higher score means more severe somatic symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <condition>Anxiety Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Psychological Distress</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Remote Problem Management Plus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Five individual sessions of low-intensity psychological intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Remote Problem Management Plus</intervention_name>
    <description>Five sessions of low-intensity, trans-diagnostic psychological intervention including the teaching and practice of the following strategies: stress management, problem solving, behavioral activation, and strengthening social support</description>
    <arm_group_label>Remote Problem Management Plus</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English-speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Help- or treatment-seeking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to a device for conducting sessions via Zoom (e.g., smartphone, tablet, laptop&#xD;
             or personal computer)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute medical conditions or severe cognitive impairment (e.g., severe intellectual&#xD;
             disability or dementia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Imminent suicide risk or expressed acute needs/protection risks (e.g., IPV risk)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of severe mental disorder (e.g., psychotic disorders)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hazardous substance use, substance dependency or substance use disorder (assessed&#xD;
             using the DAST-10 and AUDIT-C)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adam Brown, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The New School</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Brandon Kohrt, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>George Washington University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kendall Pfeffer, MEd, MA</last_name>
    <phone>212-229-5727</phone>
    <email>pfefk996@newschool.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Adam Brown, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>212-229-5727</phone>
    <email>brownad@newschool.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.who.int/mental_health/emergencies/problem_management_plus/en/</url>
    <description>Problem management plus individual manual distributed by the World Health Organization</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bryant RA, Schafer A, Dawson KS, Anjuri D, Mulili C, Ndogoni L, Koyiet P, Sijbrandij M, Ulate J, Harper Shehadeh M, Hadzi-Pavlovic D, van Ommeren M. Effectiveness of a brief behavioural intervention on psychological distress among women with a history of gender-based violence in urban Kenya: A randomised clinical trial. PLoS Med. 2017 Aug 15;14(8):e1002371. doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1002371. eCollection 2017 Aug.</citation>
    <PMID>28809935</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dawson KS, Schafer A, Anjuri D, Ndogoni L, Musyoki C, Sijbrandij M, van Ommeren M, Bryant RA. Feasibility trial of a scalable psychological intervention for women affected by urban adversity and gender-based violence in Nairobi. BMC Psychiatry. 2016 Nov 18;16(1):410.</citation>
    <PMID>27863515</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rahman A, Riaz N, Dawson KS, Usman Hamdani S, Chiumento A, Sijbrandij M, Minhas F, Bryant RA, Saeed K, van Ommeren M, Farooq S. Problem Management Plus (PM+): pilot trial of a WHO transdiagnostic psychological intervention in conflict-affected Pakistan. World Psychiatry. 2016 Jun;15(2):182-3. doi: 10.1002/wps.20312.</citation>
    <PMID>27265713</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dawson KS, Bryant RA, Harper M, Kuowei Tay A, Rahman A, Schafer A, van Ommeren M. Problem Management Plus (PM+): a WHO transdiagnostic psychological intervention for common mental health problems. World Psychiatry. 2015 Oct;14(3):354-7. doi: 10.1002/wps.20255.</citation>
    <PMID>26407793</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 5, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 5, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>De-identified individual patient data will be available through NIMH Data Archive after publication of primary results.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Materials will be shared after publication of primary results.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Contact investigators.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

