<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="384">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04627519</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pharm-202010.01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04627519</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness and Safety of Rhea Health Tone® as add-on Therapy for COVID-19 in Hospitalized Adults in Indonesia</brief_title>
  <acronym>RHEA-COVID19</acronym>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Randomized, Open-label, Controlled Trial to Assess Effectiveness and Safety of Rhea Health Tone® as add-on Therapy for COVID-19 in Hospitalized Adults in Indonesia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universitas Padjadjaran</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>PT. Rhea Pharmaceutical Sciences Indonesia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Prodia Diacro Laboratories P.T.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universitas Padjadjaran</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a multicenter, randomized, open-label, controlled trial to evaluate the effectiveness&#xD;
      and safety of Rhea Health Tone® as add-on therapy in hospitalized adults with COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is a multi-center trial that will be conducted in up to approximately 2 sites&#xD;
      nationally. New sites may be added as needed after appropriate assessment. Interim monitoring&#xD;
      will be conducted to evaluate the arms and for safety and effectiveness. Any change would be&#xD;
      accompanied by updated sample size.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be assessed while hospitalized. All subjects will undergo a series of&#xD;
      laboratory (inflammatory biomarkers (IL-6, hs-CRP, IFNγ), SGOT, SGPT and Creatinine,&#xD;
      conversion rate by PCR, QTc prolongation by ECG, chest X-ray), clinical (clinical assessment,&#xD;
      vital sign, concomitant medication, other medical conditions) and safety assessment (serious&#xD;
      adverse event).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization will be performed 1:1 for each arm. Arm 1 = Standard of Care (SoC) alone, arm 2&#xD;
      = SoC + Rhea Health Tone®.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a multicenter, randomized, open-label, controlled trial to evaluate the effectiveness&#xD;
      and safety of Rhea Health Tone® in hospitalized adults with COVID-19 confirmed by PCR.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is a multi-center trial that will be conducted in up to approximately 2 sites&#xD;
      nationally. Interim monitoring will be conducted to evaluate the arms and for safety and&#xD;
      effectiveness. Any change would be accompanied by an updated sample size.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible patients are male or female adults (age ≥ 18 years up to 50 years old) recently&#xD;
      admitted as in-patients, with mild to moderate COVID-19 confirmed by positive PCR that&#xD;
      fulfill the inclusion and exclusion criteria stated in the protocol. Laboratory assessment&#xD;
      include SGOT, SGPT and Creatinine at screening. The subjects must sign their consent in&#xD;
      writing electronically beforehand. Total subjects = 69.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects with any of these conditions will be excluded:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Any allergy to any composition of Rhea Health Tone;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pregnant and breast feeding;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  History and co-morbid of severe underlying disease where treatment and follow up is not&#xD;
           likely to be beneficial to the patient based on physician judgement (e.g. retinopathy,&#xD;
           cardiovascular disease (QTc &gt; 500 mdet (narrow QRS); QTc ≥ 550 mdet (wide QRS)), heart&#xD;
           arrythmia, uncontrolled diabetes mellitus, hypertension, chronic pulmonary disease,&#xD;
           asthma, chronic kidney disease (Creatinine &gt; 2x upper limit of normal), liver disease&#xD;
           (SGOT/SGPT &gt; 2x upper limit of normal), chronic neurological disease, or etc.). This&#xD;
           includes people requiring care in designated supported living facilities and severe&#xD;
           dementia;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Possibility of being transferred to a non-study-hospital within 72 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  History of autoimmune disease, cancer, HIV AIDS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any suspected serious adverse event reaction is reported to CRO/Sponsor and EC within 24&#xD;
      hours, using patient's study ID.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the study conduct, the study team shall keep all the relevant source documents and&#xD;
      transcribe the data in case report form (CRF). The study team should also update study&#xD;
      essential document (e.g. subject log, investigational product accountability log, etc.) and&#xD;
      keep the copy captured by scan/camera for monitoring/audit/inspection purpose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is expected to be finished in 2 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Standard of Care (SoC) treatment is based on COVID-19 Treatment Protocol (1st edition, 2020)&#xD;
      published by Medical Associations (PDPI, PERKI, PAPDI, PERDATIN, IDAI).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Arm 1: SoC alone for 9 days Arm 2: SoC + Rhea Health Tone 2 ml twice a day after meal (every&#xD;
      12 hours) for 9 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is anticipated that patients with COVID-19 will present to participating hospitals, and&#xD;
      that no external recruitment efforts towards potential subjects are needed. Recruitment&#xD;
      efforts may also include dissemination of information about this trial to other medical&#xD;
      professionals/hospitals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Ethics Committee will approve the recruitment process and all materials prior to any&#xD;
      recruitment to prospective subjects directly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Screening will begin with a brief discussion with study staff. Some will be excluded based on&#xD;
      demographic data and medical history (i.e., pregnant, &lt; 18 years of age, severe COVID-19,&#xD;
      etc.). Information about the study will be presented to potential subjects (or legally&#xD;
      acceptable representative) and questions will be asked to determine potential eligibility.&#xD;
      Screening procedures can begin only after informed consent is obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate the effectiveness of Rhea Health Tone® in the therapy of mild to moderate&#xD;
      hospitalized adults with confirmed COVID-19 based on length of stay in hospital (after&#xD;
      subject received randomization code until subject discharge/death/recovered). Secondary&#xD;
      parameters will be Incidence and duration of Oxygenation (days of oxygenation), incidence is&#xD;
      defined as number of days from randomization until the subject received oxygenation, duration&#xD;
      is defined as total days of the use of oxygenation; incidence of Ventilation (days to&#xD;
      receiving ventilation).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Incidence is defined as number of days from randomization until the subject received&#xD;
      ventilation; inflammatory biomarkers (IL-6, hs-CRP and IFNγ).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analyses relate outcome to the randomly allocated treatment (e.g. intent-to-treat). The&#xD;
      primary analyses assess any effects of treatment allocation on length of hospitalization,&#xD;
      analyzing separately people who already at mild and moderate level at entry and by age.&#xD;
      Interim analysis will be carried out after 50% subject enrolled. The results will be&#xD;
      monitored by monitor assigned by the Sponsor to ensure subject well-being and safety as well&#xD;
      as study integrity. The monitor will evaluate the study safety parameter after 50% subject&#xD;
      enrolled in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main secondary analyses assess any effects of treatment allocation on:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Incidence and duration of Oxygenation (days of oxygenation, days of free oxygenation);&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Incidence of Ventilation (days to receiving ventilation);&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Inflammatory biomarkers (IL-6, hs-CRP , IFNγ );&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Conversion rate from positive to negative by PCR result;&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Percentage of improvement of patients' clinical&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Percentage of improvement of patients based on chest X-ray; and&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. QTc prolongation by ECG.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study related data will be recorded. All the data in the source documents shall be collected&#xD;
      by the study team to be transcribed in the electronic case report form (eCRF). Once the&#xD;
      document recorded, the electronic data will be automatically available for&#xD;
      monitoring/audit/inspection purpose. All the electronic system used and data recording in the&#xD;
      study must be conducted in compliance to Good Clinical Practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigator must assure that subjects' anonymity will be maintained and that their&#xD;
      identities are protected from unauthorized parties. On CRFs or other documents submitted to&#xD;
      the sponsor, subjects should not be identified by their names, but by an identification code.&#xD;
      The investigator should keep a subject enrolment log showing codes, names and addresses. The&#xD;
      investigator should maintain documents not for submission to Sponsor, e.g. subjects' written&#xD;
      consent forms, in strict confidence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigator shall ensure the quality control and quality assurance of the data generated&#xD;
      during the study and how the data will be handled, including providing access to monitoring&#xD;
      activities, audit and inspection and source documents which will be used in the study.&#xD;
      Investigator will permit monitoring, audits and inspections by Sponsor/CRO, EC, and&#xD;
      regulatory bodies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All source records including electronic data (if any) will be stored in secured systems in&#xD;
      accordance with institutional policies and locally applicable regulation. All the essential&#xD;
      documents should be retained until at least 5 years after the study ended or based on the&#xD;
      applicable regulatory requirements or based on the agreement with the funder.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Drug Safety Monitoring Board (DSMB) is an Independent Data Monitoring Committee&#xD;
      consisting of doctors who are experienced in clinical trials, statisticians, and other&#xD;
      members who do not direct involvement with this study. The DSMB responsible for the ongoing&#xD;
      review of a clinical trial and for making recommendations to the sponsor concerning the&#xD;
      continuation, modification, and termination of the trial as it is being conducted. The DSMB&#xD;
      will be the only committee that is allowed to review the confidential data in the study. The&#xD;
      statistician will analyze the subject's security data and report to DSMB to be evaluated more&#xD;
      closely. The key responsibilities of the DSMB are to ensure patient safety by routine review&#xD;
      of overall safety data including all SAEs, SUSARs, all severe AEs and AEs leading to drug or&#xD;
      study discontinuation and, where applicable, literature cases and information from Competent&#xD;
      Authorities (CAs) and by judging the relevance of the events for patients' safety. The DSMB&#xD;
      will review the results of data that has been analyzed in accordance with SAP and consider&#xD;
      other evidence arising from other studies and will provide advice to the Trial Steering&#xD;
      Committee (TSC) (the research committee and national coordinator) regarding the&#xD;
      sustainability of this study. The DSMB may recommend the TSC to the recruitment or study&#xD;
      termination or provide recommendations related to alternatives treatment (if any).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants will be randomised to be in Arm 1 or Arm 2 using pre-defined randomisation list; 1:1 for each arm.&#xD;
Arm 1 receives Standard of Care (day 1 to 9) Arm 2 receives Standard of Care + Rhea Health Tone (day 1 to 9)</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of stay</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of randomization until the date of first documented subject discharge or death from any cause, assessed up to 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Total days the subjects were hospitalized</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of oxygenation</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of randomization until the date of first documented subject discharge or death from any cause, assessed up to 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Total days of oxygen supplementation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of ventilation</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of randomization until the date of first documented subject discharge or death from any cause, assessed up to 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Total days of receiving ventilation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PCR conversion</measure>
    <time_frame>Will be examined at days 1st , 7th, and 10th.</time_frame>
    <description>Total days of conversion rate from positive to negative by PCR result</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Inflammatory biomarkers 1</measure>
    <time_frame>Will be examined at days 1st and 10th.</time_frame>
    <description>IL-6 (pg/mL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Inflammatory biomarkers 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Will be examined at days 1st and 10th.</time_frame>
    <description>hs-CRP (mg/L)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Inflammatory biomarkers 3</measure>
    <time_frame>Will be examined at days 1st and 10th.</time_frame>
    <description>IFNγ (pg/mL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of improvement of subjects' clinical status</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of randomization until the date of first documented subject discharge or death from any cause, assessed up to 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Daily measurement of temperature, heart rate, respiratory rate, blood pressure, oxygen saturation, capillary filling time &gt;2 seconds</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>X-Ray</measure>
    <time_frame>From the date of informed consent signed by subject, until the date of first documented subject discharge or death from any cause, assessed up to 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of improvement of subjects based on chest X-ray</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">69</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SoC alone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard of Care alone (days 1 to 9)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Rhea Health Tone®</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Rhea Health Tone® 2 ml twice daily after meal (every 12 hours) for 9 days to be provided together with Standard of Care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rhea Health Tone®</intervention_name>
    <description>Rhea Health Tone® 2 ml twice daily after the meal (every 12 hours)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Rhea Health Tone®</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male and female patients aged ≥ 18 years to 50 years old, who recently admitted as&#xD;
             in-patients and have not received any standard of care yet, with COVID-19 confirmed by&#xD;
             PCR with mild to moderate symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Female subjects of child-bearing age agree to take effective contraceptive measures&#xD;
             during the study until seven days of the last oral medication of study product;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Willing to receive a random assignment to any designated treatment group and not&#xD;
             participating in another study at the same time;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Willing for not using any other immunomodulator or treatment that might bias the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient willing to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Any allergy to any composition of Rhea Health Tone®;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Pregnant and breastfeeding;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History and co-morbid of severe underlying disease where treatment and follow up is&#xD;
             not likely to be beneficial to the patient based on physician judgment (e.g.&#xD;
             retinopathy, cardiovascular disease (QTc &gt; 500 mdet (narrow QRS); QTc ≥ 550 mdet (wide&#xD;
             QRS)), heart arrhythmia, uncontrolled diabetes mellitus, hypertension, chronic&#xD;
             pulmonary disease, asthma, chronic kidney disease (Creatinine &gt; 2x upper limit of&#xD;
             normal), liver disease (SGOT/SGPT &gt; 2x limit of normal), chronic neurological disease,&#xD;
             or etc.). This includes people requiring care in designated supported living&#xD;
             facilities and severe dementia;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Possibility of being transferred to a non-study-hospital within 72 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of autoimmune disease, cancer, HIV AIDS.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Keri Lestari, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+62 811-216-942</phone>
    <email>lestarikd@unpad.ac.id</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Haig YH Babikian</last_name>
    <phone>+62 811-8202-255</phone>
    <email>haig.babikian@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.who.int/health-topics/coronavirus#tab=tab_1</url>
    <description>WHO. Coronavirus</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://covid19.go.id/p/berita/infografis-covid-19-8-mei-2020</url>
    <description>Infografis COVID-19 (31 Mei 2020) - Berita Terkini | Gugus Tugas Percepatan Penanganan COVID-19</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://ocw.ui.ac.id/pluginfile.php/2518/mod_resource/content/9/Versi%20Cetak%20Protokol%20Tatalaksana%20COVID-19-ok.pdf</url>
    <description>Burhan E, Susanto A, Nasution S, Ginanjar E, Pitoyo C, Susilo A, et al. PROTOKOL TATALAKSANA COVID-19. 1st ed. Jakarta: Perhimpunan Dokter Paru Indonesia (PDPI); 2020.</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.kompas.com/sains/read/2020/04/02/170300223/sembuh-dari-covid-19-menurut-who-ini-rerata-waktu-penyembuhan-corona?page=all</url>
    <description>Pranita E. Sembuh dari Covid-19, Menurut WHO ini Rerata Waktu Penyembuhan Corona [Internet]. 2020</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://jacobspublishers.com/journals/jacobs-journal-of-experimental-cardiology-and-research/fulltext/antibacterial-and-anti-inflammatory-properties-of-natural-herbal-oil-formulation-nhof</url>
    <description>Babikian H. Antibacterial and Anti-Inflammatory Properties of Natural Herbal Oil Formulation (NHOF). Jacobs J Exp Cardiol Res. 2019 Jun 25</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://ajps.uomustansiriyah.edu.iq/index.php/AJPS/article/view/59</url>
    <description>Al-Samarrai O, Hameed R, Naji N. Studying of Phytochemical, Nutritive values and Antioxidant ability of Commiphora myrrha. Al-Mustansiriyh J Pharm Sciences. 2017;17(1):52-63.</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.phcogj.com/sites/default/files/10.5530pj.2015.5.1.pdf</url>
    <description>Phatak RS. Phytochemistry, Pharmacological Activities and Intellectual Property Landscape of Gardenia jasminoides Ellis: a Review. Pharmacogn J. 2015 Jul 8;7(5):254-65.</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://academicjournals.org/journal/JMPR/article-abstract/68BFC7723000</url>
    <description>urishi Y, Hamidi A, Zargar M, Singh S, Saxena A. Potential role of natural molecules in health and disease: Importance of boswellic acid. J Med Plants Res. 2010;4(2):2778-85.</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10600-007-0174-2</url>
    <description>Imamu X, Yili A, Aisa HA, Maksimov VV, Veshkurova ON, Salikhov ShI. Chemical composition and antimicrobial activity of essential oil from Daucus carota sativa seeds. Chem Nat Compd. 2007 Jul;43(4):495-6.</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://epubs.surrey.ac.uk/856520/</url>
    <description>Shebaby WN. Evaluation of antioxidant, anticancer and immunomodulatory activities of wild carrot (Daucus carota ssp. carota) oil and its fractions. [Disertation]. University of Surrey; 2014.</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.intechopen.com/books/nutrition-well-being-and-health/the-therapeutic-benefits-of-essential-oils</url>
    <description>Djilani A, Ducko A. The Therapeutic Benefits of Essential Oils. Nutrition, Well-Being and Health</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://openventio.org/efficacy-of-natural-herbal-formulation-against-acute-hepatopancreatic-necrosis-disease-ahpnd-causing-vibrio-parahaemolyticus-in-penaeus-vannamei/</url>
    <description>ha R, Babikian Y, Babikian H, Khoa L, Wisoyo D, Srisombat S, et al. Efficacy of Natural Herbal Formulation against Acute Hepatopancreatic Necrosis Disease (AHPND) causing Vibrio parahaemolyticus in Penaeus vannamei</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.hilarispublisher.com/open-access/effectiveness-of-natural-herbal-oil-formulation-against-white-spotsyndrome-virus-in-penaeus-vannamei-2472-0992-1000123.pdf</url>
    <description>Jha R, Babikian Y, Babikian H, Wisoyo S, Asih Y, Srisombat S, et al. Effectiveness of Natural Herbal Oil Formulation against White Spot Syndrome Virus in Penaeus vannamei. J Pharmacogn Nat Prod</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://vetmedmosul.com/article_164760.html</url>
    <description>Al-Jameel WH, Al-Mahmood SS. Similarities and differences of COVID-19 and avian infectious bronchitis from molecular pathologist and poultry specialist view point. Iraqi Journal of Veterinary Sciences. 2020 May 15;</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.jscimedcentral.com/Pharmacology/pharmacology-8-1138.pdf</url>
    <description>Nadjib B.M. Effective Antiviral Activity of Essential Oils and their Characteristic Terpenes against Coronaviruses: An Update. Journal of Pharmacology &amp; Clinical Toxicology. 2020;8(1): 1138(19 March 2020)</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.ijhsr.org/IJHSR_Vol.10_Issue.5_May2020/25.pdf</url>
    <description>Maggo S. Dhull P, Dubey AP, Brashier, et. al. Cytokine Storm Syndrome in COVID-19: Diagnosis and Management Strategies. International Journal of Health Sciences and Research [Internet]. 2020 May;10(5)</description>
  </link>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Stebbing J, Phelan A, Griffin I, Tucker C, Oechsle O, Smith D, Richardson P. COVID-19: combining antiviral and anti-inflammatory treatments. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020 Apr;20(4):400-402. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30132-8. Epub 2020 Feb 27.</citation>
    <PMID>32113509</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tay MZ, Poh CM, Rénia L, MacAry PA, Ng LFP. The trinity of COVID-19: immunity, inflammation and intervention. Nat Rev Immunol. 2020 Jun;20(6):363-374. doi: 10.1038/s41577-020-0311-8. Epub 2020 Apr 28. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32346093</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Swamy MK, Akhtar MS, Sinniah UR. Antimicrobial Properties of Plant Essential Oils against Human Pathogens and Their Mode of Action: An Updated Review. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2016;2016:3012462. doi: 10.1155/2016/3012462. Epub 2016 Dec 20. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28090211</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Yang L, Peng K, Zhao S, Zhao F, Chen L, Qiu F. 2-methyl-L-erythritol glycosides from Gardenia jasminoides. Fitoterapia. 2013 Sep;89:126-30. doi: 10.1016/j.fitote.2013.05.018. Epub 2013 May 31.</citation>
    <PMID>23727470</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Zhang Y, Yao J, Qi X, Liu X, Lu X, Feng G. Geniposide demonstrates anti-inflammatory and antiviral activity against pandemic A/Jiangsu/1/2009 (H1N1) influenza virus infection in vitro and in vivo. Antivir Ther. 2017;22(7):599-611. doi: 10.3851/IMP3152. Epub 2017 Mar 8.</citation>
    <PMID>28272019</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Wu S, Patel KB, Booth LJ, Metcalf JP, Lin HK, Wu W. Protective essential oil attenuates influenza virus infection: an in vitro study in MDCK cells. BMC Complement Altern Med. 2010 Nov 15;10:69. doi: 10.1186/1472-6882-10-69.</citation>
    <PMID>21078173</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Su S, Hua Y, Wang Y, Gu W, Zhou W, Duan JA, Jiang H, Chen T, Tang Y. Evaluation of the anti-inflammatory and analgesic properties of individual and combined extracts from Commiphora myrrha, and Boswellia carterii. J Ethnopharmacol. 2012 Jan 31;139(2):649-56. doi: 10.1016/j.jep.2011.12.013. Epub 2011 Dec 13.</citation>
    <PMID>22178177</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tipton DA, Lyle B, Babich H, Dabbous MKh. In vitro cytotoxic and anti-inflammatory effects of myrrh oil on human gingival fibroblasts and epithelial cells. Toxicol In Vitro. 2003 Jun;17(3):301-10.</citation>
    <PMID>12781209</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Nomicos EY. Myrrh: medical marvel or myth of the Magi? Holist Nurs Pract. 2007 Nov-Dec;21(6):308-23. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17978635</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sharopov F, Valiev A, Satyal P, Gulmurodov I, Yusufi S, Setzer WN, Wink M. Cytotoxicity of the Essential Oil of Fennel (Foeniculum vulgare) from Tajikistan. Foods. 2017 Aug 28;6(9). pii: E73. doi: 10.3390/foods6090073.</citation>
    <PMID>28846628</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Lee HS, Kang P, Kim KY, Seol GH. Foeniculum vulgare Mill. Protects against Lipopolysaccharide-induced Acute Lung Injury in Mice through ERK-dependent NF-κB Activation. Korean J Physiol Pharmacol. 2015 Mar;19(2):183-9. doi: 10.4196/kjpp.2015.19.2.183. Epub 2015 Feb 25.</citation>
    <PMID>25729281</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Shalaby NM, Maghraby AS, el-Hagrassy AM. Effect of Daucus carota var. boissieri extracts on immune response of Schistosoma mansoni infected mice. Folia Microbiol (Praha). 1999;44(4):441-8. Erratum in: Folia Microbiol (Praha) 2000;45(2):191.</citation>
    <PMID>10983240</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Alves-Silva JM, Zuzarte M, Gonçalves MJ, Cavaleiro C, Cruz MT, Cardoso SM, Salgueiro L. New Claims for Wild Carrot (Daucus carota subsp. carota) Essential Oil. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2016;2016:9045196. doi: 10.1155/2016/9045196. Epub 2016 Feb 14.</citation>
    <PMID>26981143</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Yuan H, Ma Q, Cui H, Liu G, Zhao X, Li W, Piao G. How Can Synergism of Traditional Medicines Benefit from Network Pharmacology? Molecules. 2017 Jul 7;22(7). pii: E1135. doi: 10.3390/molecules22071135. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28686181</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 10, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 12, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 13, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 22, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 22, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 24, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universitas Padjadjaran</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Keri Lestari</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prof. Dr. Keri Lestari, M.Si, S.Si, Apt.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Covid19</keyword>
  <keyword>Rhea Health Tone</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

