<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2868">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04473105</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20GA039</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04473105</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Optimising Resource Allocation Via Prediction of Outcomes for Covid-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Optimising Resource Allocation Via Prediction of Outcomes for Suspected and Proven Covid-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>East Midlands Academic Health Sciences Network</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators plan to use all of the information available within their local NHS&#xD;
      hospitals Trust to work out what happens to people admitted with both suspected and proven&#xD;
      Covid-19 infections. The investigators will use all of the information that they can to&#xD;
      provide the most evidence possible to use in their investigation as this will make the&#xD;
      results more accurate. This will include information on existing health conditions (e.g. by&#xD;
      looking at previous discharge letters, GP summaries), clinical observations recorded in the&#xD;
      hospital (e.g. temperature, blood pressure, pulse, oxygen levels) and laboratory measures&#xD;
      (e.g. blood markers of infection). The investigators experienced team will then analyse all&#xD;
      of this together with information about whether the person has Covid-19 to help work out what&#xD;
      any new patients' risk will be. To do this the investigators need to use individual patients'&#xD;
      information, however once removed from the hospital records system it will not be&#xD;
      identifiable and will be held securely within the hospital at all times. As a result of this&#xD;
      work the investigators plan to be able to do two things:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. When a patient is admitted to hospital with possible or confirmed Covid-19 the&#xD;
           investigators will be able to make a highly accurate prediction of what is likely to&#xD;
           happen to them (e.g. being admitted to high dependency or intensive care, dying or&#xD;
           surviving to discharge) which will help health care professional make decisions about&#xD;
           their care.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. By knowing what is likely to happen to a patient the investigators are able to make&#xD;
           informed decisions about how to distribute healthcare resources e.g. which areas are&#xD;
           likely to need more ventilators (machines to help with breathing), need for intensive&#xD;
           care beds, discharge planning.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Relatively simple clinical risk scores based upon easily available clinical information can&#xD;
      greatly aid in the triaging of patients to early discharge or more rapid and intensive&#xD;
      intervention. One example of this is in upper gastrointestinal bleeding where several such&#xD;
      scores (https://www.mdcalc.com/glasgow-blatchford-bleeding-score-gbs4 5;&#xD;
      https://www.mdcalc.com/rockall-score-upper-gi-bleeding-complete6) have permitted safe early&#xD;
      discharge thereby relieving pressure on hospitals. The investigators believe that similar&#xD;
      results might potentially be achievable from data routinely collected in our trust on&#xD;
      patients with proven or suspected Covid-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators aim to answer the following questions&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. What pattern of clinical history and symptoms, observations, blood and other&#xD;
           investigative markers best predicts that a patient suspected of Covid-19 or proven to&#xD;
           have it will progress to requiring ventilation?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. What pattern of clinical history and symptoms, observations, blood and other&#xD;
           investigative markers best predicts that a patient suspected of Covid-19 or proven to&#xD;
           have it will die during their illness?&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. What pattern of clinical history and symptoms, observations, blood and other&#xD;
           investigative markers best predicts that a patient suspected of Covid-19 or proven to&#xD;
           have it will make a full recovery without requiring supplemental oxygen?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators propose to two main approaches to the first two of the aims above.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A standard approach assessing baseline characteristics to predict poor outcome, similar to&#xD;
      other ongoing studies like ISARIC and PRIEST, but benefitting from an unbiased sample of&#xD;
      patients as no additional samples or data are to be collected and so the investigators&#xD;
      believe that it will be ethically acceptable subject to due attention to confidentiality to&#xD;
      analyse all patients presenting and not only those willing and able to consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A multi-level modelling approach that uses the rich repeated daily laboratory and clinical&#xD;
      measurements to predict the daily risk of a subsequent deterioration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This second approach complements other ongoing studies like ISARIC and PRIEST, as it can only&#xD;
      feasibly be delivered within a single institution like NUH as it requires detailed&#xD;
      longitudinal linked electronic health data. Furthermore, it is an efficient, low cost study&#xD;
      design that does not require manual data collection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will utilize the data held in the electronic systems of Nottingham&#xD;
      University Hospitals (NUH) NHS Trust, to identify all patients either suspected of having&#xD;
      Covid-19 infection or in whom the diagnosis is eventually confirmed. This will be performed&#xD;
      from the start of the pandemic retrospectively and then in a rolling program prospectively to&#xD;
      maximise available data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For these patients the investigators will gather all relevant data on diagnoses&#xD;
      (comorbidities), daily clinical observations and daily laboratory parameters both at&#xD;
      presentation and on a rolling basis going forward from that until the point of death or&#xD;
      discharge. These data will include repeated measures of, temperature, pulse, blood oxygen&#xD;
      saturation, inspired oxygen concentration, respiratory rate, C reactive protein, and white&#xD;
      cell count among others.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data will be analysed, and outcomes modelled within the Nottingham University Hospitals Trust&#xD;
      network to ensure that confidentiality is maintained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Characteristics of patients who go on to intubation The investigators will assess the&#xD;
      association of any baseline parameters and demographics of patients who require ventilation&#xD;
      compared to those who do not by cross tabulating baseline parameters with ventilation, and&#xD;
      calculating adjusted associations using a logistic regression model. The investigators will&#xD;
      also examine daily risk of intubation using a random effects model with the repeated daily&#xD;
      measurements. In order to examine the potential for an easily calculable clinical risk score,&#xD;
      logistic models will be prepared, but retaining continuous variables as continuous (to&#xD;
      maximise the retention of useful predictive data) and reducing them to categorical data (for&#xD;
      ease of clinical calculation). The investigators will select predictors for the model using&#xD;
      backward elimination with the Akaike information criterion and alpha = 0.05. For candidate&#xD;
      models the investigators will calculate the C-index and receiver operating curves and assess&#xD;
      calibration using the Hosmer-Lemeshow test. Bootstrapping and cross validation will be used&#xD;
      to avoid overfitting and assess model performance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Time trends analysis to identify markers leading to intubation The investigators will examine&#xD;
      the data for trends over time in repeated measurements where available and describe these&#xD;
      using appropriate summary statistics. If there are enough repeated measurements, then each&#xD;
      covariate will be assessed with a JoinPoint analysis to assess if there is an obvious&#xD;
      inflexion in time to indicate a change in the clinical picture which marks a decline towards&#xD;
      ventilation. This process will feed into the rational choice of categories for categorical&#xD;
      representation of the data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Predictors at intubation suggesting death The investigators will assess the association of&#xD;
      any parameters and demographics of ventilated patients who die compared to those who do not&#xD;
      by cross tabulating parameters at point of ventilation with death, and calculating adjusted&#xD;
      associations using a logistic regression model. The investigators will also examine daily&#xD;
      risk of death using a random effects model with the repeated daily measurements. In order to&#xD;
      examine the potential for an easily calculable clinical risk score, logistic models will be&#xD;
      prepared, but retaining continuous variables as continuous (to maximise the retention of&#xD;
      useful predictive data) and reducing them to categorical data (for ease of clinical&#xD;
      calculation). The investigators will select predictors for the model using backward&#xD;
      elimination with the Akaike information criterion and alpha = 0.05. For candidate models the&#xD;
      investigators will calculate the c index and receiver operating curves and assess calibration&#xD;
      using the Hosmer-Lemeshow test. Bootstrapping and cross validation will be used to avoid&#xD;
      overfitting and assess model performance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Time trends analysis to identify markers leading to death We will examine the data for trends&#xD;
      over time in repeated measurements where available and describe these using appropriate&#xD;
      summary statistics. If there are enough repeated measurements, then each covariate will be&#xD;
      assessed with a JoinPoint analysis to assess if there is an obvious inflexion in time to&#xD;
      indicate a change in the clinical picture which marks a decline towards death Baseline&#xD;
      characteristics of patients discharged without supplemental oxygen We will assess the&#xD;
      association of any baseline parameters and demographics of patients who are discharged&#xD;
      without supplemental oxygen compared to those who are not by cross tabulating baseline&#xD;
      parameters with ventilation, and calculating adjusted associations using a logistic&#xD;
      regression model. In order to examine the potential for an easily calculable clinical risk&#xD;
      score, logistic models will be prepared, but retaining continuous variables as continuous (to&#xD;
      maximise the retention of useful predictive data) and reducing them to categorical data (for&#xD;
      ease of clinical calculation). The investigators will select predictors for the model using&#xD;
      backward elimination with the Akaike information criterion and alpha = 0.05. For candidate&#xD;
      models the investigators will calculate the c index and receiver operating curves and assess&#xD;
      calibration using the Hosmer-Lemeshow test. Each of these steps will be repeated in 10&#xD;
      randomly selected 20% subsamples of the dataset.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stratified supplemental analyses To identify different patient groups at risk of poor&#xD;
      outcomes, interactions with each risk model will be assessed to identify if stratification is&#xD;
      needed by age bands, sex, prior co-morbidities and baseline factors such as lymphopaenia, CRP&#xD;
      etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All analyses will be repeated for groups of PCR proven Covid-19 patients and those only&#xD;
      suspected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the analysis of discharge without supplemental oxygen the investigators will examine the&#xD;
      risk of readmission for those so discharged and repeat the analysis only for those not&#xD;
      subsequently readmitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria • All patients admitted to Nottingham University Hospitals Trust either&#xD;
      suspected of having Covid-19 infection or in whom the diagnosis is eventually confirmed and&#xD;
      who are over the age of 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Aged under 18.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ventilation</measure>
    <time_frame>During admission up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The need to ventilate the patient</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Death</measure>
    <time_frame>During admission or within 30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Death of the patient</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">500</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID19</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All patients meeting above criteria during the study period and prior to it for whom follow&#xD;
        up to 30 days can be completed during the period (i.e. admissions until 30 days prior to&#xD;
        study closes)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • All patients admitted to Nottingham University Hospitals Trust either suspected of having&#xD;
        Covid-19 infection or in whom the diagnosis is eventually confirmed and who are over the&#xD;
        age of 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Aged under 18.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Timothy R Card, FRCP, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Nottingham</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Timothy R Card, FRCP, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0115 8231346</phone>
    <email>tim.card@nottingham.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Colin Crooks, MRCP, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0115 823 1058</phone>
    <email>colin.crooks@nottingham.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nottingham</city>
        <zip>NG7 2UH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 16, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 7, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 7, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 8, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>prognostic score</keyword>
  <keyword>ventilation</keyword>
  <keyword>mortality</keyword>
  <keyword>early discharge</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

