<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3121">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04581291</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Aerobic exercise, COVID-19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04581291</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Aerobic Exercise on Immune Biomarkers and Symptoms Severity and Progression in Patients With COVID-19: A Pilot Randomized Control Trial</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Aerobic Exercise on Immune Biomarkers and Symptoms Severity and Progression in Patients With COVID-19: A Pilot Randomized Control Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istanbul Gelisim University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istanbul Gelisim University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Participants were assigned randomly into two groups, exercise and control groups. All&#xD;
      participants in both groups followed the WHO guidelines of quarantine and used standardized&#xD;
      medications given by the physician according to the Turkish Ministry of Health guidelines,&#xD;
      including the Hydroxyclorocin Sulphate 200 Mg Film Tablet (Plaquenil 200 Mg Film Tablet). The&#xD;
      dose was 2 times/ day, 200Mg/time, for 5 days. Besides, the exercise group performed&#xD;
      moderate-intensity aerobic exercises for 40 min/ 3 sessions/week, 40 minute/session.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Evaluative procedures There were two main dependent variables including blood immune markers&#xD;
      and severity of respiratory symptoms. These measurements were collected at the baseline after&#xD;
      one week and 48 h after the end of the exercise program (two weeks).&#xD;
&#xD;
      A lab technician was asked to visit the patient at home (quarantine). The lab technician wore&#xD;
      special protective equipment recommended by WHO. Three visits were performed, one at the&#xD;
      beginning of the research procedures, one week after, and the last visit at the 48 hours&#xD;
      after the end of the exercise program (two weeks). The technician collected blood and saliva&#xD;
      samples to be analyzed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood sample collection Blood samples were taken in the morning (8:30-9:30). 10mL of venous&#xD;
      blood was collected. Participants were asked to stop any exercise for at least 24 hours&#xD;
      before blood sampling. Also, participants were asked to stop eating any food or liquid from&#xD;
      22:00 the prior day of measurement. Samples were collected in vacutainer tubes with sodium&#xD;
      ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid (EDTA) for plasma separation. The blood was centrifuged at&#xD;
      3,000 rpm for 15 min at 4◦C. We measured total lymphocytes, leukocytes, and monocytes from&#xD;
      total-blood samples utilizing a multichannel hemocyte analysis system (SE-9000; Sysmex Corp,&#xD;
      Hyogo, Japan). The concentrations of IL-6, IL-10, and TNF-α were analyzed by using ELISA&#xD;
      commercial kits assay (R&amp;D Systems, Minneapolis, USA) following the manufacturer's&#xD;
      instructions for analysis on an EZ-Reader microplate reader at 450 nm. The samples were&#xD;
      stored at -20◦C for further analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Saliva sample collection A saliva sample was collected to measure the salivary IgA-S&#xD;
      concentration. The saliva sample was taken without any saliva stimulation methods, the&#xD;
      participant was asked to rinse their mouths with distilled water and to evacuate their mouth&#xD;
      just before collection. We used the passive drainage method for the collection, in which the&#xD;
      participant slightly flexed their head forward to allow the saliva to move into a sterilized&#xD;
      and pre-weighed Falcon tube for 5min. The weight of tubes were measured again following&#xD;
      collection, to estimate the volume and the saliva flow rate. The tubes were weighed with&#xD;
      0.1mg accuracy with proposed saliva density as 1.0 g.mL-1. The samples were stored at -80◦C&#xD;
      for further analysis. The S-IgA concentration were analyzed utilizing commercial ELISA kits&#xD;
      (IgA Salivary, DRG, Minneapolis, USA). The IgA-S secretion rate (ng/min) was measured by&#xD;
      multiplying the whole concentration of IgA-S present in the mucosal surface per unit of time&#xD;
      by the saliva flow rate (mL/min).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Wisconsin Upper Respiratory Symptom Survey The Wisconsin Upper Respiratory Symptom Survey&#xD;
      (WURSS) is an empirically derived patient-oriented illness-specific quality-of-life&#xD;
      evaluative outcomes instrument. The development process of this survey was described in&#xD;
      detail by Barrett et al. WURSS-24 is designed to evaluate the negative effect of acute upper&#xD;
      respiratory infection, presumed viral (the common cold). Its a valid and reliable measurement&#xD;
      tool to evaluate the measure items and domains that change over time including influenza-like&#xD;
      illness symptoms of headache, body aches, and fever. The participants were asked to fill the&#xD;
      survey before starting the study and the 2 times/week.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment Procedures Participants were assigned randomly into two groups, exercise and&#xD;
      control groups. All participants in both groups followed the WHO guidelines of quarantine and&#xD;
      used standardized medications given by the physician according to the Turkish Ministry of&#xD;
      Health, including the Hydroxyclorocin Sulphate 200 Mg Film Tablet (Plaquenil 200 Mg Film&#xD;
      Tablet). The dose was 2 times/ day, 200Mg/time, for 5 days Besides, the exercise group&#xD;
      performed a moderate-intensity aerobic exercises for 40 min/ 3 sessions/week, 40&#xD;
      minute/session.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in the exercise group performed a two weeks aerobic exercise program. The&#xD;
      exercise program consisted of walking/running on a treadmill or bicycling on a stationary&#xD;
      bicycle. Each session is composed of five-minute warm-up slow walking or bicycling. Then the&#xD;
      main intervention which composed of thirty-minutes of moderate-intensity aerobic exercises&#xD;
      (walking/running or bicycling). Lastly, a five-minute of cool-down exercise (walking/running&#xD;
      or bicycling). The exercise intensity was 60-75% of the predicted MHR (calculated as&#xD;
      MHR=210-age).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Borg Rating of Perceived Exertion (RPE) scale was used to control the exercise intensity.&#xD;
      PRE is a reliable and validated scale to allow individuals to monitor and guide the exercise&#xD;
      intensity by rating their level of exertion during exercise. After explaining the scale in&#xD;
      detail for the patients, we asked them to keep the exertion rating level between 12 to 14&#xD;
      (light - somewhat hard) on the Borg Scale, which suggests that the patient is exercising on a&#xD;
      moderate exercise level. The exercise was stopped if the patients experienced any of the&#xD;
      following signs and symptoms: chest pain, shortness of breath, fainting, claudication,&#xD;
      fatigue, ataxia, dizziness, cyanosis, or pallor.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 1, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Immune system markers</measure>
    <time_frame>4 Months</time_frame>
    <description>A blood was centrifuged at 3,000 rpm for 15 min at 4◦C. We measured total lymphocytes, leukocytes, and monocytes from total-blood samples utilizing a multichannel hemocyte analysis system (SE-9000; Sysmex Corp, Hyogo, Japan).&#xD;
A saliva sample was collected to measure the salivary IgA-S concentration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Upper respiratory tract infection symptoms severity and progression</measure>
    <time_frame>4 Months</time_frame>
    <description>The Wisconsin Upper Respiratory Symptom Survey (WURSS) is an empirically derived patient-oriented illness-specific quality-of-life evaluative outcomes instrument. The development process of this survey was described in detail by Barrett et al. WURSS-24 is designed to evaluate the negative effect of acute upper respiratory infection, presumed viral (the common cold). Its a valid and reliable measurement tool to evaluate the measure items and domains that change over time including influenza-like illness symptoms of headache, body aches, and fever. The participants were asked to fill the survey before starting the study and the 2 times/week.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Moderate Intensity Aerobic Exercises</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants in the exercise group performed a two weeks aerobic exercise program. The exercise program consisted of walking/running on a treadmill or bicycling on a stationary bicycle. Each session is composed of five-minute warm-up slow walking or bicycling. Then the main intervention which composed of thirty-minutes of moderate-intensity aerobic exercises (walking/running or bicycling). Lastly, a five-minute of cool-down exercises (walking/running or bicycling). The exercise intensity was 60-75% of the predicted MHR (calculated as MHR=210-age).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  the patient has a recent mild or moderate COVID-19 with no or low-grade fever 99.5-&#xD;
             100.94 °F (37.5-38.3 °C). Mild COVID-19 included that the patient has symptoms of&#xD;
             acute upper respiratory tract infection (fever, cough, myalgia, runny nose, fatigue,&#xD;
             sore throat, sneezing) or gastrointestinal symptoms (nausea, vomiting, abdominal pain,&#xD;
             diarrhea). Moderate grade of COVID 19 included that the participant has pneumonia&#xD;
             (cough, frequent fever) with no obvious hypoxemia, the presence of lesions on chest CT&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  that patient was not hospitalized and has moderate or high-grade fever &lt;100.94 °F&#xD;
             (&lt;38.3 °C) or other chronic diseases such as heart problems, hypertension or diabetes.&#xD;
             Women how were using contraceptives were excluded due to contraceptives decrease&#xD;
             immune functions and might affect the subjectivity to autoimmune disorders with marked&#xD;
             increases in risk for various autoimmune disorders&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>24 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Motaz Alawna</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <zip>3</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 7, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 7, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 7, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 9, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Istanbul Gelisim University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Motaz Alawna</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor (Principal Investigator)</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Disease Progression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

