<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1497">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04715815</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>REC.63-359-8-1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04715815</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19 and Its Effects on Chronic Pain Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of COVID-19 on Chronic Pain Patients in Terms of Pain and Pain Management</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Prince of Songkla University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Prince of Songkla University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Pain is an unpleasant sensory and emotional experience associated with actual or potential&#xD;
      tissue damage, or described in terms of such damage. Many factors can affect pain and its&#xD;
      severity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study aims to explore how the COVID-19 affects chronic pain patients in terms of pain in&#xD;
      general, intensity of pain, desire for pain treatment including follow up visits and pain&#xD;
      medication refills as well as sleep.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Research question&#xD;
&#xD;
      What are the effects of the COVID-19 on chronic pain patients in terms of pain and pain&#xD;
      management?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Conceptual framework&#xD;
&#xD;
      The COVID-19 is a novel emerging infectious disease which has unimaginable and unbelievable&#xD;
      large scale distressing effects worldwide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Up to date, there is no study which aims to evaluate the effects of the COVID-19 on chronic&#xD;
      pain patients in terms of pain and pain management. The previous survey in patients focused&#xD;
      on the worrisome of them for getting this infection and their confidence in their government&#xD;
      to control the COVID-19 situation in the US.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Materials and methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is an in-depth interview. The in-depth interview is the principal method to&#xD;
      collect qualitative data by setting up open-ended questions beforehand. Patients who are&#xD;
      interviewed, can express their attitudes freely. This method is flexible which words,&#xD;
      sentences and questions can be adjusted to suit each interviewee (participant). The process&#xD;
      consists of active and intentional listening as well as ask on an in-depth basis. All&#xD;
      conversations during the in-depth interview are tape-recorded.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To explain how the COVID-19 affects chronic pain patients in terms of pain and pain management.</measure>
    <time_frame>January to December 2021</time_frame>
    <description>An in-depth interview will be conducted to find out how the COVID-19 affects chronic pain patients. The investigators will measure pain intensity and sleep disturbance level by using an 11-point numerical rating scale where 0 means that the patient's pain condition is not affected by the COVID-19 and 10 means that the patient's pain condition is maximally affected. The higher the score is the worse.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To explain how the COVID-19 affects chronic pain patients' psychological status.</measure>
    <time_frame>January to December 2021</time_frame>
    <description>An in-depth interview will be performed to find out how the COVID-19 affects the psychological aspect of chronic pain patients. The level of anxiety and stress will be measured using the 11-point verbal numerical rating scale where 0 means that the patient's psychological status is not affected by the COVID-19 and 10 means that the patient's psychological status is maximally affected. The higher the score is the worse.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Pain</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No intervention (only interview)</intervention_name>
    <description>Interview</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients aged 18 years and older who have chronic pain for at least 3 months' duration.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with chronic pain who have been under the health care service of the pain&#xD;
             clinic of Songklanagarind hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic pain patients are patients with persistent pain for at least 3 months. Pain&#xD;
             can be from any etiologies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The expected number of interviwees for this in-depth interview is 30 or until the&#xD;
             gathered interview data are saturated.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are not willing to participate this study and have time for an in person&#xD;
             'in-depth interview'.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are not influence in Thai language.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are physically or mentally too ill to participate this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sasikaan Nimmaanrat, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Prince of Songkla University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sasikaan Nimmaanrat, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+66887907842</phone>
    <email>snimmaanrat@yahoo.com.au</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Wolf MS, Serper M, Opsasnick L, O'Conor RM, Curtis L, Benavente JY, Wismer G, Batio S, Eifler M, Zheng P, Russell A, Arvanitis M, Ladner D, Kwasny M, Persell SD, Rowe T, Linder JA, Bailey SC. Awareness, Attitudes, and Actions Related to COVID-19 Among Adults With Chronic Conditions at the Onset of the U.S. Outbreak: A Cross-sectional Survey. Ann Intern Med. 2020 Jul 21;173(2):100-109. doi: 10.7326/M20-1239. Epub 2020 Apr 9.</citation>
    <PMID>32271861</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 15, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 20, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Prince of Songkla University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sasikaan Nimmaanrat</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Primary Investigator, Head of Pain Clinic, Clinical Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>IPD will be shared upon request.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

