<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4605">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04025580</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>190126</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>19-I-0126</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04025580</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Systems Analyses of the Immune Response to the Seasonal Influenza Vaccine</brief_title>
  <official_title>Systems Analyses of the Immune Response to the Seasonal Influenza Vaccine</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vaccines help prevent disease by causing the body to have an immune response. Many parts of&#xD;
      this response happen in the blood. This response happens over days and weeks after getting&#xD;
      the vaccine. Researchers want to how the blood changes over time in response to vaccines.&#xD;
      They want to find out why vaccines work better for some people than for others. This could&#xD;
      help make more effective vaccines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To learn about how the body responds to vaccines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy people ages 18 and older&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with a medical history, physical exam, and blood and urine&#xD;
      tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have 9 visits over 6 months. All visits will include blood tests and a&#xD;
      physical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have the first visit 1 week before they get the vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will get the flu vaccine at the second visit. The vaccine will be injected into&#xD;
      the muscle of the upper arm with a needle. They will be watched for side effects for 15&#xD;
      minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have the next 2 visits exactly 1 day and 1 week after they get the vaccine.&#xD;
      They will have the other 5 visits about 14, 28, 70, and 100 days after they get the vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will take email questionnaires about whether they had any side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may have optional extra study visits. These will be no more than once a month&#xD;
      for up to 1 year after they get the vaccine. Optionally, they can also repeat the study each&#xD;
      year through the 2023 - 2024 flu season&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Certain functions of the immune system are revealed only when the immune system is&#xD;
      challenged. When a person is vaccinated, a coordinated response results: activation and&#xD;
      interaction of distinct innate and adaptive immune cell populations and pathways, culminating&#xD;
      in the formation of germinal centers from which antibody-producing plasma cells and memory B&#xD;
      cells derive. By taking measurements at various time points before and after vaccination, we&#xD;
      can build a comprehensive picture of how the immune system responds to a vaccine challenge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The seasonal influenza vaccination provides an excellent model of coordinated immune activity&#xD;
      involving innate and adaptive responses, as demonstrated in a past NIH study in 2009-2011;&#xD;
      however, scientific advances and the possibility of multi-season responses in individuals&#xD;
      warrant a new follow-up study with more comprehensive sampling. This is an open-label,&#xD;
      prospective, exploratory study to assess the baseline and post-vaccination immune responses&#xD;
      of healthy volunteers to an approved seasonal influenza vaccine. Subjects will undergo&#xD;
      baseline blood collections on day -7 and on day 0 before receiving the study vaccine. After&#xD;
      vaccination, blood will be collected on days 1, 7, 14, 28, 70, and 100. Optionally, subjects&#xD;
      may also give blood once a month, as requested, up until 1 year after vaccination. Blood&#xD;
      samples will be used to assess short- and long-term immunological effects of immunization.&#xD;
      Evaluations will include vaccine antibody titers. Additional evaluations may include&#xD;
      peripheral immune cell phenotyping, RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) of whole blood and defined&#xD;
      peripheral blood cell subsets, and measurement of serum proteins and antibodies. Subjects may&#xD;
      optionally provide stool samples at some visits for exploratory microbiome assessment.&#xD;
      Additionally, subjects may optionally continue study participation annually through the&#xD;
      2023-24 influenza season.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of this protocol is to use the collective information gathered across all healthy&#xD;
      volunteers to understand how the immune system works as a whole.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 2, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Microneutralization titers</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>Change in antibody titer response to vaccination, as measured by microneutralization titers at day 0 and day 70 and its relationship with novel baseline biomarkers</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Microneutralization titers</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>Change in antibody titer response to vaccination, as measured by microneutralization titers at day 0 and day 70 and its relationship with established baseline biomarkers (CD38+ CD20+ B cell frequencies and /or transcriptomic signatures) and post-vaccination biomarkers (plasmablast cell frequencies and/or transcriptomic signatures)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Microneutralization titers</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in antibody titer response to vaccination between subjects with a history of symptomatic or asymptomatic SARS CoV 2 infection and those with no evidence of SARS CoV 2 infection</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Volunteer</condition>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Flucelvax, Fluvirin, or Fluzone High Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Healthy Volunteer between ages 18-65 receiving Flucelvax</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Flucelvax</intervention_name>
    <description>Seasonal influenza vaccine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Flucelvax, Fluvirin, or Fluzone High Dose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fluvirin</intervention_name>
    <description>Seasonal influenza vaccine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Flucelvax, Fluvirin, or Fluzone High Dose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fluzone High Dose</intervention_name>
    <description>Seasonal influenza vaccine for adults ages 65 and older</description>
    <arm_group_label>Flucelvax, Fluvirin, or Fluzone High Dose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Individuals must meet all of the following criteria to be eligible for study participation:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Aged 18 years and older (no upper age limit).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Able to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Willing to have samples and data stored for future research.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Able to proficiently speak, read, and write English.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Individuals meeting any of the following criteria will be excluded from study&#xD;
        participation:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. CBC with differential, lymphocyte phenotyping with T, B, and natural killer cells&#xD;
             (TBNK), acute care, mineral, and hepatic panels, anti-CMV immunoglobulin (Ig) G and&#xD;
             IgM, and/or anti-Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) antibody panel values outside of the NIH&#xD;
             Department of Laboratory Medicine normal reference ranges and deemed clinically&#xD;
             significant by the PI at the time of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Positive result for anti-HIV 1/2 antibody, antibody to hepatitis B surface antigen, or&#xD;
             anti-hepatitis C virus antibody screening at the time of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Prior receipt of a current seasonal influenza vaccine (for the season of&#xD;
             participation).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of allergy or hypersensitivity to any components of the study vaccine (e.g.,&#xD;
             egg protein, latex).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of severe reactions to vaccines.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Use of an oral glucocorticoid within the past 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Receipt of a live-attenuated vaccine within the past 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Receipt of any experimental vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Receipt of any other type of vaccine (non-live and non-experimental, e.g., tetanus,&#xD;
             diphtheria, and pertussis [TDaP]) within the past 14 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Planned vaccination before day 100 after study vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Current or recent use (within the past 90 days) of immunoglobulin therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Surgery within the past 8 weeks, or planned surgery before day 100.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Current (within the past 30 days) treatment for active malignancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Cancer chemotherapy in the past 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Administration of any blood products within 90 days of the screening, or planned&#xD;
             administration before day 100.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. History of parasitic, amebic, fungal, or mycobacterial infections within the past 1&#xD;
             year with the exception of tinea pedis and onychomycosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Diabetes mellitus.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. History of autoimmune or autoinflammatory disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. History of a bleeding disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Current use (within the past 30 days) of illicit drugs (per subject report).&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Current use (within the past 30 days) of nicotine-containing products, including&#xD;
             cigarettes and chewing tobacco, nicotine patches, gum, electronic cigarettes, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Current alcohol use disorders (criteria per Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of&#xD;
             Mental Disorders, fifth edition), within the past 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Serious, ongoing, uncontrolled infection within the past 30 days as per the judgement&#xD;
             of the PI.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. History of Guillain-Barre syndrome (GBS).&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. BMI greater than or equal to 30.&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Known or suspected immunodeficiency within 1 year, including documented HIV infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. Pregnancy or planning to become pregnant during the study period. (Women of&#xD;
             childbearing potential must have a negative urine or serum pregnancy test at&#xD;
             screening.)&#xD;
&#xD;
         28. Presence of conditions that, in the judgment of the PI, may put the individual at&#xD;
             undue risk or compromise the scientific objectives of the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rachel D Sparks, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rachel D Sparks, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(240) 292-4642</phone>
    <email>niaidflustudy2020@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2019-I-0126.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tsang JS, Schwartzberg PL, Kotliarov Y, Biancotto A, Xie Z, Germain RN, Wang E, Olnes MJ, Narayanan M, Golding H, Moir S, Dickler HB, Perl S, Cheung F; Baylor HIPC Center; CHI Consortium. Global analyses of human immune variation reveal baseline predictors of postvaccination responses. Cell. 2014 Apr 10;157(2):499-513. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2014.03.031. Erratum in: Cell. 2014 Jul 3;158(1):226.</citation>
    <PMID>24725414</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 10, 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 18, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 18, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 19, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 13, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Systems Biology</keyword>
  <keyword>Immunology</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

