<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1407">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04625296</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AP-HP 200512</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04625296</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Behaviour and Experience of Communities Healthcare Professionals Facing the SARS CoV-2 (COVID-19) Epidemic</brief_title>
  <acronym>COVecu</acronym>
  <official_title>Behaviour and Experience of Communities Healthcare Professionals Facing the SARS CoV-2 Epidemic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to identify behaviours and experiences of communities healthcare&#xD;
      professionals (doctors, nurses and physiotherapists) in the management of the SARS-CoV 2&#xD;
      epidemic by identifying the impact of the epidemic on their work, their personal life and the&#xD;
      difficulties they had experienced.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Given the overcrowding in hospital services, the management of the health crisis linked to&#xD;
      the SARS-CoV-2 epidemic relies in particular on the Territorial Professional Health&#xD;
      Communities, which include doctors, nurses and physiotherapists. The challenge of caring for&#xD;
      patients in a health system described as suffering, raises questions about the experience of&#xD;
      the epidemic at all levels of action. To our knowledge, there is no information to date on&#xD;
      the experience of the health crisis of urban health professionals in terms of the impact on&#xD;
      their professional and personal lives and the difficulties encountered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Using a mixed, cross-sectional, observational and multicentric methodology, the aim of this&#xD;
      study, lasting a total of 12 months, is to identify the impact on professional and personal&#xD;
      life as well as the difficulties experienced by doctors, nurses and physiotherapists working&#xD;
      in private practice in connection with a CPTS involved in the management of the health&#xD;
      crisis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Semi-directive interviews, lasting a maximum of 45 minutes, will be carried out with doctors,&#xD;
      nurses and physiotherapists integrated into a CPTS and digitally recorded audio digitally and&#xD;
      then transcribed literally and in full. They will be conducted by the researcher&#xD;
      participating in the study. The transcribed interviews will be anonymised and kept in an&#xD;
      office of the Clinical Research Unit Paris Centre in order to carry out the analysis as the&#xD;
      interviews are carried out. Following the interview, the participant will be asked to answer&#xD;
      the &quot;Preparedness for Caregiving Scale&quot; composed of 8 questions, each evaluated by a 4-level&#xD;
      Likert scale. Over a planned inclusion period of 3 months, 75 health professionals (25&#xD;
      doctors, 25 nurses, 25 physiotherapists) will be included. The evaluation criteria of the&#xD;
      study will be: i) The diversity of themes extracted during the analysis of the interviews,&#xD;
      leading after analysis to a set of meta-themes describing all the experience stories ii) The&#xD;
      score on 24 of the &quot;Preparedness for Caregiving Scale&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will allow an enrichment of knowledge about the impact of the health crisis on&#xD;
      professional and personal life and the difficulties encountered by urban health professionals&#xD;
      (doctors, nurses and physiotherapists). But also the identification of the key needs of&#xD;
      self-employed health professionals in the management of a health crisis, both in terms of&#xD;
      health care skills and in terms of organisation and communication between the various&#xD;
      players. Finally, this study will make it possible to identify the traumas experienced and/or&#xD;
      felt by self-employed health professionals and the possible consequences of these traumas.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 17, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Diversity of themes extracted about care situations management of the COVID-19 epidemic.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 Day</time_frame>
    <description>The greatest possible diversity of themes extracted during the analysis of interviews. Identifying the impact of the epidemic of healthcare worker, their personal life and the difficulties they had experienced</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Preparedness for caregiving scale (PCS)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 Day</time_frame>
    <description>8 questions, each evaluated by a 4-level Likert scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">75</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthcare Worker Facing COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthcare professional</arm_group_label>
    <description>Communities Health professionals (doctors, nurses, physiotherapist) Working in the city, In metropolitan France, Having managed patients with COVID-19</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Semi-directive interview</intervention_name>
    <description>Semi-directive interview, lasting a maximum of 45 minutes</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthcare professional</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaire : Preparedness for Caregiving Scale</intervention_name>
    <description>Preparedness for Caregiving Scale - 8 questions</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthcare professional</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The population of healthcare workers will be selected through Territorial Professional&#xD;
        Health Communities (TPHC). These TPHC are organizations designed around a health project&#xD;
        and formed on the initiative of city health professionals based on a territory defined by&#xD;
        the professionals themselves.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Communities Health professionals (doctors, nurses, physiotherapist)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be integrate to a Territorial Professional Health Communities (TPHC)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having managed patients during the COVID-19 epidemic&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Health professionals working in the hospital sector&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Health Students (medical, nursing, physiotherapy)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Flora DEVOS, Nurse MSC PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>APHP</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Flora DEVOS, nurse Msc PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+33 1 58 41 28 84</phone>
    <email>flora.devos@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Marie BENHAMMANI</last_name>
    <phone>+33 1 58 41 12 11</phone>
    <email>marie.godard@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>URC/CIC Paris Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75014</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Flora DEVOS, nurse</last_name>
      <phone>01 58 41 28 84</phone>
      <email>flora.devos@aphp.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 10, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 10, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 10, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Healthcare worker ,</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>behaviour</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

