<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3967">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04364711</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ReCoVer - MERMAIDS 2.0</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04364711</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>EuRopean Study of MAjor Infectious Disease Syndromes Related to COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>MERMAIDS 2</acronym>
  <official_title>Multi-centre EuRopean Study of MAjor Infectious Disease Syndromes (MERMAIDS) - Acute Respiratory Infections (MERMAIDS ARI) 2.0</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>UMC Utrecht</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>UMC Utrecht</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background Rapid European COVID-19 Emergency Research response (RECoVER), is a project&#xD;
      involving 10 international partners that has been selected for funding by the European Union&#xD;
      under the Horizon 2020 research framework responding to call topic SC1-PHE-CORONAVIRUS-2020:&#xD;
      Advancing knowledge for the clinical and public health response to the SARS-CoV-2 epidemic.&#xD;
      MERMAIDS 2.0 is the hospital care study within RECOVER.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rationale Detailed patient-oriented studies are needed to determine the spectrum of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 disease and the combined influences of age, comorbidities and pathogen&#xD;
      co-infections on the development of severe disease, together with virological and&#xD;
      immunological profiles. This research is key to understanding the pathophysiology and&#xD;
      epidemiology of this new disease, as well as to identifying potential targets for therapeutic&#xD;
      or preventive interventions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective To establish the prevalence, disease spectrum and severity, clinical features, risk&#xD;
      factors, spread and outcomes of novel 2019 coronavirus infection (SARS-CoV-2) in Hospital&#xD;
      Care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design Prospective observational cohort study in selected European countries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population&#xD;
&#xD;
      Children and adults with 1) acute respiratory illness (ARI) presenting to hospital care&#xD;
      during the SARS-CoV-2 epidemic (including both COVID-19 and non-COVID-19 patients) and 2)&#xD;
      patients with confirmed COVID-19 infection, but with atypical presentation (non-ARI) or with&#xD;
      nosocomial acquisition. Sites can optionally participate in the following tiers:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tier 0 (Clinical data collection only) - Clinical data will be collected but no biological&#xD;
      samples will be obtained for research purposes. Summary of the illness episode and outcome,&#xD;
      including a selection of risk factors and comorbidities and medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tier 1 (Clinical data and biological sampling) - Clinical samples and data will be collected&#xD;
      on enrolment day and then at scheduled time points.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tier 2 (Clinical data an extended biological sampling).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Optional add-on study In a subset of sites and patients, COVID-19 positive patients will be&#xD;
      followed post-discharge for 6 months to study clinical recovery and long-term sequelae Main&#xD;
      study parameters/endpoints: Prevalence of COVID-19 among patients with acute respiratory&#xD;
      illness. COVID-19 disease spectrum and host and pathogen risk factors for severity. Long-term&#xD;
      sequelae of COVID-19 requiring hospital care. Proportion hospital-acquired COVID-19&#xD;
      infections and characteristics of nosocomial transmission.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Duration Scheduled 2 years and based on COVID-19 dynamics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nature and extent of the burden associated with participation, benefit and group relatedness&#xD;
      This study is observational in nature. There will be no direct benefit to research&#xD;
      participants. The study may include biological sampling in addition to sampling required for&#xD;
      medical management. The results of the tests done on these samples may not contribute to&#xD;
      improving the participant's health. Minimal inconvenience and discomfort to the participant&#xD;
      may arise from study visits and biological sampling.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pneumonia Severity indexes</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Need for supplemental oxygen; non-invasive or invasive mechanical ventilation; extra-corporeal life support</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital - and ICU/HCU length of stay</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>In-hospital mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Activities of daily life, quality of life, variations in home living status and employment status</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of SARS-CoV2 positive patients</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2000</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <condition>SARS-CoV 2</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This is a descriptive study of the clinical syndrome caused by SARS-CoV-2. Patients will&#xD;
        only be considered for enrolment if appropriate local infection control and prevention&#xD;
        measures are in place and can be maintained. In hospital, potential participants will be&#xD;
        identified through hospital workers upon presentation at recruiting sites. The clinical&#xD;
        research infrastructures of COMBACTE CLIN-NET will be used for site selection for an&#xD;
        efficient establishment of a clinical network with broad European coverage providing access&#xD;
        to a large patient population across all age groups and differing healthcare environments.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Clinical suspicion of a new episode of acute respiratory tract infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient is admitted to hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Primary reason for hospital admission is clinical suspicion of a new episode of ARI&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Onset of the following symptoms within the last 7 days: i. Sudden onset of&#xD;
             self-reported fever OR temperature of ≥ 38°C at presentation AND ii. At least one&#xD;
             respiratory symptom (cough, sore throat, runny or congested nose, dyspnea) AND iii. At&#xD;
             least one systemic symptom (headache, muscle ache, sweats or chills or tiredness)&#xD;
&#xD;
        OR&#xD;
&#xD;
        Laboratory confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection at the time of eligibility check.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Inability to obtain consent from patient or surrogate&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Previous enrollment in current study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>April 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 24, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 28, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 24, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 24, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 28, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>UMC Utrecht</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>MJM Bonten</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor Medical Microbiology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>acute respiratory infection</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

