<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3984">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04597242</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CF-301-107</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04597242</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Expanded Access Study of Exebacase in COVID-19 Patients With Persistent MRSA Bacteremia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Expanded Access Study of a Single Dose of Exebacase in Addition to Antistaphylococcal Antibiotics for the Treatment of Persistent Methicillin-Resistant Staphylococcus Aureus (MRSA) Bloodstream Infections (Including Right Sided Endocarditis) in Patients Who Are Hospitalized With Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>ContraFect</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>ContraFect</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label, expanded access study of exebacase used in addition to&#xD;
      antistaphylococcal antibiotics in adult patients with persistent methicillin-resistant&#xD;
      Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) bloodstream infections (BSI), including right-sided endocarditis&#xD;
      (R-IE), who are hospitalized with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Patients with&#xD;
      left-sided endocarditis (L-IE) are excluded. Patients will receive a single dose of&#xD;
      exebacase. Patients will continue to receive antistaphylococcal antibiotics as prescribed by&#xD;
      the treating physician. Exebacase Phase 3 study sites (Study CF-301-105) may participate in&#xD;
      this Expanded Access study (Study CF-301-107).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exebacase, a direct lytic agent, is an entirely new treatment modality against S. aureus.&#xD;
      Exebacase is a recombinantly-produced, purified cell wall hydrolase enzyme that results in&#xD;
      rapid bacteriolysis, potent biofilm eradication, synergy with antibiotics, low propensity for&#xD;
      resistance, and the potential to suppress antibiotic resistance when used together with&#xD;
      antibiotics. Exebacase represents a first-in-field, first-in-class treatment with the&#xD;
      potential to improve clinical outcome when used in addition to standard-of-care antibiotics&#xD;
      to treat S. aureus BSI including IE.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Available</overall_status>
  <study_type>Expanded Access</study_type>
  <expanded_access_info>
    <expanded_access_type_intermediate>Yes</expanded_access_type_intermediate>
  </expanded_access_info>
  <condition>MRSA Bloodstream Infection</condition>
  <condition>MRSA Bacteremia</condition>
  <condition>MRSA Right-sided Endocarditis</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exebacase</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will receive a single IV infusion of exebacase in addition to antistaphylococcal antibiotics prescribed by the treating physician. Patients with normal renal function or mild renal impairment will be administered a dose of 18 mg of exebacase; patients with moderate or severe renal impairment will be administered a dose of 12 mg; patients with end-stage renal disease, including those on hemodialysis, will be administered a dose of 8 mg.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female, 18 years of age or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hospitalized with known COVID-19 infection confirmed by positive diagnostic test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not eligible for the exebacase Phase 3 study (CF-301-105).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood cultures positive for MRSA for ≥3 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is not pregnant or breastfeeding and is not of reproductive potential or&#xD;
             agrees to remain abstinent or use contraception if of reproductive potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected left-sided IE.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intubated for COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of prosthetic valve or cardiac valve support ring, or presence of known&#xD;
             infected orthopedic hardware, prosthetic joint, or cardiac device.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected brain abscess or meningitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in an investigational study or expanded access protocol for another&#xD;
             antistaphylococcal antibacterial agent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Medical Director, ContraFect</last_name>
    <phone>914-207-2300</phone>
    <email>clinicalstudies@contrafect.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CF-301-107 Study Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Butte</city>
        <state>Montana</state>
        <zip>59701</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Available</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 20, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bacteremia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endocarditis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

