<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3383">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04717089</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TMH-ExRR-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04717089</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Extended Recovery During COVID-19: Multi-perspective Value-based Analysis</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Rapid Conversion of Ordinary Recovery Beds to an Overnight Intensive Recovery (OIR) to Alleviate the High Pressure on Postoperative Intensive Care Demands During COVID-19 Pandemics in a Local Tertiary Hospital: a Multi-perspective Value-based Analysis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tuen Mun Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Anaesthesia &amp; Operation Theatre Service, Tuen Mun Hospital, Hong Kong</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Intensive Care Unit, Tuen Mun Hospital, Hong Kong</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tuen Mun Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the value-based effectiveness of the implementation of TMH Extended Recovery&#xD;
      during COVID-19 pandemics by an institutional matched case-control and quantitative survey&#xD;
      study Two ordinary recovery beds were converted to an overnight intensive recovery (&quot;Extended&#xD;
      Recovery&quot;) within the operating theatre complex of Tuen Mun Hospital during COVID-19&#xD;
      pandemics, in an attempt to free the ICU bed and resources from postoperative patients. This&#xD;
      study was designed to evaluate the efficacy and staff perceptions towards the abrupt&#xD;
      implementation of TMH Extended Recovery by mobilization of the existing OT resources to cope&#xD;
      with the COVID-19 emergency situations. The value-based analysis would look into the&#xD;
      implementation effectiveness in twofold: 1) the clinical efficacy using a case-control audit&#xD;
      on clinical outcomes and 2) the staff acceptance by means of the staff attitudes survey .&#xD;
      Hopefully this would provide a multi-perspective evaluation of the implementation strategies&#xD;
      and aid planning of new services in the future.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      2 parts are included in this study&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Matched Case Control study, with the aim of analyzing the clinical efficacy of TMH&#xD;
      Extended Recovery during COVID-19 in value based healthcare model. We included all&#xD;
      postoperative patient admitted in TMH Extended Recovery during COVID epidemics, excluding&#xD;
      patient awaiting ICU in the ordinary recovery room or patient requiring level 3 intensive&#xD;
      care on arrival in the recovery room. Three activation periods of extended recovery service&#xD;
      (10 Feb - 26 Apr 2020 / 27 Jul - 13 Sep 2020 / 4th wave, still ongoing), and performed case&#xD;
      matching with the post operative patient with similar clinical characteristics entering&#xD;
      intensive care unit directly in recent 3-5 years, with each case matched with specifically 5&#xD;
      control. We evaluate the value based health care efficacy, including the amount of healthcare&#xD;
      expenditure based on bed occupancy and manpower, rate of elective discharge to intensive care&#xD;
      unit from extended recovery, rate of unanticipated intensive care admission within 48hrs upon&#xD;
      discharge to general ward, and length of hospital stay, and total number of ICU bed spared.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The staff attitude survey, with the aim to investigate the staff perception towards the&#xD;
      implementation of TMH extended recovery during COVID-19 pandemics based on Technology&#xD;
      Acceptance Model in healthcare. We designed a questionnaire based on Technology Acceptance&#xD;
      Model, and distributed to medical and nursing staffs involved in extended recovery service,&#xD;
      and evaluate the perceived usefulness, perceived ease of use, social influence of subjective&#xD;
      norm, and perceived behavioral control of facilitating condition. Differential analysis would&#xD;
      be conducted for the evaluation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 10, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>total number of ICU bed days spared</measure>
    <time_frame>during study period, up to 1 year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>amount of healthcare expenditures based on bed occupancy and manpower</measure>
    <time_frame>during study period, up to 1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>number of unanticipated intensive care unit admission within 48 hours upon discharge to general ward</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hour</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>rate of elective discharge to the intensive care unit</measure>
    <time_frame>After extended recovery service by case. Up to 24 hour</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>length of hospital stays</measure>
    <time_frame>during admission or patient death, typically up to 1 month</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Overnight Intensive Recovery</condition>
  <condition>Postoperative Care</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>postoperative patients admitted to TMH Extended Recovery during COVID-19 pandemics</arm_group_label>
    <description>Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
Patients awaiting ICU admission in the ordinary recovery room&#xD;
Patients requiring level 3 intensive care on arrival at the recovery room</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Postoperative patient admitted to ICU with case matched</arm_group_label>
    <description>Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
o Based on case matched with the Extended Recovery Group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>overnight intensive recovery / extended recovery</intervention_name>
    <description>From January 2020, during COVID-19 first panademics in Hong Kong, a bundle of interim measures were implemented with the joint efforts of the Department of Anaesthesia and Operating Theatre Services (A&amp;OT) and Intensive Care Unit (ICU), and two ordinary recovery beds were converted into Extended Recovery (ExRR), based on the concept of overnight intensive recovery (OIR) to provide level 2 intensive care to patients undergoing major or ultra-major operations or having multiple comorbidities warranted intensive care in the immediately postoperative periods. This was conducted over 3 panademics wave in Hong Kong.</description>
    <arm_group_label>postoperative patients admitted to TMH Extended Recovery during COVID-19 pandemics</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        o The operation periods of TMH Extended Recovery during COVID-19 and therefore the number&#xD;
        of cases included in this study was largely bound by the administrative decision of&#xD;
        hospital management based on the ICU bed pressure during COVID-19 situations. All patients&#xD;
        being admitted to TMH Extended Recovery during the two periods of service activation amid&#xD;
        COVID-19 pandemics, i.e. from 10 February 2020 to 26 April 2020 and from 27 July 2020 to 13&#xD;
        September 2020 were included in this audit. To increase the statistical power above 0.8, a&#xD;
        control-to-case ratio of 5 will be adopted for case matching based on the assumption of&#xD;
        having the correlation coefficient greater than 0.2 or the prevalence of exposure in the&#xD;
        control group less than 0.15.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
        o Postoperative patients admitted to TMH Extended Recovery during COVID-19 pandemics&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients awaiting ICU admission in the ordinary recovery room&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients requiring level 3 intensive care on arrival at the recovery room&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carmen Lam</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Tuen Mun Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hon Wai Lau, MBChB CUHK</last_name>
    <phone>852 61261347</phone>
    <email>lauhonwai@outlook.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Operation Theatre, Tuen Mun Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tuen Mun</city>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Benny Cheng</last_name>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Carmen Lam</last_name>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 20, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Tuen Mun Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lau Hon Wai</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Medical Officer</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

