<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="952">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04741178</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Paesi-COV-19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04741178</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PAtterns and Extension in Sars-Cov-2 Related Interstitial Pneumonia: CT Analysis</brief_title>
  <acronym>Paesi-COV-19</acronym>
  <official_title>PAtterns and Extension in Sars-Cov-2 Related Interstitial Pneumonia: CT Analysis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Morgagni Pierantoni Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Morgagni Pierantoni Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The hallmark of the L phenotype is the vasoplegia, as confirmed by the rapid change in&#xD;
      density and distribution of CT findings from the supine to the prone position (Piciucchi S,&#xD;
      Ravaglia C, Vizzuso A, Bertocco M, Poletti V. Reversibility of venous dilatation and&#xD;
      parenchymal changes density in Sars-Cov-2 pneumonia: toward the definition of a peculiar&#xD;
      pattern. Pulmonology. 2020). The benefit of a prone position in awake, nonintubated,&#xD;
      spontaneously breathing Covid-19 patients has been emerging as potential tool to improve&#xD;
      oxygenation and to prevent the access to ICU (Elharrar X, Trigui Y, Dols AM, Touchon F,&#xD;
      Martinez S, Prud'homme E, Papazian L. Use of Prone Positioning in Nonintubated Patients With&#xD;
      COVID-19 and Hypoxemic Acute Respiratory Failure. JAMA. 2020 Jun 9;323(22):2336-2338; Coppo&#xD;
      A, Bellani G, Winterton D, Di Pierro M, Soria A, Faverio P, Cairo M, Mori S, Messinesi G,&#xD;
      Contro E, Bonfanti P, Benini A, Valsecchi MG, Antolini L, Foti G. Feasibility and&#xD;
      physiological effects of prone positioning in non-intubated patients with acute respiratory&#xD;
      failure due to COVID-19 (PRON-COVID): a prospective cohort study. Lancet Respir Med. 2020&#xD;
      Aug;8(8):765-774;Jiang LG, LeBaron J, Bodnar D, Caputo ND, Chang BP, Chiricolo G, Flores S,&#xD;
      Kenny J, Melville L, Sayan OR, Sharma M, Shemesh A, Suh E, Farmer B. Conscious Proning: An&#xD;
      Introduction of a Proning Protocol for Nonintubated, Awake, Hypoxic Emergency Department&#xD;
      COVID-19 Patients. Acad Emerg Med. 2020 Jul;27(7):566-569.).&#xD;
&#xD;
      No evidence of radiological modifications related to Aim of our study is to evaluate CT&#xD;
      changes in terms of extension, distribution and prevalence of findings, in the supine&#xD;
      compared with the prone position.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients were considered eligible if were with a confirmed diagnosis of Covid-19 infection,&#xD;
      as documented by RT-PCR nasal swab, or, confirmed by a subsequent BAL, aged between 18 and 90&#xD;
      years old, able to maintain both the supine and prone position on the CT scan table. Patients&#xD;
      who were pregnant, scarcely collaborative were excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once adopted the supine position on the CT scan table, the patient received the oximeter. At&#xD;
      the end of the supine scan, arterial oxygenation was recorded. Soon after the supine scan the&#xD;
      patient adopted prone position with both arms extended anteriorly. CT scan was performed with&#xD;
      a low dosage protocol, finally the second arterial oxygenation was recorded at the end of the&#xD;
      prone scan. Patients who had oxygen requirement below 3 L/min temporarily suspended the&#xD;
      supply; whilst those with an oxygen supply more than 3 L/min maintained it.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three experienced radiologists analyzed CT images on a PACS workstation, in three stages.&#xD;
      First to score the total severity score, secondly to analyze the supine scan and finally the&#xD;
      prone CT images. The images were viewed in the lung window settings (width 1000-1500 HU;&#xD;
      level 700 to -550 HU).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The TSS was calculated dividing each lung into three zones (Zhou S, Wang Y, Zhu T, Xia L. CT&#xD;
      Features of Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Pneumonia in 62 Patients in Wuhan, China. AJR&#xD;
      Am J Roentgenol. 2020 Jun;214(6):1287-1294).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The upper zone included parenchyma above the carina; the middle zone from carina and&#xD;
      inferiori pulmonary vein and, finally the lower zone included the parenchyma below the&#xD;
      inferior pulmonary vein. Each lung zone was further subdivided into anterior and posterior,&#xD;
      so that the resulting zones were 12. Each zone was scored as follows: 0 with no changes; 1&#xD;
      with changes extent &lt;25%; 2 with changes between 26 and 50%; 3, 51-75% and finally 4, &gt;75%.&#xD;
      To obtain the final score, the sum of each zone score was calculated, with a maximum value of&#xD;
      48.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After this first step, for each zone, the percentage of extension of patterns was calculated&#xD;
      visually and recorded. Patterns included: pure ground glass; crazy paving; part-solid ground&#xD;
      glass; perilobular pattern, and consolidation. This semiquantitative evaluation of this five&#xD;
      patterns, was then evaluated for the prone scanning. The extension of the five patterns were&#xD;
      averaged multiplying 1 for ground glass, 2 for crazy paving; 3 for part solid ground glass; 4&#xD;
      for perilobular pattern and 5 for consolidation. Each zone showed a final averaged score.&#xD;
      Summarization of the anterior zones and posterior allows to calculate the anterior-posterior&#xD;
      ratio both in supine and prone. Moreover, summarizing the scores in supine and prone, the&#xD;
      prone-supine ratio has been calculated. A target vein, representing a &quot;outside&quot; vessel&#xD;
      enlargement&quot; has ben identified in dorsal segment of right upper lobe or in the posterobasal&#xD;
      segment of right lower lobe, measured in supine and prone, and calculated prone-supine ratio.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a final step, CT scan has been reviewed in consensus with pulmonologists in order to&#xD;
      define qualitative pattern.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 20, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CT evidence of peculiar patterns in Covid-19 pneumonia</measure>
    <time_frame>March 2020-January 2021</time_frame>
    <description>Identification of CT findings in order to define peculiar pattern of Covid-19 pneumonia</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patient with Covid-pneumonia</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patient with CT scan of pulmonary infiltrates suggestive of Covid pneumonia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients were considered eligible if were with a confirmed diagnosis of Covid-19 infection,&#xD;
        as documented by RT-PCR nasal swab, or, confirmed by a subsequent BAL, aged between 18 and&#xD;
        90 years old, able to maintain both the supine and prone position on the CT scan table.&#xD;
        Patients who were pregnant, scarcely collaborative were excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
        CT analysis was conducted by two experienced thoracic radiologists and one pulmonologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Extension of each CT finding and presence of vessel enlargement has been scored.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed diagnosis of Covid-19 infection, as documented by RT-PCR nasal swab, or,&#xD;
             confirmed by a subsequent BAL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age between 18 and 90 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to maintain both the supine and prone position on the CT scan table.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who were pregnant, scarcely collaborative&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Morgagni Pierantoni Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Forlì</city>
        <state>FC</state>
        <zip>47121</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sara Piciucchi, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+390543 735863</phone>
      <email>piciucchi.sara@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 3, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Morgagni Pierantoni Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sara Piciucchi</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Interstitial</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

