<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4856">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04595695</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-2229</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04595695</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Clear Masks in Improving Patient Relationships</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Clear Masks in Improving Patient Relationships</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the effect of wearing masks that hide a surgeon's facial features versus one that&#xD;
      shows them. New patients with no prior relationship with the surgeon will be asked questions&#xD;
      regarding communication and trust with the surgeon.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Surgeons within the University of North Carolina Department of Surgery will be recruited via&#xD;
      an email list-serve. This recruitment email will describe the study and have the consent&#xD;
      attached. If the surgeons are interested in participating they will respond to the email and&#xD;
      sign the consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The project personnel will arrange to attend their clinic that has new patients scheduled. A&#xD;
      random group generator will be used to randomize the patients. The surgeons will be provided&#xD;
      either a transparent mask that demonstrates their full facial features or their typical mask&#xD;
      that covers their mouth, for each new patient visit. Following each visit, the surgeon will&#xD;
      tell the project personnel that they are complete and the project personnel will enter the&#xD;
      room, introduce the project, obtain verbal consent (enroll the patient) and if agreeable,&#xD;
      provide a brief verbal survey to the patient. The survey will entail confidential questions&#xD;
      regarding basic demographics, surgeon communication and trust, as well as an impression of&#xD;
      the masks. Survey answers will be Likert scale and open ended. Patients will also be given a&#xD;
      debriefing form at the completion of their participation. Surgeons will be asked their&#xD;
      impression of the mask at the completion of their participation. All data will be kept&#xD;
      confidential on password protected devices.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If patients do not agree to the study they will not be included. If surgeons feel&#xD;
      uncomfortable at any point they may withdraw from the study. Any patient demonstrating&#xD;
      concerning symptoms of an infection will not be included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators expect to recruit 10 surgeons, with 10 patients each, totally 100 patients&#xD;
      (50 in each arm, clear vs. covered mask). Using Mann-Whitney U test, data will be analyzed&#xD;
      for differences in responses between the two groups. Demographic data for both the patient&#xD;
      and surgeon will also be analyzed. Patient comments will be qualitatively analyzed for themes&#xD;
      by trained researchers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 3, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 14, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 12, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patients will be randomized into typical covered mask versus transparent mask worn by the surgeon.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>Patients will not know that their surgeon is participating in a research study. Visits will be completed as they typically would with the surgeon wearing a mask.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Mask Preference Quantitative</measure>
    <time_frame>During 1-minute survey assessed immediately after clinic visit completion</time_frame>
    <description>Using a Likert scale question evaluating patient preference for the type of mask (What was your impression of the surgeon's mask? &quot;Did not like the mask&quot;, &quot;somewhat did not like the mask&quot;, &quot;somewhat liked the mask&quot;, &quot;completely liked the mask&quot;, scored as 1 to 4 with higher score indicating greater preference).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Mask Preference Qualitative</measure>
    <time_frame>During 1-minute survey assessed immediately after clinic visit completion</time_frame>
    <description>Patients will be asked for their comments about the surgeon's mask and these will be immediately transcribed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Survey Scores Evaluating Surgeon Communication Skills</measure>
    <time_frame>During 1-minute survey assessed immediately after clinic visit completion</time_frame>
    <description>Using Likert scale questions evaluating patient perception of surgeon communication, taken from the Clinician and Group Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems (CG-CAHPS) healthcare survey, each scored 1-4 with higher number indicating greater communication skills, from &quot;not at all&quot;, &quot;somewhat&quot;, &quot;mostly&quot; to &quot;completely&quot;. This will include 6 questions evaluating communication skills with identical answer choices. Each participants total score will range from 6 to 24 with higher indicating better communication skills.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Survey Scores Describing Trust in the Surgeon</measure>
    <time_frame>During 1-minute survey assessed immediately after clinic visit completion</time_frame>
    <description>Using Likert scale questions evaluating patient trust of the surgeon, asked, &quot;How comfortable do you feel trusting this surgeon's decisions&quot;. Answer choices are score 1 - 4 with 4 indicating great trust, from &quot;Completing uncomfortable&quot;, &quot;somewhat uncomfortable&quot;, &quot;somewhat comfortable&quot;, &quot;completely comfortable&quot;</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Communication</condition>
  <condition>Trust</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Surgery</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Transparent Mask</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Surgeons will be provided a transparent mask for use during in-person clinic visits with a new patient. Otherwise, visits will be conducted as per usual and the patient will be surveyed immediately after the visit.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Covered Mask</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Surgeons will be instructed to wear a typical, covered mask for the in-person clinic visit with a new patient. The visit will be conducted as it typically would, and the patient will be surveyed immediately after the visit.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Transparent mask</intervention_name>
    <description>A transparent mask worn by the surgeons in customary fashion will be used.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Transparent Mask</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ClearMask</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Typical surgical covered mask</intervention_name>
    <description>A standard covered surgical mask worn by the surgeons in in customary fashion will be used.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Covered Mask</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Halyard</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria Surgeon:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Faculty within Department of Surgery at the University of North Carolina at Chapel&#xD;
             Hill&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be English speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Plans to see new in person visits in clinic&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria Surgeon:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria Patient:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Can understand and speak English without the use of an interpreter&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has capacity to make independent medical decisions&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria Surgeon:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a prior relationship with the surgeon&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has symptoms of a respiratory infection (cough, shortness of breath, fever)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ian Kratzke, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Department of Surgery</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27514</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 14, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Masks</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Surgeon-identifying information will only be available to the primary investigator and will not be shared. Patient-identifying information will not be collected beyond basic demographics. Patient quotations may be published but will not be identifiable.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

