<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1513">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04377477</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NP 4097</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04377477</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19 Pneumonitis Low Dose Lung Radiotherapy (COLOR-19)</brief_title>
  <acronym>COLOR-19</acronym>
  <official_title>Pilot Study on the Feasibility of Low Dose Radiotherapy for SARS-Cov-2 Pneumonitis (COVID-19 Low Dose Radiotherapy - COLOR 19)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Azienda Socio Sanitaria Territoriale degli Spedali Civili di Brescia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Azienda Socio Sanitaria Territoriale degli Spedali Civili di Brescia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Low-dose radiotherapy treatment delivered to both lungs in patients with immune-related&#xD;
      pneumonia following COVID-19 infection is backed up by biological and clinical bases that&#xD;
      justify its use as a possible therapeutic option in these patients. This is a preliminary&#xD;
      exploratory study (non-pharmacological interventional) to evaluate the feasibility and&#xD;
      tolerability of low-dose radiotherapy treatment of SARS-Cov-2 immune-mediated pneumonia, for&#xD;
      the subsequent implementation of a phase II study.This is a preliminary, monocentric,&#xD;
      single-arm, interventional, non-pharmacological exploratory study. All enrolled patients will&#xD;
      be treated with low-dose radiotherapy. Participants will undergo irradiation of the lungs,&#xD;
      administered in a single fraction at the average prescription dose of 0.7 Gy (further details&#xD;
      in the dedicated section).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      BACKGROUND&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since the first case of Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome - Coronavirus - 2 (SARS-CoV-2)&#xD;
      infection and its subsequent clinical manifestation (COronaVIrus Disease 19, COVID-19) in the&#xD;
      city of Wuhan (Hubei, China) in December 2019, contagion abruptly spread to different regions&#xD;
      of China and, subsequently, to all continents. To date, 1 521 252 cases have been confirmed&#xD;
      worldwide. With the first case ascertained in Lombardy at the end of February 2020, Italy&#xD;
      soon became the first European country to face the exponential growth in the number of&#xD;
      infected people (to date -May 3, 2020-210,717 total cases, currently positive 100,179).The&#xD;
      disease turned into an actual health emergency due to the rapid spread and the need of&#xD;
      hospitalization and respiratory function support in Intensive Care Unit (ICU) for a&#xD;
      significant fraction of the patients. However, the clinical presentation of COVID-19 is&#xD;
      non-specific and extremely heterogeneous. Many patients are asymptomatic or exhibit mild&#xD;
      symptoms, which include cough, fever, general malaise with myalgias, anosmia and ageusia. The&#xD;
      most common changes in blood tests include lymphopenia, thrombocytopenia and increased&#xD;
      C-reactive protein and ferritin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As emerged by clinical data, the viral infection could be divided into three different&#xD;
      phases: stage I, asymptomatic incubation period with little or undetectable viral load; stage&#xD;
      II, mild symptomatic period with considerable and detectable viral load; stage III, severe&#xD;
      symptomatic period with high viral load.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The definitive diagnosis requires a positive molecular test with Real Time PCR (RT-PCR)&#xD;
      method for SARS-CoV-2 on nasopharyngeal swab. However, this technique suffers from&#xD;
      sub-optimal sensitivity, which may require repetition on bronchoalveolar lavage. The&#xD;
      execution of chest CT is therefore essential, as it is characterized by high sensitivity and&#xD;
      can detect highly suggestive findings even in patients with negative RT-PCR.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although the majority of infections resolve spontaneously without the need for specific&#xD;
      therapy, up to 20% of patients can develop severe clinical pictures with pneumonia&#xD;
      characterized by dyspnea, tachypnea and hypoxemia that requires treatment in a hospital&#xD;
      setting. Pulmonary involvement is typically bilateral, peripheral and basal in most cases,&#xD;
      presenting on CT scan with multifocal ground glass opacities and interstitial infiltrations;&#xD;
      complete resolution usually takes several weeks. Despite active treatment, about 5-10% of&#xD;
      cases can precipitate, often suddenly, into critical conditions including respiratory&#xD;
      failure, ARDS and multi-organ dysfunction that require ICU admission and are burdened with&#xD;
      high mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Even though the understanding of the pathogenesis of COVID-19 is still incomplete, the&#xD;
      central role of the immune response in determining the development of severe clinical&#xD;
      pictures is increasingly being defined. Organ damage could therefore not be induced by the&#xD;
      direct effect of the infection, but mediated by an uncontrolled immune response resulting in&#xD;
      the development of a &quot;cytokine storm&quot;, as suggested by the high levels of inflammatory&#xD;
      cytokines (among which interleukin 6 (IL-6), tumor necrosis factor (TNF) and interferon γ&#xD;
      (IFNγ) play a major role) in patients who exhibit severe or fatal disease. To date, no drug&#xD;
      has been approved with a specific indication for the treatment of COVID-19. The current&#xD;
      treatment encompasses antiviral agents approved for other viral infections, including&#xD;
      protease inhibitors (lopinavir and ritonavir), anti-influenza drugs (oseltamivir and arbidol)&#xD;
      and compassionate use of nucleotide analogues. Several studies are evaluating the possible&#xD;
      effectiveness of the inhibition of pro-inflammatory cytokines activity in preventing or&#xD;
      treating severe COVID-19, through the use of immunomodulators (chloroquine and&#xD;
      hydroxychloroquine) or monoclonal antibodies such as tocilizumab, which targets the IL-6&#xD;
      receptor. Despite promising preliminary results, a multitude of patients need an immediate&#xD;
      treatment while the results of ongoing clinical trials are awaited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      RATIONALE&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although most COVID-19 infections resolve spontaneously without the need for specific&#xD;
      therapy, up to 20% of patients can develop severe clinical pictures with&#xD;
      interstitial-alveolar pneumonia characterized by dyspnoea, tachypnea and hypoxemia up to an&#xD;
      acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), severe respiratory failure and multi-organ&#xD;
      dysfunction requiring ICU hospitalization and burdened with high mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To date, the pathogenesis of SARS-CoV-2 pneumonia is poorly understood, but the&#xD;
      immune-inflammatory response to infection is progressively emerging as pivotal in the&#xD;
      development of severe clinical manifestations. An adequate viral load might stimulate the&#xD;
      immune cells to synthesize pro-inflammatory cytokines as interleukin 1 and 6 (IL-1, IL-6),&#xD;
      tumor necrosis factor α (TNF α) and attract macrophages, responsible for the secretion of&#xD;
      several chemokines that could trigger an unregulated &quot;cytokine storm&quot;. A few reports of&#xD;
      histological analysis of lung tissue specimens from COVID-19 patients highlighted nonspecific&#xD;
      inflammatory changes with the appearance of edema, hyaline membranes and an inflammatory&#xD;
      infiltrate dominated mainly by lymphocytes. Peripheral blood tests often reveal&#xD;
      lymphocytopenia and a high neutrophil count are found, especially in case of severe disease,&#xD;
      with a high value of neutrophil to lymphocyte ratio (NLR), and a relevant increase in&#xD;
      circulating pro-inflammatory cytokines levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While vaccines and drugs directly targeting the virus are currently being developed and are&#xD;
      not yet available, preventing the excessive and uncontrolled cytokine release and&#xD;
      inflammatory response could be the key to avoid the occurrence of severe disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Different clinical trials are exploring this path, evaluating immunomodulators and monoclonal&#xD;
      antibodies targeting mediators such as interleukin 6(IL-6).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although conventionally fractionated (1.8-2 Gy/fraction) and hypofractionated (&gt; 3 Gy&#xD;
      fraction) radiotherapy, used in the field of neoplastic diseases, provides its therapeutic&#xD;
      effect also inducing pro-inflammatory molecules, it has widely been documented in the first&#xD;
      decades of the last century that low-dose radiotherapy (LD-RT) is potentially effective and&#xD;
      relatively safe in the control of acute and/or chronic inflammatory diseases (e.g. skin&#xD;
      diseases such as psoriasis, necrotizing abscesses, tendonitis, impingement syndrome).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Many studies reported the effectiveness of radiation treatment after a single application,&#xD;
      with a prompt improvement of symptoms, usually occurring within 24 ours and often definitive&#xD;
      or long-lasting. Low dose radiotherapy exerts its effect on several cells involved in the&#xD;
      immune response: endothelial cells, polymorphonuclear leukocytes, lymphocytes and&#xD;
      macrophages. This is true also for pneumonia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endothelial cells play a crucial role in the inflammation process, both for the &quot;homing&quot;&#xD;
      process of leukocytes, and for the expression of a wide variety of cytokines and growth&#xD;
      factors. Different studies have shown that a dose of 0.5 Gy induces an over-expression of&#xD;
      tumor growth factor β (TGF-β), which has immunosuppressive activity and leads to a reduction&#xD;
      in leukocyte adhesion on endothelial cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The leukocyte &quot;rolling&quot; on the endothelium in the sites where inflammation is present&#xD;
      represents the initial step of the inflammatory cascade. The effects of LD-RT were analyzed&#xD;
      in vitro; after radiation doses of 0.3 - 0.6 Gy, there was a 25-40% reduction in adhesion&#xD;
      compared to control after 24 hours from irradiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ionizing radiation at doses below 1 Gy are also capable to polarize macrophages towards the&#xD;
      M2 anti-inflammatory phenotype. Conversely, doses greater than 1 Gy tend to induce&#xD;
      polarization towards the M1 pro-inflammatory subtype. The use of low doses of radiation seems&#xD;
      to act on macrophages also reducing their cytotoxic action, reducing the production of nitric&#xD;
      oxide (NO) through to the inhibitory action on the enzyme cytokine inducible nitric oxide&#xD;
      synthetase (iNOS) .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Neutrophils play a central role in lung damage induced by Middle East Respiratory Syndrome&#xD;
      (MERS) and SARS-CoV, and likewise in COVID-19, as they migrate into the alveoli where they&#xD;
      release proteinases and trigger the innate response, with consequent development of cell&#xD;
      damage and clinical presentations like ARDs (30,31). Low-dose radiation therapy is able to&#xD;
      initiate the apoptotic process of polymorphonuclear granulocytes (neutrophils), thus reducing&#xD;
      their cytotoxic activity (32). This treatment can therefore exert an anti-inflammatory&#xD;
      activity through several mechanisms of action, with an optimal and long lasting effect&#xD;
      demonstrated for a dose of 0.5 Gy (32).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the absence of a specific treatment, while ongoing trial are evaluating pharmacological&#xD;
      approaches and vaccines, innovative approaches could be undertaken to face the emergency and&#xD;
      allow a satisfactory management of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A single fraction radiation treatment delivering low doses to the entire bilateral lung&#xD;
      parenchyma (whole lung treatment) is a reasonable and conceptually valid option to inhibit&#xD;
      inflammation and obtain a prompt improve of the symptoms in the short term.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Unlike most of the drugs analyzed so far in the framework of COVID-19 infection, low dose&#xD;
      radiotherapy is characterized by a minor risk of side effect (negligible, considering the&#xD;
      acute phase) and could therefore represent an optimal complementary therapeutic approach due&#xD;
      to its safety and absence of interaction with pharmacological treatments. Moreover, this&#xD;
      treatment requires less than one hour including treatment planning and administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TREATMENT DELIVERY&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patient will undergo radiation treatment on both lungs in a single session. From the&#xD;
      physical-dosimetric point of view, the treatment plan will be calculated in an isocentric&#xD;
      manner. The isocenter will be positioned at a depth of 10 cm with respect to an anterior skin&#xD;
      landmark specifically defined during CT-scan acquisition. The treatment plan will be&#xD;
      elaborated using a field in field irradiation technique, with 2 beams each one composed by 3&#xD;
      beamlets: one conformed to the volume resulting by the union of the lungs with a 2 cm margin,&#xD;
      the other two will be obtained by shielding the spine and alternately one lung each. This set&#xD;
      up allows to obtain a dose distribution in which the vertebral bodies receive a dose lower&#xD;
      than 55 cGy with an average lung dose of 70 cGy and maximum lungs dose lower than than 90&#xD;
      centigray (cGy). The Pinnacle ® treatment planning system (TPS) with Collapsed Convolution&#xD;
      calculation algorithm will be used. Prescription doses were determined according to data and&#xD;
      indications currently published and optimized to minimize the dose to the vertebrae.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 10, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 10, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Lenght of hospital stay (days)</measure>
    <time_frame>Six months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the feasibility of low-dose radiotherapy treatment of SARS-Cov2 pneumonia, for the purpose of the subsequent implementation of a phase II study; lenght of hospital stay will be recorded</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Intensive Care Unit admissions</measure>
    <time_frame>Six months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the feasibility of low-dose radiotherapy treatment of SARS-Cov2 pneumonia; the number of intensive care unit admissions will be recorded</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Variation of the Brescia COVID-19 Respiratory Severity Scale after treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6 and 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of the patient's score according to the Brescia COVID-19 Respiratory Severity Scale (minimum value 0, maximum value 8; higher scores mean a worse outcome) with baseline, assessed at 3, 6 and 10 days after treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurence of CTCAE 5.0 adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>10 days and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the safety and tolerance of the low-dose radiotherapy treatment of SARS-Cov2 ( using the CTCAE 5.0 scale)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Variation of the chest X-ray radiological findings according to Brixia scoring system</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6 days</time_frame>
    <description>Variation of the radiological findings, assessed by chest X-ray (performed 3 and 6 days after treatment) and defined according to the Brixia scoring system (0-18 scale, with 18 meaning the worse outcome)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lung low dose radiotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Irradiation of the lungs, administered in a single fraction at the average prescription dose of 0.7 Gy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Single fraction whole lung radiotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will undergo irradiation of the lungs, administered in a single fraction at the average prescription dose of 0.7 Gy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lung low dose radiotherapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 50 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with confirmed diagnosis of SARS-Cov2 infection by RT-PCR on nasopharyngeal&#xD;
             swab and / or bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with Brescia Covid Respiratory Severity Scale (BCRSS) score 2-3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suggestive picture finding for interstitial pneumonia on chest X-ray and / or chest CT&#xD;
             (optional)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 3 of the following laboratory criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  PCR&gt; 5 times the maximum limit of the normal value&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ferritin&gt; 500 ng / ml&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) &gt; 2 times the maximum limit of the normal value&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  D-dimer&gt; 3 times the maximum limit of the normal value&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST)&gt; 2 times the maximum limit of the normal value&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total lymphocytes &lt;1000 / ml&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and sign informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to acquire and maintain the set-up necessary for the delivery of radiotherapy&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A negative pregnancy test will be required of patients of childbearing age before&#xD;
             starting radiotherapy treatment. Patients with reproductive potential of both sexes&#xD;
             will have to agree to use an effective contraceptive method for at least 6 months from&#xD;
             the date of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt;50 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Brescia Covid Respiratory Severity Scale (BCRSS) score greater than 3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing invasive mechanical ventilation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with active autoimmune systemic diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with active infections that are not responsive to current treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a positive pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impossibility to maintain the set-up necessary for radiotherapy treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other concomitant treatments for COVID-19 do not represent an exclusion criterion,&#xD;
             however they must be reported (specifying the starting date and dosage)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Stefano M Magrini, Prof</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Brescia University - ASST Spedali Civili Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Stefano M Magrini, Prof</last_name>
    <phone>++393492970156</phone>
    <email>stefano.magrini@unibs.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Davide Tomasini, MD</last_name>
    <phone>++393331404184</phone>
    <email>tomad88@libero.it</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Radiation Oncology Department, ASST SpedaliCivili, Brescia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brescia</city>
        <zip>25123</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Stefano M Magrini, Prof</last_name>
      <phone>039 0303995</phone>
      <phone_ext>281</phone_ext>
      <email>stefano.magrini@unibs.it</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Davide Tomasini, MD</last_name>
      <phone>039 0303995</phone>
      <phone_ext>281</phone_ext>
      <email>davide.tomasini@unibs.it</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 5, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 6, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 21, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 21, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 22, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Azienda Socio Sanitaria Territoriale degli Spedali Civili di Brescia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Stefano Maria Magrini</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prof</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>RADIOTHERAPY</keyword>
  <keyword>PNEUMONITIS</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All Individual Participant Data that underlie results in the publication</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data will be available starting six months from the publication and for five years.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Written request to principal investigator , indicating the details of the data requested, the reasons of the inquiry and the purpose of the data use; data will be released after Local Ethics Committee approval. Data will be released only for no-profit use, in particular for research purposes.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

