<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4852">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03115359</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2017-0353</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>A532007</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>SMPH/FAMILY MED/FAMILY MED</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>Protocol_V18-01, 10.09.2020</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03115359</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Strategies to Assist With Management of Pain</brief_title>
  <acronym>STAMP</acronym>
  <official_title>A Comparative Effectiveness Randomized Controlled Trial of Mindfulness Meditation Versus Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Opioid-Treated Chronic Low Back Pain</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Wisconsin, Madison</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Patient-Centered Outcomes Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Wisconsin, Madison</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chronic low back pain (CLBP) has no known effective treatment. While often treated with&#xD;
      long-term opioid therapy, opioids do not work well for many patients and can cause serious&#xD;
      side effects, including addiction, poorer mental health, and overdose death. Even when paired&#xD;
      with a standard-of-care cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT), results are limited. Patients,&#xD;
      families and clinicians are very interested in using alternative treatments for CLBP,&#xD;
      especially complementary and integrative treatments such as mindfulness meditation (MM). MM&#xD;
      helps train the mind to bring non-judgmental and accepting attention to present-moment&#xD;
      experiences such as pain. MM offers an active and safe self-care approach to chronic pain&#xD;
      that contrasts with the passive and potentially harmful nature of opioid treatment, and may&#xD;
      prove more effective than CBT in helping improve health and well-being, and reduce reliance&#xD;
      on opioids in adults with opioid-treated CLBP. Although this hypothesis is supported by early&#xD;
      research, including a pilot study by the Principal Investigator, evidence on MM's&#xD;
      effectiveness in this population is inconclusive, presenting a critical knowledge gap.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With input from patients, family members, and clinicians, the Investigators have designed a&#xD;
      study to address this gap and propose a clinical trial that will compare the effectiveness of&#xD;
      MM to standard-of-care CBT in opioid-treated CLBP. Based on the existing research, it is&#xD;
      hypothesized that MM training will lead to a larger reduction in pain intensity, increase in&#xD;
      physical function, improvement in quality of life, and decrease in daily opioid dose, as&#xD;
      compared to CBT training, with benefits of MM especially notable in adults with worse mood,&#xD;
      anxiety or unhealthy opioid-use behaviors who often experience more severe symptoms of CLBP&#xD;
      and less improvement in response to existing therapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To test these hypotheses, 766 adults with opioid-treated CLBP will be randomly assigned into&#xD;
      one of two 8-week treatment groups: MM (383 participants) that will receive the MM training&#xD;
      or CBT (383 participants) that will receive the CBT training. Due to the COVID-19&#xD;
      pandemic-related restrictions, the study protocol was modified in October 2020 so that the&#xD;
      study can be completed virtually.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The effectiveness of MM versus CBT will be assessed over a 12-month period with&#xD;
      patient-reported measures, recommended by experts and endorsed by our stakeholder partners,&#xD;
      including patients with opioid-treated CLBP, their families and clinicians.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Chronic low back pain (CLBP) is the most common disabling chronic noncancer pain condition&#xD;
      treated with opioids. Many opioid-treated patients experience inadequate pain relief and&#xD;
      disability as well as dose-dependent adverse effects of opioids, such as worse mental health,&#xD;
      opioid misuse, overdose and death. They frequently have co-occurring depression, anxiety, and&#xD;
      opioid use disorders, which worsen outcomes. Poor outcomes and opioid-related harms&#xD;
      underscore the need for safe and effective strategies for chronic pain care and opioid dose&#xD;
      reduction, especially in high-impact, opioid-treated pain, as noted by the Institute of&#xD;
      Medicine, the National Institutes of Health, and the Patient-Centered Outcomes Research&#xD;
      Institute.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators pilot randomized controlled trial (RCT) of mindfulness meditation (MM), a&#xD;
      popular mind-body modality, demonstrated its potential to safely improve the health of&#xD;
      patients and reduce opioid dosage in opioid-treated CLBP. To expand the evidence for MM for&#xD;
      use in opioid-treated chronic pain, the investigators propose a 5-year multi-site,&#xD;
      mixed-methods pragmatic RCT comparing the effectiveness of MM to standard-of-care cognitive&#xD;
      behavioral therapy (CBT) for improving outcomes in opioid-treated CLBP. The study team will&#xD;
      follow 766 participants over 12 months and compare outcomes that matter to patients and their&#xD;
      families in 383 adults randomized to the MM group to 383 adults randomized to the CBT group,&#xD;
      controlling for relevant factors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The specific aims of this study are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To compare the effectiveness of MM to CBT for reducing pain and increasing function.&#xD;
           Current study is based on hypothesis that adults with opioid-treated CLBP in the MM&#xD;
           group will report a greater reduction in pain severity and a greater increase in&#xD;
           function at 6 and 12 months compared to those in the CBT group.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To compare the effectiveness of MM to CBT for improving quality of life (QoL) and&#xD;
           reducing daily opioid dose. Study team hypothesize that adults with opioid-treated CLBP&#xD;
           in the MM group will report a greater improvement in QoL and a greater decrease in daily&#xD;
           opioid dose at 6 and 12 months compared to those in the CBT group.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To examine if participant baseline characteristics impact treatment response to MM or&#xD;
           CBT. Study team hypothesize that among those with increased baseline symptom severity of&#xD;
           anxiety, depression and opioid misuse behaviors, MM will be more beneficial than CBT for&#xD;
           improving Aim 1 and Aim 2 outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Both MM and CBT interventions are patterned after established programs, adapted to meet the&#xD;
      needs of patients with opioid-treated CLBP, with input from content experts and patient&#xD;
      partners. The manualized interventions are delivered by trained therapists over 8 weeks in&#xD;
      weekly two-hour group sessions in addition to care the participants are already receiving&#xD;
      from their regular clinicians; during the COVID-19 pandemic, the interventions are delivered&#xD;
      virtually. Participants are also be asked to practice MM or CBT strategies at home during the&#xD;
      entire study (at least 30 minutes/day, 6 days/week).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility criteria will focus on English-speaking adults ≥21 years old, with&#xD;
      moderate-to-severe CLBP treated with ≥15 mg/day of morphine-equivalent opioid dose for ≥3&#xD;
      months. The study will implement a limited set of exclusionary criteria to ensure a diverse&#xD;
      sample, from which findings can be generalized.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome measures were selected and prioritized based on guidelines and stakeholder input.&#xD;
      They are collected at baseline, at 3, 6, 9 and 12 months. Only baseline and 12 months&#xD;
      post-entry data collection is conducted in person; the 3, 6, and 9-month data collection&#xD;
      occurs online or by phone to minimize burden. Due the COVID-19 pandemic, the study protocol&#xD;
      was modified to allow for the completion of all assessments and data collection virtually.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pain severity and function, as assessed by standard, validated survey measures, will serve as&#xD;
      primary (Aim 1), and quality of life and opioid dose (morphine-equivalent mg/day) as&#xD;
      secondary (Aim 2) outcomes. Severity of negative affect (depression, anxiety) and opioid&#xD;
      misuse behaviors, also measured by validated surveys, are the main hypothesized predictors of&#xD;
      treatment success (Aim 3). The repeated measures intention-to-treat outcome analysis will&#xD;
      compare the change in primary and secondary outcomes over the 12 month period and across the&#xD;
      two groups. To determine prognostic factors of treatment effect, a linear mixed model&#xD;
      analysis will be performed for Aim 1 and Aim 2 outcomes, adjusting for potential confounders,&#xD;
      study site and a random intercept for subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A team of experienced investigators and engaged stakeholders will carry out this multi-health&#xD;
      system, multi-site study led by the faculty from the University of Wisconsin (Madison, WI),&#xD;
      Harvard Medical School (Boston, MA) and the University of Utah (Salt Lake City, UT).&#xD;
      Stakeholders helped develop this proposal and will be integrally involved as partners in all&#xD;
      aspects of the study, from finalizing the methods, trouble-shooting implementation of the&#xD;
      research plan, and dissemination of results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Positive findings of this study could help improve health outcomes and reduce daily opioid&#xD;
      dose in patients with opioid-treated CLBP, and inform clinical decisions of patients and&#xD;
      clinicians about the choice between MM and CBT for opioid-treated CLBP.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 30, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Comparative effectiveness randomized controlled trial of two behavioral interventions</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Although participants, therapists and outcome assessors cannot be blinded to the study intervention, investigators and analysts will be blinded to the group status until the first stages of analysis and reporting are completed.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain Intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>4 pain severity items from the Brief Pain Inventory</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical Function</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>10-item Oswestry Disability Index</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>12-item Short Form-12</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Daily Opioid Dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Timeline Followback Method (morphine-equivalent dose [mg/day] over the prior 14 days)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Depression Symptom Severity</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>14-item Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety Symptom Severity</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>14-item Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid Use Behaviors</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>17-item Current Opioid Misuse Measure</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid Medication Compliance</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>8-item Opioid Compliance Checklist</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">766</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Low Back Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mindfulness Meditation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Mindfulness Meditation intervention, adjunctive to usual care for opioid-treated chronic low back pain.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cognitive Behavioral Therapy intervention, adjunctive to usual care for opioid-treated chronic low back pain.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mindfulness Meditation</intervention_name>
    <description>The Mindfulness Meditation intervention will teach participants the mindfulness meditation-based strategies, tailored to the needs of those with opioid-treated chronic lower back pain. It consists of eight weekly 2-hour group sessions guided by trained therapists. In addition to session attendance, participants are asked to practice at home at least 6 days/week, 30 minutes/day during the study.&#xD;
In addition to the intervention, the participants will receive usual care for opioid-treated CLBP through their regular clinicians, per their recommendations.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mindfulness Meditation</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Meditation</other_name>
    <other_name>Mindfulness</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>The Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (CBT) intervention will teach participants the CBT-based strategies, tailored to the needs of those with opioid-treated chronic lower back pain. It consists of eight weekly 2-hour group sessions guided by trained therapists. In addition to session attendance, participants are asked to practice at home at least 6 days/week, 30 minutes/day during the study.&#xD;
In addition to the intervention, the participants will receive usual care for opioid-treated CLBP through their regular clinicians, per their recommendations.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CBT</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria (per self-report): English-speaking; age ≥ 21 years old; chronic low&#xD;
        back pain (defined as a pain in lumbosacral region or sciatica for ≥3 months), with an&#xD;
        average daily back pain score ≥3 on a 0-10 numerical rating scale (question from the Brief&#xD;
        Pain Inventory), treated with ≥30 mg/day of morphine-equivalent dose for ≥3 months; at&#xD;
        least moderate CLBP-related disability (≥21 score on the Oswestry Disability Index);&#xD;
        capable of giving informed consent; willing to complete the study activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria (per self-report): prior formal Mindfulness Meditation or Cognitive&#xD;
        Behavioral Therapy training; current pregnancy; diagnosis of borderline personality,&#xD;
        delusional, or bipolar (mania) disorder; inability to safely or reliably participate in the&#xD;
        study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aleksandra E Zgierska, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Penn State University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bruce P Barrett, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Wisconsin, Madison</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Cindy A Burzinski, MS</last_name>
    <phone>608-262-6549</phone>
    <email>cindy.burzinski@fammed.wisc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brigham and Women's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lauren Papianou, BS</last_name>
      <phone>617-732-9181</phone>
      <email>lpapianou@bwh.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Robert Edwards, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pennsylvania State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hershey</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>16802</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Utah</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salt Lake City</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84112</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Amy Watson, BS</last_name>
      <phone>801-581-6276</phone>
      <email>amy.watson@utah.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Eric Garland, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Wisconsin-Madison</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madison</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>53715</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Cindy A Burzinski, MS</last_name>
      <phone>608-262-6549</phone>
      <email>cindy.burzinski@fammed.wisc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bruce P Barrett, MD PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.STAMPstudy.org</url>
    <description>Strategies To Assist with Management of Pain (STAMP) Study Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 11, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 11, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 14, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 14, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Chronic Low Back Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Opioid Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Mindfulness Meditation</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Opioid-treated Chronic Low Back Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>CLBP</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data dictionaries, programming codes, qualitative codebooks, and other study materials will be provided to the funding agency, Patient-Centered Research Outcomes Institute (PCORI) after the study completion in order to promote replication of the research process. A final, clean dataset will be available for data sharing after the project and analysis completion. PCORI may share these materials and data upon request, after consultation with the PI.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

