<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4680">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04666558</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00103715</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04666558</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Heal-Me Personalized Online Nutrition and Exercise Routines</brief_title>
  <acronym>PiONEeR</acronym>
  <official_title>Heal-Me PiONEeR (Personalized Online Nutrition and Exercise Routines) - Reconnecting Vulnerable Outpatients With Multidisciplinary Care - a Randomized Controlled Trial Assessing 3 Levels of Online Programming in the Time of COVID</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alberta</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Alberta Innovates Health Solutions</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alberta</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to compare 12-weeks of virtual multidisciplinary programming&#xD;
      provided at three levels of support intensity to determine impacts on clinical outcomes,&#xD;
      acceptability, and cost amongst outpatients with cancer, liver disease, or lung disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be randomized to one of three groups: (i) standard care, (ii) a&#xD;
      personnel-light app-based intervention, (iii) a personnel-intensive app-based intervention.&#xD;
      Participants randomized to standard care will receive exercise and nutrition resources as&#xD;
      well as a Garmin watch. Participants in the experimental groups will receive standard care,&#xD;
      plus a 12-week multidisciplinary app-based personalized program involving 12 weeks of&#xD;
      exercise programming and 10-weeks of nutrition programming. Participants in study group 3&#xD;
      will receive additional one-on-one care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Research Ethics Board at the University of Alberta has approved this study. The protocol&#xD;
      will measure patient-related outcome measures including physical function, quality of life,&#xD;
      social isolation, and anxiety, as well as measures of acceptability and cost. 216&#xD;
      participants will take part in this study (n=72 per arm).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analyses: fitness testing and patient-reported outcomes will be administered before and after&#xD;
      the intervention. Fitness and patient-reported outcomes will be compared using linear mixed&#xD;
      models with random effects. App acceptability will be compared between groups using&#xD;
      Chi-Square.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      INTRODUCTION:&#xD;
&#xD;
      COVID-19 related social distancing have a profound impact on vulnerable people living with&#xD;
      chronic conditions, including cancer and organ failure. Pre-pandemic, many of these patients&#xD;
      relied on and benefited from multidisciplinary supports and structured programming to&#xD;
      maintain well-being and function. Many of these in-person supports are not currently&#xD;
      available, which has disconnected these patients from the care they need to stay well.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Virtual modalities are a promising solution that allow multidisciplinary programs (i.e.&#xD;
      exercise and nutrition) to continue to deliver support for these patients when social&#xD;
      distancing doesn't allow these programs to run in-person. However, it's currently unclear&#xD;
      whether virtual programming is acceptable in these populations, and what level of support is&#xD;
      best in terms of benefits and costs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to compare 12-weeks of virtual multidisciplinary programming&#xD;
      provided at three levels of support intensity to determine impacts on clinical outcomes,&#xD;
      acceptability, and cost amongst outpatients with cancer, liver disease, or lung disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. As compared to control, assess the impact of a 12-week virtual exercise and nutrition&#xD;
           program (delivered at 2 levels of support) on: physical function and mental health&#xD;
           outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. As compared to the modeled costs of in-person programming, assess the cost of a 12-week&#xD;
           virtual exercise and nutrition program (delivered at 2 levels of support).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Assess the acceptability of the virtual exercise and nutrition programming to patients&#xD;
           and members of the study team who deliver the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a mixed-methods, 12-week randomized controlled trial with randomization to one of&#xD;
      three study groups with increasing virtual multidisciplinary support for outpatients.&#xD;
      Participants will include people living with one of the following three chronic conditions:&#xD;
      cancer, lung disease, or lung or liver disease (post-transplantation).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 1 - The standard of care response to COVID. Educational materials will be provided to&#xD;
      patients via email. As needed, the package will include a combination of personalized&#xD;
      exercises, disease-tailored tips for healthy eating and COVID precautions. Ad hoc telephone&#xD;
      or virtual contact with patients will be at the providers' discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 2 - An app-based, &quot;personnel-light&quot; approach to virtual care with a focus on support&#xD;
      through group-based interactions with the Trainers and other participants during live group&#xD;
      exercise and nutrition classes (~3/week). The patient's personalized 12-week home based&#xD;
      exercise program will be enabled in the app after a baseline exercise specialist appointment&#xD;
      and the 10-week nutrition program will be enabled at week 3 after a dietitian assessment in&#xD;
      week 2. The home programs will auto-progress.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 3 - An app-based, &quot;personnel-intensive&quot; approach. In addition to Group 2 features,&#xD;
      patient interaction with Trainers will be via live group classes AND 1-to-1 sessions: seven&#xD;
      1-to-1 consultations with an exercise specialist and three 1-to-1 consultations with a&#xD;
      dietitian to review progress and goals and make any necessary modifications to programming.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTCOMES &amp; ANALYSES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All analyses adhere to the intention-to-treat-principle (ITT). Fitness assessments and&#xD;
      patient-reported outcomes will be collected at baseline and 12-weeks. Primary and secondary&#xD;
      outcomes from these data will be analyzed using linear mixed models with random effects.&#xD;
      Adherence and app acceptability (survey) will be compared between groups using the&#xD;
      chi-square. Costs of each level of support will be compared with the cost of in-person&#xD;
      programming using a publicly funded provincial payer perspective and will be presented in the&#xD;
      Net Benefit framework.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Interviews will be conducted with participants, caregivers, and program instructors to&#xD;
      determine program acceptability and barriers and facilitators. Inductive content analysis&#xD;
      will be used to analyze qualitative data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 30, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 17, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 17, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Lower Extremity Functional Scale (LEFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in LEFS score between groups (score range: 0-80, higher scores indicate higher function)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Upper Extremity Functional Index (UEFI)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in UEFI score between groups (score range: 0-80, higher scores indicate higher function)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>6-Minute Walk Test (6MWT) Distance</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in 6MWT distance between groups. Not possible if testing is virtual.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Timed Sit-to-Stand (60 &amp; 30 seconds)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in # of repetitions completed over the Timed Sit-to-Stand between groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Timed One-Legged Stance</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in Timed One-Legged Stance between groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>2-Minute Step Test (2MST)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in the # of steps completed in the 2MST between groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sit-and-Reach</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in the sit-and-reach distance between groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Step Count &amp; Activity Minutes</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in step count and activity minutes (Garmin watch) between groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Well-Being (The World Health Organization-5 [WHO-5] Well-Being Index)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in The World Health Organization-5 (WHO-5) Well-Being Index between groups (score range: 0-25, higher scores indicate higher well-being)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resilience (10-Item Connor Davidson Resilience Scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in resilience, as measures by the 10-Item Connor Davidson Resilience Scale, between groups (score range: 0-40, higher scores indicate higher resilience)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>General health-related quality of life (36-Item Short Form Survey [SF-36])</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in health-related quality of life, as measured by the SF-36, between groups (score range: 0-100, higher scores indicate a more favorable health state)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>General health-related quality of life (5-Level EQ-5D [EQ-5D-5L])</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in health-related quality of life, as measured by the EQ-5D-5L, between groups (visual analogue score range: 0-100, higher scores indicate a more favorable health state)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Physical activity</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in proportion of &quot;yes&quot; answers to the single-item physical activity questionnaire from pre- to post-intervention between groups</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Sedentary Time (International Sedentary Assessment Tool - ISAT)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in sedentary time, as self-reported on the ISAT between groups</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Protein Intake</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in protein intake (grams) between groups, based on 3-day food record(s)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Calorie Intake</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in calorie intake (kilocalories) between groups, based on 3-day food record(s)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Micronutrient Intake</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in micronutrient intake (milligrams) between groups, based on 3-day food record(s)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Beliefs and outcome expectations about exercise</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in the 6-item COM-B scale between groups (score range: 0-120, higher scores indicate higher capability, opportunity, motivation)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Program acceptability (Unified Theory of Acceptance and Use of Technology - UTAUT)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the pre- vs post-intervention change in the UTAUT scale between groups (score range: 0-92, higher scores indicate higher app acceptance and use)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">216</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Lung Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Liver Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The standard of care response to COVID. Educational materials will be provided to patients via email. The package will include a combination of personalized exercises, and nutrition information for healthy eating. Participants will also receive a Garmin watch to track their activity over the intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>App-Based, Personnel-Light Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>An app-based, &quot;personnel-light&quot; approach to virtual care with a focus on support through group-based interactions with the Trainers, Dietitians and other participants. The patient's personalized 12-week home based exercise program will be enabled in the app after a baseline exercise specialist appointment. The 10-week nutrition program will be enabled at week 3 after a virtual dietitian assessment in week 2 (~1 hour). The home programs will auto-progress. Participants will also receive a Garmin watch to track their activity over the intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>App-Based, Personnel-Intensive Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>An app-based, &quot;personnel-intensive&quot; approach to virtual care with support through a combination of group-based interactions with Trainers, Dietitians and other participants, as well as one-on-one support with Exercise Trainers and Dietitians. In addition to Group 2 features, patient interaction with Trainers will be via live group classes AND 1-to-1 sessions: up to seven 1-to-1 consultations with an exercise specialist and three 1-to-1 consultations with a dietitian to review progress and goals and make any necessary modifications to programming. Participants will also receive a Garmin watch to track their activity over the intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exercise &amp; Nutrition</intervention_name>
    <description>App-based live group exercise classes, personalized follow-up asynchronous workouts, live group nutrition classes, and protein tracking.</description>
    <arm_group_label>App-Based, Personnel-Light Care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exercise &amp; Nutrition</intervention_name>
    <description>App-based live group exercise classes, personalized follow-up asynchronous workouts, live group nutrition classes, and protein tracking. Additional one-one-one exercise and nutrition support is provided too.</description>
    <arm_group_label>App-Based, Personnel-Intensive Care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥ 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In one of the following 3 disease groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Cancer survivor who has completed treatment or is receiving maintenance therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Patient who is currently post-transplantation from liver or lung transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Patient with chronic lung disease who may or may not be listed for organ&#xD;
                  transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous enrolment in exercise rehabilitation program (i.e. rehabilitation &quot;graduate&quot;)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to an Internet connected device with video and audio capabilities&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Compassionate care&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unsafe to participate in a virtual exercise program&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to provide informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
    <phone>780-718-5188</phone>
    <email>hmpioneer@ualberta.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Puneeta Tandon, MD</last_name>
    <phone>780-492-9844</phone>
    <email>ptandon@ualberta.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alberta</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edmonton</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T6G 2G4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Puneeta Tandon, MD</last_name>
      <phone>780-492-9844</phone>
      <email>ptandon@ualberta.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Puneeta Tandon, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Margaret McNeely, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 30, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 7, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 7, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 7, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>Nutrition</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Virtual</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

