<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1597">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04641481</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BBIL/BBV152-C/2020</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>BBIL/BBV152-C/2020</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04641481</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Efficacy and Safety Clinical Trial of an Investigational COVID-19 Vaccine (BBV152) in Adult Volunteers</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Event-Driven, Phase 3, Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled, Multicenter Study to Evaluate Efficacy, Safety, Immunogenicity, Lot-to-Lot Consistency of BBV152, a Whole-Virion Inactivated SARS-CoV-2 Vaccine in Adults≥18 Yrs of Age</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bharat Biotech International Limited</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Indian Council of Medical Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Iqvia Pty Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bharat Biotech International Limited</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The BBV152 vaccine is being developed to prevent COVID-19, the disease resulting from Severe&#xD;
      Acute Respiratory Syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) infection. The study is designed to&#xD;
      primarily evaluate the efficacy, safety, and immunogenicity of BBV152 to prevent COVID-19 for&#xD;
      up to 1 year after the second dose of BBV152.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase 3 Event-Driven, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicentre&#xD;
      study to Evaluate the Efficacy, Safety, and Immunogenicity of BBV152, a Whole-Virion&#xD;
      Inactivated SARS-CoV-2 Vaccine in Volunteers aged 18 years and above.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of 25,800 subjects will be enrolled and randomized in a 1:1 ratio to receive the&#xD;
      BBV152 vaccine and control. All participants will be assessed for efficacy and safety&#xD;
      endpoints and provide a Nasopharyngeal(NP) swab and blood sample before the first dose of IP.&#xD;
      The NP swab and blood collected will be subject to RT-PCR and Anti-SARS-CoV-2 IgG antibodies.&#xD;
      The results of this will not affect the enrollment of the participant. Participants who are&#xD;
      found to be positive for either RT-PCR Or Anti-SARS-CoV-2 IgG antibodies will be excluded&#xD;
      from the primary efficacy analysis. A safety follow-up will be done for all.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, sites will be segregated based on the study objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Category 1 (Symptomatic): In addition to administering the IP, a series of post-dose&#xD;
      telephonic follow-up visits will be scheduled to detect suspect symptomatic COVID-19&#xD;
      infections. If a suspect is identified, a nasopharyngeal sample will be collected from the&#xD;
      participant for detecting the presence of COVID-19 infection. Telephonic follow-up will occur&#xD;
      at 15 Day intervals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Category 2 (Symptomatic/Asymptomatic): In addition to administering the IP, a series of&#xD;
      post-dose Nasopharyngeal samples for detecting an incidence of asymptomatic COVID-19&#xD;
      infection at 1-Month intervals will be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Category 3 (Symptomatic/Asymptomatic+Immunogenicity): In addition to administering the IP and&#xD;
      collecting NP samples, a series of blood samples will be collected for analyzing serum for&#xD;
      immunological assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Phase 3 study will follow randomized study participants for efficacy until virologically&#xD;
      confirmed (RT-PCR positive) symptomatic COVID-19 participants will be eligible for the&#xD;
      primary efficacy analysis. After reaching the target number (n=130) of symptomatic COVID-19&#xD;
      cases, the study will continue to assess safety until the completion of the study duration.&#xD;
      It is planned to continue the Phase 3 trial until 130 study participants in the per-protocol&#xD;
      population develop PCR-confirmed symptomatic COVID-19 disease during follow-up beginning 14&#xD;
      days after the second dose of vaccine or placebo. We estimate that approximately 25,800&#xD;
      participants should be randomized to accrue these 130 events. The Lot-to-Lot consistency&#xD;
      (Immunogenicity) study will be nested within the Phase 3 (Efficacy) study (in three selected&#xD;
      sites). The Immunogenicity study will assess the immune response of a 2-dose regimen of&#xD;
      BBV152B vaccine through geometric mean titers (GMTs) by neutralizing antibody, S-protein, and&#xD;
      RBD specific anti-IgG binding titer in a subset of 600 (450 vaccine: 150 placebo)&#xD;
      participants, across three consecutive manufacturing Lots. Data generated through Day 56&#xD;
      (Month 2) will be unblinded only to the biostatistician for evaluation of immune responses in&#xD;
      the Immunogenicity subset.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Formal interim analyses are planned when approximately 1/3 and 2/3 of the target number of&#xD;
      participants with confirmed symptomatic COVID-19 have been accrued, to determine whether the&#xD;
      sample size and/or length of follow-up should be increased. This interim report containing&#xD;
      safety and immunogenicity data will be submitted to CDSCO.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 25, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>All vaccine and placebo formulations are at a volume of 0.5mL per dose filled into a single-use glass vial. The appearance, color, and viscosity are identical across all vaccine and control formulations.&#xD;
Participants, investigators, study coordinators, study-related personnel, and the sponsor will be blinded to the treatment group allocation (excluding an unblinded CRO, who is tasked with the dispatch and labeling of vaccine vials and the generation of the master randomization code). Participants will be assigned a computer-generated randomization code that maintains blinding. The blinded study nurse is responsible for vaccine preparation and administration. Each vial contains a unique code that ensured appropriate blinding.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>First occurrence of Virologically confirmed (RT-PCR positive) symptomatic cases of COVID-19.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 42 to Month 12</time_frame>
    <description>(RT-PCR positive) symptomatic cases of COVID-19.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>First occurence of Virologically confirmed (RT-PCR positive) symptomatic cases of COVID-19 based on the case definition for the secondary efficacy symptomatic endpoint.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 42 to Month 12</time_frame>
    <description>(RT-PCR positive) symptomatic cases of COVID-19.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Virologically confirmed (RT-PCR positive) severe cases of COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 42 to Month 12</time_frame>
    <description>(RT-PCR positive) severe symptomatic cases of COVID-19.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Virologically confirmed COVID-19 cases of any severity occurring among participants 18 through 59 years of age and ≥60 years of age.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 42 to Month 12</time_frame>
    <description>(RT-PCR positive) symptomatic cases of COVID-19</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Virologically confirmed COVID-19 asymptomatic and symptomatic cases occurring from two weeks after the second vaccination.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 42 to Month 12</time_frame>
    <description>(RT-PCR positive) asymptomatic/symptomatic cases of COVID-19.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reactogenicity and Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 42 to Month 12</time_frame>
    <description>Solicited, Unsolicited, Serious Adverse Events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The occurrence of enhanced respiratory disease episodes.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 42 to Month 12</time_frame>
    <description>Reported by participant/documented in hospital records throughout the trial.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenicity: Lot-to-Lot consistency of three consecutive GMP Lots</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0 to Day 42</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed based Wild-type SARS-CoV-2 Specific Neutralizing Antibody (nAb)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Titer (GMT) of SARS-CoV-2 Specific Neutralizing Antibody (nAb)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0 to Month 12</time_frame>
    <description>Specific Neutralizing Antibody (nAb)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">25800</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>SARS-CoV Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Study vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>BBV152B (6µg-Algel-IMDG)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Phosphate buffered saline with Alum (without antigen)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BBV152</intervention_name>
    <description>BBV152 (6µg-Algel - Imidazoquinoline)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Study vaccine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo (PBS+Alum, without antigen)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to provide written informed consent and availability to fulfill the study&#xD;
             requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants of either gender of aged 18 years and above.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with good general health as determined by the discretion of the&#xD;
             investigator, or participants with stable medical conditions. A stable medical&#xD;
             condition is defined as a disease not requiring significant change in therapy or&#xD;
             hospitalization or worsening disease during the 3 months before enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For a female participant of child-bearing potential, planning to avoid becoming&#xD;
             pregnant (use of an effective method of contraception or abstinence) from the time of&#xD;
             study enrolment until at least eight weeks after the last vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male subjects of reproductive potential: Use of condoms to ensure effective&#xD;
             contraception with the female partner and to refrain from sperm donation from first&#xD;
             vaccination until at least 3 months after the last vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees not to participate in another clinical trial at any time during the study&#xD;
             period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees not to take any COVID-19 licensed vaccination for the entire duration of the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees to remain in the study area for the entire duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to allow storage and future use of biological samples for future research&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of any other COVID-19 investigational or licensed vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of SARS-CoV-2 infection, as declared by the subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For women, positive urine pregnancy test before the first dose of vaccination, or any&#xD;
             time during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Temperature &gt;38.0°C (100.4°F) or symptoms of an acute self-limited illness such as an&#xD;
             upper respiratory infection or gastroenteritis within three days prior to each dose of&#xD;
             vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Resident of COVID-19 infection in the same household.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known case of HIV, hepatitis B, or hepatitis C infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of any licensed/experimental vaccine within four weeks before enrolment in&#xD;
             this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of immunoglobulin or other blood products within the three months before&#xD;
             vaccination in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immunosuppression as a result of an underlying illness or treatment with&#xD;
             immunosuppressive or cytotoxic drugs, or use of anticancer chemotherapy or radiation&#xD;
             therapy within the preceding 36 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immunoglobulins, anti-cytokine antibodies, and blood products within 6 months prior to&#xD;
             study vaccination, during, and 21 days following the last dose of vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, lactation, or willingness/intention to become pregnant during the first 6&#xD;
             months after enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe and/or uncontrolled cardiovascular disease, respiratory disease,&#xD;
             gastrointestinal disease, liver disease, renal disease, an endocrine disorder, and&#xD;
             neurological illness (mild/moderate well-controlled comorbidities are allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Re-Vaccination Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of virologically (RT-PCR) confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anaphylactic reaction following administration of the investigational vaccine.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Chadramani Singh</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>All India Institute of Medical Sciences Patna</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Sanjay Kumar Rai</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>All India Institute of Medical Sciences Delhi</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Azhar Ali Khan</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Baba Raghav Das Medical Gorakhpur</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>DrAnil Kumar Pandey</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>ESIC Medical College and Hospital Faridabad</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Simmi Dube</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Gandhi Medical College, Bhopal</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Anjan Jyoti Talukdar</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Gauhati Medical College &amp; Hospital Assam</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Priti Meshram</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Grant Government Medical College and Sir J.J. Group of Hospitals Mumbai</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Laxmi S Kumari</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Guntur Medical College ,Guntur</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Shiva Narang</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Guru Teg Bahadur Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr E Venkat Rao</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Institute of Medical Sciences and SUM Hospital Odisha</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr P Venugopal</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>King George Hospital Visakhapatnam</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr. N.T. Awad</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Lokamanya tilak Municipal Medical College and General hospital Mumbai</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Pajanivel Ranganadin</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Mahatma Gandhi Medical College&amp; Research Institute Pondicherry</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Prabhakar Reddy</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Nizam's Institute of Medical Sciences Hyderabad</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Raghavendra Gumashta</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Peoples university Bhopal</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Tapan Kumar Saikia</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Prince Aly Khan Hospital Mumbai</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Savita Verma</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Pt BO Sharma,PGIMS/UHS. Rohtak, Haryana</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Manish Multani</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rahate Surgical Hospital ,Nagpur</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Sagar Vivek Redkar</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Redkar Hospital and Research Centre Goa</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Meghana Murthy</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Vagus Super speciality hospital,Bangalore</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Akshata</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Vydehi Institute of Medical Sciences and Research Centre,Bangalore</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr T S Selvavinayagam</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Directorate of Public Health and Preventive Medicine,Chennai</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Suman Kanungo</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>ICMR-National Institute of Cholera and Enteric Diseases,West Bengal</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Mohammad Shameem</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Aligarh Muslim University,Uttar Pradesh</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr Parul Bhatt</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Gmers Medical College and Civil Hospital,Ahmedabad</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Dr.V.Krishna Mohan</last_name>
    <phone>914023480567</phone>
    <email>kmohan@bharatbiotech.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pt BD SHARMA,PGIMS/UHS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rohtak</city>
        <state>Haryana</state>
        <zip>124001</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dr Savita Verma, MD</last_name>
      <phone>9812283746</phone>
      <email>verma.savi@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 20, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 23, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 25, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

