<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2985">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04699058</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>B3002020000144</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04699058</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19 Sero-prevalence Health Care Workers Kinshasa</brief_title>
  <acronym>PRESTACOV</acronym>
  <official_title>Sero-prevalence and Sero-conversion Study of Health Care Workers and Their Households, Democratic Republic of the Congo</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Institute of Tropical Medicine, Belgium</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut National de Recherche Biomédicale. Kinshasa, République Démocratique du Congo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institute of Tropical Medicine, Belgium</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a cohort study, in which the investigators will follow-up 650 health care workers&#xD;
      (HCW) and a selection of their households (of COVID positive and COVID negative HCW) at&#xD;
      baseline and in three follow-up surveys, with 4 to 6 weeks of time interval. The&#xD;
      investigators will select HCW from different wards and different health care structures in 5&#xD;
      communes of Kinshasa. Additionally, in the first survey among HCW, the investigators will&#xD;
      test with different diagnostic platform to evaluate the performance of serological tests in&#xD;
      the African setting and the effect of malaria infection on the performance of tests.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Rationale:&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is no information on how intense transmission of COVID-19 happens in Kinshasa, partly&#xD;
      due to a reduced laboratory capacity for polymerase chain reaction (PCR) confirmation of&#xD;
      acute cases, and an aspecific presentation of clinical symptoms. The focus of this COVID-19&#xD;
      seroprevalence study on health care workers and their households, was based on the following&#xD;
      rationale. Health care workers (HCW) are among the groups at higher risk as they are directly&#xD;
      or indirectly exposed to COVID-19 patients. They also form a group of specific interest as&#xD;
      they are in close contact to vulnerable patients at high risk for severe COVID-19. In&#xD;
      addition, their illness or absence from work significantly affects the health system's&#xD;
      ability to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic and retain its other essential functions. HCW are&#xD;
      trained in infection prevention and control (IPC). However, it is likely that at least some&#xD;
      of them will get infected either at their workplace(s) or elsewhere. In particular health&#xD;
      facilities with limited access to personal protective equipment (PPE) and regular water and&#xD;
      sanitation facilities, IPC could even potentially be hampered, resulting in an increased risk&#xD;
      of infection transmission among HCW, from HCW to their patients as well as to their household&#xD;
      members. Because of this crucial role played by HCW in the transmission chain, it is of&#xD;
      utmost importance to assess the proportion of asymptomatic infections among them.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study aims to investigate severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS-CoV-2) seroprevalence&#xD;
      and seroconversion among HCW in Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) and their household&#xD;
      members, including asymptomatic ones, in order to generate insights into the transmission&#xD;
      dynamics as well as the clinical presentation of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine seroprevalence of SARS-CoV-2 infection among active HCW of hospitals and&#xD;
           primary health care units of Kinshasa at T0;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine seroprevalence of SARS-CoV-2 infection among household members of active HCW&#xD;
           of hospitals and primary health care units of Kinshasa at T0;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine incidence of SARS-CoV-2 seroconversions among HCW of hospitals and primary&#xD;
           health care units of Kinshasa over a 3 months' time period;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine SARS-CoV-2 seroconversion among household members of active HCW of hospitals&#xD;
           and primary health care units of Kinshasa over a three months' time period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Identify work-related risk factors (infrastructural, availability of equipment and&#xD;
           behavioral) for seroconversion of HCW;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Identify socio-demographic and behavioral risk factors for seroconversion of household&#xD;
           members;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine the proportion of asymptomatic cases among seroconversions occurred during the&#xD;
           study period among HCW as well as among their household members;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Assess secondary attack rate among household members of symptomatic and asymptomatic&#xD;
           HCW.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare the performance of an in-house Luminex platform serologic diagnostic test,&#xD;
           commercialized antibody ELISA test and an antibody rapid diagnostic test (RDT) against&#xD;
           the gold standard serological test (neutralization) in tropical settings with intense&#xD;
           cocirculation of malaria and other infectious diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
      Description: 650 HCW and 1000 household members will be surveyed at 4 time moments. At each&#xD;
      moment, a questionnaire is filled exploring the professional and community risk exposure and&#xD;
      the appearance of symptoms compatible with a COVID infection. At the same time, a serum&#xD;
      sample is taken by the HCW and a 'dried blood spot' is done by the household members. These&#xD;
      samples will be analyzed to verify if the participants were exposed to the SARS-CoV2 since&#xD;
      the start of the epidemic. The use of a cohort will allow us to describe how the epidemic&#xD;
      evolves over a 4 to 6 month period in Kinshasa, but will also make it possible to evaluate&#xD;
      how the antibodies are waning or not waning over time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 17, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Ecologic or Community</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID antibody prevalence in Health care workers (serological test)</measure>
    <time_frame>Month 2</time_frame>
    <description>Antibody detection through ELISA and Luminex multiplex platform to estimate seroprevalence of SARS-CoV-2 infection among active HCW of hospitals and primary health care units of Kinshasa</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID antibody prevalence in Household members (serological test)</measure>
    <time_frame>Month 2</time_frame>
    <description>Antibody detection through Luminex multiplex platform to estimate of SARS-CoV-2 infection among household members of active HCW of hospitals and primary health care units of Kinshasa</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Seroconversion COVID Health care workers (serological test)</measure>
    <time_frame>Month 6</time_frame>
    <description>Serial antibody detection through Luminex multiplex platform to estimate incidence of SARS-CoV-2 seroconversions among HCW of hospitals and primary health care units of Kinshasa over a 5 months' time period</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Seroconversion COVID household members (serological test)</measure>
    <time_frame>Month 6</time_frame>
    <description>Serial antibody detection through Luminex multiplex platform to estimate incidence of SARS-CoV-2 seroconversion among household members of active HCW of hospitals and primary health care units of Kinshasa over a five months' time period</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>work-related risk factors (questionnaire)</measure>
    <time_frame>Month 6</time_frame>
    <description>work-related risk factors (infrastructural, availability of equipment and behavioral) for seroconversion of HCW</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>behavioural risk factors (questionnaire)</measure>
    <time_frame>Month 6</time_frame>
    <description>Identify socio-demographic and behavioral risk factors for seroconversion of household members</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1650</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV Infection</condition>
  <condition>Seroprevalence</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Health care workers</arm_group_label>
    <description>questionnaire and COVID antibody test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Household members</arm_group_label>
    <description>questionnaire and COVID antibody test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>COVID-antibody test</intervention_name>
    <description>Questionnaire and COVID-antibody test for all participants</description>
    <arm_group_label>Health care workers</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Household members</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      - For health care workers: Blood sample : a fingerprick , and one clotted blood tube to&#xD;
      obtain serum (of 5 ml)&#xD;
&#xD;
      - For Household members: Dried Blood spots: a fingerprick to collect minimum 3 - max 6 whole&#xD;
      bloodspots&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Health care workers: All staff working in health care facilities of the selected health&#xD;
        zones of Kinshasa: Lingwala, Bandalungwa, Limete, Ndjili and Lemba.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Household members: All household members of participating Health care workers. Household&#xD;
        members can be defined as the members of a household, which consists of a person or group&#xD;
        of persons who live together in the same house, share the same housekeeping arrangements&#xD;
        and usually eat meals together.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For Both groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being sick or having had COVID-19 is not an exclusion criterion&#xD;
&#xD;
        Health care workers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Health care worker (all categories from specialist doctors to allied and auxiliary&#xD;
             health workers) of the selected health services&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  foreseen to be employed (or place of internship) for the next three months in he&#xD;
             selected health facility&#xD;
&#xD;
        Household members&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing not to change the residence during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Household member of included Health care workers&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria: not giving consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Veerle Vanlerberghe, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>ITG</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Veerle Vanlerberghe, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+3232476386</phone>
    <email>vvanlerberghe@itg.be</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Placide Mbala, PhD</last_name>
    <email>mbalaplacide@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut Nationale de recherche Biomédicale</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kinshasa</city>
        <country>Congo, The Democratic Republic of the</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Placide Mbala, PhD</last_name>
      <email>placidembala@inrb.net</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Congo, The Democratic Republic of the</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Institute of Tropical Medicine, Belgium</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Veerle Vanlerberghe</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>COVID-19 related information (sero-prevalence, individual status of infection, etc.) will not be made available openly to avoid stigmatisation, they will be made available upon request using a data sharing agreement to assure confidentiality for the individuals.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

