<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4867">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04647760</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>5U18DP006429-02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04647760</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Packaging and Disseminating the JOIN for ME Program in Low-Income Settings</brief_title>
  <official_title>Packaging and Disseminating the JOIN for ME Program in Low-Income Settings</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The Miriam Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Brown University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Tufts University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Brandeis University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The Miriam Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      One in five children in the United States have obesity, and under-served populations are&#xD;
      differentially impacted by both obesity and its related health consequences. Thus,&#xD;
      community-based programs that improve the dissemination of effective obesity treatments are&#xD;
      needed within low income settings. The current study aims to test the effectiveness of an&#xD;
      evidence-based, community centered program, JOIN for ME, in two types of community settings:&#xD;
      housing authorities and patient-centered medical homes. Children between the ages of 6-12&#xD;
      years old and who meet study eligibility criteria will be enrolled in the study and&#xD;
      participate in the JOIN for ME weight control intervention. Participants will be assigned to&#xD;
      active or delayed treatment conditions (4-month delay) but all participants will receive the&#xD;
      JOIN for ME program. Primary outcomes include change in child and parent weight status and&#xD;
      health-related quality of life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The U.S. Preventive Services Task Force (USPSTF) recently reissued a Grade B recommendation,&#xD;
      initially made in 2010, for clinicians to screen children ages 6-18 years for obesity and&#xD;
      refer identified youth to comprehensive, multi-component programs with &gt;26 contact hours that&#xD;
      include nutrition and physical activity targets and are supported by behavioral strategies.&#xD;
      Re-issue of this recommendation highlights the continued importance of comprehensive&#xD;
      family-based obesity treatment programs with broad accessibility. The challenge in meeting&#xD;
      this objective is the lack of community-based obesity treatments for children. The majority&#xD;
      of children in the U.S. do not receive evidence-based treatment of obesity, with few such&#xD;
      programs available to youth from low-income backgrounds.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are multiple efforts underway to broaden both the empirical support for, and&#xD;
      accessibility of, pediatric weight management interventions. One such strategy is&#xD;
      implementation within the primary care setting as families are already accustomed to&#xD;
      attending visits for medical concerns and because physicians are important drivers of health&#xD;
      behavior change. An alternative strategy, also with high impact potential, is embedding&#xD;
      interventions in established organizations within the communities in which families live,&#xD;
      thereby decreasing logistical barriers (e.g. transportation) and enhancing program&#xD;
      credibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The JOIN for ME program, developed as a collaboration between United HealthGroup and Y-USA,&#xD;
      is an empirically tested, effective pediatric weight control intervention for children ages&#xD;
      6-12 years that is delivered by facilitators within a community setting and potentially&#xD;
      scalable nationally. The primary aim of this study is to test the effectiveness of the the&#xD;
      JOIN for ME intervention in two different types of community setting, housing authorities and&#xD;
      patient-centered medical homes, with the intention to increase equity and access to care for&#xD;
      families in low-income settings. To accomplish this aim, formative qualitative work was&#xD;
      conducted during 2019-2020 with key community stakeholders and families within the targeted&#xD;
      community settings. The formative work resulted in adapting &quot;participant facing&quot; intervention&#xD;
      materials and tools as well as the development of systems to connect families with local&#xD;
      community resources. These developments will be implemented in intervention delivery as a&#xD;
      means of increasing acceptability of the intervention and assessing its potential for broader&#xD;
      scale dissemination within community settings. Further, certified Community Health Workers&#xD;
      (CHWs) will deliver the proposed intervention given their ability to serve as intermediaries&#xD;
      between healthcare systems and the community.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of 128 children (ages 6-12) with BMI &gt; 85th% will be enrolled in this study and&#xD;
      receive the JOIN for ME weight control intervention. Participants will be assigned to active&#xD;
      or delayed treatment conditions (4-month delay) based on an a priori set of rules pertaining&#xD;
      to recruitment strategies and timeline. Evaluation of primary outcomes, change in child and&#xD;
      parent weight status and health-related quality of life (HRQL), will be obtained at baseline,&#xD;
      4 months, and 10 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following hypotheses will be tested:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Children who receive the JOIN for ME program immediately will demonstrate greater&#xD;
           decreases in percent over median BMI and zBMI from baseline to 4 months compared to&#xD;
           those in the delayed treatment onset prior to receiving the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Children who receive the JOIN for ME program immediately will demonstrate improvements&#xD;
           in HRQL from baseline to 4 months compared to those in the delayed treatment onset.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Hybrid-implementation effectiveness design incorporating a delayed-treatment design for treatment group assignment</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Outcome - Change in child weight status</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, post-intensive treatment 1 (4 months), post-maintenance treatment 2 (10 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Body Mass Index (BMI, kg/m2)-for age-percentile</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Outcome - Change in parent weight status</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, post-intensive treatment 1 (4 months), post-maintenance treatment 2 (10 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Body Mass Index (BMI, kg/m2)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Outcome - Change in child health-related quality of life (HRQL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, post-intensive treatment 1 (4 months), post-maintenance treatment 2 (10 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Obesity-specific child self-report measure, Size Me Up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Outcome - Change in parent health-related quality of life (HRQL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, post-intensive treatment 1 (4 months), post-maintenance treatment 2 (10 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Obesity-specific parent self-report measure, Sizing Them Up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">128</enrollment>
  <condition>Pediatric Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will start the intervention immediately upon study enrollment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Delayed treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will start the intervention 4-months post enrollment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>JOIN for ME</intervention_name>
    <description>JOIN for ME is an empirically tested, effective weight management program for children ages 6-12 years.The curriculum includes 16 weekly in person sessions followed by 4 biweekly and 4 monthly maintenance sessions for a 10-month program. Weekly meetings are attended by the parent/caregiver and child, and occur at a location within their community setting (public housing or patient-centered medical home). Each session is 60 minutes and led by a certified Community Health Worker, with a private weigh-in for each dyad prior to the start of each session. Key behavioral targets include self-monitoring of dietary intake and physical activity, limiting LESS foods, limiting screen time, and weekly attendance. A family-based incentive structure is incorporated into the program such that parents/caregivers reinforce their children for achieving goals. Due to the COVID-19 pandemic, in-person sessions will be conducted virtually until it is safe to resume in-person group sessions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Delayed treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  be 6 to 12 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have a BMI &gt; 85th percentile&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have at least one caregiver available to provide consent and participate in sessions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  speak English or Spanish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  agree to study participation and delayed treatment onset if applicable.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  either the child or the parent is currently involved in another weight loss program&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have a medical condition that would interfere with the prescribed dietary plan or&#xD;
             participation in physical activity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  are developmentally delayed such that the intervention materials will not be&#xD;
             appropriate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  are in treatment for or diagnosed with a major psychiatric disorder, including an&#xD;
             eating disorder&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Elissa Jelalian, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The Miriam Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andrea M Grenga, BA</last_name>
    <phone>401-793-8997</phone>
    <email>agrenga@lifespan.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Weight Management and Diabetes Research Center, The Miriam Hospital/Alpert Medical School of Brown University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Providence</city>
        <state>Rhode Island</state>
        <zip>02903</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andrea M Grenga, BA</last_name>
      <phone>401-793-8997</phone>
      <email>agrenga@lifespan.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 1, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The Miriam Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Elissa Jelalian</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor; Associate Director, Weight Control &amp; Diabetes Research Center</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pediatric</keyword>
  <keyword>Pediatric obesity</keyword>
  <keyword>Pediatric overweight</keyword>
  <keyword>Community-based</keyword>
  <keyword>Behavioral weight loss</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>A de-identified data set will be submitted to a data repository or to an investigator created website, if a central repository is not available. IPD which underlie results in a publication will be included in the repository.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data will be submitted to a repository or otherwise made available within 12 months of completion of the grant or coincident with publication of a manuscript based on the study findings, whichever is sooner. Long-term preservation will be described once a repository/website for deidentified data has been identified and the details are known.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Access criteria will be provided once a repository/wesbite for deidentified data has been identified and the details are known.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

