<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3701">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04698044</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>COVFAIROFALL</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04698044</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Anxiety and Depression Perceived by Individuals With and Without Cancer During the COVID-19 Pandemic Period</brief_title>
  <official_title>Anxiety and Depression Perceived by Individuals With and Without Cancer During the COVID-19 Pandemic Period: A Population-based Comparative Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sultan Abdulhamid Han Training and Research Hospital, Istanbul, Turkey</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sultan Abdulhamid Han Training and Research Hospital, Istanbul, Turkey</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The COVID-19 pandemic has negatively affected individuals not only physiologically but also&#xD;
      psychologically. The aim of this study is to examine the anxiety and depression status of&#xD;
      cancer patients, individuals with non-cancer chronic diseases and healthy individuals with an&#xD;
      online screening questionnaire during the COVID-19 pandemic period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Our aim is to evaluate and compare the anxiety and depression status of cancer patients,&#xD;
      individuals with non-chronic chronic diseases and healthy individuals during the COVID-19&#xD;
      period with an online screening program.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A simple random sampling method performed by a computer was used in selecting the&#xD;
      participants from 7,000 people whose information was available in the hospital automation&#xD;
      system. The computer program enumerates the items in the sampling frame, determines its own&#xD;
      random numbers, and presents the selected items to the researcher in writing or digitally&#xD;
      (Newman &amp; Ridenour, 1998).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample groups were randomly selected from cancer patients, patients with non-cancer&#xD;
      chronic diseases and those without any diseases. The study included individuals who were aged&#xD;
      18 years and above, volunteered to participate in the study and were literate. The diagnoses&#xD;
      recorded in the electronic medical records of the patients were examined, and those diagnosed&#xD;
      with psychiatric diseases (depression, mania, bipolar disorder, psychosis,&#xD;
      obsessive-compulsive disorder, etc.), mental retardation, dementia, and Alzheimer's disease&#xD;
      were excluded. In addition, the questionnaire questions include the question of the presence&#xD;
      of existing psychiatric and neurological diseases. The patient was excluded from the study&#xD;
      also if these diagnoses were reported by the patient. Moreover, the participation of the&#xD;
      patient in the study was not allowed in the presence of both cancer and a non-cancer chronic&#xD;
      disease. Non-cancer chronic diseases were defined as diabetes mellitus, hypertension,&#xD;
      neurological diseases, asthma, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), other pulmonary&#xD;
      diseases, cardiovascular diseases, and hypothyroidism. Other patients who used chronic&#xD;
      medication and/or were followed up for any chronic disease (rheumatic disease, endocrinal&#xD;
      disorders, liver disease, kidney diseases) were classified as other chronic diseases.&#xD;
      Approval was taken from the University of Health Sciences, XXX Ethics Committee (approval&#xD;
      number: 20/133) before the study commenced. The patients were called with phone and confirmed&#xD;
      whether they wanted to participate in the study, and their consents were obtained.&#xD;
      Individuals who wanted to participate in the study was informed about the purpose of the&#xD;
      study, procedure and data privacy, and told that participation was on a voluntary basis, and&#xD;
      individuals could leave the research at any time they wanted. Individuals read and signed&#xD;
      their consent forms online. The study was conducted in compliance with the &quot;Ethical&#xD;
      principles for medical research involving human subjects&quot; of the Helsinki Declaration. All&#xD;
      data were collected with Survey Monkey (2005 SurveyMonkey.com), which provides electronic&#xD;
      self-control, prevents multiple entries from the same person, and makes it easier to collect&#xD;
      and track data (last data entry: 07/06/2020). Confidentiality was guaranteed by completely&#xD;
      deactivating electronic records and IP address records.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 8, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 25, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 25, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>HADS</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>The score of Hospital Anxiety Depression Scale</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1107</enrollment>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy</arm_group_label>
    <description>Have not chronic disease</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cancer</arm_group_label>
    <description>Have cancer</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Non-Cancer Crhronic Disease</arm_group_label>
    <description>Have non-cancer chronic disease</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hospital Anxiety Depression Scale</intervention_name>
    <description>HADS is a self-report questionnaire designed to screen the symptoms of anxiety and depression in individuals with medical diseases other than psychiatric illnessesHADS is a self-report questionnaire designed to screen the symptoms of anxiety and depression in individuals with medical diseases other than psychiatric illnesses The 4-point Likert type scale, which consists of 14 items, has 2 subscales. Each of the HADS-Anxiety (HADS-A) and HADS-Depression (HADS-D) subscales has 7 items. The score given for each question varies between 0 and 3. A high score indicates a high level of anxiety and depression. The responses given to the questions are given certain scores, and as a result, a score of 0-7 refers to a normal level, 8-10 to a level at the limit and 11 and above to a high level (abnormal level).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cancer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Non-Cancer Crhronic Disease</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The sample groups were randomly selected from cancer patients, patients with non-cancer&#xD;
        chronic diseases and those without any diseases&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cancer patients, patients with non-cancer chronic diseases and those without any&#xD;
             diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years or above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Literate&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric diseases (depression, mania, bipolar disorder, psychosis,&#xD;
             obsessive-compulsive disorder, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mental retardation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dementia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alzheimer's disease were excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sultan Abdülhamid Han Training and Research Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <zip>34660</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sultan Abdulhamid Han Training and Research Hospital, Istanbul, Turkey</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Elif Yıldırım Ayaz</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>M.D.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>depression</keyword>
  <keyword>covid-19</keyword>
  <keyword>cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>chronic disease</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

