<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1148">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04595773</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10000102</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>000102-CC</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04595773</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19, Chronic Adaptation and Response to Exercise (COVID-CARE)</brief_title>
  <official_title>COVID-19, Chronic Adaptation and Response to Exercise (COVID-CARE): A Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People who are recovering from COVID-19 may continue to have problems that affect their daily&#xD;
      life. For instance, they might feel overly tired. Researchers want to learn if exercise can&#xD;
      help people recover after COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To study if participation in a rehabilitation exercise program can help people recovering&#xD;
      from COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults ages 18-80 with a lab-confirmed SARS-CoV2 infection (the virus that causes COVID-19),&#xD;
      and are still having some symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have a medical history and physical exam. They will give blood and urine&#xD;
      samples. They will have tests to measure heart and lung function. Their blood vessels will be&#xD;
      assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have a computed tomography scan of the body. They will have an ultrasound&#xD;
      of the muscles in their arms, legs, and chest.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will take a 6-minute walk test. They will take other balance and movement tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will walk on a treadmill while hooked up to a monitor. Then they will be&#xD;
      interviewed. It will be audio-recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will complete surveys about their symptoms and daily activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will take a smell test. For this, they will identify different smells. They will&#xD;
      also have memory, attention, and mental functioning tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will wear an activity monitor on their wrist 24 hours a day. They will exercise&#xD;
      3 times a week for 10 weeks by moving vigorously on a track or treadmill for 30 minutes. They&#xD;
      will attend education classes once a week for 10 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be contacted by phone or email every 3 months for 1 year after they&#xD;
      complete the exercise part of the study. They will wear an activity monitor for up to 2&#xD;
      weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Description: This randomized controlled trial will determine whether aerobic exercise&#xD;
      training has a beneficial effect on physical function, health-related quality of life,&#xD;
      free-living physical activity and sleep quality among survivors of COVID-19. Participants&#xD;
      will be randomized to either an aerobic exercise training and education (AET+) group or a&#xD;
      control education only group (CON) for 10 weeks. Assessments for physical function,&#xD;
      self-reported health outcomes for quality of life (QOL), free-living physical activity and&#xD;
      sleep quality will be measured at baseline and following the 10-week intervention period.&#xD;
      Participants in the CON group will then crossover and perform AET after the 10-week follow-up&#xD;
      visit. All participants will be monitored for one year to capture free-living physical&#xD;
      activity, sleep quality and health-related QOL outcomes over time. It is hypothesized that&#xD;
      following 10 weeks, physical function, health-related QOL, free-living physical activity and&#xD;
      sleep quality will show greater improvement with AET+.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective: To examine the effect of aerobic exercise training on physical function in&#xD;
      participants recovering from COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives: To examine the effect of aerobic exercise training on patient reported&#xD;
      outcomes and other health-related QOL components in participants recovering from COVID-19; To&#xD;
      examine the effect of aerobic exercise training on free-living physical activity and sleep&#xD;
      quality in participants recovering from COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory Objectives: To explore the effect of aerobic exercise training on clinical&#xD;
      outcomes, cardiorespiratory function, cognition, biomarkers, metabolomics, ultrasound-based&#xD;
      muscle measurements, and vascular function in participants recovering from COVID-19; To&#xD;
      explore the feasibility of conducting the AET program remotely in the crossover CON group of&#xD;
      participants recovering from COVID-19; To explore follow-up physical activity, sleep quality&#xD;
      and health-related QOL outcomes over 1 year in participants recovering from COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Endpoints: Physical function as measured by distance walked during the 6 minute walk&#xD;
      test after 10 weeks post-randomization with AET+ and CON.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Endpoints: Patient-reported outcomes and other health-related components after 10&#xD;
      weeks post-randomization with AET+ and CON; Free-living physical activity and sleep quality&#xD;
      after 10 weeks post-randomization with AET+ and CON.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory Endpoints: Clinical outcomes, cardiorespiratory function, cognition, biomarkers,&#xD;
      metabolomics, ultrasound-based muscle measurements, and vascular function after 10 weeks&#xD;
      post-randomization with AET+ and CON; Collection of initial feasibility data to conduct&#xD;
      exercise sessions remotely; Explore relationships between the physiological variables and&#xD;
      post-study health outcome variables over time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population: Ninety male and female adults (18 to 80 years old) recovering from&#xD;
      COVID-19, from the greater Washington DC metropolitan area.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Description of Sites/Facilities Enrolling Participants: Single-site study (NIH Clinical&#xD;
      Center)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Description of Study Intervention:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aerobic Exercise Training: Participants will perform aerobic exercise, 3 times a week for 10&#xD;
      weeks, with supervision by credentialed RMD staff members. Participants will be encouraged to&#xD;
      target 30 minutes of continuous aerobic exercise. The intensity of exercise will be gradually&#xD;
      increased from light-moderate to moderate-high as safely tolerated by the participant and&#xD;
      guided using heart rate targets.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Education: Participants will have weekly education sessions for 10 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All sessions are approximately 1 hour and will be conducted remotely by credentialed RMD&#xD;
      staff members.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants randomized to AET+ will perform both exercise training and education during the&#xD;
      10 week intervention period. Participants randomized to CON will perform education only&#xD;
      during the first 10 weeks, followed by exercise training during the second 10 weeks&#xD;
      (crossover).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Duration: 36 months&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant Duration: Up to 16 months if randomized to AET+, and up to 19 months if&#xD;
      randomized to CON&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 22, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>6 minute walk test distance</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 10 weeks, 20 weeks (for cross-over group)</time_frame>
    <description>The 6MWT distance has been used to reflect longitudinal changes in physical function among patients with acute lung disease and SARS. A minimal important difference (MID) has yet to be established among survivors of COVID-19. We will consider 30 meters as the MID for this study based on reported ranges of 20 to 30 meters in patients with lung disease.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient reported outcomes and quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 10 weeks, 20 weeks (for cross-over group), every 3 months for 1 year after exercise</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported outcomes related to fatigue, sleep, post-traumaticstress disorder, depression, anxiety, general and COVID-19 specific QOL outcomes will be captured.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Free-living physical activity and sleep quality</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 10 weeks, 20 weeks (for cross-over group), every 3 months for 1 year after exercise</time_frame>
    <description>Quantification of free-living physical activity and sleep quality and patterns using wearable accelerometer device.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Aerobic Exercise Training and Education (AET+)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will perform both exercise training and education for 10 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Education only (CON)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will perform only education for the first 10 weeks, then cross-over to perform exercise in the second 10 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Aerobic Exercise Training</intervention_name>
    <description>Aerobic exercise training will consist of 10 weeks of aerobic exercise, performed 3 times/week for 30 minutes. Each session will include a warm-up and cool-down period. The intensity will be guided by heart rate and gradually increased from light-moderate to moderate-high intensity as safely tolerated by the subject. All sessions are supervised by credentialed RMD staff members.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Aerobic Exercise Training and Education (AET+)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Education only (CON)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Education</intervention_name>
    <description>Education consisting of weekly lectures lasting approximately 1 hour for 10 weeks. Topics related to exercise programming, safety and well-being will be covered.&#xD;
Conducted remotely by credential RMD staff members.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Aerobic Exercise Training and Education (AET+)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Education only (CON)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Screening procedures will be performed as part of this study. In order to be eligible to&#xD;
        participate in this study, an individual must meet all of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female, aged 18 to 80 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Previous laboratory-confirmed infection with SARS-CoV2&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Considered non-infectious with COVID-19 as demonstrated by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Greater than or equal to 28 days since initial onset of symptoms or initial&#xD;
                  positive test date, (for asymptomatic infection), and greater than or equal to 72&#xD;
                  hours since resolution of fever (without fever-reducing medication), and symptoms&#xD;
                  (e.g. cough, shortness of breath) have improved, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Greater than or equal to 10 days since initial positive test date, and at least 2&#xD;
                  consecutive nasopharyngeal or oropharyngeal swabs collected greater than or equal&#xD;
                  to 24 hours apart that are negative for SARS-CoV2&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Presence of physical limitations or significant fatigue since COVID-19 as demonstrated&#xD;
             by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Total score less than or equal to 19 on the PROMIS short form for physical&#xD;
                  function or total score greater than or equal to 9 on the PROMIS short form for&#xD;
                  fatigue, AND&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Score greater than or equal to 1 on the Patient Global Rating of Flu Severity and&#xD;
                  Patient Global Assessment of Interference with Daily Activities&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Able to read, speak and understand English or Spanish&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Able to understand and willing to sign a written informed consent document&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Willing and able to complete study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        An individual who meets any of the following criteria will be excluded from participation&#xD;
        in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Above normal performance (i.e, greater than or equal to 100% predicted) in the 6MWT&#xD;
             based on normative data for gender and age (85,86)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History or cardiac condition as determined by NIH cardiology to be unsafe for exercise&#xD;
             participation (e.g. ischemic heart disease, right- or left-sided heart failure, cor&#xD;
             pulmonale or pulmonary hypertension, dilated or hypertrophic cardiomyopathy or&#xD;
             non-idiopathic cardiomyopathy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Significant hepatic or renal dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Cancer diagnosis with evidence of metastasis or a life expectancy of less than one&#xD;
             year&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of stroke resulting in impairments in functional mobility that limits safe&#xD;
             participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Active substance abuse including EtOH&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Severe psychiatric disease, not responsive to treatment or medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of diabetes and on insulin pump therapy, or uncontrolled diabetes with HbA1c &gt;&#xD;
             9.0%&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Acceptance onto a lung transplant waiting list&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Extreme obesity with BMI &gt; 40 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. On medications that would influence exercise performance such as beta blockers or&#xD;
             antiretroviral therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Ongoing tobacco and/or nicotine product use&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Enrolled in another interventional clinical research trial&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Any other medical or health condition(s) that unduly increases the risk of exercise&#xD;
             testing or training, affects the normal physiologic response to exercise testing or&#xD;
             training, and/or would otherwise interfere with the ability to interpret the data as&#xD;
             determined by the PI&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION OF VULNERABLE PARTICIPANTS:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participation of Employees:&#xD;
&#xD;
        NIH employees may be enrolled in this study as this population meets the study entry&#xD;
        criteria. Neither participation nor refusal to participate as a participant in the research&#xD;
        will have an effect, either beneficial or adverse, on the participant s employment or&#xD;
        position at NIH.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Every effort will be made to protect participant information, but such information may be&#xD;
        available in medical records and may be available to authorized users outside of the study&#xD;
        team in both an identifiable and unidentifiable manner.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The NIH Information Sheet on Employee Research Participation will be made available.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Leighton Chan, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>COVID-CARE Rehab Team</last_name>
    <phone>Not Listed</phone>
    <email>covidcarerehabteam@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_000102-CC.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>February 2, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 20, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Aerobic Exercise Training</keyword>
  <keyword>Physical Function</keyword>
  <keyword>Physical Activity</keyword>
  <keyword>Convalescence</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

