<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3212">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04646590</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LKM-2020-NCV-GJ01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04646590</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase III Clinical Trial to Determine the Safety and Efficacy of ZF2001 for Prevention of COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase III Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled Clinical Trial in 18 Years of Age and Above to Determine the Safety and Efficacy of ZF2001, a Recombinant Novel Coronavirus Vaccine (CHO Cell) for Prevention of COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Anhui Zhifei Longcom Biologic Pharmacy Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Anhui Zhifei Longcom Biologic Pharmacy Co., Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled international multicenter clinical trial&#xD;
      design will be adopted. A total of 29,000 subjects aged 18 years and above are planned to be&#xD;
      recruited, including 750 subjects aged 18-59 years and 250 subjects aged 60 years and above&#xD;
      in China; 21,000 subjects aged 18-59 years and 7,000 subjects aged 60 years and above will be&#xD;
      recruited outside China. Safety and immunogenicity will be evaluated among the Chinese&#xD;
      subjects, and efficacy, immunogenicity and safety will be evaluated among the subjects&#xD;
      outside China. Among them, 750 subjects aged 18-59 and 250 subjects aged 60 and above from&#xD;
      outside China and all subjects from China will be selected as the immunogenicity subgroup for&#xD;
      immunogenicity bridging study. The IgG levels of SARS-COV-2 neutralizing antibody and RBD&#xD;
      protein binding antibody will be detected by blood sampling before vaccination, 14 days and 6&#xD;
      months after full course of vaccination to evaluate the immunogenicity and immune&#xD;
      persistence.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      After signing the informed consent form, the volunteers aged 18 years and above will receive&#xD;
      the relevant examinations after an inquiry by investigator of the medical history (including&#xD;
      COVID-19 history), recent medication(vaccine) history, allergy history and concomitant&#xD;
      medications, and demographic data collection by the investigators, including physical&#xD;
      examination (skin and mucous membranes, lymph nodes, head, neck, chest, abdomen,&#xD;
      spine/limbs), novel Coronavirus (SARS-COV-2) nucleic acid test and antibody test, urine&#xD;
      pregnancy (women of childbearing age) test, and vital signs (blood pressure, axillary/oral&#xD;
      temperature, pulse) evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Screening eligible subjects will be 1:1 randomly assigned to the experimental group and the&#xD;
      placebo control group, and vaccinated as per the 0, 1, 2 month immunization schedule.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All adverse events (AEs) up to 30 minutes after each dose of vaccination, all AEs from 0 to 7&#xD;
      days (including both solicited and unsolicited), and all AES from 8 to 30 days (unsolicited)&#xD;
      will be collected; All serious adverse events (SAEs) will be collected from the first dose of&#xD;
      vaccination to 12 months after the whole vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The incidence rate and efficacy of any severity of COVID-9 of any severity 14 days after&#xD;
      whole vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood samples (5ml) will be collected before the first dose of vaccination and 14 days and 6&#xD;
      months after the whole course of vaccination to detect neutralizing antibody of SARS-COV-2&#xD;
      and protein binding antibody IgG of receptor binding region (RBD) .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 16, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The endpoint of efficacy study</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days to one year after whole vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>The number of any severity of COVID-9 cases 14 days after whole vaccination</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The endpoint of safety study</measure>
    <time_frame>From the first dose of vaccination until 30 days after full course of vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Analysis of adverse events from the first dose of vaccination until 30 days after full course of vaccination</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The endpoint of safety study</measure>
    <time_frame>From the first dose of vaccination until 12 months after full course of vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Analysis of serious adverse events from the first dose of vaccination until 12 months after full course of vaccination</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The endpoint of efficacy study</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to one year after the vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>The number of severe and severity above COVID-19 cases 14 days after whole vaccination; The number of any severity of COVID-9 cases after first dose of vaccination; The number of COVID-19 cases of any severity in populations of different age group (18-59 years vs. 60 years and above) 14 days after whole vaccination.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Endpoint of immunogenicity and immune persistence study</measure>
    <time_frame>At 14 days and 6 months after full course of vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>The level of neutralizing antibody to SARS-COV-2 and IgG level of RBD protein binding antibody at 14 days and 6 months after full course of vaccination.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">29000</enrollment>
  <condition>Prevention of COVID-19</condition>
  <condition>Safety and Efficacy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Investigational Vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Recombinant Novel Coronavirus Vaccine (CHO cell), 0.5mL/vial, contains 25 μg NCP-RBD protein. After mixing, take all the liquid and inject intramuscularly into deltoid muscle of upper arm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo comparator</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo for Recombinant Novel Coronavirus Vaccine (CHO cell), 0.5mL/vial, contains 0.25mg Aluminum hydroxide adjuvant. After mixing, take all the liquid and inject intramuscularly into deltoid muscle of upper arm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cell) group</intervention_name>
    <description>Intramuscular injection of deltoid muscle of upper armof 25μg/0.5ml/person doseRecombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Investigational Vaccine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells) placebo group</intervention_name>
    <description>Intramuscular injection of deltoid muscle of upper arm of 0.5ml/person doseRecombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells) placebo.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo comparator</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Population aged 18 years and above;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects voluntarily participate in the study and sign the informed consent form; and&#xD;
             are able to provide valid identification, and understand and comply with the&#xD;
             requirements of the trial protocol;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects of childbearing age agree to use effective contraceptive measures from&#xD;
             the beginning of the study to 2 months after full course of vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suspected or confirmed as fever(axillary temperature ≥37.3°C / oral temperature&#xD;
             ≥37.5°C) within 72 hours before the enrollment, or axillary temperature ≥37.3°C / oral&#xD;
             temperature ≥37.5°C at the day of screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diastolic blood pressure ≥ 100mmhg and / or systolic blood pressure ≥ 150mmhg;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with previous history of a COVID-19;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Detection of SARS-COV-2 nucleic acid or antibody is positive;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who are suffering from the following diseases:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. With thrombocytopenia, any coagulation dysfunction or receiving anti-coagulatory&#xD;
                  treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Congenital or acquired immune deficiency or autoimmune disease history; no&#xD;
                  spleen, or history of splenic surgery and trauma, or receiving immunomodulator&#xD;
                  treatment within 6 months, e.g., immunosuppressive dose of glucocorticoids&#xD;
                  (reference dose: equivalent to 20mg/ day of prednisone, over 1 week); Or&#xD;
                  monoclonal antibodies; Or thymosin; Or interferon etc.; However, topical&#xD;
                  application (such as ointment, eye drops, inhalers or nasal sprays) is permitted;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Symptoms related to acute respiratory tract infection (such as sneezing, nasal&#xD;
                  congestion, runny nose, cough, sore throat, loss of taste, chills, shortness of&#xD;
                  breath, etc.);&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Cancer patients (except basal cell carcinoma).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With a history of serious allergy to any vaccine or any composition of Investigational&#xD;
             product (including: aluminum preparations), such as allergic shock, allergic throat&#xD;
             edema, allergic purpura, thrombocytopenic purpura, localized allergic necrosis&#xD;
             reaction (Arthus reaction), dyspnea and angioneuroedema;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inoculated with subunit vaccine and inactivated vaccine within 14 days before the&#xD;
             first dosing of investigational vaccine, or inoculated with attenuated live vaccine&#xD;
             within 30 days;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous receiving blood transfusion or blood relevant products (including&#xD;
             immunoglobulin) within 3 months, or planning to receive such products from the&#xD;
             starting of study to &lt;6 months after the whole-course inoculation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have participated in or are participating in other covid-19 related clinical trials;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women in breastfeeding period or in pregnant period (including women at childbearing&#xD;
             age with positive result of urine pregnancy test);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Considered by investigators as any disease or state possibly making the subject at&#xD;
             unacceptable risk; not conforming to the requirements of study protocol; interference&#xD;
             of assessment of reactions of vaccine.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Fangjun Li, Bachelor</last_name>
    <phone>13574109585</phone>
    <email>646022285@qq.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Fan Di, Master</last_name>
    <phone>18119631130</phone>
    <email>dingfan@zhifeishengwu.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hunan Provincial Center for Disease Control and Prevention</name>
      <address>
        <city>Changsha</city>
        <state>Hunan</state>
        <zip>410005</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Fangjun Li, Bachelor</last_name>
      <phone>13574109585</phone>
      <email>646022285@qq.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 16, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 16, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

