<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4846">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04659590</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>263745</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04659590</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Exploratory Study Investigating the Potential of a Rectal Mucus Sample for Development of Biomarker Assays in Subjects With Gastrointestinal Diseases</brief_title>
  <acronym>ORI-EGI-02</acronym>
  <official_title>An Exploratory Study Investigating the Potential of a Rectal Mucus Sample for Development of Biomarker Assays in Subjects With Gastrointestinal Diseases</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Origin Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Origin Sciences</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The identification of patients with colorectal cancer is challenging as they present with a&#xD;
      variable symptom profile and require invasive tests (colonoscopy) for diagnosis (through&#xD;
      histological analysis of biopsies) and complimented by cross-sectional radiology, prior to&#xD;
      commencement of treatment. The biopsy forms the basis of the diagnosis and management&#xD;
      planning for a patient with colorectal cancer through the multidisciplinary team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The biggest challenge currently faced in the management of colorectal cancer is the accurate&#xD;
      identification of patients who present with various symptoms none of which are specific for&#xD;
      bowel cancer. Currently the NICE referral guidelines are used to determine the&#xD;
      appropriateness of referral pathway, i.e. Fast-Track/Two-Week Wait referral. A recent review&#xD;
      of over 10000 referrals revealed a colorectal cancer diagnosis in 4.1% of referrals. Previous&#xD;
      literature reports rates as high as 8%, but in series of cases with only 72-89% adherence to&#xD;
      the referral guidance leading to at best 40% of all colorectal cases being diagnosed through&#xD;
      this route. The remainder of colorectal cancers being diagnosed through the bowel cancer&#xD;
      screening programme (NBCSP), non-two-week wait referrals and other processes such as&#xD;
      emergency admissions. Inherently the Two-Week Wait pathway refers a large volume of&#xD;
      &quot;symptomatic patients&quot; and it has become a &quot;cancer exclusion pathway.&quot; Once cancer has been&#xD;
      excluded, patients are often discharged back to General Practice, yet the patients often&#xD;
      still have symptoms. The current Covid-19 pandemic has had a significant impact on the&#xD;
      already pressed Two-Week pathway impacting on the reduction of endoscopic and radiological&#xD;
      appointments available leading to delays in treatment. Each test performed in the diagnostic&#xD;
      pathway has a significant financial, personal, and institutional resource profile.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is our aim to develop a novel diagnostic device based upon the identification of genetic&#xD;
      mutations and genomic alterations from material trapped in the rectal mucous layer allowing&#xD;
      focused endoscopic assessment, confirmation/exclusion of cancer diagnosis from&#xD;
      cross-sectional imaging in those unfit for endoscopic examination and identification of&#xD;
      high-risk lesions (dysplasia). This would allow a greater triage, and focus colonoscopic&#xD;
      services onto therapeutic procedures, improving overall care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Colorectal cancer (CRC) is the fourth most common cancer overall worldwide contributing to&#xD;
      9.7% of global cancer burden. It affects 746,000 men (10% of all cancer cases) and 614,000&#xD;
      women (9.2% of all cancer cases) with most cases (55%) occurring in developed countries.&#xD;
      Furthermore, in the UK, 42,300 new colorectal cancer cases are diagnosed each year making it&#xD;
      the fourth most common cancer overall, and third most common in males and females. In&#xD;
      addition, the incidence of colorectal cancer increased between 1991 and 2016 and is&#xD;
      attributed to lifestyle, environmental changes, and aging populations. Although bowel cancer&#xD;
      incidence has fallen in the UK in the past decade by 4%, the lifestyle risk factors remain.&#xD;
      Moreover, the burden of CRC is expected to increase with 2.2 million new cases and 1.1&#xD;
      million deaths expected globally by 2030. In addition, significant challenges remain in&#xD;
      managing disease burden.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In England, five-year overall survival for CRC is 58.4% which is lower than the US reported&#xD;
      60-65%. Further challenges remain due to the ageing demographic and advanced presentation of&#xD;
      disease. Older patients, above age 75 years, make up 44% of new colorectal cancer diagnoses&#xD;
      and an estimated 20-25% of CRC is diagnosed at the metastatic stage with an additional 25% of&#xD;
      patients developing metastasis during their illness. As a result, CRC accounts for 8.5% of&#xD;
      cancer related deaths worldwide with 16,300 deaths per year in the UK making it the second&#xD;
      most frequent cause of cancer related deaths at 10%. Although survival is stage dependent&#xD;
      with 92% survival for stage I, compared to 10% in stage IV, there has been an improvement in&#xD;
      survival for the 60-69-year age group attributed to screening. Thus, CRC remains a prevalent&#xD;
      challenge in cancer management emphasizing the need for early diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Declining mortality due to improvements has been shown with early detection through screening&#xD;
      and effective treatment. The UK CRC screening program relying on faecal detected occult blood&#xD;
      (FOBT) and colonoscopy has led to 16% decline in overall mortality rate without affecting&#xD;
      incidence. However, FOBT has reduced sensitivity for advanced adenomas and CRC which may&#xD;
      improve with newly implemented immunochemical testing (qFiT). With the pressures on service&#xD;
      from the Covid-19 pandemic, qFIT has been implemented into the Two-Week Pathway to attempt to&#xD;
      stratify patients at highest risk of colorectal cancer and the NICE-qFiT Study publication is&#xD;
      awaited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biomarkers are molecular patterns that can be used as a tool for early cancer detection and&#xD;
      individualized CRC treatment. They can be divided into diagnostic, prognostic, or predictive&#xD;
      categories. Thus, biomarkers provide utility at different stages of the disease to determine&#xD;
      disease progression, recurrence, as well as providing a personalized indicator for&#xD;
      therapeutic effectiveness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Firstly, early diagnosis in asymptomatic patients remains a key target to achieve favourable&#xD;
      survival outcomes through identification of early CRC as well as pre-malignant lesions&#xD;
      including high risk polyps. This forms the basis of the National Bowel Screening Programme.&#xD;
      The sensitivity for detecting CRC using current qFIT testing (100ng/mL) is 73.8% versus 92.3%&#xD;
      for a stool-based DNA assay screening KRAS, aberrant NDRG4 and BMP3 methylation. Furthermore,&#xD;
      qFIT testing sensitivity for advanced precancerous lesions is 23.8% versus 42.4% with stool&#xD;
      DNA testing. Moreover, the rate of detection of polyps with high-grade dysplasia is 46.2%&#xD;
      with qFIT testing verses 69.2% with stool DNA testing, whereas the detection rate of serrated&#xD;
      sessile polyps measuring &gt;1 cm is only 5.1% (qFIT) versus 42.4% with stool DNA sampling.&#xD;
      These findings highlight the limits of current diagnostic screening and difficulty in&#xD;
      establishing appropriate surrogate markers for early disease detection in asymptomatic&#xD;
      individuals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Current non-invasive screening stools are not sensitive to detect pre-cancerous lesions and&#xD;
      regularly miss significant early CRC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As outlined, the investigator currently have a low threshold in symptomatic patients for&#xD;
      colonoscopy in these patients and further tools are required to support identifying early&#xD;
      pre-malignant lesions (adenomas) and CRC .&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigator knows from the recognition of the adenoma - carcinoma sequence and the&#xD;
      impact of hyper- and hypomethylation that the local environment that there are a number of&#xD;
      steps both in carcinogenesis and the associated risks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At an epigenetic level, DNA methylation changes is one of the hallmark events in&#xD;
      carcinogenesis, characterized by global hypomethylation and paradoxical gene-specific&#xD;
      hypermethylation. Hypomethylation is primarily involved in chromosomal instability and global&#xD;
      loss of imprinting, while gene-specific hypermethylation anchors to promoters, it causes&#xD;
      transcriptional silencing of tumour suppressor genes and consequently sets the stage for&#xD;
      neoplastic transformation. Deregulated DNA methylation is well known to be associated with&#xD;
      CRC. The first evidence of DNA methylation contributing to CRC was presented, in which a&#xD;
      global loss in DNA methylation was identified. Then, extensive efforts have been made in&#xD;
      identifying aberrant hypermethylation in promoters of CRC-related suppressor genes, such as&#xD;
      APC, SFRP2, SEPT, and CDH1. Remarkably, a near universal phenomenon that gene-specific&#xD;
      hypermethylation occurred in both pre-neoplastic and neoplastic phase of colorectal cancer&#xD;
      was observed. This might shed light on the process of tumorigenesis. However, few studies&#xD;
      have defined precisely the hierarchy of methylation events during the transformation from&#xD;
      normal epithelial cells to malignant cells in colorectal carcinogenesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is becoming increasingly apparent that the occurrence of molecular alterations could be&#xD;
      found not only in tumour tissue but also in histological normal-appearing tissue adjacent to&#xD;
      the tumour. The presence of such molecular alterations in histological normal-appearing&#xD;
      tissue is commonly known as field cancerization or field effect. This has been thought to&#xD;
      constitute the earliest clone in the carcinogenesis process. In colorectal carcinogenesis, a&#xD;
      few numbers of gene-specific hypermethylation events have been reported in normal-appearing&#xD;
      colonic mucosa from CRC patients (such as APC, DKKI, MGMT, CDKN2A, and SFRP4). In addition,&#xD;
      previous studies have also demonstrated the effect of aberrant DNA methylation on suppressor&#xD;
      genes such as MINT1, MINT31, SLC5A8, and MGMT, during adenoma-carcinoma sequence. These&#xD;
      findings suggest that the presence of field effect in methylation might be a useful&#xD;
      intermediate biomarker in etiologic studies. A better understanding of when these epigenetic&#xD;
      tags occur and how they take part in colorectal progression may represent a practical&#xD;
      opportunity for colorectal cancer risk assessment. The use of a unique biological material&#xD;
      capture device with genomic and epigenetic assessment of the retrieved specimen is the basis&#xD;
      of the trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 6, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Stability of buffer transfer medium</measure>
    <time_frame>through study, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Sample loss rate</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison to qFiT test</measure>
    <time_frame>through study, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison to pathology identified</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison between tumour surface imprint and rectal mucous imprint</measure>
    <time_frame>through study, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison between tumour imprint surface and rectal mucous imprint</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Bowel Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Bowel Disease</condition>
  <condition>Genomic</condition>
  <condition>Epigenetic Disorder</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Banked DNA retrieved from specimen taken from bowel lumen&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Subjects with known or suspected gastrointestinal disease(s).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        General inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  aged 18 years or over&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  be able to give voluntary, written informed consent to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with confirmed collagenous colitis or symptoms that would make proctoscopic&#xD;
             examination inappropriate, including acute anal fissure, symptomatic thrombosed&#xD;
             haemorrhoids or obstructing anorectal tumours as determined by rectal examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with a previous history of cancer or who have previously received&#xD;
             radiotherapy, chemotherapy or immunotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        The following populations will be included:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with confirmed colorectal cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with suspected colorectal cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with known or suspected inflammatory bowel disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known controls&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ian Daniels</last_name>
    <phone>+447920517187</phone>
    <email>Ian.Daniels@originsciences.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Cornwall Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Truro</city>
        <state>Cornwall</state>
        <zip>TR1 3LQ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nicholas Battersby</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>John Radcliffe Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oxford</city>
        <state>Oxfordshire</state>
        <zip>OX3 9DU</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christopher Cunningham</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Shrewsbury &amp; Telford Hospitals NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Shrewsbury</city>
        <state>Shropshire</state>
        <zip>SY3 8XQ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jonathon Lacy-Colson</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Devon &amp; Exeter NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Exeter</city>
        <zip>EX2 4UG</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ian Daniels</last_name>
      <phone>+447920517187</phone>
      <email>Ian.Daniels@originsciences.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 2, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 2, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Digestive System Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

