<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4531">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04363177</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P2SKP3_187728</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04363177</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Global Mental Health of Urban Mothers</brief_title>
  <acronym>MUM</acronym>
  <official_title>Mental Health of Urban Mothers (MUM) Study: A Multi-center Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Karolinska Institutet</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Swiss National Science Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Karolinska Institutet</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Mental health disorders are common during pregnancy and the postnatal period, and can have&#xD;
      serious adverse effects on the well-being of woman and child. Every tenth woman has&#xD;
      depressive symptoms and 5% suffer major depression during pregnancy. The consequences for&#xD;
      global mental health due to the novel coronavirus disease, COVID-19, are likely to be&#xD;
      significant and may have long-term impact on the global burden of disease. Pregnant women may&#xD;
      be particularly vulnerable due to partial immune suppression. Besides physical vulnerability,&#xD;
      the women could be at increased risk of mental health problems, such as anxiety, depression,&#xD;
      and post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), due to social distancing leading to less support&#xD;
      from the family and friends, and in some cases, partners not being allowed to be present&#xD;
      during prenatal visits, labor and delivery. Furthermore, many pregnant women may feel&#xD;
      insecure and worried about the effect of COVID-19 on their unborn child, if the women get&#xD;
      infected during pregnancy. Today, young urban women are used to utilizing internet services&#xD;
      frequently and efficiently. Therefore, providing mental health support to pregnant women via&#xD;
      web-based support may be effective in ameliorating their anxiety/depression and reduce the&#xD;
      risk of serious mental health disorders leading to improved maternal and perinatal outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Pregnancy is a period of transition and great change, which may make some women more&#xD;
      vulnerable to mental health problems. It is known that depressive symptoms during pregnancy&#xD;
      may influence birth outcomes. Perinatal mental health disorders may become more prevalent&#xD;
      during a time of acute crisis, and the prevalence of maternal anxiety, distress, and&#xD;
      perinatal depression can be expected to increase globally, as a result of the COVID-19&#xD;
      pandemic. However, there might be cross-national differences in the risk factors and impact&#xD;
      of pandemic on the prevalence of perinatal mental health disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some pregnant women might be predisposed to posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD) during a&#xD;
      crisis situation, such as the COVID-19 pandemic. Mothers who developed PTSD in response to&#xD;
      the 9/11 terrorist attacks had lower morning and evening salivary cortisol levels, compared&#xD;
      to mothers who did not develop PTSD. Beyond effects on the mother alone, perinatal mental&#xD;
      health issues can have long-term effects on child´s mental and physical health, as well as&#xD;
      the participants behavior and cognition. Distress in pregnant women may affect the fetus and&#xD;
      is known to induce epigenetic changes in the placental genes. Increased risk of&#xD;
      psychopathology is observed in children exposed to maternal prenatal distress. Elevated&#xD;
      maternal cortisol and epigenetic regulation of placental glucocorticoid-pathway genes are&#xD;
      potential mechanisms for these observations. Women often express feelings of inadequacy in&#xD;
      the new mothering role, which can furthermore negatively impact the participants mental&#xD;
      health and the relationship to the infant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Effective treatments are needed to address high global rates of postpartum depression (PPD)&#xD;
      with onset typically within 4 weeks after delivery and maternal depression up to two years&#xD;
      after delivery. Programs aimed at reducing PPD could achieve the most cost-efficient results&#xD;
      by focusing efforts in the critical time periods around childbirth. Web-based psychosocial&#xD;
      support provided by trained public health nurses is an effective treatment method for PPD.&#xD;
      Limited public health resources are challenges to the accessibility of mental health&#xD;
      services, which is why the use of web-based psychosocial support could be a good alternative.&#xD;
      Women perceive the risk for themselves or their infants to be above average during global&#xD;
      crises, which increases the levels of uncertainty. However, face-to-face consultations during&#xD;
      a pandemic are likely to increase the risk of disease transmission. Therefore, easily&#xD;
      accessible eHealth support could provide fast and resource-effective care during the COVID-19&#xD;
      pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will generate evidence on whether web-based early intervention programs could be&#xD;
      efficient in ameliorating the risk and severity of perinatal mental health disorders, and&#xD;
      inform best clinical practice for women affected by the consequences of the COVID-19&#xD;
      pandemic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Edinburgh Postnatal Depression Scale (EPDS)</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 weeks postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>To investigate the impact of a web-based psychosocial intervention on Edinburgh Postnatal Depression Scale (EPDS) in urban women living in Hong Kong and Shanghainese women.&#xD;
Scores of EPDS range from min = 0 to max=30. The higher the score, the more depressed a woman is.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mental health status and COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 weeks postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between mental health status (EPDS, GAD7, IES-R) and COVID-19 pandemic among pregnant women.&#xD;
GAD 7 Generalized anxiety questionnaire IES-R Impact Event Scale to assess Post traumatic stress Disorder (PTSD) COVID-19 questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Socio-economic status (education level, income, marital status, profession, nationality)</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 weeks postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Impact of web-based psychosocial intervention on mental health and pregnancy outcomes among women from different socio-economic and cultural environments.&#xD;
Socio-economic information gained by sociodemographic questions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Elective CS</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 weeks postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Relationship between mental health status of pregnant women and rates of elective cesarean section (CS) on maternal request.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Perinatal Depression</condition>
  <condition>COVID19</condition>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <condition>PTSD</condition>
  <condition>Pregnancy Related</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Web-based psychosocial peer-to-peer support</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Web-based psychosocial peer-to-peer support, using &quot;Thinking Healthy&quot; two times during pregnancy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard perinatal care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Perinatal standard care in Hong Kong, Shanghai</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Web-based psychosocial peer-to-peer support</intervention_name>
    <description>The evidence-based eHealth peer-to-peer psychosocial intervention &quot;Thinking Healthy&quot;, will be tested in this RCT. In line with the World Health Organization's mhGAP Intervention Guide (mhGAP-IG), &quot;Thinking Healthy&quot; is used to identify and manage perinatal mental health conditions (distress, symptoms of depression, and anxiety) in non-specialized psychosocial support setting.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard perinatal care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Web-based psychosocial peer-to-peer support</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women between 12 and 18 weeks of gestation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Viable intrauterine pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe psychiatric&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Substance abuse disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Requiring medical treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of fetal chromosomal/structural abnormality&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Simone E Schwank, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Karolinska Institute CLINTEC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ganesh Acharya, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Karolinska Institute CLINTEC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Simone E Schwank, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>‭+41796137255</phone>
    <email>simone.schwank@ki.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Ganesh Acharya, MD PhD</last_name>
    <phone>‭+46 70-099 63 35‬</phone>
    <email>ganesh.acharya@ki.se</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Shanghai Women's and Children's Health Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Shanghai</city>
        <state>Shanghai</state>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Liping Zhu, PhD</last_name>
      <email>shzhuliping@163.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <phone>0086 021-32576339</phone>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chinese University Hong Kong</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hong Kong</city>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hsuan-Ying Huang, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>‭+852 9137 8406‬</phone>
      <email>hsuan-ying.huang@cuhk.edu.hk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brand SR, Engel SM, Canfield RL, Yehuda R. The effect of maternal PTSD following in utero trauma exposure on behavior and temperament in the 9-month-old infant. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2006 Jul;1071:454-8.</citation>
    <PMID>16891597</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Buss C, Davis EP, Hobel CJ, Sandman CA. Maternal pregnancy-specific anxiety is associated with child executive function at 6-9 years age. Stress. 2011 Nov;14(6):665-76. doi: 10.3109/10253890.2011.623250.</citation>
    <PMID>21995526</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Doyle C, Werner E, Feng T, Lee S, Altemus M, Isler JR, Monk C. Pregnancy distress gets under fetal skin: Maternal ambulatory assessment &amp; sex differences in prenatal development. Dev Psychobiol. 2015 Jul;57(5):607-25. doi: 10.1002/dev.21317. Epub 2015 May 6.</citation>
    <PMID>25945698</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Liang H, Acharya G. Novel corona virus disease (COVID-19) in pregnancy: What clinical recommendations to follow? Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2020 Apr;99(4):439-442. doi: 10.1111/aogs.13836. Epub 2020 Mar 5.</citation>
    <PMID>32141062</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Thapa SB, Mainali A, Schwank SE, Acharya G. Maternal mental health in the time of the COVID-19 pandemic. Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2020 Jul;99(7):817-818. doi: 10.1111/aogs.13894.</citation>
    <PMID>32374420</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Monk C, Feng T, Lee S, Krupska I, Champagne FA, Tycko B. Distress During Pregnancy: Epigenetic Regulation of Placenta Glucocorticoid-Related Genes and Fetal Neurobehavior. Am J Psychiatry. 2016 Jul 1;173(7):705-13. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.2015.15091171. Epub 2016 Mar 25.</citation>
    <PMID>27013342</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brummelte S, Galea LA. Postpartum depression: Etiology, treatment and consequences for maternal care. Horm Behav. 2016 Jan;77:153-66. doi: 10.1016/j.yhbeh.2015.08.008. Epub 2015 Aug 28. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26319224</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 21, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 22, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 22, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 22, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Karolinska Institutet</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Simone Eliane</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

