<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1654">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04699227</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20/SC/0192</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04699227</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Can RIC Prevent Deterioration to Critical Care in Covid19</brief_title>
  <official_title>CAN REMOTE ISCHAEMIC CONDITIONING REDUCE INFLAMMATORY MARKERS IN COVID-19 PATIENTS - A MULTI-SITE, RANDOMISED PILOT STUDY</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Derek Yellon</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University College London Hospitals</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The coronavirus disease (COVID-19) emerged in late 2019 and has since been diagnosed in over&#xD;
      a million persons worldwide. As this virus progresses, it causes an extreme and uncontrolled&#xD;
      response from the patient's immune system accompanied by reduced oxygen flow to major organs,&#xD;
      and subsequent ischaemic injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current treatment of COVID-19 is largely supportive without any cure or vaccine available&#xD;
      at this time. Developing new methods to reduce this heightened inflammatory response is&#xD;
      essential to halting progression of COVID-19 in patients and reducing the severity of damage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The cellular mechanisms seen in COVID-19 are similar to those seen in patients with sepsis. A&#xD;
      process known as Remote Ischemic Conditioning (RIC) is an intervention which has been shown&#xD;
      to prevent cellular injury including those associated with sepsis. Based on the evidence from&#xD;
      studies looking at sepsis, it is anticipated the same benefit would be seen in patients&#xD;
      diagnosed with COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      RIC is a simple, non-invasive procedure where a blood pressure cuff is applied to the arm for&#xD;
      repeated cycles of inflating and deflating (typically 3-5 cycles of 5 minutes each). This&#xD;
      process activates pro-survival mechanisms in the body to protect vital organs and improve the&#xD;
      immune system. Therefore, we believe it represents an exciting strategy to protect organs&#xD;
      against reduced blood flow and extreme immune response, as seen in COVID-19 infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study has already been fully approved&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      COVID-19 has an early phase and a late, with rapid progression to ARDS (due to cytokine&#xD;
      storm), multi-organ failure and death. Suppressing these cytokine elevations maybe a key to&#xD;
      improved outcomes. Acute and Chronic (repeated) RIC has been shown to benefit in reducing the&#xD;
      levels cytokines following LPS-induced sepsis in animal models (1). Furthermore, mortality&#xD;
      was significantly reduced, following chronic RIC administration as opposed to acute RIC&#xD;
      administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      RIC in COVID-19 patients is a pilot, multi-centre, randomised study, designed to ascertain&#xD;
      whether RIC decreases the severity of inflammatory markers associated with a &quot;storm&quot; score.&#xD;
&#xD;
      20 adult patients admitted to either The Royal Free or The Lister Hospital (Stevenage) with&#xD;
      diagnosed COVID-19 will be enrolled into the study, of confirmed but not critical status.&#xD;
      After enrolment, patients will be randomised (n = 10 per group) 1:1 to receive RIC or no&#xD;
      adjunctive intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      RIC will consist of 3-4 cycles of cuff inflations to 200 mmHg for 5 min with deflation to 0&#xD;
      mmHg for another 5 min, which is automatically administered by the pre-programmed cuff. Those&#xD;
      randomised to the control group will have the blood pressure cuff placed on the arm, but it&#xD;
      will not be inflated. RIC will be performed daily for 15 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Venous blood will be collected following RIC administration (where possible) and saved for&#xD;
      the subsequent measurement of inflammatory markers such as TNF, IL-1β, IL-6, and HMGB1 in&#xD;
      addition to cardiac biomarkers Troponin T and NT pro terminal BNP. All biomarker analysis&#xD;
      will occur at The Hatter Cardiovascular Institute, UCL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The endpoint is area under the curve of inflammatory markers and cardiac biomarkers.&#xD;
      Secondary endpoint will be the need for intensive care admission or death.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It would be our intention to use autoRIC devices (CellAegis, Canada) to ascertain whether RIC&#xD;
      can lower the cytokine response. These devices are specifically designed, blood-pressure&#xD;
      cuffs pre-programmed for the number of uses required by each patient; the intent being &quot;a&#xD;
      single patient-multiple use&quot; cuff.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 23, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary Endpoint</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome is to demonstrate that remote ischaemic conditioning reduces the severity of inflammatory cytokine release which are responsible for the cytokine &quot;storm&quot; that occurs in following COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
The endpoint is area under the curve of inflammatory markers and cardiac biomarkers.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary Endpoint</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Secondary endpoint will be the need for intensive care admission or death.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Ischemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group not receiving RIC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Those randomised to the control group will have the blood pressure cuff placed on the arm, but it will not be inflated.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Interventional group receiving RIC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>RIC will consist of 3-4 cycles of cuff inflations to 200 mmHg for 5 min with deflation to 0 mmHg for another 5 min, which is automatically administered by the pre-programmed cuff.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cuff application with inflation</intervention_name>
    <description>The blood pressure cuff will be placed on the arm and inflated.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Interventional group receiving RIC</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sham inflation</intervention_name>
    <description>The blood pressure cuff will be placed on the arm and not inflated.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group not receiving RIC</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Adult patients (aged 18 - 80 yrs) with diagnosed COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication for the use of a brachial cuff on either arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intercurrent disease with an expected life expectancy of less than 24 h, cardiac&#xD;
             arrest, - Pregnant or breastfeeding women.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bleeding disorder or platelet count below 50.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently enrolled in another research study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Free London NHS Foundation Trust,</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>NW3 2QG</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alan Salama, MBBS PhD</last_name>
      <phone>020 7794 0500</phone>
      <email>alan.salama@nhs.net</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alan Salama, MBBS PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>East and North Hertfordshire NHS TrusEast and North Hertfordshire NHS Trus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stevenage</city>
        <zip>SG1 4AB</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Diana A Gorog, MB BS MD PhD</last_name>
      <phone>01707247512</phone>
      <email>d.gorog@nhs.net</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Diana A Gorog, MB BS MD PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 6, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University College London Hospitals</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Derek Yellon</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Covid19</keyword>
  <keyword>Ischemia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>No identifiable, personal data will be collected as part of this study.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

