<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4800">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04586309</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2008969193</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04586309</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Improving the Mental Health of Resident Physicians and Fellows Through Transcendental Meditation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Improving the Mental Health of Resident Physicians and Fellows : Reducing Burnout &amp; Enhancing Resilience Through Transcendental Meditation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Arizona</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>David Lynch Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Tucson Transcendental Meditation Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Arizona</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This proposal aims to optimize resident physician and fellow wellness and performance at&#xD;
      Banner University Medical Center through an evidence-based stress reduction program,&#xD;
      Transcendental Meditation (TM). It is particularly timely due to the enormous pressure and&#xD;
      stress that residents face as front-line workers during the current 2019 novel coronavirus&#xD;
      (COVID-19) pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be randomly assigned to the TM training (group 1), or delayed TM training&#xD;
      (group 2). Study outcomes will be assessed at baseline and at 1 and 3 months post-training.&#xD;
      Participants who are assigned to group 2 , will receive the TM training following the three&#xD;
      month assessment, and then complete assessments at 1 and 3 months post-training.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These assessment tools look at anxiety (Generalized Anxiety Disorder Scale-GAD-7), depression&#xD;
      (Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ-9), insomnia (Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index PSQI),&#xD;
      psychological distress (Brief Symptom Inventory BSI18), burnout (Maslach Burnout&#xD;
      Inventory-MBI), resilience (Conner-Davidson Resilience Scale- RISC), and alcohol use (Alcohol&#xD;
      Use Disorder Identification Test - AUDIT).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Up to one hundred resident and fellow physicians employed by Banner Health will participate&#xD;
      in the project. Participants will be randomly assigned to either the TM program or to a&#xD;
      delayed TM training, treatment-as-usual control group . Study outcomes will be assessed at&#xD;
      baseline, 1-month and 3-month post-training , with change in burnout as the primary outcome.&#xD;
      Control subjects (aka delayed TM training or Group 2) will be eligible to learn TM after&#xD;
      completing 3 month post-testing. Group 2 will also complete post-training assessments at&#xD;
      1-month and 3-months post-training. The total duration of this project will be 60 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two experienced certified TM instructors will conduct the instruction. All certified TM&#xD;
      teachers have been extensively trained in the teaching of the TM program, including teaching&#xD;
      the course of instruction, verifying continued correctness of effortless practice of the&#xD;
      technique, and conducting additional follow-up sessions. The same standardized TM course&#xD;
      sequence will be used for all study participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outline of Transcendental Meditation Program: TM group will involve 10 total sessions over 12&#xD;
      weeks (about 75 minutes per session). The core instruction in the TM technique will involve a&#xD;
      course of instruction, taught over five sessions. The five core instruction sessions will&#xD;
      include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Introductory session-Review of previous scientific research on the TM program and a&#xD;
           vision of possible benefits; Preparation- discussion of the mechanics and origin of the&#xD;
           TM technique(75 minutes- group session); After the introductory session, a Personal&#xD;
           Interview is conducted telephonically-with a teacher of the TM program. The participant&#xD;
           completes a brief interview form prior to the call. The interviewer (a teacher with the&#xD;
           TM program) reviews the form with the participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
           The four classes of TM instruction adhere to a standardized teaching protocol and are&#xD;
           conducted by certified teachers of the Transcendental Meditation program trained and&#xD;
           approved by the Transcendental Meditation organization.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Personal Instruction-individual one-on-one instruction in the TM technique (75 minutes).&#xD;
           The student learns the mechanics of the TM technique. At the conclusion of this class&#xD;
           the student is able to meditate properly.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. First Day of Verification of Correct Practice and Further Instruction (90 minutes-group&#xD;
           session); The first follow-up session provides information to help students incorporate&#xD;
           TM into their daily life.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Second Day of Verification of Correct Practice-understanding the mechanics of the TM&#xD;
           technique from personal experiences (90 minutes-group session); The second session&#xD;
           provides information about how the meditation reduces stress and improves health&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Third Day of Verification of Correct Practice-understanding the mechanics of the&#xD;
           development of higher human potential and wellness (90 minutes-group session). The third&#xD;
           session reviews students' experiences both during and after meditation, and provides&#xD;
           further instruction to support their ongoing home practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following the initial phase of the intervention (5 sessions), there will be 5 additional&#xD;
      group sessions of 45-60minutes each provided once a month for the remainder of the 6-month&#xD;
      intervention period. These sessions will include: a) discussion of personal experiences and&#xD;
      verification of correctness of practice of the TM technique, and b) knowledge of the human&#xD;
      potential and its relationship to mental and physical health.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Compliance with treatment sessions will be defined as attending at least 70% of the treatment&#xD;
      sessions. Subjects randomized to the TM group will continue with their usual care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      No research data is collected during the sessions described above.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although it is the intent for all of these sessions to be conducted at the Tucson&#xD;
      Transcendental Meditation Center, in small physically distanced groups of participants&#xD;
      wearing whatever level of personal protective equipment is being recommended by the CD at the&#xD;
      time of the session, in the event that in person sessions are not possible, the group&#xD;
      sessions will be held virtually through Zoom video conferencing. Additionally, participants&#xD;
      may be able to complete sessions 3-5 over the TM App (a series of pre-recorded lectures).&#xD;
&#xD;
      For participants who choose to use the TM App, they will be asked to create an account&#xD;
      through the app, and will be given the opportunity to review the Terms of Service and Privacy&#xD;
      Policies. Maharishi Foundation International (the owners/developers of the App) monitor the&#xD;
      participants progress through the digital content so that they know when to release the next&#xD;
      session (as described above). Participants can also use the App to time their meditation&#xD;
      sessions, although this is not required.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Home Practice: Home practice will consist of two 20-minute TM sessions daily - morning and&#xD;
      evening. Compliance with TM practice will be defined as meditating at least once a day.&#xD;
      Participants will complete a home practice questionnaire at 1 month and 3 months (attached as&#xD;
      an addendum-will be included in the REDCap bundle with assessments).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Delayed TM training/Control Condition: Subjects randomized to the control group will continue&#xD;
      with their usual care. Control subjects will be invited to learn the TM program after 3-month&#xD;
      post-training assessment. If they chose to complete the TM training, they will be subject to&#xD;
      the same training as Group 1, and the same assessments after the end of their training.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants will be randomly assigned to the TM training (group 1), or delayed TM training (group 2). Study outcomes will be assessed at baseline and at 1 and 3 months post-training. Participants who are assigned to group 2 , will receive the TM training following the three month assessment, and then complete assessments at 1 and 3 months post-training.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Burnout</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Maslach Burnout Inventory- Participants respond to each prompt 0-6, high score in first 2 sections, low score in third may indicate risk of burnout.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Burnout</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Maslach Burnout Inventory- Participants respond to each prompt 0-6, high score in first 2 sections, low score in third may indicate risk of burnout.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Burnout</measure>
    <time_frame>3 month</time_frame>
    <description>Maslach Burnout Inventory- Participants respond to each prompt 0-6, high score in first 2 sections, low score in third may indicate risk of burnout.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resilience</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale- Participants respond to each prompt 0-5 x 25 items, low score indicates poor resilience.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resilience</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale- Participants respond to each prompt 0-5 x 25 items, low score indicates poor resilience.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resilience</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale- Participants respond to each prompt 0-5 x 25 items, low score indicates poor resilience.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Alcohol use</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>AUDIT: Alcohol Use Disorders Identification Test- Participants respond to 10 items with 0-4, higher score more concerning for alcohol use disorder.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Alcohol use</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>AUDIT: Alcohol Use Disorders Identification Test- Participants respond to 10 items with 0-4, higher score more concerning for alcohol use disorder.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Alcohol use</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>AUDIT: Alcohol Use Disorders Identification Test- Participants respond to 10 items with 0-4, higher score more concerning for alcohol use disorder.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Depression</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>PHQ-9: Patient Health Questionnaire- Participants answer each prompt (not all all, some days, most days, nearly every day) higher numbers indicate greater depressive symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Depression</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>PHQ-9: Patient Health Questionnaire- Participants answer each prompt (not all all, some days, most days, nearly every day) higher numbers indicate greater depressive symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Depression</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>PHQ-9: Patient Health Questionnaire- Participants answer each prompt (not all all, some days, most days, nearly every day) higher numbers indicate greater depressive symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep Quality</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>PSQI: Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index- Participant answers 19 questions in 7 sections, Seven sections are combined for global score of 0-21 where ) is no problems and 21 is problems in all areas.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep Quality</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>PSQI: Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index- Participant answers 19 questions in 7 sections, Seven sections are combined for global score of 0-21 where ) is no problems and 21 is problems in all areas.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep Quality</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>PSQI: Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index- Participant answers 19 questions in 7 sections, Seven sections are combined for global score of 0-21 where ) is no problems and 21 is problems in all areas.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Distress</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>BSI18: Brief Symptom Inventory 18- Participants answer 18 questions on 0-4 scale. Higher numbers indicate more distress.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Distress</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>BSI18: Brief Symptom Inventory 18</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Distress</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>BSI18: Brief Symptom Inventory 18</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>GAD7: Generalized Anxiety Disorder 7- Participants answer 7 questions 0-3. Higher scores indicate greater anxiety,</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>GAD7: Generalized Anxiety Disorder 7- Participants answer 7 questions 0-3. Higher scores indicate greater anxiety,</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>GAD7: Generalized Anxiety Disorder 7- Participants answer 7 questions 0-3. Higher scores indicate greater anxiety,</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Burnout, Professional</condition>
  <condition>Stress, Psychological</condition>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <condition>Job Stress</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Early TM Training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group will receive training in Transcendental Meditation and will complete assessments at baseline, 1 month and 3 months.(3 assessments in total).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Delayed TM training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm will complete the baseline, 1 month and 3 month assessments and then will receive the TM training, followed by additional 1 month and 3 month post-training assessments (5 in total)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Transcendental meditation</intervention_name>
    <description>Instruction in the TM technique is taught over five sessions.&#xD;
Introductory session-Review of previous scientific research on the TM program and a vision of possible benefits; Preparation- discussion of the mechanics and origin of the TM technique After the introductory session, a Personal Interview is conducted telephonically-with a teacher of the TM program.&#xD;
Personal Instruction-individual one-on-one instruction in the TM technique. The student learns the mechanics of the TM technique. At the conclusion of this class the student is able to meditate properly.&#xD;
First Day of Verification of Correct Practice and Further Instruction.&#xD;
Second Day of Verification of Correct Practice-understanding the mechanics of the TM technique from personal experiences.&#xD;
Third Day of Verification of Correct Practice-understanding the mechanics of the development of higher human potential and wellness.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Delayed TM training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Early TM Training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Full-time Resident physicians or Fellows employed by Banner Health&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Some participants included will have treated COVID-19 patients or be working at&#xD;
             locations where COVID-19 patients are being treated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Willing to take part in either group assignment (randomized to either immediate start&#xD;
             or TM training, or delayed TM training)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Willing to complete baseline, 1-month and 3-month post- assessments&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. If being treated with psychoactive medications, the maintenance of a stable regimen&#xD;
             for at least two months before enrollment (by self-report).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Already instructed in the Transcendental Meditation technique&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Currently unstable psychotic symptoms, mania or bipolar disorder as demonstrated by&#xD;
             self-report, or psychiatric hospitalizations in the past six months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Current suicidal or homicidal ideation with intent or plan.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rachel E M Cramton, MD</last_name>
    <phone>14013459729</phone>
    <email>rcramton@peds.arizona.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Alison Sutton-Ryan, LCSW</last_name>
    <email>asuttonryan@email.arizona.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <link>
    <url>http://healthehealersnow.org</url>
    <description>Information from David Lynch Foundation regarding grant</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://TM.org</url>
    <description>Information about transcendental meditation and other TM research</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lai J, Ma S, Wang Y, Cai Z, Hu J, Wei N, Wu J, Du H, Chen T, Li R, Tan H, Kang L, Yao L, Huang M, Wang H, Wang G, Liu Z, Hu S. Factors Associated With Mental Health Outcomes Among Health Care Workers Exposed to Coronavirus Disease 2019. JAMA Netw Open. 2020 Mar 2;3(3):e203976. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.3976.</citation>
    <PMID>32202646</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Valosek L, Link J, Mills P, Konrad A, Rainforth M, Nidich S. Effect of Meditation on Emotional Intelligence and Perceived Stress in the Workplace: A Randomized Controlled Study. Perm J. 2018;22:17-172. Published 2018 Oct 29. doi:10.7812/TPP/17-172</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 13, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 13, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>transcendental meditation</keyword>
  <keyword>resilience</keyword>
  <keyword>burnout</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Occupational Stress</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Burnout, Professional</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Burnout, Psychological</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stress, Psychological</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

