<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4205">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04678843</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>12722</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04678843</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Adapting and Adopting Highly Specialized Pediatric Eating Disorder Treatment to Virtual Care: Implementation Research for the COVID-19 Context and Beyond</brief_title>
  <acronym>vFBT</acronym>
  <official_title>Adapting and Adopting Highly Specialized Pediatric Eating Disorder Treatment to Virtual Care: Implementation Research for the COVID-19 Context and Beyond</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Jennifer Couturier</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>McMaster University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The COVID-19 pandemic has had detrimental effects on mental health. Individuals with eating&#xD;
      disorders (EDs) are no exception, exhibiting increased symptoms and exacerbated feelings of&#xD;
      isolation and anxiety. Across Canada, in-person outpatient services have been quickly&#xD;
      replaced with virtual care, yet practitioners and patients have noted substantial challenges&#xD;
      in adapting ED-related care virtually. Given the success of our previous research on&#xD;
      Family-Based Treatment (FBT) for EDs, as well as the rapid transition to virtual care during&#xD;
      COVID-19, there is an urgent need to adapt FBT to virtual formats and adopt it in the ED&#xD;
      network. Using a multi-site case study with a mixed method pre/post design, this study aims&#xD;
      to examine the implementation of virtual FBT (vFBT) as well as its impact within six ED&#xD;
      programs in Ontario, building on the investigator's previous work, and further developing&#xD;
      capacity in the system. The investigator will develop implementation teams at each site and&#xD;
      provide a virtual training workshop on vFBT, with ongoing consultation during initial&#xD;
      implementation. The investigator proposes to examine implementation success by studying&#xD;
      fidelity to vFBT, as well as team and patient/family experience with virtual care, and&#xD;
      patient outcomes. These findings for virtual care will not only be important in the COVID-19&#xD;
      context but are also vital in the North, where access to specialized services is extremely&#xD;
      limited.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Key components of FBT</measure>
    <time_frame>Completed after session 4 of treatment, approximately 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by a self-report questionnaire entitled Key Measure of Therapist Behaviours and Self-Efficacy in FBT (an indicator of therapist adherence to the key components of standard FBT within the vFBT model)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fidelity</measure>
    <time_frame>Completed after the session 4 of treatment, approximately 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Fidelity to vFBT, measured by FBT fidelity ratings of the first four sessions of vFBT using the FBT Fidelity and Adherence Check (experts in FBT fidelity rating will rate the recordings).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Qualitative experience of participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Completed after session 4 of treatment, approximately 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Experiences of the therapists, medical practitioners, administrators, and families in vFBT, qualitatively measured during semi-structured focus groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Weight</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline before treatment, and at 1 week, 2 weeks, 3 weeks, and 4 weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>Weight will be measured in kilograms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Number of Binge/Purge Episodes</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline before treatment, and at 1 week, 2 weeks, 3 weeks, and 4 weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>The number of binge/purge episodes each week will be recorded by patients/their families.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Therapists' Change in Readiness</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline, after training (approx. 1 month), and after 4 sessions of treatment (approx. 4 months)</time_frame>
    <description>The Brief Individual Readiness to Change Scale will indicate how ready therapists feel they are to change. Higher scores indicate greater readiness to use research-based direct service techniques. Minimum score is 0, maximum score is 20.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Therapists' Change in Attitudes about Evidence Based Practice</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline, after training (approx. 1 month), and after 4 sessions of treatment (approx. 4 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Their attitudes about evidence-based practice will be assessed using the Evidence Based Practice Attitudes Scale (EBPAS). The subscales include requirements, appeal, openness and divergence. The score for each subscale is created by computing a mean score for the items that load on a given subscale. Minimum score for each subscale is 0, maximum score for each subscale is 4.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Therapists' Change in Confidence related to the Intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline, after training (approx. 1 month), and after 4 sessions of treatment (approx. 4 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Their confidence related to the intervention will be assessed by administering an adapted version of the Perceived Attributes of the Principles of Effectiveness Scale (MPAS). Higher scores are indicative of more favorable perception for adoption of the Family-Based Treatment model. The minimum score is 18, the maximum score is 90.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Anorexia Nervosa</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Virtual Family-Based Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Family-based treatment is the gold standard treatment for youth and adolescents with anorexia nervosa. A therapist works with the family to help parents take charge of the process of re-feeding their child, and with progress this control is gradually given back to the youth/adolescent. Other developmental issues are discussed in order to help the youth/adolescent get back to normal development.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Virtual Family-Based Treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>Treatment involving the youth/adolescent who has been diagnosed with anorexia nervosa and their family, delivered virtually via videoconferencing.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Virtual Family-Based Treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Youth must be under 18 years of age in order to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Youth must have a diagnosis of Anorexia Nervosa in order to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have the capacity to write, speak, and understand English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have access to a computer and the internet.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals 18 years of age and older are unable to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Youth without a diagnosis of Anorexia Nervosa are unable to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who cannot write, speak and understand English are unable to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who do not have access to a computer and the internet are unable to&#xD;
             participate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jennifer Couturier, MD MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>McMaster University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Danielle Pellegrini, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>2898804149</phone>
    <email>pellegdm@mcmaster.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Laura Grennan, BSc</last_name>
    <phone>9052203995</phone>
    <email>grennanl@mcmaster.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 18, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 18, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 22, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>McMaster University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jennifer Couturier</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>anorexia nervosa</keyword>
  <keyword>youth</keyword>
  <keyword>adolescents</keyword>
  <keyword>eating disorders</keyword>
  <keyword>family-based treatment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anorexia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Feeding and Eating Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anorexia Nervosa</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

