<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3338">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04663555</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CZECRIN No. 2020/47</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-005887-70</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04663555</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Two Different Doses of Dexamethasone in Patients With ARDS and COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>REMED</acronym>
  <official_title>Effect of Dexamethasone in Patients With ARDS and COVID-19 - Prospective, Multi-centre, Open-label, Parallel-group, Randomized Controlled Trial (REMED Trial)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Brno University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Masaryk University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital Královské Vinohrady Prague</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>General University Hospital in Prague</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital Ostrava</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>St. Anne's University Hospital Brno</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital Motol Prague</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital Olomouc</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital Plzeň</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Tomáš Baťa Regional Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Military University Hospital Praha</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Brno University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      REMED is a prospective, phase II, open-label, randomised controlled trial testing superiority&#xD;
      of dexamethasone 20 mg vs 6 mg. The trial aims to be pragmatic, i.e. designed to evaluate the&#xD;
      effectiveness of the intervention in conditions that are close to real-life routine clinical&#xD;
      practice. The study is multi-centre and will be conducted in the intensive care units (ICUs)&#xD;
      of ten university hospitals in the Czech Republic. This is an open-label trial in which the&#xD;
      participants and the study staff will be aware of the allocated intervention. Blinded&#xD;
      pre-planned statistical analysis will be performed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Since December 2019, Covid-19 virus has infected millions of people worldwide. A significant&#xD;
      number of patients develop hyperinflammatory state affecting lungs, which may lead to the&#xD;
      need of oxygen therapy. In most severe cases, acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS)&#xD;
      develops and high flow oxygen therapy or invasive mechanical ventilation is necessary (Wu et&#xD;
      al., 2020). Therapeutic options in Covid-19 associated ARDS patients remain limited and&#xD;
      mortality is still excessive. Systemic corticosteroids have potential to limit&#xD;
      hyperinflammatory response by modulating immune system. This effect is mediated mainly by&#xD;
      binding to glucocorticosteroid receptor α (GRα)(Meduri et al., 2020). Their effectiveness was&#xD;
      proved in heterogeneous ARDS patients recently (Villar et al., 2020). In patients with&#xD;
      Covid-19 pneumonia in need for oxygen therapy or mechanical ventilation, dexamethasone 6 mg&#xD;
      per day is currently recommended. This therapy is mandated by the results of RECOVERY trial&#xD;
      (Horby et al., 2020). After this trial was published, three randomised trials comparing&#xD;
      hydrocortisone (Angus et al., 2020; Dequin et al., 2020) or dexamethasone (Tomazini et al.,&#xD;
      2020) against placebo were stopped prematurely. All these studies were included in the&#xD;
      subsequent IPD metaanalysis (Sterne et al., 2020). However, dose of 6 mg of dexamethasone is&#xD;
      currently being reappraised. The aforementioned study in non Covid-19 ARDS patients (Villar&#xD;
      et al., 2020) used 20 mg of dexamethasone per day, which is roughly equivalent to the&#xD;
      methylprednisolone regimen (1mg/kg/day) studied in early severe ARDS patients (Meduri et al.,&#xD;
      2007). Only these moderate doses (80-100 mg of methylprednisolone, equivalent to 15-19 mg of&#xD;
      dexamethasone) have full potential to modulate immune response by saturating GRα receptors&#xD;
      (Meduri et al., 2020). Importantly, prematurely stopped CoDEX trial (Tomazini et al., 2020)&#xD;
      comparing dexamethasone against placebo in Covid-ARDS patients, used initial daily dose of 20&#xD;
      mg of dexamethasone versus placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the light of these facts, 6 mg of dexamethasone given to COVID-19 patients with different&#xD;
      severity of illness (WHO classification group 5-10) may miss important therapeutic potential&#xD;
      or may prevent a potential deleterious effects of a full dose therapeutic corticosteroid.&#xD;
      Authors hypothesize that the patients with moderate to severe ARDS undergoing mechanical&#xD;
      ventilation may benefit from higher doses of dexamethasone (Villar et al., 2020; Tomazini et&#xD;
      al., 2020; Meduri et al., 2007).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective of this study is to test the hypothesis that administration of&#xD;
      dexamethasone 20 mg is superior over 6 mg in adult patients with moderate or severe ARDS due&#xD;
      to confirmed COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary endpoint: Number of ventilator-free days (VFDs) at 28 days after randomisation,&#xD;
      defined as being alive and free from mechanical ventilation (more than 48 hours).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Mortality from any cause at 60 days after randomization;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Dynamics of inflammatory marker (CRP) change from Day 1 to Day 14;&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. WHO Clinical Progression Scale at Day 14 (range 0-10; 0 = no illness, 1-9 = increasing&#xD;
           level of care, and 10 = death);&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Adverse events related to corticosteroids (new infections, new thrombotic complications)&#xD;
           until Day 28 or hospital discharge;&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Independence at 90 days after randomization assessed by Barthel Index The long-term&#xD;
           outcomes of this study are to assess long-term consequences on mortality and quality of&#xD;
           life at 180 and 360 days through telephone structured interview using Barthel Index.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 2, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>REMED is a prospective phase II open-label randomized controlled trial testing superiority of dexamethasone 20 mg vs 6 mg. The study is multi-centre and will be conducted in intensive care units (ICUs) of university hospitals in the Czech Republic. The trial aims to be pragmatic, i.e. designed to evaluate the effectiveness of the intervention in conditions that are very close to the real-life routine clinical practice. Dexamethasone will be administered once daily intravenously for 10 days. 300 participants will be enrolled and followed up for 360 days after randomization.&#xD;
Following stratification factors will be applied:&#xD;
Age &lt; 65 and ≥ 65 (12);&#xD;
Charlson Comorbidity index (CCI; APPENDIX B Assessment tools, scores, and scales, Chapter 14.2) &lt; 3 and ≥ 3;&#xD;
CRP &lt; 150 mg/L and ≥ 150 mg/L&#xD;
Trial centre. Patients will be randomized in 1 : 1 ratio in one of the two treatment arms. Randomization through eCRF will be available 24 hours every day.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of ventilator-free days (VFDs) at 28 days after randomization</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of ventilator-free days (VFDs) at 28 days after randomisation, defined as being alive and free from mechanical ventilation (more than 48 hours)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality from any cause at 60 days after randomization</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>WHO clinical progression scale at day 14</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>WHO clinical progression scale (range, 0-10, where 0 = no illness, 1-9 = increasing level of care, and 10 = death) (WHO Working Group on the Clinical Characterisation and Management of COVID-19 infection, 2020) assessed at day 14</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dynamics of inflammatory marker</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Dynamics of inflammatory marker (CRP) change from Day 1 to Day 14</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events related to corticosteroids</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>new infections, new thrombotic complications</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional independence</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Independence at 90 days after randomization assessed by Barthel Index</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Long-term outcome regarding mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>180 and 360 days</time_frame>
    <description>Death from any cause at 180 and 360 days</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Long-term outcome regarding functional independence</measure>
    <time_frame>180 and 360 days</time_frame>
    <description>Functional independence at 180 and 360 days assesed through telephone structured interview using Barthel Index.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>ARDS</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>DEX 20 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in the intervention group after randomization will receive dexamethasone 20 mg intravenously once daily on day 1-5, followed by dexamethasone 10 mg intravenously once daily on day 6-10.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>DEX 6 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in the control group after randomization will receive dexamethasone 6 mg day 1-10.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexamethasone</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients in the intervention group after randomization will receive dexamethasone 20 mg intravenously once daily on day 1-5, followed by dexamethasone 10 mg intravenously once daily on day 6-10. If successful extubation occurs before day 10, treatment with dexamethasone is withdrawn.</description>
    <arm_group_label>DEX 20 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>DEX 6 mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects will be eligible for the trial if they meet all of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adult (≥ 18 years of age) at time of enrolment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Present COVID-19 (infection confirmed by RT-PCR or antigen testing);&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Intubation/mechanical ventilation or ongoing high-flow nasal cannula (HFNC) oxygen&#xD;
             therapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Moderate or severe ARDS according to Berlin criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Moderate - PaO2/FiO2 100-200 mmHg;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Severe - PaO2/FiO2 &lt; 100 mmHg;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Admission to ICU in the last 24 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects will not be eligible for the trial if they meet any of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Known allergy/hypersensitivity to dexamethasone or excipients of the investigational&#xD;
             medicinal product (e.g. parabens, benzyl alcohol);&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Fulfilled criteria for ARDS for ≥ 14 days at enrolment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pregnancy or breastfeeding;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Unwillingness to comply with contraception measurements from the enrolment to at least&#xD;
             1 week after the last dose of dexamethasone (sexual abstinence is considered as the&#xD;
             adequate contraception method);&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. End-of-life decision or patient is expected to die within next 24 hours;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Decision not to intubate or ceilings of treatment in place;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Immunosuppression and/or immunosuppressive drugs in medical history:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Systemic immunosuppressive drugs or chemotherapy in the past 30 days;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Systemic corticosteroids use before hospitalization;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Any dose of dexamethasone during the present hospital stay for COVID-19 for more&#xD;
                  than (≥) last 5 days before enrolment;&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Systemic corticosteroids during present hospital stay for other conditions than&#xD;
                  COVID-19 (e.g. septic shock);&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Present haematological or generalized solid malignancy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Any of contraindications of corticosteroids, e.g.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  intractable hyperglycaemia;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  active gastrointestinal bleeding;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  adrenal gland disorders;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  a presence of superinfection diagnosed with locally established clinical and&#xD;
                  laboratory criteria without adequate antimicrobial treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Cardiac arrest before ICU admission;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Participation in another interventional trial in the last 30 days.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jan Maláska, MD, PhD, EDIC</last_name>
    <phone>+420723784101</phone>
    <email>jan.malaska@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Jan Stašek, MD, PhD, EDIC</last_name>
    <phone>+420532232009</phone>
    <email>janstasek@centrum.cz</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Brno</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brno</city>
        <zip>62500</zip>
        <country>Czechia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jan Maláska, MD, PhD, EDIC</last_name>
      <phone>+420723784101</phone>
      <email>jan.malaska@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Jan Stašek, MD, EDIC</last_name>
      <phone>+420532232009</phone>
      <email>janstasek@centrum.cz</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Czechia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu C, Chen X, Cai Y, Xia J, Zhou X, Xu S, Huang H, Zhang L, Zhou X, Du C, Zhang Y, Song J, Wang S, Chao Y, Yang Z, Xu J, Zhou X, Chen D, Xiong W, Xu L, Zhou F, Jiang J, Bai C, Zheng J, Song Y. Risk Factors Associated With Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome and Death in Patients With Coronavirus Disease 2019 Pneumonia in Wuhan, China. JAMA Intern Med. 2020 Jul 1;180(7):934-943. doi: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2020.0994. Erratum in: JAMA Intern Med. 2020 Jul 1;180(7):1031.</citation>
    <PMID>32167524</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Meduri GU, Annane D, Confalonieri M, Chrousos GP, Rochwerg B, Busby A, Ruaro B, Meibohm B. Pharmacological principles guiding prolonged glucocorticoid treatment in ARDS. Intensive Care Med. 2020 Dec;46(12):2284-2296. doi: 10.1007/s00134-020-06289-8. Epub 2020 Nov 4. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>33150472</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Villar J, Ferrando C, Martínez D, Ambrós A, Muñoz T, Soler JA, Aguilar G, Alba F, González-Higueras E, Conesa LA, Martín-Rodríguez C, Díaz-Domínguez FJ, Serna-Grande P, Rivas R, Ferreres J, Belda J, Capilla L, Tallet A, Añón JM, Fernández RL, González-Martín JM; dexamethasone in ARDS network. Dexamethasone treatment for the acute respiratory distress syndrome: a multicentre, randomised controlled trial. Lancet Respir Med. 2020 Mar;8(3):267-276. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(19)30417-5. Epub 2020 Feb 7.</citation>
    <PMID>32043986</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>RECOVERY Collaborative Group, Horby P, Lim WS, Emberson JR, Mafham M, Bell JL, Linsell L, Staplin N, Brightling C, Ustianowski A, Elmahi E, Prudon B, Green C, Felton T, Chadwick D, Rege K, Fegan C, Chappell LC, Faust SN, Jaki T, Jeffery K, Montgomery A, Rowan K, Juszczak E, Baillie JK, Haynes R, Landray MJ. Dexamethasone in Hospitalized Patients with Covid-19 - Preliminary Report. N Engl J Med. 2020 Jul 17. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2021436. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>32678530</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Angus DC, Derde L, Al-Beidh F, Annane D, Arabi Y, Beane A, van Bentum-Puijk W, Berry L, Bhimani Z, Bonten M, Bradbury C, Brunkhorst F, Buxton M, Buzgau A, Cheng AC, de Jong M, Detry M, Estcourt L, Fitzgerald M, Goossens H, Green C, Haniffa R, Higgins AM, Horvat C, Hullegie SJ, Kruger P, Lamontagne F, Lawler PR, Linstrum K, Litton E, Lorenzi E, Marshall J, McAuley D, McGlothin A, McGuinness S, McVerry B, Montgomery S, Mouncey P, Murthy S, Nichol A, Parke R, Parker J, Rowan K, Sanil A, Santos M, Saunders C, Seymour C, Turner A, van de Veerdonk F, Venkatesh B, Zarychanski R, Berry S, Lewis RJ, McArthur C, Webb SA, Gordon AC; Writing Committee for the REMAP-CAP Investigators, Al-Beidh F, Angus D, Annane D, Arabi Y, van Bentum-Puijk W, Berry S, Beane A, Bhimani Z, Bonten M, Bradbury C, Brunkhorst F, Buxton M, Cheng A, De Jong M, Derde L, Estcourt L, Goossens H, Gordon A, Green C, Haniffa R, Lamontagne F, Lawler P, Litton E, Marshall J, McArthur C, McAuley D, McGuinness S, McVerry B, Montgomery S, Mouncey P, Murthy S, Nichol A, Parke R, Rowan K, Seymour C, Turner A, van de Veerdonk F, Webb S, Zarychanski R, Campbell L, Forbes A, Gattas D, Heritier S, Higgins L, Kruger P, Peake S, Presneill J, Seppelt I, Trapani T, Young P, Bagshaw S, Daneman N, Ferguson N, Misak C, Santos M, Hullegie S, Pletz M, Rohde G, Rowan K, Alexander B, Basile K, Girard T, Horvat C, Huang D, Linstrum K, Vates J, Beasley R, Fowler R, McGloughlin S, Morpeth S, Paterson D, Venkatesh B, Uyeki T, Baillie K, Duffy E, Fowler R, Hills T, Orr K, Patanwala A, Tong S, Netea M, Bihari S, Carrier M, Fergusson D, Goligher E, Haidar G, Hunt B, Kumar A, Laffan M, Lawless P, Lother S, McCallum P, Middeldopr S, McQuilten Z, Neal M, Pasi J, Schutgens R, Stanworth S, Turgeon A, Weissman A, Adhikari N, Anstey M, Brant E, de Man A, Lamonagne F, Masse MH, Udy A, Arnold D, Begin P, Charlewood R, Chasse M, Coyne M, Cooper J, Daly J, Gosbell I, Harvala-Simmonds H, Hills T, MacLennan S, Menon D, McDyer J, Pridee N, Roberts D, Shankar-Hari M, Thomas H, Tinmouth A, Triulzi D, Walsh T, Wood E, Calfee C, O'Kane C, Shyamsundar M, Sinha P, Thompson T, Young I, Bihari S, Hodgson C, Laffey J, McAuley D, Orford N, Neto A, Detry M, Fitzgerald M, Lewis R, McGlothlin A, Sanil A, Saunders C, Berry L, Lorenzi E, Miller E, Singh V, Zammit C, van Bentum Puijk W, Bouwman W, Mangindaan Y, Parker L, Peters S, Rietveld I, Raymakers K, Ganpat R, Brillinger N, Markgraf R, Ainscough K, Brickell K, Anjum A, Lane JB, Richards-Belle A, Saull M, Wiley D, Bion J, Connor J, Gates S, Manax V, van der Poll T, Reynolds J, van Beurden M, Effelaar E, Schotsman J, Boyd C, Harland C, Shearer A, Wren J, Clermont G, Garrard W, Kalchthaler K, King A, Ricketts D, Malakoutis S, Marroquin O, Music E, Quinn K, Cate H, Pearson K, Collins J, Hanson J, Williams P, Jackson S, Asghar A, Dyas S, Sutu M, Murphy S, Williamson D, Mguni N, Potter A, Porter D, Goodwin J, Rook C, Harrison S, Williams H, Campbell H, Lomme K, Williamson J, Sheffield J, van't Hoff W, McCracken P, Young M, Board J, Mart E, Knott C, Smith J, Boschert C, Affleck J, Ramanan M, D'Souza R, Pateman K, Shakih A, Cheung W, Kol M, Wong H, Shah A, Wagh A, Simpson J, Duke G, Chan P, Cartner B, Hunter S, Laver R, Shrestha T, Regli A, Pellicano A, McCullough J, Tallott M, Kumar N, Panwar R, Brinkerhoff G, Koppen C, Cazzola F, Brain M, Mineall S, Fischer R, Biradar V, Soar N, White H, Estensen K, Morrison L, Smith J, Cooper M, Health M, Shehabi Y, Al-Bassam W, Hulley A, Whitehead C, Lowrey J, Gresha R, Walsham J, Meyer J, Harward M, Venz E, Williams P, Kurenda C, Smith K, Smith M, Garcia R, Barge D, Byrne D, Byrne K, Driscoll A, Fortune L, Janin P, Yarad E, Hammond N, Bass F, Ashelford A, Waterson S, Wedd S, McNamara R, Buhr H, Coles J, Schweikert S, Wibrow B, Rauniyar R, Myers E, Fysh E, Dawda A, Mevavala B, Litton E, Ferrier J, Nair P, Buscher H, Reynolds C, Santamaria J, Barbazza L, Homes J, Smith R, Murray L, Brailsford J, Forbes L, Maguire T, Mariappa V, Smith J, Simpson S, Maiden M, Bone A, Horton M, Salerno T, Sterba M, Geng W, Depuydt P, De Waele J, De Bus L, Fierens J, Bracke S, Reeve B, Dechert W, Chassé M, Carrier FM, Boumahni D, Benettaib F, Ghamraoui A, Bellemare D, Cloutier È, Francoeur C, Lamontagne F, D'Aragon F, Carbonneau E, Leblond J, Vazquez-Grande G, Marten N, Wilson M, Albert M, Serri K, Cavayas A, Duplaix M, Williams V, Rochwerg B, Karachi T, Oczkowski S, Centofanti J, Millen T, Duan E, Tsang J, Patterson L, English S, Watpool I, Porteous R, Miezitis S, McIntyre L, Brochard L, Burns K, Sandhu G, Khalid I, Binnie A, Powell E, McMillan A, Luk T, Aref N, Andric Z, Cviljevic S, Đimoti R, Zapalac M, Mirković G, Baršić B, Kutleša M, Kotarski V, Vujaklija Brajković A, Babel J, Sever H, Dragija L, Kušan I, Vaara S, Pettilä L, Heinonen J, Kuitunen A, Karlsson S, Vahtera A, Kiiski H, Ristimäki S, Azaiz A, Charron C, Godement M, Geri G, Vieillard-Baron A, Pourcine F, Monchi M, Luis D, Mercier R, Sagnier A, Verrier N, Caplin C, Siami S, Aparicio C, Vautier S, Jeblaoui A, Fartoukh M, Courtin L, Labbe V, Leparco C, Muller G, Nay MA, Kamel T, Benzekri D, Jacquier S, Mercier E, Chartier D, Salmon C, Dequin P, Schneider F, Morel G, L'Hotellier S, Badie J, Berdaguer FD, Malfroy S, Mezher C, Bourgoin C, Megarbane B, Voicu S, Deye N, Malissin I, Sutterlin L, Guitton C, Darreau C, Landais M, Chudeau N, Robert A, Moine P, Heming N, Maxime V, Bossard I, Nicholier TB, Colin G, Zinzoni V, Maquigneau N, Finn A, Kreß G, Hoff U, Friedrich Hinrichs C, Nee J, Pletz M, Hagel S, Ankert J, Kolanos S, Bloos F, Petros S, Pasieka B, Kunz K, Appelt P, Schütze B, Kluge S, Nierhaus A, Jarczak D, Roedl K, Weismann D, Frey A, Klinikum Neukölln V, Reill L, Distler M, Maselli A, Bélteczki J, Magyar I, Fazekas Á, Kovács S, Szőke V, Szigligeti G, Leszkoven J, Collins D, Breen P, Frohlich S, Whelan R, McNicholas B, Scully M, Casey S, Kernan M, Doran P, O'Dywer M, Smyth M, Hayes L, Hoiting O, Peters M, Rengers E, Evers M, Prinssen A, Bosch Ziekenhuis J, Simons K, Rozendaal W, Polderman F, de Jager P, Moviat M, Paling A, Salet A, Rademaker E, Peters AL, de Jonge E, Wigbers J, Guilder E, Butler M, Cowdrey KA, Newby L, Chen Y, Simmonds C, McConnochie R, Ritzema Carter J, Henderson S, Van Der Heyden K, Mehrtens J, Williams T, Kazemi A, Song R, Lai V, Girijadevi D, Everitt R, Russell R, Hacking D, Buehner U, Williams E, Browne T, Grimwade K, Goodson J, Keet O, Callender O, Martynoga R, Trask K, Butler A, Schischka L, Young C, Lesona E, Olatunji S, Robertson Y, José N, Amaro dos Santos Catorze T, de Lima Pereira TNA, Neves Pessoa LM, Castro Ferreira RM, Pereira Sousa Bastos JM, Aysel Florescu S, Stanciu D, Zaharia MF, Kosa AG, Codreanu D, Marabi Y, Al Qasim E, Moneer Hagazy M, Al Swaidan L, Arishi H, Muñoz-Bermúdez R, Marin-Corral J, Salazar Degracia A, Parrilla Gómez F, Mateo López MI, Rodriguez Fernandez J, Cárcel Fernández S, Carmona Flores R, León López R, de la Fuente Martos C, Allan A, Polgarova P, Farahi N, McWilliam S, Hawcutt D, Rad L, O'Malley L, Whitbread J, Kelsall O, Wild L, Thrush J, Wood H, Austin K, Donnelly A, Kelly M, O'Kane S, McClintock D, Warnock M, Johnston P, Gallagher LJ, Mc Goldrick C, Mc Master M, Strzelecka A, Jha R, Kalogirou M, Ellis C, Krishnamurthy V, Deelchand V, Silversides J, McGuigan P, Ward K, O'Neill A, Finn S, Phillips B, Mullan D, Oritz-Ruiz de Gordoa L, Thomas M, Sweet K, Grimmer L, Johnson R, Pinnell J, Robinson M, Gledhill L, Wood T, Morgan M, Cole J, Hill H, Davies M, Antcliffe D, Templeton M, Rojo R, Coghlan P, Smee J, Mackay E, Cort J, Whileman A, Spencer T, Spittle N, Kasipandian V, Patel A, Allibone S, Genetu RM, Ramali M, Ghosh A, Bamford P, London E, Cawley K, Faulkner M, Jeffrey H, Smith T, Brewer C, Gregory J, Limb J, Cowton A, O'Brien J, Nikitas N, Wells C, Lankester L, Pulletz M, Williams P, Birch J, Wiseman S, Horton S, Alegria A, Turki S, Elsefi T, Crisp N, Allen L, McCullagh I, Robinson P, Hays C, Babio-Galan M, Stevenson H, Khare D, Pinder M, Selvamoni S, Gopinath A, Pugh R, Menzies D, Mackay C, Allan E, Davies G, Puxty K, McCue C, Cathcart S, Hickey N, Ireland J, Yusuff H, Isgro G, Brightling C, Bourne M, Craner M, Watters M, Prout R, Davies L, Pegler S, Kyeremeh L, Arbane G, Wilson K, Gomm L, Francia F, Brett S, Sousa Arias S, Elin Hall R, Budd J, Small C, Birch J, Collins E, Henning J, Bonner S, Hugill K, Cirstea E, Wilkinson D, Karlikowski M, Sutherland H, Wilhelmsen E, Woods J, North J, Sundaran D, Hollos L, Coburn S, Walsh J, Turns M, Hopkins P, Smith J, Noble H, Depante MT, Clarey E, Laha S, Verlander M, Williams A, Huckle A, Hall A, Cooke J, Gardiner-Hill C, Maloney C, Qureshi H, Flint N, Nicholson S, Southin S, Nicholson A, Borgatta B, Turner-Bone I, Reddy A, Wilding L, Chamara Warnapura L, Agno Sathianathan R, Golden D, Hart C, Jones J, Bannard-Smith J, Henry J, Birchall K, Pomeroy F, Quayle R, Makowski A, Misztal B, Ahmed I, KyereDiabour T, Naiker K, Stewart R, Mwaura E, Mew L, Wren L, Willams F, Innes R, Doble P, Hutter J, Shovelton C, Plumb B, Szakmany T, Hamlyn V, Hawkins N, Lewis S, Dell A, Gopal S, Ganguly S, Smallwood A, Harris N, Metherell S, Lazaro JM, Newman T, Fletcher S, Nortje J, Fottrell-Gould D, Randell G, Zaman M, Elmahi E, Jones A, Hall K, Mills G, Ryalls K, Bowler H, Sall J, Bourne R, Borrill Z, Duncan T, Lamb T, Shaw J, Fox C, Moreno Cuesta J, Xavier K, Purohit D, Elhassan M, Bakthavatsalam D, Rowland M, Hutton P, Bashyal A, Davidson N, Hird C, Chhablani M, Phalod G, Kirkby A, Archer S, Netherton K, Reschreiter H, Camsooksai J, Patch S, Jenkins S, Pogson D, Rose S, Daly Z, Brimfield L, Claridge H, Parekh D, Bergin C, Bates M, Dasgin J, McGhee C, Sim M, Hay SK, Henderson S, Phull MK, Zaidi A, Pogreban T, Rosaroso LP, Harvey D, Lowe B, Meredith M, Ryan L, Hormis A, Walker R, Collier D, Kimpton S, Oakley S, Rooney K, Rodden N, Hughes E, Thomson N, McGlynn D, Walden A, Jacques N, Coles H, Tilney E, Vowell E, Schuster-Bruce M, Pitts S, Miln R, Purandare L, Vamplew L, Spivey M, Bean S, Burt K, Moore L, Day C, Gibson C, Gordon E, Zitter L, Keenan S, Baker E, Cherian S, Cutler S, Roynon-Reed A, Harrington K, Raithatha A, Bauchmuller K, Ahmad N, Grecu I, Trodd D, Martin J, Wrey Brown C, Arias AM, Craven T, Hope D, Singleton J, Clark S, Rae N, Welters I, Hamilton DO, Williams K, Waugh V, Shaw D, Puthucheary Z, Martin T, Santos F, Uddin R, Somerville A, Tatham KC, Jhanji S, Black E, Dela Rosa A, Howle R, Tully R, Drummond A, Dearden J, Philbin J, Munt S, Vuylsteke A, Chan C, Victor S, Matsa R, Gellamucho M, Creagh-Brown B, Tooley J, Montague L, De Beaux F, Bullman L, Kersiake I, Demetriou C, Mitchard S, Ramos L, White K, Donnison P, Johns M, Casey R, Mattocks L, Salisbury S, Dark P, Claxton A, McLachlan D, Slevin K, Lee S, Hulme J, Joseph S, Kinney F, Senya HJ, Oborska A, Kayani A, Hadebe B, Orath Prabakaran R, Nichols L, Thomas M, Worner R, Faulkner B, Gendall E, Hayes K, Hamilton-Davies C, Chan C, Mfuko C, Abbass H, Mandadapu V, Leaver S, Forton D, Patel K, Paramasivam E, Powell M, Gould R, Wilby E, Howcroft C, Banach D, Fernández de Pinedo Artaraz Z, Cabreros L, White I, Croft M, Holland N, Pereira R, Zaki A, Johnson D, Jackson M, Garrard H, Juhaz V, Roy A, Rostron A, Woods L, Cornell S, Pillai S, Harford R, Rees T, Ivatt H, Sundara Raman A, Davey M, Lee K, Barber R, Chablani M, Brohi F, Jagannathan V, Clark M, Purvis S, Wetherill B, Dushianthan A, Cusack R, de Courcy-Golder K, Smith S, Jackson S, Attwood B, Parsons P, Page V, Zhao XB, Oza D, Rhodes J, Anderson T, Morris S, Xia Le Tai C, Thomas A, Keen A, Digby S, Cowley N, Wild L, Southern D, Reddy H, Campbell A, Watkins C, Smuts S, Touma O, Barnes N, Alexander P, Felton T, Ferguson S, Sellers K, Bradley-Potts J, Yates D, Birkinshaw I, Kell K, Marshall N, Carr-Knott L. Effect of Hydrocortisone on Mortality and Organ Support in Patients With Severe COVID-19: The REMAP-CAP COVID-19 Corticosteroid Domain Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA. 2020 Oct 6;324(13):1317-1329. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.17022.</citation>
    <PMID>32876697</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dequin PF, Heming N, Meziani F, Plantefève G, Voiriot G, Badié J, François B, Aubron C, Ricard JD, Ehrmann S, Jouan Y, Guillon A, Leclerc M, Coffre C, Bourgoin H, Lengellé C, Caille-Fénérol C, Tavernier E, Zohar S, Giraudeau B, Annane D, Le Gouge A; CAPE COVID Trial Group and the CRICS-TriGGERSep Network. Effect of Hydrocortisone on 21-Day Mortality or Respiratory Support Among Critically Ill Patients With COVID-19: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA. 2020 Oct 6;324(13):1298-1306. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.16761.</citation>
    <PMID>32876689</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tomazini BM, Maia IS, Cavalcanti AB, Berwanger O, Rosa RG, Veiga VC, Avezum A, Lopes RD, Bueno FR, Silva MVAO, Baldassare FP, Costa ELV, Moura RAB, Honorato MO, Costa AN, Damiani LP, Lisboa T, Kawano-Dourado L, Zampieri FG, Olivato GB, Righy C, Amendola CP, Roepke RML, Freitas DHM, Forte DN, Freitas FGR, Fernandes CCF, Melro LMG, Junior GFS, Morais DC, Zung S, Machado FR, Azevedo LCP; COALITION COVID-19 Brazil III Investigators. Effect of Dexamethasone on Days Alive and Ventilator-Free in Patients With Moderate or Severe Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome and COVID-19: The CoDEX Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA. 2020 Oct 6;324(13):1307-1316. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.17021.</citation>
    <PMID>32876695</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>WHO Rapid Evidence Appraisal for COVID-19 Therapies (REACT) Working Group, Sterne JAC, Murthy S, Diaz JV, Slutsky AS, Villar J, Angus DC, Annane D, Azevedo LCP, Berwanger O, Cavalcanti AB, Dequin PF, Du B, Emberson J, Fisher D, Giraudeau B, Gordon AC, Granholm A, Green C, Haynes R, Heming N, Higgins JPT, Horby P, Jüni P, Landray MJ, Le Gouge A, Leclerc M, Lim WS, Machado FR, McArthur C, Meziani F, Møller MH, Perner A, Petersen MW, Savovic J, Tomazini B, Veiga VC, Webb S, Marshall JC. Association Between Administration of Systemic Corticosteroids and Mortality Among Critically Ill Patients With COVID-19: A Meta-analysis. JAMA. 2020 Oct 6;324(13):1330-1341. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.17023.</citation>
    <PMID>32876694</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Meduri GU, Golden E, Freire AX, Taylor E, Zaman M, Carson SJ, Gibson M, Umberger R. Methylprednisolone infusion in early severe ARDS: results of a randomized controlled trial. Chest. 2007 Apr;131(4):954-63.</citation>
    <PMID>17426195</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Harhay MO, Casey JD, Clement M, Collins SP, Gayat É, Gong MN, Jaber S, Laterre PF, Marshall JC, Matthay MA, Monroe RE, Rice TW, Rubin E, Self WH, Mebazaa A. Contemporary strategies to improve clinical trial design for critical care research: insights from the First Critical Care Clinical Trialists Workshop. Intensive Care Med. 2020 May;46(5):930-942. doi: 10.1007/s00134-020-05934-6. Epub 2020 Feb 18.</citation>
    <PMID>32072303</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yehya N, Harhay MO, Curley MAQ, Schoenfeld DA, Reeder RW. Reappraisal of Ventilator-Free Days in Critical Care Research. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2019 Oct 1;200(7):828-836. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201810-2050CP. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31034248</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>WHO Working Group on the Clinical Characterisation and Management of COVID-19 infection. A minimal common outcome measure set for COVID-19 clinical research. Lancet Infect Dis. 2020 Aug;20(8):e192-e197. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(20)30483-7. Epub 2020 Jun 12. Review. Erratum in: Lancet Infect Dis. 2020 Oct;20(10):e250.</citation>
    <PMID>32539990</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Brno University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jan Malaska</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD. Ph.D. EDIC</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Covid19</keyword>
  <keyword>ARDS</keyword>
  <keyword>dexamethasone</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Collected data will be shared with other ongoing clinical trials on the same topic for individual patient ́s data (IPD) metaanalysis or shared upon relevant requests. Also de-identified participant-level dataset will be made available 6 months after the publication of the results of the study at www.mendeley.com</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>De-identified participant-level dataset will be made available 6 months after the publication of the results of the study at www.mendeley.com</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Planned IPD metaanalysis or other relevant request</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 15, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/55/NCT04663555/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

