<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4820">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04524286</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>19/20/IRAS/CC</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>262369</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>45534</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04524286</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Role of Midwifery Continuity of Care in Reducing Health Inequalities</brief_title>
  <acronym>Mi-CARE</acronym>
  <official_title>The Role of a Midwifery Continuity of CARE Model in Reducing Health Inequalities in Childbearing Women and Babies Living on a Low-income: The Mi-CARE Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bournemouth University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital Southampton NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bournemouth University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The impact of living in a deprived area has far reaching consequences on maternal and infant&#xD;
      health. Studies in England show women living in deprived areas have some of the poorest&#xD;
      experiences of care, poor birth outcomes and are 50% more likely to die of pregnancy related&#xD;
      complications than women in the least deprived neighbourhoods. Life expectancy has also&#xD;
      stalled for women living in the most deprived areas and the global COVID-19 pandemic has&#xD;
      further amplified existing health inequalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Social Determinants of Health (SDH) are the conditions in which people are born, grow,&#xD;
      work, live, and age, and are mostly responsible for health inequities - the unfair and&#xD;
      avoidable differences in health seen within and between populations. Evidence shows taking&#xD;
      action on the SDH alongside Midwifery Continuity of Care (MCC) models, improves birth&#xD;
      outcomes and reduces health inequalities. How midwives working in MCC models in areas of high&#xD;
      deprivation address the SDH as part of their public health and prevention role is currently&#xD;
      not clear. There is also a lack of qualitative evidence exploring the SDH from the&#xD;
      perspectives of women themselves.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Drawing on Constructivist Grounded Theory methods, this research will take place in a&#xD;
      low-income setting in England. Through the use of semi-structured interviews with women and&#xD;
      midwives working in an NHS MCC model, the study will generate theory to help explain how and&#xD;
      indeed whether midwives take action to address the SDH as part of their public health role.&#xD;
      The study also seeks to understand the SDH impacting upon women's lives and what mechanisms&#xD;
      exist to support or obstruct engagement with the SDH. Examining these domains will contribute&#xD;
      to the evidence base about the impact of MCC and the public health and prevention strategy in&#xD;
      NHS maternity services.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 6, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 18, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 18, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Interviews with childbearing women</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Women living in the case setting willing to participate and share their maternity care experiences in one-to-one interviews.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Interviews with childbearing women</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Women living in the case setting willing to participate and share their childbearing experiences in one-to-one interviews.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Interview with midwives</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Midwives willing to participate and share their experiences of providing care to women in the case setting.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Interview with midwives</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Midwives willing to participate and share their knowledge about their public health role and how the actions they take to meet the needs of women.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Document analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Analysis of documents such as policies, reports and guidelines which focus on maternal health inequalities, the public health role of midwives, and the role of midwifery-led continuity of care.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Memo writing</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Memos will be written throughout data collection and incorporated into data analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</condition>
  <condition>Social Determinants</condition>
  <condition>Public Health</condition>
  <condition>Pregnancy Related</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Public - Childbearing Women</arm_group_label>
    <description>Childbearing women living in three deprived areas in a city in the South of England.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Staff - Midwives</arm_group_label>
    <description>Midwives working in caseloading teams providing continuity of care to women living in three deprived areas in a city in the South of England.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Interviews only.</intervention_name>
    <description>Interviews will be conducted with childbearing women and midwives.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Public - Childbearing Women</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Staff - Midwives</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        -  Childbearing women - Women who receive their care from one of the MCC caseloading&#xD;
             teams. In the context of this study the term 'childbearing woman' is defined as any&#xD;
             woman of childbearing age over the age of 16 years who is currently pregnant or up to&#xD;
             five years post childbirth;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Midwives - Midwives working in the study setting or have worked in one of the MCC&#xD;
             caseloading teams. Also, midwives at the study site who have managerial and leadership&#xD;
             oversight of the MCC teams.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria - Childbearing Women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are currently receiving maternity care from the MCC caseloading teams;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who have previously received care from one of the caseloading teams;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women aged 16 and over;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who can understand English and are able to independently provide their informed&#xD;
             consent;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women at any point in their pregnancy or up to five years following the birth of their&#xD;
             babies. This time frame is considered appropriate in order to capture women who are&#xD;
             currently receiving maternity care and those who have received care locally in the&#xD;
             last five years. This will aim to also capture women's experiences before referral to&#xD;
             the caseloading teams changed;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who had or are currently having their maternity care provided by UHS.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria - Midwives&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Midwives who work in the MCC caseloading teams in the study setting;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Midwives who have previously worked in the local MCC caseloading teams.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Midwifery managers who have managerial oversight of the MCC caseloading teams.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria - Childbearing women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who have not received care from one of the MCC caseloading teams;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who gave birth more than five years ago;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women below the age of 16 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who cannot speak English due to a lack of financial resources to fund&#xD;
             translation services;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are in labour;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who had their maternity care at a different NHS Trust;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who lack capacity to provide informed consent;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who decline to participate and decline to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria - Midwives&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Midwives who work in the universal teams;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  MSWs due to different professional roles and responsibilities;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Midwives who decline to participate and decline to provide informed consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Charlotte Clayton</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Bournemouth University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Charlotte Clayton</last_name>
    <phone>+447507857525</phone>
    <email>claytonc@bournemouth.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Suzy Wignall</last_name>
    <phone>+441202961073</phone>
    <email>swignall@bournemouth.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Princess Anne Hospital - University Hospital Southampton</name>
      <address>
        <city>Southampton</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Charlotte Clayton</last_name>
      <email>claytonc@bournemouth.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 20, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 24, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 24, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 25, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Midwifery Continuity of Care</keyword>
  <keyword>Social Determinants of Health</keyword>
  <keyword>Childbearing women</keyword>
  <keyword>Health inequalities/inequities</keyword>
  <keyword>Constructivist Grounded Theory</keyword>
  <keyword>Qualitative research</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The final dataset will be anonymised, cleaned and stored within Bournemouth University's online research data repository BORDaR. This is a central location where research data generated by Bournemouth University is stored. This is accessible to the public for reuse.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>After the study has ended and for 25 years after this.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_url>http://bordar.bournemouth.ac.uk/</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

