<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2420">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04662437</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>08122020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04662437</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Status of Parathyroid Hormone Secretion in Covid-19 Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Status of Parathyroid Hormone Secretion and Its Relationship With White Blood Cells, Neutrophil / Lymphocyte Ratio, c Reactive Protein, Fibrinogen, Procalcitonin, Ferritin and D-dimer in Hospitalized Covid-19 Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bezmialem Vakif University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Didem Ertorul</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bezmialem Vakif University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      COVID-19 infection causes a hypersensitive immune reaction and widespread inflammation in&#xD;
      various organs of the body, especially through cytokines in the lungs. This cytokine-mediated&#xD;
      widespread inflammation can also affect the parathyroid glands, resulting in impaired&#xD;
      parathyroid secretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Researchers evaluated the levels of parathyroid hormone, calcium, phosphorus, and alkaline&#xD;
      phosphatase in patients hospitalized for COVID-19 infection. Researchers excluded patients on&#xD;
      intensive care therapy and patients with known parathyroid disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The researchers examined the association of parathyroid hormone secretion with COVID-19&#xD;
      disease, white blood cells, neutrophil / lymphocyte ratio, C reactive protein, fibrinogen,&#xD;
      procalcitonin, ferritin, and D-dimer in these patients. The researchers compared the&#xD;
      parathyroid hormone level of healthy people without COVID-19 infection and known parathyroid&#xD;
      disease with the parathyroid hormone level of Covid-19 patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The coronavirus-2 (SARS-COV-2) virus, which can cause severe acute respiratory syndrome&#xD;
      through the droplet, has caused the global Coronavirus 19 (COVID-19) pandemic. COVID-19&#xD;
      infection can be asymptomatic or lead to serious illness and even death. This virus causes a&#xD;
      hypersensitive immune reaction and varying degrees of widespread inflammation through&#xD;
      cytokines in various organs of the body, mainly the lungs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cytokine-mediated widespread inflammation caused by the virus may also affect the parathyroid&#xD;
      glands, causing their functions to deteriorate. Thus, it may cause changes in parathyroid&#xD;
      hormone secretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The researchers evaluated the results of serum parathyroid hormone, calcium, phosphorus,&#xD;
      alkaline phosphatase tests in patients who were symptomatic and hospitalized with COVID-19&#xD;
      infection. Participants also evaluated the relationship of parathormone with white blood&#xD;
      cells, neutrophil / lymphocyte ratio, c reactive protein, fibrinogen, procalcitonin,&#xD;
      ferritin, and D-dimer in these patients. The researchers compared the parathyroid hormone&#xD;
      levels of patients with COVID-19 infection with the parathyroid hormone levels of healthy&#xD;
      individuals without COVID-19 infection and parathyroid disease. So the investigators looked&#xD;
      for differences in parathyroid hormone levels between both groups. Researchers did not&#xD;
      include patients in the intensive care unit and patients with known parathyroid disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 10, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 9, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 1, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of parathyroid hormone between groups</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum parathyroid hormone results of the Covid patient group and non-Covid control groups were recorded and compared statistically.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of calcium between groups</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum calcium results of the Covid patient group and non-Covid control groups were recorded and compared statistically.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of phosphorus between groups</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum phosphorus results of the Covid patient group and non-Covid control groups were recorded and compared statistically.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of alkaline phosphatase between groups</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum alkaline phosphatase results of the Covid patient group and non-Covid control groups were recorded and compared statistically.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>White blood cells (WBC) results of Covid 19 patient group</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum WBC results were recorded in Covid 19 patient groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Neutrophil / lymphocyte ratio (N/LO) results of Covid 19 patient group</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum N/LO results were recorded in Covid 19 patient groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>C-reactive protein (CRP) results of Covid 19 patient group</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum CRP results were recorded in Covid 19 patient groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fibrinogen results of Covid 19 patient group</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum fibrinogen results were recorded in Covid 19 patient groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Procalcitonin results of Covid 19 patient group</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum procalcitonin results were recorded in Covid 19 patient groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ferritin results of Covid 19 patient group</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum ferritin results were recorded in Covid 19 patient groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>D-dimer results of Covid 19 patient group</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the study, serum D-dimer results were recorded in Covid 19 patient groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">150</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19 Infection</condition>
  <condition>Parathyroid Gland</condition>
  <condition>Parathyroid Hormone</condition>
  <condition>Calcium</condition>
  <condition>Phosphorus</condition>
  <condition>Alkaline Phosphatase</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Covid-19 Patient Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>10 ml of venous blood was taken from the forearm venous vein from people in the Covid-19 Patient Group, and the level of parathyroid hormone, calcium, phosphorus, alkaline phosphatase was measured from this blood.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>10 ml of venous blood will be taken from the forearm venous vein from the healthy control group and the parathyroid hormone, calcium, phosphorus, alkaline phosphatase level will be measured from this blood.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Venous blood was collected for biochemistry testing</intervention_name>
    <description>From the people in the healthy control group, 10 ml of venous blood was collected from the venous vein in the forearm of all individuals in the study. Parathyroid hormone, calcium, phosphorus, alkaline phosphatase levels were measured from this blood.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Covid-19 Patient Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Control Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients who were hospitalized and treated for COVID-19 without parathyroid disease were&#xD;
        formed.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  To accept research.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being over the age of 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID 19 test results to be positive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not taking parathyroid disease medication before.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving inpatient treatment in the COVID service in the hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not accepting research.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be under the age of 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative COVID 19 test results for patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID patients treated as outpatient.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parathyroid disease in the healthy control group.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Derya Özalp Çelikçi, Dr</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Sancaktepe Education and Research Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bezmialem VU</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <zip>34093</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sun JK, Zhang WH, Zou L, Liu Y, Li JJ, Kan XH, Dai L, Shi QK, Yuan ST, Yu WK, Xu HY, Gu W, Qi JW. Serum calcium as a biomarker of clinical severity and prognosis in patients with coronavirus disease 2019. Aging (Albany NY). 2020 Jun 25;12(12):11287-11295. doi: 10.18632/aging.103526. Epub 2020 Jun 25.</citation>
    <PMID>32589164</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>di Filippo L, Formenti AM, Doga M, Frara S, Rovere-Querini P, Bosi E, Carlucci M, Giustina A. Hypocalcemia is a distinctive biochemical feature of hospitalized COVID-19 patients. Endocrine. 2021 Jan;71(1):9-13. doi: 10.1007/s12020-020-02541-9. Epub 2020 Nov 9.</citation>
    <PMID>33165763</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Somasundaram NP, Ranathunga I, Ratnasamy V, Wijewickrama PSA, Dissanayake HA, Yogendranathan N, Gamage KKK, de Silva NL, Sumanatilleke M, Katulanda P, Grossman AB. The Impact of SARS-Cov-2 Virus Infection on the Endocrine System. J Endocr Soc. 2020 Jul 2;4(8):bvaa082. doi: 10.1210/jendso/bvaa082. eCollection 2020 Aug 1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32728654</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 8, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 10, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 9, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 9, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 10, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Bezmialem Vakif University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sabahattin Destek</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The study will be shared when it becomes an article.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

