<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4742">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04299711</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SW888999</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04299711</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mental Health and Its Correlates Among Chinese Adolescents Exposed to the Novel Coronavirus Disease 2019</brief_title>
  <official_title>Mental Health and Its Correlates Among Chinese Adolescents Exposed to the Novel Coronavirus Disease 2019: A Longitudinal Study Protocol</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Macau</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Macau</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Direct exposure to public health emergencies is associated with increased mental&#xD;
      disorders. It is less clear about the prevalence of common mental disorders and its&#xD;
      correlates in Chinese adolescents after experiencing public health emergencies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: This longitudinal study aims to estimate the prevalence of common mental disorders&#xD;
      (i.e. depression, anxiety, and post-traumatic stress disorder) and its correlates in a sample&#xD;
      of Chinese adolescents after experience a public health emergency, namely the novel&#xD;
      coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method: This study intends to recruit 3,428 Chinese adolescent students from high and middle&#xD;
      schools in the baseline survey. This study will track these recruited participants every 6&#xD;
      months via three-wave follow-up (i.e. 6-month, 12-month, and 18-month follow-ups). The&#xD;
      demographics (e.g. age, gender, education, family background, and residence) and psychosocial&#xD;
      factors (i.e. exposure to traumatic events, religious belief, social media exposure,&#xD;
      loneliness, and perceived social support) associated with common mental disorders (i.e.&#xD;
      depression, anxiety, and post-traumatic stress disorder) will be investigated in this sample&#xD;
      population. Furthermore, a hardcopy self-report questionnaire will be disturbed to all&#xD;
      participants. Additionally, the cross-sectional analyses will be first conducted to estimate&#xD;
      the prevalence of mental disorders and their correlates in data of baseline survey. After&#xD;
      obtaining the longitudinal data, the relative risk, incident rate ratios, latent class&#xD;
      analysis, and structural equation model may be performed in this study. Missing data will be&#xD;
      solved by the multiple imputations. Data analysis tools included the Stata 16.0 and Mplus&#xD;
      8.4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Discussion: This longitudinal study will better help to understand the prevalence changes of&#xD;
      mental disorders among Chinese adolescents following the COVID-19. These findings have the&#xD;
      potential to provide empirical evidence about the burden of mental disease and key drivers of&#xD;
      Chinese adolescents following the COVID-19, which can benefit the formation of public policy&#xD;
      and mental health intervention programming. This study will close the gaps that a lack of&#xD;
      epidemiological studies about the mental disorder prevalence and related risk factors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 15, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 15, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The prevalence and incidence changes of common mental disorders</measure>
    <time_frame>15 Oct 2020 - 15 Nov 2020</time_frame>
    <description>The prevalence and incidence changes of common mental disorders (i.e. depression, anxiety, and PTSD) in a representative sample of Chinese adolescents</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mental disorders and its' correlates</measure>
    <time_frame>15 Oct 2020 - 15 Nov 2020</time_frame>
    <description>To identify demographics (e.g. age, gender, education, family background, and residence) the major psychosocial factors (i.e. exposure to traumatic events, religious belief, social media exposure, loneliness, and perceived social support) contributing to prevalence and incidence of mental disorders</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">3428</enrollment>
  <condition>Mental Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Baseline</arm_group_label>
    <description>This study intends to recruit 3,428 Chinese adolescent students exposed to the novel coronavirus disease 2019 in the baseline survey</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>6-month follow-up</arm_group_label>
    <description>This study will track the mental health status among these recruited 3,428 participants exposed to the novel coronavirus disease 2019 in the 6 follow-up study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>12-month follow-up</arm_group_label>
    <description>This study will track the mental health status among these recruited 3,428 participants exposed to the novel coronavirus disease 2019 in the 12 follow-up study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>18-month follow-up</arm_group_label>
    <description>This study will track the mental health status among these recruited 3,428 participants exposed to the novel coronavirus disease 2019 in the 18 follow-up study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exposed to the novel coronavirus disease 2019</intervention_name>
    <description>Exposed to the novel coronavirus disease 2019</description>
    <arm_group_label>12-month follow-up</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>18-month follow-up</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>6-month follow-up</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Baseline</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study will be conducted in Yibin City, Sichuan province, China. A total of six schools&#xD;
        (two high schools and four middle schools) will be contacted for the data collection.&#xD;
        According to the formula for the finite population for prevalence studies and the attrition&#xD;
        rate of the cohort study, the total number of estimated sample size is 3,428, which will be&#xD;
        recruited in the baseline study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. age range: 10-19;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. full-time students in these targets high or middle schools;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. nationality: China;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. exposure context: COVID-19;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. able to adequately understand the content of consent form and questionnaire;&#xD;
&#xD;
        (d) able to sufficiently state the purpose of the research and acknowledge the potential&#xD;
        risks and benefits based on the questionnaire&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>19 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>March 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 4, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 4, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 4, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 9, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Macau</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Vivian SHI</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dr.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

