<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="932">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04493307</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1602903</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04493307</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Evaluation of Hemostasis in Hospitalized COVID-19 Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>TARGET-COVID</acronym>
  <official_title>The Evaluation of Hemostasis by Thromboelastography, Platelet Function Testing, and Biomarker Analysis in Hospitalized COVID-19 Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>LifeBridge Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Haemonetics Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Inflammatory Markers Laboratory</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Chronolog Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Precision Biologics, Inc</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>LifeBridge Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), a viral respiratory illness caused by the severe acute&#xD;
      respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), has been shown to predispose patients to&#xD;
      thrombotic diseases (venous and arterial) with reported rates in hospitalized patients&#xD;
      between 17-40%. The influence of SARS-CoV-2 infection on the coagulation is hypothesized to&#xD;
      be regulated by platelet activation, proinflammatory cytokines, endothelial cell injury and&#xD;
      stasis. The elevated levels of d-dimer and fibrinogen and clinical signs of organ damage&#xD;
      point to a significant hypercoagulable state. The latter induces a high risk for&#xD;
      micro-thrombi and multi-organ ischemia. Therefore, early detection and a comprehensive&#xD;
      understanding of the influence of the virus on the coagulation and platelet pathways are&#xD;
      essential to address this epidemic. It is critical at this time to make all efforts possible&#xD;
      to optimize our available technology to care for COVID-19 patients who are at risk for&#xD;
      thrombotic disease through appropriate choice, dosing, and laboratory monitoring of&#xD;
      antithrombotic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesize that COVID-19 is a heightened prothrombotic/hypercoagulability&#xD;
      state that can be characterized using platelet function testing and thrombelastography. More&#xD;
      information is required to study the effect of COVID-19 on coagulation and platelet pathways&#xD;
      to develop effective antithrombotic treatment strategies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a multi-center center, non-interventional study enrolling patients who are COVID-19&#xD;
      positive or who have tested negative showing indication of the disease (high D-dimer and&#xD;
      positive lung imaging). The study specific laboratory assessments will be obtained at&#xD;
      baseline (closest to time of hospitalization), Day 3, and Day 8 from baseline and at hospital&#xD;
      discharge. Laboratory measurements for TEG 6S , platelet aggregation, T-TAS, urinary&#xD;
      thromboxane, genotyping, serum and plasma biomarkers will be analyzed . In-hospital and&#xD;
      clinical follow-up data will be entered into a COVID registry Patients will be followed for&#xD;
      clinical events during hospitalization, and up to 6 months after discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients (n=100) hospitalized with at least one of the following will be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. With a confirmed diagnosis of COVID-19 infection using a positive RT- PCR or a positive&#xD;
           IgG antibody test prior to or during hospitalization or&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. With a negative COVID-19 RT-PCR test but with symptoms of possible&#xD;
&#xD;
      COVID-19 infection and:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. an elevated D-dimer and/or&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. positive imaging results showing unilateral or bilateral pneumonia or ground-glass&#xD;
           opacity in lungs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigators hypothesize that serial evaluation of (a) intrinsic thrombogenicity&#xD;
      measured by thromboelastography (b) platelet activation and aggregation, and (c) selected&#xD;
      biomarkers will provide the &quot;blueprint&quot; of individual hemostasis to precisely characterize&#xD;
      COVID-19 patients who are at heightened risk for thrombosis or bleeding. The latter will&#xD;
      facilitate future efforts to personalize antithrombotic therapy regimens in COVID-19&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), a viral respiratory illness caused by the severe acute&#xD;
      respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), has been shown to predispose patients to&#xD;
      thrombotic diseases (venous and arterial) with reported rates in hospitalized patients&#xD;
      between 17- 40%. The influence of SARS-CoV-2 infection on the coagulation is hypothesized to&#xD;
      be regulated by platelet activation, proinflammatory cytokines, endothelial cell injury and&#xD;
      stasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The elevated levels of d-dimer and fibrinogen and clinical signs of organ damage point to a&#xD;
      significant hypercoagulable state. The latter induces a high risk for micro-thrombi and&#xD;
      multiorgan ischemia. Therefore, early detection and a comprehensive understanding of the&#xD;
      influence of the virus on the coagulation and platelet pathways are essential to address this&#xD;
      epidemic. It is critical at this time to make all efforts possible to optimize our available&#xD;
      technology to care for COVID-19 patients who are at risk for thrombotic disease through&#xD;
      appropriate choice, dosing, and laboratory monitoring of antithrombotic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our research group and others have reported a &quot;thrombo-inflammatory&quot; state-a distinct&#xD;
      pathophysiological state -of heightened platelet function, hypercoagulability, and&#xD;
      inflammation in several cardiovascular disease (CVD) processes. It has been demonstrated that&#xD;
      patients with acute respiratory infections are at elevated risk for acute myocardial&#xD;
      infarction after influenza (incidence ratio [IR] 6.1, 95% CI 3.9-9.5) and after non-influenza&#xD;
      viral illnesses including other coronavirus species (IR 2.8, 95% CI 1.2-6.2). Tantry et al.&#xD;
      proposed a mechanistic link between inflammation and heightened thrombogenicity in the&#xD;
      presence of unstable CVD state. Furthermore, investigators have hypothesized that this&#xD;
      thrombo-inflammatory state becomes even more relevant when patients with CVD and human&#xD;
      immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection undergo percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI).A&#xD;
      similar scenario may be present during COVID-19 infection, where evidence of an early&#xD;
      myonecrosis may be related to fundamental changes in pathways affecting thrombosis. However,&#xD;
      currently, there is no information on how COVID-19 influences hemostasis/thrombosis pathways&#xD;
      and subsequent adverse clinical event occurrences.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiovascular comorbidities including hypertension, obesity, high cholesterol, and diabetes&#xD;
      mellitus are common in patients with COVID-19 and such patients are at higher risk for&#xD;
      morbidity and mortality.12 Furthermore, emerging demographic data in COVID-19 patients shows&#xD;
      that incidence and mortality is disproportionately higher in African Americans and Latinos.&#xD;
      In a study conducted at Sinai hospital, Lev et al. analyzed a large cohort of racially&#xD;
      diverse patients (n=1,172) with CAD or CV risk and demonstrated that sex and race are&#xD;
      significantly associated with platelet-fibrin clot strength, a marker of hypercoagulability.&#xD;
      Most interesting, AA women had the highest thrombogenicity profile, potentially conferring a&#xD;
      highrisk phenotype for thrombotic event occurrence. Furthermore, in a study entitled,&#xD;
      &quot;PlateletReactivity in Different Ethnicities&quot; also conducted at Sinai hospital, investigators&#xD;
      have demonstrated that Latino and AA races had the highest platelet-fibrin clot strength as&#xD;
      compared to Caucasians and others races studied.The latter findings may be described by&#xD;
      difference in frequency of a single-nucleotide variant in protease-activated receptor-4&#xD;
      (PAR-4) between AA and Caucasians respectively (63% vs 19%). PAR-4 is an active thrombin&#xD;
      receptor on human platelets essential for thrombin-induced platelet activation and has been&#xD;
      shown to be more active in African Americans as compared to Caucasians. This evidence may&#xD;
      provide a potential mechanistic explanation for racial disparities observed in COVID-19&#xD;
      patients and require further investigation. Hence, investigators will collect a genetic&#xD;
      sample to analyze single-nucleotide variant of PAR-4 and other genetic markers related to&#xD;
      thrombosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thromboelastography (TEG) is a method for measuring global hemostasis and has been widely&#xD;
      used in surgery and anesthesiology, emergency departments, trauma centers, intensive care&#xD;
      units,and cardiac catheterization labs for transfusion management, prediction of thrombotic&#xD;
      and bleeding events, and choice/adjustment of anticoagulation and antiplatelet therapies.&#xD;
      Light transmittance aggregometry (LTA) is a widely used gold standard method for identifying&#xD;
      heightened platelet reactivity to various agonists, a marker of thrombotic risk.More common&#xD;
      conventional coagulation tests include prothrombin time (PT, INR), partial thromboplastin&#xD;
      time (aPTT), fibrinogen, platelet count, and d-dimer. However, these latter tests do not&#xD;
      reflect interactions between platelets, endothelium, and fibrinolytic factors and must be&#xD;
      used in combination to provide a complete picture of hemostasis status. Unlike these tests,&#xD;
      the TEG can assess platelet function, clot strength, and fibrinolysis. Furthermore, The TEG6s&#xD;
      Hemostasis Analyzer is a portable, all-in-one cartridge-based system that requires minimal&#xD;
      blood sample and minimal sample processing, a potential safety advantage when processing&#xD;
      blood samples in COVID-19 patients. Lastly, COVID-19 infection may be associated with acute&#xD;
      cardiac injury as indicated by elevation of cardiac biomarkers to &gt; 99th percentile of the&#xD;
      upper reference limit, but also electrocardiographic and echocardiographic abnormalities.&#xD;
      Cardiac injury is highly prevalent in patients with COVID-19 but may not be an important&#xD;
      marker as it occurs after damage has been done. Inosine and hypoxanthine are specific markers&#xD;
      of acute cardiac ischemia (ACI) that are measurable within 20 minutes as compared to 4 hours&#xD;
      with CKMB and Troponin testing. Investigators believe that this marker may indicate the early&#xD;
      presence of micro-thrombi and organ damage. Investigators plan to investigate these novel&#xD;
      markers in this trial. Investigators hypothesize that COVID-19 is a heightened&#xD;
      prothrombotic/hypercoagulability state that can be characterized using platelet function&#xD;
      testing and Thromboelastography. More information is required to study the effect of COVID-19&#xD;
      on coagulation and platelet pathways to develop effective antithrombotic treatment&#xD;
      strategies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is a multi-center, non-interventional study involving laboratory testing of blood&#xD;
      samples and data collection for a COVID registry using electronic medical records. The study&#xD;
      specific laboratory assessments will be obtained at baseline (closest to time of&#xD;
      hospitalization), Day 3 and Day 8 from baseline, and at hospital discharge. Patients will be&#xD;
      followed for clinical events during hospitalization, and 1 and 6 months after discharge.&#xD;
      Patients (n=100) hospitalized at Sinai Hospital of Baltimore and Northwest Hospital with at&#xD;
      least one of the following will be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. With a confirmed diagnosis of COVID-19 infection using a positive RT-PCR or a positive&#xD;
           IgG antibody test prior to or during hospitalization or,&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. With a negative COVID-19 RT-PCR test but with symptoms of possible COVID-19infection&#xD;
           and:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. an elevated D-dimer and/or&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. positive imaging results showing unilateral or bilateral pneumonia or ground glass&#xD;
                opacity in lungs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 30, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of Hypercoagulability as measured by thromboelastography measured by TEG and platelet aggregation.</measure>
    <time_frame>up to day 8</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of Hypercoagulability as measured by point-of-care thromboelastography (TEG6s)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of High Platelet Reactivity (HPR)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to day 8</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of High Platelet Reactivity as measured by platelet aggregation and TEG6s</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of thrombo-inflammatory syndrome</measure>
    <time_frame>up to day 8</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of thrombo -inflammatory syndrome as determined by D-Dimer and TEG6s</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between TEG6s parameters and clinical outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between TEG6s parameters and clinical outcomes (thrombotic and bleeding events, need for ventilation, death)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between HPR and clinical outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between HPR and clinical outcomes (thrombotic and bleeding events, need for ventilation, death)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine response to anticoagulation therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>up to day 8</time_frame>
    <description>Determine response to anticoagulation therapy by calculating change in R-value (CK -CKH)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine level of platelet aggregation</measure>
    <time_frame>up to day 8</time_frame>
    <description>Determine level of platelet aggregation by impedance aggregometry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine level of platelet aggregation</measure>
    <time_frame>up to day 8</time_frame>
    <description>Determine percent platelet aggregation by TEG-6S platelet Mapping assay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine platelet thrombi and fibrin rich platelet thrombus Area Under the Curve</measure>
    <time_frame>up to day 8</time_frame>
    <description>Determine platelet thrombi and fibrin rich platelet thrombus Area Under the Curve using TTAS analyzer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine short and long IgG, IgM and IgG antibody levels</measure>
    <time_frame>up to day 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Determine short and long IgG, IgM and IgG antibody levels against using multiple specimen types (saliva, whole blood, serum, plasma, urine)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Phlebotomy</intervention_name>
    <description>Serial assessment of hemostasis by blood and urine collection</description>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood and urine samples will be collected at study timepoints for the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. TEG6S with citrated multi-channel and Platelet Mapping cartridges&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Platelet aggregation will be assessed using a Chronolog Lumi- Aggregometer&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Serum and Plasma Biomarkers of Inflammation/Cytokine Storm, Coagulation,and&#xD;
           Ischemia/Organ Injury&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Urinary 11-dehydrothromboxane B2&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Evaluation of whole blood thrombogenicity using The Total Thrombus- Formation Analysis&#xD;
           System (T-TAS)&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Genotyping: Genetic variations of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) related to&#xD;
           coagulation, platelet function, immune response and thrombosis related clinical outcomes&#xD;
           using SNP microarrays and PCR-based methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. COVID-19 Antibody Detection&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study's intended population is inclusive of both genders (males and females), aged 3&#xD;
        years and older, and all racial and ethnic groups.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  · Confirmed diagnosis of COVID-19 infection using a positive RT-PCR or a positive IgG&#xD;
             antibody test prior to or during hospitalization or,&#xD;
&#xD;
             · With a negative COVID-19 RT-PCR test but with symptoms of possible COVID-19&#xD;
             infection and:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  elevated D-dimer and/or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  positive imaging results showing unilateral or bilateral pneumonia or ground-glass&#xD;
             opacity in lungs · The subject or legal authorized representative able to read and&#xD;
             sign an informed consent document including authorization permitting release of&#xD;
             personal health information approved by the investigator's Institutional Review Board&#xD;
             (IRB).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects will be excluded from entry if ANY of the criteria listed below are met:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than 3 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active treatment for cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of long-term use of immunosuppressive agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe chronic respiratory disease and requirement for long-term oxygen&#xD;
             therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing hemodialysis or peritoneal dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on full dose anticoagulant at the time of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition unsuitable for the study as determined by investigators&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Paul A Gurbel, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>LifeBridge Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>kevin bliden, MBA</last_name>
    <phone>4432441497</phone>
    <email>kbliden@lifebridgehealth.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Cescelle Barbour, MSN</last_name>
    <phone>4106014194</phone>
    <email>cbarbour@lifebridgehealth.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sinai Center for Thrombosis Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kevin P Bliden, B.S. MBA</last_name>
      <phone>443-244-1497</phone>
      <email>kbliden@lifebridgehealth.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Cescelle B Barbour, MSN</last_name>
      <phone>4106014194</phone>
      <email>cbarbour@lifebridgehealth.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Paul A Gurbel, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jaime Barnes, DO</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ashwin Dharmadhikari, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 20, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 20, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

