<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4558">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03708718</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>119220</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03708718</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prednisolone in Early Diffuse Systemic Sclerosis</brief_title>
  <acronym>PRedSS</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase II Randomised Study of Oral Prednisolone in Early Diffuse Cutaneous Systemic Sclerosis (Initially Double-blind, Then Switched to Open-label Because of Covid-19)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Prof. Ariane herrick</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Versus Arthritis</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Manchester</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomised placebo-controlled study of moderate dose prednisolone for 6 months in&#xD;
      patients with early diffuse cutaneous systemic sclerosis (dcSSc). Seventy-two patients within&#xD;
      3 years of the onset of skin thickening will be recruited from 14 UK centres over 3 years.&#xD;
      Co-primary end-points will be the Health Assessment Questionnaire Disability Index (HAQ-DI)&#xD;
      and the modified Rodnan skin score (mRSS). Patients will be assessed 5 times: screening,&#xD;
      baseline, 6 weeks, 3 and 6 months, with a code-break on exit from the study at 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Please note: From August 2020, the trial was re-started following halt due to Covid-19 as&#xD;
      open-label. The placebo arm is the 'no treatment' arm and there is no longer a code-break at&#xD;
      study exit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study is a non-commercial phase II randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled,&#xD;
      multi-centre study to test moderate dose prednisolone versus placebo in patients with early&#xD;
      diffuse cutaneous systemic sclerosis (dcSSc).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our aim is to investigate whether treatment with the steroid prednisolone is beneficial in&#xD;
      patients with early diffuse cutaneous systemic sclerosis (also termed &quot;scleroderma&quot;). This is&#xD;
      a controversial subject. Although it is very possible that prednisolone can help relieve the&#xD;
      severe pain, itching, and disability (due to contractures and musculoskeletal involvement) of&#xD;
      early diffuse scleroderma, doctors are often reluctant to prescribe prednisolone because of&#xD;
      possible side effects, particularly an increased risk of serious kidney problems. Our&#xD;
      proposed trial, treating patients with either prednisolone or placebo therapy for 6 months,&#xD;
      should provide clinicians with a long awaited answer to the important clinical question: Can&#xD;
      prednisolone be used as a therapy in this group of patients?&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study, funded by Arthritis Research UK, aims to determine:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Is moderate dose prednisolone effective in reducing pain, disability and skin thickening&#xD;
           in patients with early diffuse scleroderma?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Is moderate dose prednisolone a safe therapy in patients with early diffuse scleroderma&#xD;
           (with particular reference to kidney function)?&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the answer to both is 'yes', then prednisolone therapy will be much more widely prescribed&#xD;
      for this patient group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patient population will be selected from individuals with early dcSSc, as defined by skin&#xD;
      involvement of less than 3 years, who are considered potentially able to benefit from this&#xD;
      treatment. Following screening, to minimise bias, eligible patients will be randomised at the&#xD;
      baseline visit to receive either daily moderate dose prednisolone (as determined by body&#xD;
      weight) or a matched placebo. To further eliminate subjective and unrecognised bias both the&#xD;
      research team and patients will be blind to the randomisation. A placebo control, as opposed&#xD;
      to an active treatment control, will be administered. This is necessary as the study&#xD;
      treatment is adjunctive to and not a substitute for any other therapies which may be&#xD;
      prescribed, such as immunosuppressant therapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will attend on 5 occasions (screen, baseline, 6 weeks, 3 and 6 months). All patients&#xD;
      will be considered off-study at the end of the 6 month visit whereupon the treatment code&#xD;
      will be broken. At each visit a number of measurements will be taken including functional&#xD;
      ability, degree of skin involvement (skin score), mood and kidney function. This will allow&#xD;
      us to determine whether 'active' (prednisolone) therapy is effective and free from serious&#xD;
      side-effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Please note: from August 2020, due to Covid-19 the trial was re-designed and re-started&#xD;
      following trial halt as open-label. A placebo is no longer required. The aims, primary&#xD;
      outcome measures and number of visits remain unchanged. However, to further mitigate the&#xD;
      ongoing impact of Covid-19, the screen and baseline assessments may now be conducted at the&#xD;
      same visit. Remote visits can also be carried out at 6 weeks and 6 months, if necessary.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 21, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patients are allocated to received either prednisolone or matched placebo for the duration of the trial. The allocation is randomised 1:1.&#xD;
From August 2020: Under the open-label design, patients are allocated to receive prednisolone or no additional treatment. The randomisation allocation is 1:1.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Double-blind. The trial management team are blind to treatment allocation for the duration of the trial. The site research teams and patients are blind to treatment until code-break. At this point the on-site team and patient are unblind to allocation for continuing care. The site pharmacy personnel, PRedSS trial monitor and supervising statistician are unblind throughout.&#xD;
From August 2020: Open-Label - The patient, site research team and site pharmacy are unblind. The trial management team are unblind for patients recruited from August 2020 onwards but remain blind to patients randomised to trial under the double-blind design. The trial monitor and trial statistician continue to be unblind for all patients randomised to trial.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Health Assessment Questionnaire Disability Index (HAQ-DI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The mean difference in HAQ-DI at 3 months</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>modified Rodnan Skin Score (mRSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in mRSS at 3 months</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life and functional ability - Assessed by Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>HAQ-DI</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain and disability</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Skin involvement as measured by the mRSS</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional ability - Assessed by Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>11-point Scleroderma Functional Index</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain associated with itch - Assessed by Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of Pruritus</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hand function - Assessed by Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Cochin Hand Function</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fatigue - Assessed by Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Functional Assessment of Chronic Illness Therapy (FACIT)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety and depression - Assessed by questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS) . This questionnaire has 14 questions, each with 4 options designed to assess aspects of mental health</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health related quality of life - Assessed by Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Helplessness Questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health related quality of life - Assessed by Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Short Form (36) Health Survey</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health related quality of Life - Assessed by Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>EuroQol 5 Dimensions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain and disability</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient Global Assessment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain and disability</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Physician Global Assessment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of pain - Clinician assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Digital Ulcer Count: The site and total number of ulcers on the hand are recorded by the patients clinician on a diagram of a hand</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of pain - Clinician assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Tender Friction Rubs - the total number of tendon friction rubs on 12 possible anatomical sites are recorded</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of pain - Clinician assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Joint Count: The number of tender or swollen joints are assessed from 14 anatomical sites (both left and right side) and recorded out of a total of 28 (14 sites, left and right side) tender joints and 28 swollen joints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain and disability - Assessed by Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of Arthritis Index</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain and disability</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 6 weeks, 3 months and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment in percentage change of mRSS</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">72</enrollment>
  <condition>Systemic Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prednisolone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Prednisolone 5mg enteric-coated tablets, over-encapsulated in a hard gelatine capsule and filled with lactose BP. The prednisolone will be self-administered, orally with water before or after a meal once a day. Dosing will be continuous for a total of 6 months.&#xD;
The total dose prescribed will be equivalent to approximately 0.3mg/kg/day. The minimum dose prescribed will be 10mg per day (2 capsules) and a maximum of 30mg per day (6 capsules).&#xD;
From August 2020: The prednisolone is no longer over-encapsulated. Prednisolone 5mg enteric-coated tablets will be prescribed and taken as above.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo oral capsule; From August 2020 - 'no additional treatment'</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The placebo will be a hard gelatine capsule filled with lactose BP and identically matched to the prednisolone capsules. The placebo will be self-administered once a day, orally with water before or after a meal. Dosing will be continuous for a total of 6 months.&#xD;
From August 2020 - no placebo capsule will be administered.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prednisolone 5 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>5mg prednisolone, once a day for 6 months</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prednisolone</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo oral capsule; From August 2020 'no additional treatment'</intervention_name>
    <description>Matched placebo capsule, once a day for 6 months; From August 2020 - no additional treatment above standard of care medication</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo oral capsule; From August 2020 - 'no additional treatment'</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients presenting with dcSSc with skin involvement extending to the proximal limb&#xD;
             and/or trunk.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Male or female age ≥ 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Skin involvement of less than 3 years defined by patient report or clinician opinion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient is able and willing to follow the requirements of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Fully written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with significant uncontrolled Stage 1 Hypertension (clinic BP &gt;140/90mmHg&#xD;
             i.e. either &gt;140mmHg OR &gt;90mmHg). Patients with previous hypertension which is&#xD;
             controlled (clinic BP &lt;140/90mmHg) for at least 4 weeks are considered eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Previous renal crisis or significant renal impairment (estimated Glomerular Filtration&#xD;
             Rate (eGFR) &lt; 40 ml/min).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients currently on steroid therapy, or previous steroid therapy within the last 4&#xD;
             weeks, with the exception of inhaled steroids for respiratory diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients currently participating in another randomised controlled trial of an&#xD;
             investigational agent or device, or previous participation within the last 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients currently receiving an immunosuppressant or biologic therapy the dose of&#xD;
             which has changed in the last 4 weeks, or is likely to change during the first 3&#xD;
             months of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with major myositis or inflammatory arthritis. Patients with low level&#xD;
             myositis or inflammatory arthritis are eligible for inclusion (for example, in the&#xD;
             case of myositis, a creatine kinase less than 4 times the upper limit of normal or&#xD;
             myositis only demonstrable on magnetic resonance imaging).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Female patients who are pregnant at time of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Female patients who are breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients with significant inflammatory bowel disease as judged by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. It is important that patients do not suddenly stop taking the study medication.&#xD;
             Patients who do not fully understand this, will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients who are unwilling or unable to provide informed consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Professor Ariane Herrick</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Manchester</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Deb Griffiths-Jones, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>(+44) 161 275 1675</phone>
    <email>deb.griffiths-jones@manchester.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aberdeen Royal Infirmary - NHS Grampian</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aberdeen</city>
        <state>Aberdeenshire</state>
        <zip>AB25 2ZN</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dr Hazem Youssef</last_name>
      <email>hazem.youssef@nhs.scot</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Addenbrooke's Hospital - Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cambridge</city>
        <state>Cambridgeshire</state>
        <zip>CB2 0QQ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dr Frances Hall</last_name>
      <phone>+44 (0)1223 245 151</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Salford Royal NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salford</city>
        <state>Greater Manchester</state>
        <zip>M6 8HD</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Professor Ariane Herrick</last_name>
      <phone>+44 (0)161 789 7373</phone>
      <email>ariane.herrick@srft.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Glasgow Royal Infirmary -</name>
      <address>
        <city>Glasgow</city>
        <state>Lanarkshire</state>
        <zip>G4 0SF</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aintree University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Liverpool</city>
        <state>Merseyside</state>
        <zip>L9 7AL</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dr Marina Anderson</last_name>
      <phone>+44 (0)151 525 5980</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Queen's Medical Centre - Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nottingham</city>
        <state>Nottinghamshire</state>
        <zip>NG7 2UH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dr Peter Lanyon</last_name>
      <phone>+44 (0)115 924 9924</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal National Hospital For Rheumatic Diseases - Royal United Hospitals Bath NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bath</city>
        <state>Somerset</state>
        <zip>BA1 1RL</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dr John Pauling</last_name>
      <phone>+44 (0)1225 465941</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Hallamshire Hospital - Sheffield Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sheffield</city>
        <state>South Yorkshire</state>
        <zip>S10 2JF</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dr Mohammed Akil</last_name>
      <phone>+44 (0)114 271 1900</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Freeman Hospital - The Newcastle upon Tyne Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Newcastle Upon Tyne</city>
        <state>Tyne And Wear</state>
        <zip>NE7 7DN</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dr Bridget Griffiths</last_name>
      <phone>+44 (0)191 233 6161</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Dudley Group NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dudley</city>
        <state>West Midlands</state>
        <zip>DY1 2HQ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dr Karen Douglas</last_name>
      <email>karendouglas@nhs.net</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Leeds Institute of Rheumatic and Musculoskeletal Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leeds</city>
        <state>West Yorkshire</state>
        <zip>LS7 4SA</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Professor Maya Buch</last_name>
      <phone>+44 (0)113 392 4884</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Southmead Hospital Bristol - North Bristol NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bristol</city>
        <zip>BS10 5NB</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ninewells Hospital and Medical School - NHS Tayside</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dundee</city>
        <zip>DD1 9SY</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dr Smita Bhat</last_name>
      <email>smita.bhat@nhs.scot</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Free London NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>NW3 2QG</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Professor Christopher Denton</last_name>
      <phone>+44 (0)20 7794 0500</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 8, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 11, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 17, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 5, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 5, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 6, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Manchester</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Prof. Ariane herrick</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Rheumatology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diffuse cutaneous systemic sclerosis (dcSSc)</keyword>
  <keyword>Prednisolone</keyword>
  <keyword>Randomised Controlled Trial</keyword>
  <keyword>Disability</keyword>
  <keyword>Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Fatigue</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Scleroderma, Systemic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Scleroderma, Diffuse</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>IPD will be shared with collaborating centres. It is undecided if this information will be shared with researchers unconnected with the trial.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

