<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="563">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04742595</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-0759</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2020-13875</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-0759</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04742595</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SARS-CoV-2 Specific Cytotoxic T Lymphocytes for the Treatment of COVID-19 in Patients With Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Administration of Expanded, Most Closely HLA Matched SARS-CoV-2-Specific T Cells for the Treatment of COVID-19 in Patients With Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This early phase I trial evaluates the side effects of SARS-CoV-2 specific cytotoxic T&#xD;
      lymphocytes (CTLs) and their effect in treating patients with severe acute respiratory&#xD;
      syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection. CTLs are made from donated blood cells grown&#xD;
      in the laboratory and are designed to kill viruses that can cause infections. Giving CTLs may&#xD;
      help control the SARS-CoV-2 virus that causes coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To assess the feasibility and safety of administering most closely human leukocyte antigen&#xD;
      (HLA)-matched severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-COV-2) specific T cell&#xD;
      lines generated by ex vivo expansion as therapy of COVID19 pneumonia in cancer patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To obtain preliminary data about the efficacy of administering most closely HLA-matched&#xD;
      SARS-COV-2 specific T cell lines generated by ex vivo expansion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To assess the persistence of the administered cells in the patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive SARS-COV-2 specific cytotoxic T lymphocytes intravenously (IV) over 30&#xD;
      minutes on day 1. Treatment may repeat every 14 days at investigators' discretion if patients&#xD;
      fails to respond, the infection reoccurs, until the viral load becomes negative or until&#xD;
      complete resolution of clinical and radiological signs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 7, 14, 21, 28, and 45 days,&#xD;
      and 3 months after each cytotoxic T lymphocyte infusion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 18, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients who receive at least one severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-COV-2) specific cytotoxic T lymphocytes infusion</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 months post-infusion</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 months post-infusion</time_frame>
    <description>Will collect adverse events and grade them according to Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events version 4.0. Attribution will be assigned based on the relationship to the cell infusion.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Response to cytotoxic T lymphocytes</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 weeks post-infusion</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as extubation for patients who required intubation and mechanical ventilation, reduction in the need of oxygen of 50% or a reduction in the fraction of inspired oxygen (FiO2) below 30% or oxygen discontinuation for patients who are not intubated but require oxygen, or resolution of clinical and radiological signs and symptoms for patients who do not require oxygen. Proportion of patients experiencing response will be computed with associated 95% confidence interval.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>From treatment start date to date of death, assessed up to 3 months post-infusion</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated using the Kaplan-Meier method.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Relapse free survival (original malignancy)</measure>
    <time_frame>From treatment start date to the date of documented disease recurrence or death, assessed up to 3 months post-infusion</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated using the Kaplan-Meier method.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative incidence of coronavirus disease 2019 pneumonia resolution after therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 months post-infusion</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative incidence of grade 2-4 or 3-4 graft versus host disease (GVHD), and chronic GVHD</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 months post-infusion</time_frame>
    <description>Will be assessed using the competing risks method. The competing risks will include relapse and death and patients who are still alive without disease progression at end of study will be censored.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All-cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>At 28 days post-infusion</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects alive and free of respiratory failure</measure>
    <time_frame>At 28 days post-infusion</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reconstitution of anti-virus immunity</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 months post-infusion</time_frame>
    <description>Number of SARS-COV-2 specific T-cells in blood will be determined for each patient.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">16</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19-Associated Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>COVID-19-Associated Pneumonia</condition>
  <condition>Hematopoietic and Lymphoid Cell Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Symptomatic COVID-19 Infection Laboratory-Confirmed</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (SARS-COV-2 specific cytotoxic T cells)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive SARS-COV-2 specific cytotoxic T lymphocytes IV over 30 minutes on day 1. Treatment may repeat every 14 days at investigators' discretion if patients fails to respond, the infection reoccurs, until the viral load becomes negative or until complete resolution of clinical and radiological signs.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SARS-CoV-2 Antigen-specific Cytotoxic T-lymphocytes</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (SARS-COV-2 specific cytotoxic T cells)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SARS-CoV-2 Antigen-specific CTLs</other_name>
    <other_name>SARS-CoV-2 Antigen-specific Cytotoxic T Lymphocytes</other_name>
    <other_name>SARS-CoV-2-specific Cytotoxic T-lymphocytes</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients age 18 years or older with COVID19 pneumonia or acute respiratory distress&#xD;
             syndrome (ARDS), defined as patients with a positive SARS-CoV-2 positive reverse&#xD;
             transcriptase polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) test (bronchoalveolar lavage [BAL],&#xD;
             nasal or pharyngeal) within 2 weeks of enrollment and radiological and clinical signs&#xD;
             of pneumonia or ARDS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immunocompromised patient with cancer defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Recipients of an stem cell transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with hematological malignancies who have been in minimal residual&#xD;
                  disease (MRD)-negative complete remission (CR) for less than 3 years&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with hematological malignances who have received chemotherapy, targeted&#xD;
                  therapy or immunotherapy within 6 months prior enrolment and who are not planned&#xD;
                  to receive additional therapy for at least 6 weeks after the infusion. All&#xD;
                  non-hematological toxicity from prior therapy must have been recovered to grade&#xD;
                  II or less prior enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients organ solid malignances who have received chemotherapy, targeted therapy&#xD;
                  or immunotherapy within 6 months prior enrolment and who are not planned to&#xD;
                  receive additional chemotherapy, targeted therapy or immunotherapy for at least 6&#xD;
                  weeks after the infusion. All toxicity from prior therapy must have been&#xD;
                  recovered to grade II or less prior enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with hematological malignancies who have been in MRD-negative CR for&#xD;
                  more than 3 years and have a peripheral blood CD4 count &lt; 200 x 10^9cells/liter&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with organ solid malignancies who received chemotherapy, targeted&#xD;
                  therapy or immunotherapy more than six months prior enrolment and have a&#xD;
                  peripheral blood CD4 count &lt; 200 x 10^9cells/liter&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent and/or signed assent from patient, parent or guardian&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative pregnancy test in female patients of childbearing potential, defined as not&#xD;
             post-menopausal for 12 months or no previous surgical sterilization. Women of child&#xD;
             bearing potential must be willing to use an effective contraceptive measure while on&#xD;
             study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to comply with the study protocol requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving prednisone &gt; 0.1 mg/kg/day or equivalent at time of enrollment, or&#xD;
             who have received anti-thymocyte globulin (ATG) within 14 days or have received donor&#xD;
             lymphocyte infusion (DLI) or Campath within 28 days of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with other uncontrolled infections other than COVID19: For bacterial&#xD;
             infections, patients must be receiving therapy and have no signs of progressing&#xD;
             infection for 72 hours prior to enrollment. For fungal infections patients must be&#xD;
             receiving anti-fungal therapy and have no signs of progressing infection for 1 week&#xD;
             prior to enrollment. Progressing infection is defined as hemodynamic instability&#xD;
             attributable to sepsis or new symptoms, worsening physical signs or radiographic&#xD;
             findings attributable to infection. Persisting fever without other signs or symptoms&#xD;
             will not be interpreted as progressing infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnosky &lt; 70 prior to SARS-COV-2 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active acute graft versus host disease (GVHD) Grade &gt;= 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with primary lung cancer not in remission and patients with existing lung&#xD;
             metastasis of solid organ tumors&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David Marin</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M D Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>David Marin</last_name>
      <phone>713-792-4179</phone>
      <email>dmarin@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>David Marin</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 3, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Laboratory Infection</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Adult</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acute Lung Injury</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

