<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2277">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04743401</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>F3731-P</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>42402</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04743401</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Feasibility of a Tele-game-based Exercise (Tele-exergame) Program to Prevent Deconditioning in Hospitalized COVID-19 Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Feasibility of a Tele-game-based Exercise (Tele-exergame) Program to Prevent Deconditioning in Hospitalized COVID-19 Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Baylor College of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Conventional face-to-face in-hospital mobility program (MP) is challenging for&#xD;
      COVID-19 patients because of its associated risk of infection to hospital staff, staffing&#xD;
      shortages as well as indirect risk of exposure to other hospitalized patients. Exergames are&#xD;
      digital or web-based games that use body movement to promote physical activity and generally&#xD;
      involve strength, balance, and flexibility exercises. The tele-exergame MP, developed by the&#xD;
      team, uses a remotely supervised and game-based approach, which helps to increase patient&#xD;
      motivation and engagement in a cognitively demanding exercise program.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives: To demonstrate the feasibility, acceptability, and effectiveness of the&#xD;
      Tele-Exergame mobility program in COVID-19 or PUI (persons under investigation), during&#xD;
      hospitalization and examine post-hospitalization outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Design: Prospective randomized&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      KEY RESEARCH AIMS:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 1: To examine feasibility of Tele-exergame. The investigators will evaluate feasibility&#xD;
      by documenting missing exercise sessions, exercise dropout, and acceptability questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2: To examine proof of concept effectiveness to reduce deconditioning. The investigators&#xD;
      will assess deconditioning (using wearables) and patient reported mental health assessed at&#xD;
      baseline at discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 3: Examine proof of concept effectiveness to accelerate recovery post hospital discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 4 weeks after discharge, patients will be contacted by telemedicine or&#xD;
      telephone and requested to self-report on the Veterans mental health and the Veterans&#xD;
      mobility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS:&#xD;
&#xD;
      COVID-19 patients or PUI (persons under investigation) admitted to the MEDVAMC (n=60), with&#xD;
      an anticipated length of stay of at least 3 days will be recruited. Participants will be&#xD;
      randomized (n=1:1) to either intervention (IG) or control (CG) groups. Both groups will&#xD;
      receive standard of care. IG will additionally receive Tele-Exergame MP therapy.&#xD;
      Tele-Exergame sessions will range from 3-10 minutes based on patient ability and completed&#xD;
      twice daily. They will complete assessments at baseline and at one-month post-hospital&#xD;
      discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SCIENTIFIC MERIT:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The proposed contact-less mobility program could address the limitations of conventional&#xD;
      in-hospital mobility program and advance the field of in-hospital exercise program.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will use innovative wearables to exploring potential digital biomarkers of&#xD;
      hospital-acquired illness including cognitive-frailty. illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will advance the field of remote patient monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
      BENEFIT TO VETERANS:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Its implementation not only for mobility program for hospitalized COVID-19 Veteran patients&#xD;
      but also to deliver personalized exercise for non-COVID-19 Veteran patients with limited&#xD;
      mobility including in bedbound and hospitalized Veteran patients Mobilizing hospitalized&#xD;
      Veteran patients could mitigate hospital acquired complications like deconditioning, VTE and&#xD;
      nosocomial infections and accelerate recovery post hospitalization&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>COVID-19 patients or PUI (persons under investigation) admitted to the MEDVAMC (n=60), with an anticipated length of stay of at least 3 days will be recruited. Participants will be randomized (n=1:1) to either intervention (IG) or control (CG) groups. Both groups will receive standard of care. IG will additionally receive Tele-Exergame MP therapy. Tele-Exergame sessions will range from 3-10 minutes based on patient ability and completed twice daily. They will complete assessments at baseline and at one-month post-hospital discharge.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Exercise dropout rate</measure>
    <time_frame>The time frame will be from enrollment to within the first week of inpatient stay</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will evaluate feasibility of Tele-Exergame objectively by documenting the daily missed exercise session and exercise dropout within the first week of inpatient stay.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Katz Activities of Daily Living Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>The time frame will be from enrollment to 4 weeks post discharge</time_frame>
    <description>The investigators will assess deconditioning and patient reported community mobility by the Katz Activities of Daily Living Scale questionnaire at baseline, within the first week of inpatient stay and at 4 weeks.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Measuring cognition (MOCA) scale</measure>
    <time_frame>The time frame will be from enrollment to 4 weeks post discharge</time_frame>
    <description>The MOCA ( Montreal Cognitive Assessment Scale) will be used to measure cognition at baseline, within the first week of inpatient stay and at 4 weeks .</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID 19</condition>
  <condition>Rehabilitation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Tele-exergame arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>COVID-19 patients or PUI (persons under investigation) admitted to the MEDVAMC (n=60), with an anticipated length of stay of at least 3 days will be recruited. Participants will be randomized (n=1:1) to either intervention (IG) or control (CG) groups. Both groups will receive standard of care. IG will additionally receive Tele-Exergame MP therapy. Tele-Exergame sessions will range from 3-10 minutes based on patient ability and completed twice daily. They will complete assessments at baseline and at one-month post-hospital discharge.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Convention care or control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard of care only</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tele-exergaming Tablet</intervention_name>
    <description>The Tele-Exergame platform virtually supervises exercise tasks and coaches patients to perform evidence-based foot and ankle exercises that have been designed to improve balance, cognition, and lower extremity vascular health.&#xD;
The exergame program uses a game-based approach, similar to playing a video game, which helps to increase patient motivation and engagement in the cognitively demanding exercise program.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Tele-exergame arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants: Men or women Veterans with COVID-19 or PUI admitted to MEDVAMC.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Length of stay: Anticipated length of stay at least 3 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ambulatory. Self-report of being ambulatory with or without an assistive device in the&#xD;
             2 weeks before admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ICU admission: The investigators will exclude those admitted to ICU at any point in&#xD;
             their hospital stay.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Admission of observation only: These patients will be excluded as length of stay is&#xD;
             usually anticipated to be less than 3 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Median life expectancy: Those with imminently terminal (death expected in the next 30&#xD;
             days) will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive impairment: The investigators will exclude those with delirium, dementia, or&#xD;
             severe cognitive impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical condition: The investigators will exclude those who have any medical diagnosis&#xD;
             deemed by the primary physician to be a contraindication to ambulation (i.e.: unstable&#xD;
             from pulmonary embolus, unstable angina, severe hemodynamic instability etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Foot problem: The investigators will exclude those who have active foot ulcer or&#xD;
             infection or major lower extremities amputation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vision or hearing problems: The investigators will exclude those with hearing or&#xD;
             visual problems that cannot be corrected with medical devices (glasses or hearing&#xD;
             aids). Hearing or visual problems can limit their ability to interact with the&#xD;
             exergame platform.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  lack of capacity to consent, and inability or unwillingness to participate regularly&#xD;
             in the exercise program;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unable to communicate in English or Spanish, or unlikely to fully comply with the&#xD;
             follow-up protocol (e.g., lack of caregiver support to safely perform exercise tasks&#xD;
             at home or complete the questionnaires).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Clarifying exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing treatment: The investigators will NOT exclude those who are participating in&#xD;
             standard of care physical therapy program (Receipt of Physical Therapy (PT),&#xD;
             Occupational Therapy (OT), Speech Therapy (ST), Mental Health (MH), and Social Work&#xD;
             (SW) Services). However, the investigators will document these services and will&#xD;
             control for it. However, those who are receiving non- standard of care exercise&#xD;
             therapy (e.g. other exercise research study) or receiving active intensive or&#xD;
             induction therapy for cancer (e.g. undergoing active initial chemotherapy or&#xD;
             radiotherapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Others: The investigators will NOT exclude but will document common comorbidities such&#xD;
             as pneumonia, heart failure, and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease exacerbations.&#xD;
             Pulmonary embolism or acute coronary syndrome maybe included if there is no&#xD;
             contraindications like severe hemodynamic instability or active angina.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sarvari V Yellapragada, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Michael E. DeBakey VA Medical Center, Houston, TX</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sarvari V Yellapragada, MD</last_name>
    <phone>(713) 794-7303</phone>
    <email>sarvari.yellapragada@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Michael E. DeBakey VA Medical Center, Houston, TX</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Paula A Kinsel</last_name>
      <phone>713-794-7939</phone>
      <email>Paula.Kinsel@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Christine M Eriks</last_name>
      <phone>(713) 791-1414</phone>
      <phone_ext>26714</phone_ext>
      <email>Christine.Eriks@va.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sarvari V Yellapragada, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>gaming</keyword>
  <keyword>exer-gaming</keyword>
  <keyword>telemedicine</keyword>
  <keyword>inpatient</keyword>
  <keyword>deconditioning</keyword>
  <keyword>mobility</keyword>
  <keyword>rehabilitation</keyword>
  <keyword>virtual</keyword>
  <keyword>persons under investigation for COVID</keyword>
  <keyword>PUI</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

