<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2141">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04360278</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>200092</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>20-CC-0092</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04360278</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Plasma Collection From Convalescent and/or Immunized Donors for the Treatment of COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Plasma Collection From Convalescent and/or Immunized Donors for the Treatment of COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic is a major public health issue. Right now,&#xD;
      there is no vaccine to keep people from getting sick. There is also no treatment for people&#xD;
      who do get sick. Researchers want to collect plasma from people who have recovered from&#xD;
      COVID-19. The plasma will have antibodies against the virus that causes COVID-19. If a&#xD;
      vaccine is made, people who develop immunity from the vaccine can also donate plasma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To collect plasma from people who have recovered from COVID-19 or have been vaccinated&#xD;
      against the coronavirus that causes COVID-19, so that the plasma can be used to treat people&#xD;
      with the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults ages 18 and older who have been diagnosed with, and have recovered from, COVID-19, or&#xD;
      have been vaccinated against the virus that causes COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with a physical exam, medical history, and blood sample. Their&#xD;
      pulse, blood pressure, and temperature will be taken. Their height and weight will be&#xD;
      recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will donate plasma. It will be collected through whole blood donation or through&#xD;
      apheresis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For whole blood donation, a needle will be placed in the participant s arm vein. Blood will&#xD;
      be withdrawn.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For apheresis, a needle will be placed in the participant s arm vein. Blood will be&#xD;
      withdrawn. A machine will separate the plasma from the red cells. The plasma will be removed,&#xD;
      and the rest of the cells will be returned to the participant either through the same needle&#xD;
      or through a needle in their other arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have 3 to 20 plasma donations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation will last up to 240 days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Emerging infectious diseases such as the Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic cause&#xD;
      substantial morbidity and mortality. During the early emergent phases of such diseases, there&#xD;
      is often no vaccine to prevent infection, nor specific therapeutic agent to treat the&#xD;
      disease. The objective of this protocol is the collection of immune plasma from persons&#xD;
      post-recovery from COVID-19 or vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
      against SARS-CoV-2. This plasma may potentially be used in the treatment or prophylaxis of&#xD;
      active COVID-19 under other protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Candidates will be screened for eligibility to participate in plasma donations and their&#xD;
      blood levels of antibodies to SARS-CoV-2. Enrolled subjects will receive a baseline physical&#xD;
      and laboratory examination. Subjects with sufficient anti-SARS-CoV-2 antibody titers who meet&#xD;
      standard blood bank criteria for plasma donation will then be scheduled for plasma&#xD;
      collections. Plasmapheresis is the preferred method of collection, with up to 800 mL of&#xD;
      plasma collected per donation depending on the weight of the donor. Collected immune plasma&#xD;
      will be tested for blood-borne pathogens, and stored according to standard blood bank&#xD;
      procedures. The scope of this protocol is limited to collection of plasma from subjects with&#xD;
      sufficiently high anti-SARS-CoV-2 antibody titer. Any administration of&#xD;
&#xD;
      convalescent immune plasma to subjects will be performed under a separate protocol.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 21, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 14, 2030</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 14, 2030</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Collection of convalescent plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>240 days</time_frame>
    <description>Successful collection of convalescent or immunized donor plasma.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1500</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Plasma Donors</arm_group_label>
    <description>Persons who have recovered from COVID-19 or have been immunized against SARS-CoV-2 who meet criteria to donate plasma.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Community donors who have recovered from COVID-19, or have been immunized against&#xD;
        SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability of subject to understand, ask questions, and the willingness to sign the&#xD;
             written informed consent document&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;=18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to meet blood donor eligibility criteria as defined in the FDA Code of Federal&#xD;
             Regulations 21 CFR 630, AABB Standards and DTM SOP, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Weight &gt;=110 pounds (50 kg)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Adequate peripheral venous access for plasma donation (as judged by the examiner)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Vital signs (with exceptions as acceptable per DTM SOP)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For COVID-19 convalescent subjects, the following criteria must be met:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prior diagnosis of COVID-19 documented by a laboratory test or by physician&#xD;
                  attestation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Complete resolution of symptoms for at least 14 days prior to donation, with&#xD;
                  negative results for COVID-19 either from one or more nasopharyngeal swab&#xD;
                  specimens or by a molecular diagnostic test from blood. A partial list of&#xD;
                  available tests can be accessed at&#xD;
                  https://www.fda.gov/medical-devices/emergency-situations-medicaldevices/&#xD;
                  emergency-use-authorizations&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  If the donor is &gt;= 28 days from date of last COVID-19-related symptom, then a&#xD;
                  negative COVID-19 test results are not needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Donors with residual loss of taste/smell are acceptable as long as they have no&#xD;
                  acute symptoms of COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For vaccinated subjects, the following criteria must be met:&#xD;
&#xD;
             --Subjects must be at least 14 days post-vaccination with an FDA-approved vaccine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to engage in repeat plasma collections for a 120-day period with possible&#xD;
             extension to 240 days, provided anti-SARS-CoV-2 titers remain sufficiently high&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to have samples stored for clinical and/or genetic research testing&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who cannot give proper informed consent due to inability to understand the&#xD;
             nature of the proposed therapy and attendant risk&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age under 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females must not be pregnant (per routine blood donor criteria)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any sign of active infection, including but not limited to:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subjective or documented fever (&gt;37.5 (Infinite)C)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cough&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Shortness of breath&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Diarrhea&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Antibiotics within the prior 48 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Considered immune suppressed for example current use of oral or parenteral steroids,&#xD;
             highdose inhaled steroids (&gt;800 micrograms/day of beclomethasone dipropionate or&#xD;
             equivalent) or other immunosuppressive or cytotoxic drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Permanent deferral from blood donation as defined in the FDA Code of Federal&#xD;
             Regulations 21 CFR 630, AABB Standards, and DTM SOP&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in medical research outside DTM that includes:&#xD;
&#xD;
             --Protocols that are currently ongoing or will start during the duration of this study&#xD;
             that require more than 500 mL of blood to be given in any 8-week period of time&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of any investigational (not FDA-approved) vaccine for SARS-CoV-2 within the&#xD;
             last 12 months or during the duration of this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total plasma protein level &lt; 6.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwillingness to engage in repeat plasma collections for a 120-day period with&#xD;
             possible extension to 240 days, provided anti-SARS-CoV-2 titers remain sufficiently&#xD;
             high&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwillingness to have samples stored for clinical and/or genetic research testing&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kamille A West, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sarah Pogue, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 435-2432</phone>
    <email>spogue1@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2020-CC-0092.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>January 6, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 22, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 22, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Titer</keyword>
  <keyword>Antibodies</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

