<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4103">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04591184</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ENTVAX01-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04591184</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Clinical Trial of a Plasmid DNA Vaccine for COVID-19 [Covigenix VAX-001] in Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I/II Trial to Evaluate Safety, Tolerability, Immunogenicity of a Prophylactic Plasmid DNA Vaccine for SARS CoV-2 [Covigenix VAX-001] in Healthy Adults From 18 to &lt;85 Years of Age</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Entos Pharmaceuticals Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Canadian Institutes of Health Research (CIHR)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Entos Pharmaceuticals Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase I/II, placebo-controlled, randomized, observer-blind, dose ranging adaptive&#xD;
      clinical trial in males and non-pregnant females, 18 to &lt;55 and 65 to &lt;85 years of age, who&#xD;
      are in good health and meet all eligibility criteria. This clinical trial is designed to&#xD;
      assess the safety, reactogenicity, immunogenicity and efficacy of Covigenix VAX-001&#xD;
      manufactured by Entos Pharmaceuticals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Phase I portion of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      ENTVAX01-101 is a phase I/II, placebo-controlled, randomized, observer-blind, dose ranging&#xD;
      adaptive clinical trial in males and non-pregnant females, 18 to &lt;55 and 65 to &lt;85 years of&#xD;
      age, who are in good health and meet all eligibility criteria. This clinical trial is&#xD;
      designed to assess the safety, reactogenicity, immunogenicity and efficacy of Covigenix&#xD;
      manufactured by Entos Pharmaceuticals. Covigenix VAX-001is a novel plasmid DNA-based vaccine&#xD;
      that encodes for the full-length Spike gene from SARS-CoV-2 (VAX-001 encapsulated in a&#xD;
      proprietary Fusogenix Proteo-Lipid Vehicle (PLV)).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enrollment for the phase I portion of the study will occur at one Canadian site. Seventy two&#xD;
      subjects will be enrolled in a staggered manner into one of two cohorts (0.100 mg &amp; 0.250 mg&#xD;
      vs. placebo) in stage I, where Adults (18 to &lt;55 years) will be enrolled first and Older&#xD;
      Adults (65 to &lt;85 years) will be enrolled if safety data permit. Subjects will receive an&#xD;
      intramuscular (IM) injection (0.5 milliliter [mL]) on Days 0 and 14 in the deltoid muscle of&#xD;
      alternating arms and will be followed through 6 months post booster vaccination (Day 196).&#xD;
      Follow-up visits will occur at Days 7, 14, 17, 21, 28, 42, and 196.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective is to evaluate the safety of a 2-dose vaccination schedule of the&#xD;
      Covigenix VAX-001 vaccine, given 14 days apart. The secondary objectives are to evaluate the&#xD;
      humoral immune response as measured by Immunoglobulin G (IgG) ELISA to the SARS-CoV-2 S&#xD;
      protein and by pseudo-viral neutralization assay to pseudo-virion following a 2-dose&#xD;
      vaccination schedule of Covigenix VAX-001.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical safety data will be collected at the Day 0 of the study and at defined intervals&#xD;
      (Dose 1: Days 7, 14; Dose 2: Days: 21, 42).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical safety lab testing&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Hematology &amp; Biochemistry:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Immunogenicity testing:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ELISA and pseudo-viral neutralization tests&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  % of responders or individuals who seroconvert (with 95% CI): develop immune response&#xD;
           defined as a 4-fold or greater rise.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Geometric mean concentration/geometric mean titers (with 95% CI) and&#xD;
           pre-/post-vaccination ratios (geometric mean ratios) provide absolute values and&#xD;
           increase in antibody titers at defined time points after each vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Reverse cumulative distribution (RCD) curves display percentage of participants versus&#xD;
           antibody levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following immunogenicity tests will be performed as exploratory objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  SARS-CoV-2 neutralization antibody responses at Days 0, 7, 14, 21, 28, 42, 196.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Antigen-specific B&amp;T cell interferon (IFN)-γ cell responses measured by ELISPOT up to&#xD;
           Day 196.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Antigen-specific T cell responses measured by flow cytometry up to Day 196&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Antigen-specific T cell responses including cluster of differentiation (CD)4+ and CD8+&#xD;
           cytotoxic T lymphocytes (CTLs), through ICS up to Day 196&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Whole blood immunophenotyping (B and T cell repertoire (BCR and TCR) as measured by high&#xD;
           throughput sequencing of lymphocyte antigen receptor genes, SCS, and RNAseq to identify&#xD;
           all genes regulated by the vaccine) up to Day 196&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Biomarker and cytokine analysis by IM and BM up to Day 196. Sample size: 72&#xD;
           participants, 48 test subjects and 24 placebo controls;&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study plan:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Table 1. Study groups and treatments Arm Intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Experimental: Low dose (0.100mg), 18-&lt;55 years, 2 doses Biological: Covigenix VAX-001,&#xD;
           0.5 mL IM injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Experimental: Intermediate dose (0.250mg), 18-&lt;55 years, 2 doses Biological: Covigenix&#xD;
           VAX-001, 0.5 mL IM injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Placebo Comparator: Placebo, 18-&lt;55 years Other: Placebo, 0.5 mL IM injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Experimental: Low dose (0.100mg), 65-&lt;85 years, 2 doses Biological: Covigenix VAX-001,&#xD;
           0.5 mL IM injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Experimental: Intermediate dose (0.250mg), 65-&lt;85 years, 2 doses Biological: Covigenix&#xD;
           VAX-001, 0.5 mL IM injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Placebo Comparator: Placebo, 65-&lt;85 years Other: Placebo, 0.5 mL IM injection&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enrollment plan:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enrollment plan: Study participants will be enrolled in a staged manner at each age level&#xD;
      (Adult and Older Adult) and dosage level (Low and Intermediate), as described below:&#xD;
&#xD;
      First, three participants of the Adult cohort will be randomized (2:1; Groups 1 and 3) to the&#xD;
      low dose of Covigenix VAX-001 or placebo, a minimum of one hour apart. Once three&#xD;
      participants have received treatment there will be a 72-hour waiting period, and if no&#xD;
      holding rule is met then the remaining participants from Group 1 and 3 will be vaccinated, a&#xD;
      minimum of 30 minutes apart. Similarly, once 7-day safety data are available on a minimum of&#xD;
      75% (n=14) of participants in Groups 1/3, 1) participants of the Adult cohort will be&#xD;
      randomized (2:1; groups 2 and 3) to the intermediate dose of Covigenix VAX-001 or placebo, a&#xD;
      minimum of one hour apart (up to 6 participants per day), and 2) participants of the Older&#xD;
      Adult cohort will be randomized (2:1, groups 4 and 6) to the low dose of Covigenix VAX-001 or&#xD;
      placebo, a minimum of one hour apart (up to 6 participants per day).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once 7-day safety data are available on a minimum of 75% (n=14) of participants in Groups&#xD;
      4/6, participants of the Older Adult cohort will be randomized (2:1; groups 5 and 6) to the&#xD;
      intermediate dose of Covigenix VAX-001 or placebo, a minimum of one hour apart.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After review of day 42 data (Day 28 post second dose) on participants in Groups 1/3 (Adults,&#xD;
      low dose) and Groups 4/6 (Older Adults, mid dose), it will be decided whether these cohorts&#xD;
      will be enrolled in the Ph II of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Infection during the study: During the observation period of the study, if fever and&#xD;
      respiratory symptoms with cough develop in a participant, he/she should immediately follow&#xD;
      local procedures for care of suspected COVID-19 illness and contact the study team. The&#xD;
      participant's nasopharyngeal swab/sputum will be collected and tested for SARS-CoV-2 at a&#xD;
      designated provincial testing center. If a COVID-19 infection is found during the study, a&#xD;
      case investigation will be undertaken. Careful monitoring for vaccine-related enhanced&#xD;
      disease will be undertaken in conjunction with the participant's primary physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to the real-time PCR testing for SARS-CoV-2, the collected nasopharyngeal&#xD;
      swab/sputum will be tested for other respiratory pathogens.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study duration: 7 months&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design for the phase II portion of the study: The study design for the phase II portion&#xD;
      of the study will be detailed in an amended synopsis/study protocol.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Unblinded study nurse with no other role in the trial administers VAX-001. Observer blinded.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of a 2-dose regimen of VAX-001 when doses are given 14 days apart</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 42</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency and Grade (mild, moderate, severe, potentially life-threatening; Gr. 1-4, respectively) of solicited injection site and systemic adverse events and unsolicited systemic adverse events</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean change from baseline in safety laboratory measures</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 0-42</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse hematology /clinical chemistry parameter changes (mild, moderate, severe, or life-threatening; Gr. 1-4, respectively)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of treatment-emergent Serious Adverse Events (SAE) throughout the study and up to 6 months post-second dose immunization (Day 196).</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 0-196</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of serious AEs</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent seroconversion defined as a 4-fold or greater increase in IgG titers after one or two doses as measured by IgG ELISA</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 196</time_frame>
    <description>Percent seroconversion post second dose as measured by ELISA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric mean neutralizing antibody titers against pseudo-virion after one and two doses</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 196</time_frame>
    <description>Geometric mean of antibody titers measured by pseudo-viral neutralization assay.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent seroconversion defined as a 4-fold or greater increase in IgG titers after one or two doses as measured by pseudo-viral neutralization assay.</measure>
    <time_frame>up to Day 196</time_frame>
    <description>Seroconversion as measured by pseudo-viral neutralization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Persistence of IgG antibody titers as measured by ELISA and neutralizing antibody titers measured by pseudo-virion neutralization assay, six months after the second vaccine dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 196</time_frame>
    <description>Maintenance of antibody titers up to Six months post second dose</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">72</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV-2</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active VAX-001</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose-ranging, 2 dose levels and 2 age groups. 24 subjects receiving active i.m. vaccine/arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>placebo injection. 12 subjects receiving placebo/arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Covigenix VAX-001 placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo vaccine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Covigenix VAX-001</intervention_name>
    <description>Active Covigenix VAX-001</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active VAX-001</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy adults from 18 to &lt;55 years or 65 to &lt;85 years at the time of enrollment&#xD;
             (dependent upon study stage);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If female of child-bearing potential and heterosexually active, must have practiced&#xD;
             adequate contraception for 30 days prior to injection, have a negative pregnancy test&#xD;
             on the day of injection, and have agreed to continue adequate contraception until 90&#xD;
             days after the second injection. (Please refer to the glossary for the definition of&#xD;
             child-bearing potential and adequate contraception);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide consent to participate in and having signed an Informed Consent Form&#xD;
             (ICF);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to complete all the scheduled study procedures during the whole study&#xD;
             follow-up period (about 7 months);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative result of HIV, hepatitis B and C screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Oral temperature &lt; 38.0ºC;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative IgG and IgM antibodies against COVID-19, from RCT test;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative result of real-time quantitative PCR screening of nasopharyngeal swabs/sputum&#xD;
             for SARS-CoV-2;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hematological (including biochemistry) examination is within normal range, or no&#xD;
             greater than a grade 1 abnormality and no clinical significance as assessed by the&#xD;
             study investigator including: Complete Blood Count (CBC), hemoglobin (Hgb), platelets&#xD;
             (PLT), prothrombin time (PT), partial thromboplastin time (PTT), alanine transaminase&#xD;
             (ALT), aspartate transaminase (AST), alkaline phosphatase (ALP), total bilirubin (T&#xD;
             Bil), creatinine (Cr), Lipase, and blood glucose,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Transient mild laboratory abnormalities may be rescreened once, and the participant&#xD;
             will be deemed eligible if the laboratory repeat test is normal as per local&#xD;
             laboratory normal values.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Good general health status, as determined by history and physical examination no&#xD;
             greater than 14 days prior to administration of the test article.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Personal history of seizure disorder, encephalopathy or psychosis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergic history to any vaccine, or allergic to any vaccine ingredient;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Woman who is pregnant (positive urine pregnancy test) or lactating, or plans to become&#xD;
             pregnant during the next 3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any acute febrile disease (oral temperature ≥38.0○C) or active infectious disease on&#xD;
             the day of vaccination;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical history of SARS (SARS-CoV-1);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious cardiovascular diseases, such as arrhythmia, conduction block, history of&#xD;
             myocardial infarction, severe hypertension not controlled with medication;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious chronic disease such as asthma, diabetes and thyroid disease, etc.;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immunodeficiency, asplenia or functional asplenia;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet disorder or other bleeding disorder that may cause intramuscular injection&#xD;
             contraindication;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immunosuppressive medication, anti-allergic, cytotoxic therapy, inhaled&#xD;
             corticosteroids (excluding corticosteroid spray for allergic rhinitis, surface&#xD;
             corticosteroid therapy for acute non-complicated dermatitis) in the last 6 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior administration of blood products in last 4 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other vaccination(s) or investigational drugs within 1 month before study onset, or&#xD;
             planned use during the study period;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior administration of any live attenuated vaccine within 1 month before study onset;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior administration of subunit or inactivated non-SARS-CoV-2 vaccine within 1 month&#xD;
             before study onset;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior administration of any other vaccine considered (or being considered) to protect&#xD;
             against SARS-CoV-2 any time before study onset or during study period;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior participation in other studies involving study intervention containing lipid&#xD;
             nanoparticles;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that, in the opinion of the investigators, may interfere with the&#xD;
             participant's compliance or evaluation of study objectives or informed consent (i.e.&#xD;
             medical, psychological, social or other conditions, etc.);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), current smoker or vaper.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hypertension.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or diagnosis of coagulopathies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index (BMI) &gt;30kg/m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High risk of acquiring SARS-CoV-2 infection due to surroundings, contacts or&#xD;
             circumstances. Explicitly exclude healthcare and &quot;essential workers&quot;/at risk&#xD;
             population.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>84 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Scott A. Halperin, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Canadian Center for Vaccinology, Dalhousie University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sally Jones</last_name>
    <phone>+1 780-902-7078</phone>
    <email>sally.jones@entospharma.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Gregory Reid, M.Sc, MBA</last_name>
    <phone>+1 514-506-1542</phone>
    <email>gregory.reid@entospharma.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>anti-infective</keyword>
  <keyword>prophylaxis</keyword>
  <keyword>healthy volunteer</keyword>
  <keyword>prevention</keyword>
  <keyword>Covigenix VAX-001</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

