<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4644">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04107402</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PLACCSEPS</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2018/11DEC/469</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04107402</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PLatelets Acetyl-CoA Carboxylase Phosphorylation State in SEPtic Shock</brief_title>
  <acronym>PLACCSEPS</acronym>
  <official_title>Prospective Evaluation of PLatelets Acetyl-CoA Carboxylase Phosphorylation State in SEPtic Shock Patients. Impact of Platelets Metabolism to Inflammatory Response.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cliniques universitaires Saint-Luc- Université Catholique de Louvain</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cliniques universitaires Saint-Luc- Université Catholique de Louvain</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Knowing the dramatic increase in thrombin generation during sepsis, our research hypothesis&#xD;
      is that AMPK-induced ACC phosphorylation in platelets is increased and that this might&#xD;
      modulate platelets metabolism and more particularly platelets inflammatory mediators content,&#xD;
      coming from AA and lipids.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sepsis, a systemic inflammatory reaction occurring in response to an infection, is a major&#xD;
      public health problem and is recognized as the leading cause of death in the intensive care&#xD;
      unit (ICU). This severe inflammatory reaction causes endothelial activation and dysfunction.&#xD;
      This phenomenon is closely associated with the activation of coagulation cascade via exposure&#xD;
      of tissue factor (TF) at endothelial cell surface. TF serves as an anchor for factors of&#xD;
      coagulation VII and X allowing their activation. This results in thrombin (IIa) generation&#xD;
      and fibrin production.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thrombin is also a potent platelet agonist (activator) resulting in platelet activation and&#xD;
      consumption. The pro-coagulant activity of activated platelets during sepsis enhances the&#xD;
      formation of micro-thrombosis that impair organ perfusion and may lead to death.&#xD;
      Thrombocytopenia is common and is a strong negative prognostic marker in septic shock&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Beyond coagulation, platelets are known to play a key role in inflammation and immune&#xD;
      response. Platelets activation can be initiated by inflamed endothelium or circulatory&#xD;
      inflammatory cytokines, which in turn, modulates the inflammatory and thrombotic response.&#xD;
      Activated platelets interact with immune cells, like neutrophils. Furthermore, platelets can&#xD;
      act as microbial &quot;sensors&quot; by expressing members of Toll-Like Receptors (TLRs) family,&#xD;
      binding ligands from several infectious agents. Recent data highlight the interplay between&#xD;
      platelets and neutrophils extracellular traps (NETs). Platelets facilitate NETs formation&#xD;
      and, inversely, NETS activate platelets. NETs connect platelets, thrombosis, immune response&#xD;
      and inflammation and therefore are of particular interest in the septic context.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Platelets express Acetyl-CoA carboxylase 1 (ACC1), which is the first step enzyme of&#xD;
      lipogenesis. ACC Phosphorylation on Serine 79 by AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) leads to&#xD;
      its inhibition and AMPK is activated by thrombin. We demonstrated that AMPK-ACC axis controls&#xD;
      platelets phospholipids content, which influence TXA2 and dense granule release and, in turn,&#xD;
      thrombus formation. TXA2 is generated from phospholipids containing arachidonic acid (AA).&#xD;
      Alternatively, AA can be metabolized by lipooxygenase (LOX) pathway producing lipoxins (LX)&#xD;
      and resolvin, which are rather involved in the resolution of inflammation. The relation&#xD;
      between AMPK-ACC signalling and lipooxygenase pathway has never been investigated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research hypothesis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Knowing the dramatic increase in thrombin generation during sepsis, our research hypothesis&#xD;
      is that AMPK-induced ACC phosphorylation in platelets is increased and that this might&#xD;
      modulate platelets metabolism and more particularly platelets inflammatory mediators content,&#xD;
      coming from AA and lipids.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients selection&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consecutive patients with septic shock admitted at Cliniques universitaires Saint-Luc,&#xD;
      Brussels, will be included (experimental group)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control group will correspond to healthy volunteers with matched age and gender, based on&#xD;
      retrospective analysis of patients admitted in ICU for sepsis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory control group will correspond to patients admitted in the intensive care unit&#xD;
      without evidence of severe infection and severe systemic inflammatory response. Patients with&#xD;
      neurological disorder and intoxication will be the target population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Similar exclusion criteria will be the same in control groups than in the experimental group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Material and methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Type of study Prospective, monocentric, interventional study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood sampling Blood samples will be collected after venous catheter insertion, within 48&#xD;
      hours after septic shock diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following samples will be taken during the procedure:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Coagulation including (INR, TCA, TT, PTT, Fibrinogen, DDimers) (1 green TUBE of 3 ml)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Multiplate analysis (1 orange TUBE of 3 ml)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood sample for platelets protein analysis (including ACC phosphorylation). After&#xD;
           platelets isolation, the remaining plasma will be frozen (2 TUBES CPDA of 8.5 ml).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Urine sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection Data will be collected from Medical Explorer and Q Care, including biological&#xD;
      data that are routinely performed in patients admitted in the ICU as platelets count, CRP&#xD;
      level, coagulation assessment, renal function and liver enzymology. Follow-up will be&#xD;
      performed by at least 3 years and no additional visits will be planned. Events recorded&#xD;
      during the follow-up period will be obtained from Medical Explorer and a phone call will be&#xD;
      done in case of missing data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Measurements&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood cells count including platelets.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ACC phosphorylation via western blotting, ECLIA.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Platelets protein extract for protein acetylation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Platelet function ex vivo using Multiplate analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Plasma sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Platelets lipidomics analysis. ACC phosphorylation analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Plasma-rich-platelet (PRP) will be obtained after centrifugation. Apyrase and Integrilin&#xD;
           are added to limit platelet activation during preparation. PRP will be divided into 3&#xD;
           samples and platelets will be pelleted after centrifugation at 400 g for 10 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  One of the 3 platelets samples will be lysed with Lemli solution for Western blot&#xD;
           analysis of phosphorylated ACC, ACC1 and phosphorylated protein kinase C substrates. All&#xD;
           samples will then be stocked at -80°c. In order to compare different immunoblotting,&#xD;
           control platelets samples are obtained after thrombin stimulation. Each patient's&#xD;
           platelet sample will be compared to the same control sample. The signal of&#xD;
           phosphorylated ACC for each patient will be quantified by Image J (Rasband, W.S.,&#xD;
           ImageJ, U. S. National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland, USA,&#xD;
           http://imagej.nih.gov/ij/, 1997-2014) and will be expressed as a fraction of the control&#xD;
           sample signal.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Level of phosphorylated ACC will be confirmed by electrochemiluminescence (ECLIA, Meso&#xD;
           Scale Discovery) and flow cytometry (FACS).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Protein extracts will be used for platelets protein analysis using immunoblotting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Plasma sampling&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Coagulation markers including INR, TCA, TT, PTT, Fibrinogen, D-Dimers, Thrombin&#xD;
           antithrombin complex (TAT).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cytokines measurements (TNF-alpha, IL-1b, IL-6, chemokines- CCL 3, 5, and 18, complement&#xD;
           system) as well as inflammatory biomarkers (hypersensitive C-reactive protein).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Platelets activation biomarkers (sCD62P, sCD40L, CD62P, PF4) (collaboration with Dr C.&#xD;
           Oury, GIGA, Université de Liège, Belgium).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Fibrinolytic biomarkers (u-PA, t-PA and PAI).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Lipidomic. Urines Samples of urines will be collected in the same times that blood&#xD;
           sampling to measure TX2B generation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lipidomic analyses Lipidome will be analyzed in collaboration with Christine Des Rosiers in&#xD;
      Montréal Heart Insitute. Special attention will be given to metabolites from the COX and LOX&#xD;
      pathways (TXA2 and lipoxins).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on our preliminary data, we determined that enrollment of minimum 46 patients would&#xD;
      provide a power of 90% at a significance level of 5% to detect a difference of 0.15 in the&#xD;
      phosphorylation of ACC (difference between control group 1 and septic shock population). 20&#xD;
      patients are expected in the exploratory control group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Covid-19 - Study amendment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since December 2019, novel Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV- 2)&#xD;
      causing Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) has evolve from an epidemic outbreak in China&#xD;
      into a pandemic. Severe infection is mainly responsible for bilateral pneumonia but emerging&#xD;
      data indicate that it is a systemic disease involving multiple systems including the&#xD;
      hematopoietic and immune system. Endothelial activation, procoagulant state and&#xD;
      micro-thrombosis has been shown. However, the pathophysiology has not been demonstrated to be&#xD;
      similar to a bacterial sepsis and the above-mentioned metabolic pathway should also be&#xD;
      studied in the subgroup of Covid- 19 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Covid-19 group will correspond to patients admitted in the ICU with ARDS due to SARS-Cov-2&#xD;
      infection and PaO2/FiO2 &lt; 200. Inclusion will be done within 5 days after admission and&#xD;
      patients with bacterial co-infection will be excluded. We planned to enroll 46 patients,&#xD;
      similarly to the control and septic shock group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 15, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 15, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Platelets Acetyl-CoA Carboxylase phosphorylation rate</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>ACC phosphorylation on Ser79 (phosphoACC) in platelets of patients will be assessed using western blotting. Results will be expressed in arbitrary units (A.U). A signal above 0.5 A.U. has already been shown to be above 2 standard deviation in a healthy population.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sepsis severity</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Sepsis severity will be assessed using the SOFA score (Sepsis-related Organ Failure Assessment). Range from 0( less severe) to 24 (more severe).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sepsis severity</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Sepsis severity will be assessed using the APACHE II score) Acute Physiology And Chronic Health Evaluation) Range 0 (less severe) to 299 (more severe).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality rate</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days and 1-year follow-up</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Platelet function assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Platelet function will be assessed using platelets aggregometry. The Aggregation (in AU), the maximum height of the curve during the measurement period will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Platelet function assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Platelet function will be assessed using platelets aggregometry. Area Under the aggregation Curve (AUC) will be assessed and recorded as Units or U.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Platelet function assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Platelet function will be assessed using platelets aggregometry. Velocity (in AU/min), the maximum slope of the curve will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Thrombin generation marker rate</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>D-Dimers (ng/ml)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Thrombin generation marker rate</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Urinary Thrombin-antithrombin complex (ng/mL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tubulin acetylation rate</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Tubulin acetylation will be assessed using western blotting. Results will be expressed in arbitrary units (A.U).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total platelets lipid content and composition</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Total platelets lipid content and composition will be assessed using metabolomics approach by Mass Spectrometry. Fold-change estimates and corresponding P values were derived from regression models for each lipid species and each predictor. To control for multiple testing, all P values will be further adjusted for Benjamini-Hochberg false discovery rate (FDR), with a FDR &lt;0.05 considered statistically significant</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neutrophils extracellular trap formation</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Myeloperoxidase MPO (ng/mL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neutrophils extracellular trap formation</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Citrulinated Histon 3 H3-Cit (ng/mL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Platelets activation</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Soluble CD62P (ng/mL)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Respiratory failure</measure>
    <time_frame>At the time of inclusion and through study completion up to day 30</time_frame>
    <description>PaO2/FiO2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Septic Shock</condition>
  <condition>Platelet Signal Processing Defect</condition>
  <condition>Inflammatory Response</condition>
  <condition>Disseminated Intravascular Coagulation</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Neutrophil Extracellular Trap Formation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Septic shock</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Septic shock Patients admitted to the ICU</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients recruited at the central lab of the hospital, with matched age, gender and comorbidities</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Covid-19</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Covid-19 patients admitted to the ICU for Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrom with PaO2/FiO2 &lt; 200</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Assessment of coagulopathy, Platelets activation and Platelets-Neutrophils interplay</intervention_name>
    <description>Blood sample Urine Sample Pulmonary, hepatic and cardiac tissue from biopsy and autopsy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Covid-19</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Septic shock</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Inflammatory biomarkers</other_name>
    <other_name>Coagulation assessment</other_name>
    <other_name>Platelets activation state assessment</other_name>
    <other_name>Neutrophils Extra-cellular trap assessment</other_name>
    <other_name>Quantification and analysis of micro-thrombi</other_name>
    <other_name>Platelets Acetyl-CoA Carboxylase phosphorylation analysis</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent of patients, their relatives or independent physician&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Septic shock defined as a sepsis with vasopressor therapy needed to elevate MAP ≥65&#xD;
             mmHg, and lactate &gt; 2 mmol/L, despite adequate fluid resuscitation of 30mL/kg of&#xD;
             intravenous crystalloid within 6 hours. Inclusion within 48 hours of ICU admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Covid-19 patients with ARDS and PaO2/FiO2 &lt; 200. Inclusion within 5 days after ICU&#xD;
             admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on therapeutic anticoagulation therapy (oral or parenteral) including&#xD;
             heparins, fondaparinux, vitamin K antagonist, novel oral anticoagulants, for any&#xD;
             reasons DESPITE therapeutic anticoagulation as a treatment for Covid-19 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent (less than 1 month) chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active inflammatory disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Haemophilia and other coagulopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous history of thrombocytopenia (&lt;100 000 platelets/mm3)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cirrhosis (Child Plug &gt; A)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent (less than 48 hours) major surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria for Covid-19 patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - bacterial co-infection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christophe Beauloye, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Cliniques Universitaires St Luc</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Melanie Dechamps, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+3227642782</phone>
    <email>melanie.dechamps@uclouvain.be</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cliniques Universitaires St Luc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bruxelles</city>
        <zip>1200</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Melanie Dechamps, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+3227642782</phone>
      <email>melanie.dechamps@uclouvain.be</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 11, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 26, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 20, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 20, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 25, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Septic shock</keyword>
  <keyword>Platelets</keyword>
  <keyword>Acetyl CoA Carboxylase</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Shock, Septic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Disseminated Intravascular Coagulation</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Shock</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

