<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="463">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04678687</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>COVID-19.PMB</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04678687</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19 and Tissue Damage in Vital Organs</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Postmortem Biopsy Specimens of COVID-19 Cases</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dokuz Eylul University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dokuz Eylul University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study will be conducted in Dokuz Eylül University Hospital, COVID-19 (Coronavirus Disease&#xD;
      2019) intensive care unit. Three primary conditions will be sought for participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Cases whose treatment process resulted in death will be included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. The cases must be confirmed with the diagnosis of COVID-19 by the RT-PCR (real time&#xD;
           polymerase chain reaction) test.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. The first-degree relatives must consent for the participation of the subjects in the&#xD;
           study by their first-degree relatives.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the study, samples will be taken from the liver, kidney, lung, and heart. The samples will&#xD;
      be stored in a protective solution and sent to the pathology unit. The examinations will&#xD;
      determine the microscopic damage to these organs caused by COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Also, the presence of the SARS-CoV-2 (Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2) will&#xD;
      be investigated by RT-PCR in tissues. The presence of ACE-2 (angiotensin converting enzyme 2)&#xD;
      receptor and SARS-CoV-2 nucleoprotein antibody will be investigated by histochemical&#xD;
      examination in tissues.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The cases whose treatment resulted in death at Dokuz Eylül University Research and&#xD;
      Application Hospital Anesthesiology Intensive Care Unit and whose COVID-19 diagnosis was&#xD;
      confirmed by the RT-PCR (real time polymerase chain reaction) test and gave written consent&#xD;
      to the inclusion of the patient in the study by a first-degree relative will be included in&#xD;
      the study. In the study, samples will be taken from 10 cases in total.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Age, gender, length of hospital stay, respiratory rate at the time of hospitalization,&#xD;
      oxygene saturation on ICU admission and Horwitz ratio on ICU admission will be recorded.&#xD;
      Also, the comorbidities of these cases, the interpretation of the computed tomography&#xD;
      findings performed at the first admission to the hospital in terms of COVID-19, the RT-PCR&#xD;
      results routinely sent for COVID-19 examination will be recorded in the case report form.&#xD;
      Besides, all medical and supportive treatments applied during the intensive care treatment&#xD;
      will be recorded. Liver and kidney function tests, inflammation and coagulation markers,&#xD;
      hemoglobin level , and cardiac markers, which are routinely examined at the patient's&#xD;
      admission to the intensive care unit, will be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Postmortem biopsy samples will be performed within 1 hour after the diagnosis of death is&#xD;
      confirmed by the patient's doctor. The researchers will perform the procedures in the&#xD;
      isolated room prepared for interventional procedures in intensive care. Researchers will wear&#xD;
      personal protective equipment (cap, mask, goggles, gloves) before the procedure under the&#xD;
      Ministry of Health's instructions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biopsy specimens will be taken from the lung, liver, heart, and kidney. Heart, liver, and&#xD;
      kidney biopsies were performed as a core biopsy with tru-cut needles under ultrasonography&#xD;
      guidance; lung biopsy will be performed by passing through the airway using biopsy forceps.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each of the biopsy samples will be placed separately in 10 ml of 10% phosphate-buffered&#xD;
      formalin solution. The containers will be disinfected with 80% alcohol. It will be placed in&#xD;
      a closed zippered bag and kept at room temperature. It will be delivered to the pathology&#xD;
      unit after 24 hours. The procedures as tissue cassette, extended tissue tracing, paraffin&#xD;
      blocking, sectioning, and hematoxylin-eosin staining will be performed under biosafety level&#xD;
      2 rules in pathology. The cases will be coded as CVDPM-1... (Coronavirus Disease Postmortem&#xD;
      1...). Case report forms will be shared with researchers who will conduct pathological&#xD;
      examination over the internet. Informed consent forms received from patients' relatives will&#xD;
      be filed in the COVID-19 Intensive Care Unit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Routine pathology sections will be evaluated in light microscopy according to the following&#xD;
      criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lungs; alveolar epithelial cell damage, hyaline membrane formation, type 2 pneumocyte&#xD;
      hyperplasia, diffuse alveolar damage, fibroblastic proliferation, fibrin accumulation,&#xD;
      inflammatory infiltration, and the nature of inflammation Liver; lobular lymphocyte&#xD;
      infiltration, centrilobular sinusoidal dilatation Kidney; diffuse proximal tubule damage,&#xD;
      brushed edge loss, non-isometric vacuolar degeneration, necrosis, hemosiderin, pigmented&#xD;
      cast, capillary plugs, vasculitis, intercalary inflammation, hemorrhage, Heart; acute&#xD;
      ischemic injury, vascular pathology, inflammation Tissues will be tested for the presence of&#xD;
      the SARS-CoV-2 virus by RT-PCR test. ACE2 receptor and SARS-CoV-2 nucleoprotein antibody will&#xD;
      be examined by immunohistochemistry.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The level of histopathological changes</measure>
    <time_frame>in three months after the participant's death</time_frame>
    <description>In lung; alveolar epithelial cell damage, hyaline membrane formation, type 2 pneumocyte hyperplasia, diffuse alveolar damage, fibroblastic proliferation, fibrin accumulation, inflammatory infiltration and the nature of inflammation. In liver; lobular lymphocytic infiltration, centrilobular sinusoidal dilatation. In kidney; diffuse proximal tubule damage, brushed edge loss, non-isometric vacuolar degeneration, necrosis, hemosiderin, pigment cast, capillary plugs, vasculitis, interciliary inflammation, hemorrhage. In heart; acute ischemic injury, vascular pathology, inflammation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Postmortem Changes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Liver, lung, heart and kidney biopsies will be performed on each case in the COVID-19 group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Liver, lung, heart and kidney biopsy</intervention_name>
    <description>Liver, lung, heart and kidney biopsies will be performed on each case in the COVID-19 group.</description>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cases 18 years and older than 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cases diagnosed with COVID-19 confirmed by PCR test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cases whose treatment resulted in death.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cases that was allowed the participation in the study by signing the informed consent&#xD;
             form by their first degree relatives.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cases less than 18 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cases for which the diagnosis of COVID-19 could not be confirmed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cases for which informed consent could not be obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cases whose treatment continues or results in healing.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ali N Gökmen, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University, Department of Anaesthesiology and Reanimation, Division of Intensive Care</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mehmet N Yakar, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University, Department of Anaesthesiology and Reanimation, Division of Intensive Care</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Safiye Aktaş, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University, Oncology Institute, Department of Basic Oncology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bilgin Cömert, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University, Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Intensive Care</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Begüm Ergan, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University, Department of Chest Disease, Division of Intensive Care</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bişar Ergün, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University, Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Intensive Care</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Fırat Bayraktar, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University, Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eyüp S Uçan, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University, Department of Chest Disease</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aylin Erol</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University, Oncology Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Özde E Gökbayrak</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University, Oncology Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dokuz Eylul University</name>
      <address>
        <city>İzmir</city>
        <state>Balçova</state>
        <zip>35330</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 19, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mehmet Nuri Yakar</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD, PhD, Research Assistant</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Postmortem Changes</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

