<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4264">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04728958</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>170732</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04728958</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Reflective Tasks With Healthcare Workers During COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Studying the Effect of Written Reflective Tasks With Healthcare Staff Working During the COVID-19 Health Pandemic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Sheffield</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sheffield Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Leeds Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>York Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bradford Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Sheffield</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The healthcare workforce is amongst the most stressed in the United Kingdom (UK). The&#xD;
      Coronavirus (COVID-19) health pandemic has increased depression, anxiety, insomnia and&#xD;
      distress in this population. Gratitude interventions have been shown to improve wellbeing,&#xD;
      alongside reducing risk factors associated with the aforementioned mental health conditions.&#xD;
      This online Randomised Control Trial of 219 healthcare staff, will investigate the effects of&#xD;
      gratitude interventions on wellbeing (gratitude, positive affect, happiness and life&#xD;
      satisfaction) and psychological distress (anxiety, stress, depression and negative affect).&#xD;
      Means of pre- and post-outcome measures of three groups (journaling, letter writing and&#xD;
      control) will be assessed for differences utilising a 3x2 mixed Analysis of Variance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The healthcare workforce is amongst the most stressed in the UK, with 40.3% of staff feeling&#xD;
      unwell as a result of work-related stress in the past year. This is steadily increasing each&#xD;
      year, rising 3.5% from 36.8% since 2016. Chronic stress can cause psychological health&#xD;
      problems, including low mood, anxiety and insomnia. Unfortunately, only 29.3% of staff across&#xD;
      the NHS felt their trust took positive action on health and wellbeing, which may contribute&#xD;
      to and prolong this continued rise in work-related stress.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With the COVID-19 health pandemic adding additional pressure to the NHS, healthcare workers&#xD;
      (HCWs) are at further risk of mental health problems, including post-traumatic stress&#xD;
      disorder, depression and substance misuse, as evident from historical health pandemics.&#xD;
      Furthermore, preliminary data from China during the COVID-19 health pandemic indicated&#xD;
      frontline HCWs experienced depression (50.4%), anxiety (44.6%), insomnia (34%) and distress&#xD;
      (71.5%). A systematic review identified risk factors for increased psychological distress of&#xD;
      HCWs during a health pandemic: being female, a nurse and experiencing stigmatised attitudes&#xD;
      from the general public, as well as being quarantined. Perceived control and social support&#xD;
      were associated with lower distress. Recommendations were made, to encourage a sense of&#xD;
      autonomy (with information and resources), increase social support and to initiate public&#xD;
      health campaigns with accurate facts, to reduce stigma and distress.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Positive Psychology Interventions (PPIs) are one approach for promoting autonomy and reducing&#xD;
      distress, by increasing positive emotions, behaviours, and/or thoughts, thereby increasing&#xD;
      the wellbeing of an individual. Positive psychology focuses on optimism, positive attitude&#xD;
      and gratitude, to encourage creativity, improve happiness and reduce mental barriers to&#xD;
      productivity, as opposed to focusing on 'problems'. PPIs include gratitude journals, using&#xD;
      affirmations, strength focussing exercises and mindful meditations. PPIs in workplaces have&#xD;
      improved performance, job wellbeing, engagement and other areas, whilst reducing negative&#xD;
      performance and negative job wellbeing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PPIs have focused on gratitude as a target for improving wellbeing, due to the inverse&#xD;
      relationship found between gratitude and burnout. Burnout is a state of emotional and&#xD;
      physical exhaustion, cynicism and detachment from work, caused by prolonged stress. Gratitude&#xD;
      is a positive, social emotion, similar to appreciation, which can either be state (of being)&#xD;
      or trait (dispositional). State gratitude is experienced when undeserved acts of kindness or&#xD;
      generosity are given freely by another person. Whereas trait gratitude is viewed as a&#xD;
      characteristic of a person, that varies in intensity and frequency throughout their daily&#xD;
      life. Gratitude interventions have found improvements (with a small to medium effect size) in&#xD;
      quality of relationships, wellbeing and optimism, alongside job satisfaction . Furthermore, a&#xD;
      reduction in anxiety, depression and negative affect is also evident.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Gratitude interventions utilise both expression and self-reflection as their methodological&#xD;
      properties. Expression includes giving small tokens of appreciation or paying gratitude&#xD;
      visits. Self-reflection includes writing personal gratitude lists or journals. Gratitude&#xD;
      lists were as effective as clinical therapies when working with excessive worry. Whereas,&#xD;
      sharing a gratitude letter was not as effective at improving gratitude, furthermore&#xD;
      expression of gratitude immediately induced feelings of embarrassment and discomfort.&#xD;
      However, increases in elevation were noted here, namely improved job performance,&#xD;
      connectedness, empowerment and autonomy. The reduced effectiveness of this expressive&#xD;
      gratitude intervention, may be due to barriers in engagement with the intervention, including&#xD;
      the expected awkwardness of the situation and the 'gratitude expresser's' mood.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Effectiveness of gratitude interventions in improving gratitude is likely to be affected by&#xD;
      both traits of participants and specificities of the intervention, such as length. Research&#xD;
      found trait gratitude moderated the effectiveness of the gratitude intervention in increasing&#xD;
      gratitude. This supports the resistance hypothesis, suggesting that those who are predisposed&#xD;
      to experience gratitude will not benefit from a gratitude intervention. Irrespective of&#xD;
      gratitude moderation, wellbeing significantly improved. The duration of the intervention may&#xD;
      also have an impact on effectiveness. Research found higher life satisfaction, more gratitude&#xD;
      and an improved positive affect in HCWs, after writing a gratitude diary bi-weekly over&#xD;
      4-weeks. Whereas a shorter 5-day intervention in the workplace, using a similar journaling&#xD;
      methodology, was not effective at improving gratitude. This may be explained by research,&#xD;
      which found a cumulative improvement in gratitude and happiness over 8-weeks of grateful&#xD;
      letter writing, indicating gratitude interventions are required to be of a reasonable length&#xD;
      in order to be effective.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HCWs are suffering from psychological distress as a result of the COVID-19 health pandemic&#xD;
      .It is vital interventions are offered to support their wellbeing. Gratitude interventions&#xD;
      are effective at improving wellbeing and reducing psychological distress, namely the risk&#xD;
      factors associated with psychological distress in HCWs at present. Self-reflective gratitude&#xD;
      interventions, over a period of weeks are effective at improving gratitude with HCWs, without&#xD;
      inducing embarrassment, discomfort or barriers to engagement. However, it is not clear if&#xD;
      there are differences in effectiveness dependent upon the methodological properties of the&#xD;
      intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will aim to investigate the effects of two gratitude interventions (journaling and&#xD;
      letter writing) with HCWs, with a view to increasing trait gratitude and psychological&#xD;
      wellbeing (happiness and life satisfaction), whilst reducing psychological distress (anxiety,&#xD;
      stress and depression).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To investigate if gratitude interventions are effective at increasing trait gratitude in&#xD;
           HCWs&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To investigate if gratitude interventions are effective at reducing psychological&#xD;
           distress and improving wellbeing in HCWs&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To investigate if high baseline trait gratitude is a moderator of changes in trait&#xD;
           gratitude, psychological distress and wellbeing after a gratitude intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypotheses&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Gratitude interventions (journaling and letter writing) will increase trait gratitude in&#xD;
           HCWs&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Gratitude interventions (journaling and letter writing) will improve wellbeing&#xD;
           (satisfaction with life and subjective happiness) and reduce psychological distress&#xD;
           (anxiety/depression/ stress level) in HCWs&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. High levels of trait gratitude will moderate the change in gratitude, satisfaction with&#xD;
           life, subjective happiness, anxiety, depression and stress level pre- to&#xD;
           post-intervention&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A two-factor mixed ANOVA will compare the mean differences between groups split across the two IVs (intervention &amp; time), due to the between factors and within factors levels of the two IVs.&#xD;
Descriptive Statistics &amp; t-tests will be used to compare and assess cumulative gratitude week-by-week</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participants will only be aware of the arm they are allocated to and not the other arms available. They will also be unaware as to whether this is a treatment arm or the comparator control</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Anxiety Level</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre- to post-intervention (28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Generalised Anxiety Disorder-7 (GAD-7) Questionnaire. This 7-item questionnaire, uses a 4-point likert scale to measure anxiety level. Minimum score = 0; maximum score = 21. Higher scores indicate higher anxiety levels. Positive change scores indicates a worse outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Depression Level</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre- to post-intervention (28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9). This 9-item questionnaire, uses a 4-point likert scale to measure depression level. Minimum score = 0; maximum score = 27. Higher scores indicate higher levels of depression. Positive change scores indicates a worse outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Stress Level</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre- to post-intervention (28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Perceived Stress Scale (PSS). This 10-item questionnaire, uses a 5-point likert scale to measure stress level. Minimum score = 0; maximum score =40. Higher scores indicate higher stress levels. Positive change scores indicates a worse outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Subjective Happiness Level</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre- to post-intervention (28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Subjective Happiness Scale (SHS). This 4-item questionnaire, uses a 7-point likert scale to measure happiness level. Minimum score = 7; maximum score = 28. Higher scores indicate higher subjective happiness levels. Positive change scores indicates a better outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Satisfaction with Life</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre- to post-intervention (28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Satisfaction with Life Scale (SwLS). This 5-item questionnaire, uses a 7-point likert scale to measure satisfaction with life. Minimum score = 5; maximum score = 35. Higher scores indicate higher satisfaction with life. Positive change scores indicates a better outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in State Gratitude</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre- to post-intervention (28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Gratitude Adjective Checklist (GAC). This 3-item measures of state gratitude uses a 5-point likert scale. Minimum score = 3; maximum score = 15. Higher scores indicate higher levels of state gratitude. A positive change score indicates a better outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>State Gratitude Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly (Day 1, Day 7, Day 14, Day 28)</time_frame>
    <description>Gratitude Adjective Checklist (GAC). This 3-item measures of state gratitude uses a 5-point likert scale. Minimum score = 3; maximum score = 15. Higher scores indicate higher levels of state gratitude. A positive change score indicates a better outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Trait Gratitude</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre- to post-intervention (28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>The gratitude Questionnaire-6 (GQ-6). This 6-item measure of trait gratitude uses a 7-point likert scale. Minimum score = 6; maximum score = 42. Higher scores indicate higher levels of Trait gratitude. A positive change score indicates a better outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Trait Gratitude score</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The gratitude Questionnaire-6 (GQ-6). This 6-item measure of trait gratitude uses a 7-point likert scale. Minimum score = 6; maximum score = 42. Higher scores indicate higher levels of Trait gratitude.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Positive and Negative Affect</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly (Day 1, Day 7, Day 14, Day 28)</time_frame>
    <description>The Positive and Negative Affect Scale - Short Form (PANAS-SF) is a 10-item measure of positive and negative affect. It uses a 5-point likert scale across both positive and negative affect. Positive affect is scored separately to negative affect, each with a minimum score of 5 and a maximum score of 25. High score on positive affect items indicate higher positive affect, whilst higher scores on negative affect items indicate higher negative affect.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">219</enrollment>
  <condition>Wellbeing</condition>
  <condition>Psychological Distress</condition>
  <condition>Psychological Stress</condition>
  <condition>Emotional Distress</condition>
  <condition>Stress, Psychological</condition>
  <condition>Stress</condition>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <condition>Happiness</condition>
  <condition>Satisfaction</condition>
  <condition>Occupational Stress</condition>
  <condition>Affect</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Gratitude Journal</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be given instructions and asked to write a gratitude journal about their week, focusing upon what they are grateful for. Over the course of the 4-week intervention they will be asked to do this weekly (a total of four times).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Gratitude Letter</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be given instructions and asked to write a gratitude letter to a person in their life, for whom they are grateful for either in that week or another time in their life. Over the course of the 4-week intervention they will be asked to do this weekly (a total of four times, creating 4 different letters).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Weekly Diary</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be given instructions and asked to write a diary about their week, focusing upon both the good and the bad they have experienced that week. Over the course of the 4-week intervention they will be asked to do this weekly (a total of four times).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Gratitude</intervention_name>
    <description>A positive psychology intervention using expressions of gratitude</description>
    <arm_group_label>Gratitude Journal</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Gratitude Letter</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Weekly Diary</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Gratitude Letter</other_name>
    <other_name>Gratitude Diary</other_name>
    <other_name>Gratitude Journal</other_name>
    <other_name>Appreciation Letter</other_name>
    <other_name>expressing gratitude</other_name>
    <other_name>positive psychology intervention</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical staff working in a physical health hospital during the COVID-19 health&#xD;
             pandemic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Front-line healthcare staff (such as physicians, nursing staff, healthcare&#xD;
             assistants/workers, medical/nursing students) in patient facing roles, delivering care&#xD;
             to patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Staff self-identifying as struggling with their mental health&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English Speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Front-line staff not in predominantly patient-facing roles or delivering care to&#xD;
             patients, such as clerical / domestic staff (due to the likelihood of reduced contact&#xD;
             with patients diagnosed with COVID-19)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those engaged in other research projects&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those without access to an electronic device to complete measures on&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those without access to an email address&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those receiving any other form of psychological intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People who cannot commit to engage in a 4-week intervention study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those working in direct care with one person - specialist one-to-one services&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Vicky Lamb, MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Sheffield</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Research Support Officer</last_name>
    <phone>+44 114 2226650</phone>
    <email>a.sinha@sheffield.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Vicky Lamb</last_name>
    <email>vlamb2@sheffield.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Occupational Stress</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stress, Psychological</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>IPD will be stored securely on the UniDrive, in a shared folder between the principal investigator and the research supervisor. Raw data will also be stored on the Qualtrics system, under a password protected log-in.&#xD;
Study results will be available in the University of Sheffield Online Research Data (ORDA) hub once completed. Sensitive and personal information will not be available as the key linking participant numbers to the personal will be destroyed once the study is completed. The data available will be completely anonymised.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

