<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="119">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04413045</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Novel COVID-19 Prevalence</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04413045</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Novel COVID-19, A National Analysis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prevalence and Clinical Characteristics of Novel COVID-19 Cases at One Quarantine Hospital; a National Analysis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Pneumonia is a form of acute respiratory tract infection (ARTI) that affects the lungs. When&#xD;
      an individual has pneumonia, the alveoli in the lungs are filled with pus and fluid, which&#xD;
      makes breathing painful and limits oxygen intake. Pneumonia has many possible causes, but the&#xD;
      most common are bacteria and viruses but nowadays there is a pandemic spread from novel&#xD;
      corona virus which cause corona virus disease 2019 (COVID-19).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Corona virus comprises of a large family of viruses that are common in human beings as well&#xD;
      animals (camels, cattle, cats, and bats). There are seven different strains of corona virus.&#xD;
      Sometimes corona virus from animals infect people and spread further via human to human&#xD;
      transmission such as with MERS-CoV, SARS-CoV, and now with this COVID-19 (Corona disease&#xD;
      2019). The virus that causes COVID-19 is designated as severe acute respiratory syndrome&#xD;
      corona virus 2 (SARS-CoV-2); previously, referred to as 2019-nCoV.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On Towards December 2019, this novel corona virus was identified as a cause of upper and&#xD;
      lower respiratory tract infections in Wuhan, a city in the Hubei Province of China. It&#xD;
      rapidly spread, resulting in an epidemic throughout China and then gradually spreading to&#xD;
      other parts of the world in pandemic proportions. It has affected almost every continent in&#xD;
      this world. In February 2020, the World Health Organization designated the disease COVID-19,&#xD;
      which stands for corona virus disease 2019.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Coronaviruses are a large family of single-stranded RNA viruses (+ssRNA) that can be&#xD;
      isolated in different animal species. They have a crown-like appearance under an electron&#xD;
      microscope (coronam is the Latin term for crown) due to the presence of spike glycoproteins&#xD;
      on the envelope. These viruses can also infect humans and cause illness ranging from the&#xD;
      common cold to more severe diseases such as MERS, SARS and now COVID-19. According to recent&#xD;
      research, a spike mutation, which probably occurred in late November 2019, triggered jumping&#xD;
      to humans.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will be done at one quarantine hospital in Assiut, Egypt. After approval from our&#xD;
      Institutional Ethics Committee, a written informed consent will be obtained from all patients&#xD;
      or their legal representatives (if they are unable to provide consent) before enrollment in&#xD;
      the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design and Sample Size Calculation: This study is an investigator-initiated cross&#xD;
      sectional trial to record, assess the clinical manifestations and prognosis of all COVID-19&#xD;
      cases to be admitted in the assigned hospital with positive results of nasopharyngeal swab&#xD;
      for SARS-CoV-2 during one-month duration. According to our records, 30-60 patients may be&#xD;
      included.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical Classification of COVID-19 patients according to the Egyptian Ministry of Health and&#xD;
      Population:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Mild Cases: The clinical symptoms are mild and no pneumonia manifestations can be found&#xD;
           in imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Moderate Cases Patients have symptoms (such as fever and respiratory tract symptoms,&#xD;
           etc.) and pneumonia manifestations can be seen in imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Severe Cases Adults who meet any of the following criteria: Respiratory rate&lt; 30&#xD;
           breaths/min; Oxygen saturations &lt; 93% at a rest state; Arterial partial pressure of&#xD;
           oxygen (PaO2)/Fraction of inspired oxygen (FiO2) [P/F ratio] &lt;300 mmHg; Patients with&#xD;
           more than 50% lesions progression within 24 to 48 hours in lung imaging should be&#xD;
           treated as severe cases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Tools and Data Collection: All admitted patients to the hospital will be monitored&#xD;
      carefully and observed for medical treatment, supportive measures, hemodynamic variables, and&#xD;
      comorbid conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Demographic Data: including age, sex and occupation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  History of travelling abroad and history of contact to confirmed cases (positive to&#xD;
           SARS-CoV-2).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Vital signs (heart rate, non-invasive blood pressure, respiratory rate, peripheral&#xD;
           oxygen saturation) at admission, at day 3, and day 7.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  laboratory investigation:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Complete blood picture&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  CRP (C reactive protein)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Prothrombin time, concentration, and INR&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Liver function (ALT, AST, bilirubin)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Kidney function (blood urea and serum creatinine)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Arterial blood gas (ABG): at admission, day1, day 3 and day 5.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  D-Dimer and ferritin levels&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  HRCT chest (High resolution computed tomography) chest at admission and follow up&#xD;
                at discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Follow up and outcome: (RT-PCR for SARS-CoV-2, CT chest, ABG).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The need of invasive mechanical ventilation, the clinical outcome, the duration of ICU&#xD;
           and hospital stay.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Any complications&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 20, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 28, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 28, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Prognosis Score</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The prognosis of COVID-19 patients at one quarantine hospital delivered to home, prolonged hospital stay, death.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oxygen Saturation</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Non-invasive peripheral oxygen saturation (%)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Laboratory Data</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Complete blood picture</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Radiological Features</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>High resolution computed tomography chest at admission and follow up at discharge</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital Stay</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of patients stay at hospital</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Liver Function</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Complete liver function tests</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Kidney Function</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Complete liver function tests</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">61</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>C Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>All COVID-19 cases to be admitted in the assigned hospital with positive results of nasopharyngeal swab for SARS-CoV-2 during one-month duration.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prevalence of COVID-19</intervention_name>
    <description>All COVID-19 cases to be admitted in the assigned hospital with positive results of nasopharyngeal swab for SARS-CoV-2 during one-month duration.</description>
    <arm_group_label>C Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This study is an investigator-initiated cross sectional trial to record, assess the&#xD;
        clinical manifestations and prognosis of all COVID-19 cases to be admitted in the assigned&#xD;
        hospital with positive results of nasopharyngeal swab for SARS-CoV-2 during one-month&#xD;
        duration.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The study aims To detect epidemiology, clinical and radiological presentation, laboratory&#xD;
        findings, complications, duration needed to conversion from positive to negative PCR,&#xD;
        duration of hospital stay and outcome of COVID-19 patients admitted in one quarantine&#xD;
        hospital&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any Age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any Sex&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  non pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RT-PCR positive for SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient Refusal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients stopped participation at anytime&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mohamed F. Mostafa, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>membership/educator</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Assiut University Hospitals</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assiut</city>
        <zip>71515</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 1, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 1, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 2, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 2, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 2, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 4, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mohamed F. Mostafa</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Anesthesia and Intensive Care</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

