<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4515">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04598763</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020PI098</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04598763</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of Two Methods of Olfactory Rehabilitation in Post-viral Loss of Smell: Classic and Intensive</brief_title>
  <acronym>Odorat-Covid</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Two Methods of Olfactory Rehabilitation in Post-viral Loss of Smell: Classic and Intensive</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Central Hospital, Nancy, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Central Hospital, Nancy, France</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      One of the most common causes of loss of smell is upper respiratory tract infection. These&#xD;
      disorders can be quantitative (hyposmia or anosmia) or qualitative (parosmia or phantosmia).&#xD;
      Loss of smell has been found as a major and frequent clinical sign of Sars Cov2 infection&#xD;
      (more than 50% of patients screened at the CHU Nancy). Spontaneous recovery remains possible.&#xD;
      It usually occurs in the first month . But when symptoms persist, the therapeutic management&#xD;
      of post-viral anosmias is poorly codified in the literature. Olfactory rehabilitation could&#xD;
      allow faster recovery and better quality, but the published protocols are numerous and could&#xD;
      only be tested on small inhomogeneous series of patients (mixture of post-viral and&#xD;
      post-traumatic hypo-ansomy). The significant increase in the population of patients suffering&#xD;
      from post-viral anosmia following the current pandemic situation makes it possible to&#xD;
      consider a prospective study aiming to compare two olfactory rehabilitation protocols:&#xD;
      &quot;classic&quot; and &quot;intensive&quot; in a population of patients. suffering only from post-viral&#xD;
      hypoanosmia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: Intensive or classic olfactory rehabilitation allows better results than&#xD;
      spontaneous recovery&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      80 patients will be recruited from among the patients consulting the otorhinolaryngology&#xD;
      department of the Nancy CHRU for the assessment of viral post-infectious olfactory disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The inclusion visit will be carried out during a standard routine care consultation with the&#xD;
      following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  an endoscopic endonasal examination&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the olfactory assessment (evaluation of smell by self-assessment, Dynachron-olfaction&#xD;
           questionnaire, olfactory test by Sniffin 'Stick)&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of this assessment and after having received the information on the study and&#xD;
      signed the consent form, the patients confirmed to be hypo-anosmic will then be randomized&#xD;
      into 2 groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  &quot;classic&quot; olfactory rehabilitation group&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  &quot;intensive&quot; olfactory rehabilitation group The rehabilitation kits (8 jars or 4 jars&#xD;
           depending on the randomization group) will be provided to the patient with therapeutic&#xD;
           education in their use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patient will carry out olfactory rehabilitation (intensive or classic) at home twice a&#xD;
      day (morning and evening) for 32 weeks (i.e. 448 sessions). The patient will smell each odor&#xD;
      for 10 seconds with an interval of 10 seconds between odors. Each training will be recorded&#xD;
      by the patient in his olfactory rehabilitation agenda.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patient will go again for a follow-up consultation for the renewal of his olfactory&#xD;
      assessment at 4 months (follow-up visit 1) and at 8 months (follow-up visit 2) post-inclusion&#xD;
      as part of the routine care of disorders of the smell post virus infection. In addition to&#xD;
      the olfactory assessment during these visits, the investigator will also verify that the&#xD;
      rehabilitation schedule is being kept.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 1, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>improvement in smell</measure>
    <time_frame>eight month</time_frame>
    <description>The change in smell is based on the comparison of the results of the olfactory assessment after / before olfactory rehabilitation obtained from a single method out of the three carried out:&#xD;
Sniffin 'Stick Test Results: Threshold Test Score and Actual Identification Test Score.&#xD;
TI score: sum of the individual scores of the threshold and identification measures (TI score varying from 0 to 32). It is used to classify patients in terms of normosmia, hyposmia and functional anosmia based on normative values of &quot;Sniffin 'Sticks&quot; (according to the age and sex of each subject) with the threshold at the tenth percentile of the database provided in the study published by Hummel and Kobal.&#xD;
Self-assessment by patients using a digital scale of smell, from 0 (no smell) to 10 (normal smell)&#xD;
Self-assessment using the Dynachron-olfaction questionnaire:each question is used to assess the patient's feelings about his discomfort in the nose using a scale from 0 (no discomfort) to 10 (unbearable</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Olfaction Disorders</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>classic group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>the &quot;classic&quot; group receives classic olfactory rehabilitation using 4 scents most used in the literature (rose, eucalyptus, lemon, clove)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>intensive</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>the &quot;intensive&quot; group receiving olfactory rehabilitation using 8 scents (rose, eucalyptus, lemon, cloves, strawberries, cut grass, lavender, spruce).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>smell the odors of the olfactory rehabilitation kit according to the classic or intensive method</intervention_name>
    <description>regardless of the randomization group, the patient will smell each odor for 10 seconds with a 10 second interval between odors.</description>
    <arm_group_label>classic group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>intensive</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with a sudden loss of smell&gt; 5 weeks linked to a viral infection (including&#xD;
             SARS-CoV-2) of the upper respiratory tract treated in the ENT department of the CHRU&#xD;
             Nancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient accepting olfactory rehabilitation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient presenting with hyposmia or anosmia (confirmed by the threshold and&#xD;
             identification tests of the Sniffin 'Stick kit)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient affiliated to a social security scheme or beneficiary of such a scheme&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who has received full research information and signed an informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons referred to in Articles L. 1121-5 to L. 1121-8 and L1122-2 of the Public&#xD;
             Health Code:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pregnant woman, parturient or nursing mother Person deprived of liberty by a judicial or&#xD;
        administrative decision, Person undergoing psychiatric treatment under Articles L.3212-1&#xD;
        and L.3213-1 of the Public Health Code Minor (non-emancipated) Adult person subject to a&#xD;
        legal protection measure (guardianship, curatorship, safeguard of justice) Adult person&#xD;
        unable to express consent and who is not the subject of a legal protection measure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Qualitative smell disorder (cacosmia, hyperosmia, phantosmia, parosmia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurological, post-traumatic, neurodegenerative, congenital odor disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Post-infectious loss of smell&gt; 12 months&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Duc Trung NGUYEN</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CHRU de Nancy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Julie Lecomte</last_name>
    <phone>+33 3 83 15 52 78</phone>
    <email>ju.lecomte@chru-nancy.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Duc Trung NGUYEN</last_name>
    <phone>03 83 15 54 09</phone>
    <email>dt.nguyen@chru-nancy.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHRU de Nancy</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nancy</city>
        <zip>54000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Duc Trung NGUYEN, MD, PhD, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>33383155409</phone>
      <email>dt.nguyen@chru-nancy.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 15, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 21, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 21, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Olfaction Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

