<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3153">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04632173</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HERODOTUS</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04632173</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Head and Neck cancERs International cOviD-19 collabOraTion</brief_title>
  <official_title>HERODOTUS: Head and Neck cancERs International cOviD-19 collabOraTion</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hellenic Cooperative Oncology Group</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Fondazione IRCCS Istituto Nazionale dei Tumori, Milano</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Grupo Español de Tratamiento de Tumores de Cabeza y Cuello</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Centre, Singapore</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Emory University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Toronto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Birmingham</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The University of Queensland</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hellenic Cooperative Oncology Group</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To develop an International registry on head and neck cancer patients infected with COVID-19&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      On 11 March, the World Health Organization (WHO) formally declared the corona virus&#xD;
      disease-19 (COVID-19) outbreak a pandemic. After the first cluster of cases emerged from&#xD;
      Wuhan, in China, at the end of 2019, up today almost 2 million cases of infections from&#xD;
      severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) have been diagnosed across all&#xD;
      five continents in the last few months.By the end of February 2020 COVID-19 had already hit&#xD;
      Europe hard, particularly Italy, with 12462 confirmed cases according to the Istituto&#xD;
      Superiore di Sanità as of March 11th, and 827 deaths. Considering the high transmissibility&#xD;
      and the severe disease occurrence in a fraction of the population, healthcare systems face a&#xD;
      great challenge. The estimated risk of death varies, indeed from the 12% In China at the peak&#xD;
      of the epidemic, to ≈1% in less affected regions including Europe, USA, Australia, Latin&#xD;
      America, Iran, and Canada.COVID-19 morbidity and mortality have been linked to elderly age&#xD;
      and comorbidities, leading to a poorer outcome from the viral infection in frail patients,&#xD;
      more often resulting in hospitalization, intensive care unit admittance and need for invasive&#xD;
      tracheal intubation. Among 2 such individuals, cancer patients represent a large subgroup at&#xD;
      high risk of developing coronavirus infection and its severe complications. A recent&#xD;
      nationwide analysis in China demonstrated that, of 1590 COVID-19 cases from 575 hospitals, 18&#xD;
      had a history of cancer (1% vs 0.29% of cancer incidence in the overall Chinese population,&#xD;
      respectively), with lung cancer as the most frequent diagnosis. Patients with cancer were&#xD;
      observed to have a higher risk of severe events compared with patients without cancer (39 vs&#xD;
      8%; p = 0.0003). Moreover, cancer patients who underwent recent chemotherapy or surgery had a&#xD;
      higher risk of clinically severe events than did those not receive treatment. With the limit&#xD;
      of a small sample size, the authors concluded that patients with cancer might have a higher&#xD;
      risk of COVID-19, and poorer outcomes, than individuals without cancer. As a consequence,&#xD;
      they recommended considering an intentional postponement of adjuvant chemotherapy or elective&#xD;
      surgery for stable cancer in endemic areas. Nevertheless, as subsequently highlighted by&#xD;
      other authors, the true incidence of COVID-19 in patients with cancer would be more&#xD;
      informative in assessing whether such patients have an increased risk (and morbidity) from&#xD;
      this viral illness. Furthermore, COVID-19 pandemic has led to delay in cancer diagnosis and&#xD;
      modifications in cancer treatment to limit as much as possible the number of patients in&#xD;
      order to reduce the risks of contamination by the SARS-Cov-2 virus for both patients and the&#xD;
      caregivers. Arduino PG et al reported a substantial delay in oral cancer diagnosis in&#xD;
      north-west Italy due to COVID19 outbreak. In addition, the management of cancer patients is&#xD;
      modified during the COVID-19 pandemic including delays in surgery, delays and modification of&#xD;
      radiation treatment schedule. Cancer Societies have issued treatment guidelines of cancer&#xD;
      patients during COVID-19 which include treatment adjustments the impact of which is currently&#xD;
      unknown. In addition, the coexistence of COVID-19 and cancer may increase the incidence of&#xD;
      treatment complications such as postoperative thrombosis and pulmonary emboli. For COVID-19 +&#xD;
      thyroid cancer patients treated with tyrosine kinase inhibitors, treatment complications and&#xD;
      outcomes are very relevant clinical questions. Furthermore, the limited cancer patient&#xD;
      population described in this first report from the literature, was characterized by the lack&#xD;
      of individuals receiving anticancer immunotherapy. Indeed, only chemotherapy and surgery were&#xD;
      cited among treatments received by patients in the month prior to developing COVID-19. Maybe,&#xD;
      this could simply be due to the casualty of a small sample, or otherwise, it could suggest&#xD;
      that cancer patients receiving immunotherapy are less prone to develop COVID-19 or to be&#xD;
      admitted in hospital due to severe coronavirus symptoms. Currently, we are aware of the&#xD;
      probably higher incidence of misdiagnosed coronavirus infections compared with that reported&#xD;
      and updated every day; it is likely that a large portion of healthy and young population&#xD;
      develop COVID-19 with mild symptoms, not requiring hospital admittance and thus escaping the&#xD;
      laboratory confirmation of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cancer patients undergoing treatment with anti-PD-1/PD-L1 currently used in everyday practice&#xD;
      to treat head and neck carcinoma constitute a growing oncological population. Their specific&#xD;
      susceptibility to bacterial or viral infections has not been investigated. Considering that&#xD;
      immunotherapy with Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors (ICI) is able to restore the cellular&#xD;
      immunocompetence, as it was previously suggested in the context of influenza infection, the&#xD;
      patient undergoing immune checkpoint blockade could be more immunocompetent than cancer&#xD;
      patients undergoing chemotherapy. In the recent weeks, in the countries heavily affected by&#xD;
      the COVID-19 outbreak, such as Italy, scientific associations recommended the prudential&#xD;
      postponing of active cancer treatments,especially for stable patients not needing urgent&#xD;
      interventions. On one hand, this recommendation could be reasonable for advanced cancer&#xD;
      patients receiving chemotherapy, with the risk of hematological toxicity and of worsening an&#xD;
      immunosuppressed status, thus favoring COVID-19 morbidity. On the other hand, some&#xD;
      oncologists are even currently wondering about the risk of administering ICI in the middle of&#xD;
      the COVID-19 outbreak, essentially due to two major concerns.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first seems to be represented by the potential overlap between the coronavirus-related&#xD;
      interstitial pneumonia and the possible pneumological toxicity from anti-PD-1/PD-L1 agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Even if lung toxicity is not the most frequent adverse event of ICI, it can be life&#xD;
      threatening.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall incidence rate of ICI-related pneumonitis ranges from 2.5-5% with anti-PD1/PDL1&#xD;
      monotherapy to 7-10% with anti-CTLA-4/anti-PD-1 combination therapy. The dominant&#xD;
      radiological pattern of lung Immune-related Adverse Events (irAEs) is organizing&#xD;
      pneumonia,but ICI-related pneumonitis could exhibit a variety of patterns, also including&#xD;
      nonspecific interstitial pneumonitis. Despite being rarer than other irAEs, pneumonitis is&#xD;
      the most fatal Adverse Event (AE) associated with PD-1/PD-L1 inhibitor therapy, accounting&#xD;
      for 35% of treatment-related toxic deaths. Considering that underlying lung disease,&#xD;
      particularly including interstitial pneumopathy, is considered a risk factor for ICI-related&#xD;
      pneumonitis, it could be reasonable taking into account the risk of treating patients while&#xD;
      they are developing an initial form of COVID-19. The synergy between the two lung injuries,&#xD;
      despite only hypothetical, cannot be surely ruled out. Nevertheless, such an epidemiological&#xD;
      coincidence should not prevent the oncologist from offering a potentially effective and often&#xD;
      well-tolerated treatment even in the middle of the COVID-19 outbreak, since the duration of&#xD;
      the pandemic is still currently unpredictable. The second concern seems to be represented by&#xD;
      a possible negative interference of ICI in the pathogenesis of COVID-19. Cytokine-release&#xD;
      syndrome (CRS) is a phenomenon of immune hyperactivation typically described in the setting&#xD;
      of T cell-engaging immunotherapy, including Chimeric Antigen Receptor (CAR)-T cell therapy&#xD;
      but also anti-PD-1 agents. CRS is characterized by elevated levels of Interleukin (IL)-6,&#xD;
      Interferon (IFN)- γ and other cytokines, provoking consequences and symptoms related to&#xD;
      immune activation, ranging from fever, malaise and myalgias to severe organ toxicity, lung&#xD;
      failure and death. In parallel, one of the most important mechanisms underlying the&#xD;
      deterioration of disease in COVID-19 is represented by the cytokine storm, leading to acute&#xD;
      respiratory distress syndrome or even multiple organ failure. The cytometric analyses of&#xD;
      COVID-19 patients showed reduced counts of peripheral CD4 and CD8 T cells, while their status&#xD;
      was hyperactivated. In addition, an increased concentration of highly proinflammatory CCR6+&#xD;
      Th17 in CD4 T cells has been reported, and CD8 T cells were found to harbor high&#xD;
      concentrations of cytotoxic granules, suggesting that over activation of T cells tends to&#xD;
      contribute to the severe immune injury of the disease. Moreover, the pathological findings&#xD;
      associated with acute respiratory distress syndrome in COVID-19 showed abundant interstitial&#xD;
      mononuclear inflammatory infiltrate in the lungs, dominated by lymphocytes, once again&#xD;
      implying that the immune hyperactivation mechanisms are at least partially accountable for&#xD;
      COVID-19 severity. Considering these aspects, the hypothesis of a synergy between ICI&#xD;
      mechanisms and COVID-19 pathogenesis, both contributing to a counter-producing immune&#xD;
      hyperactivation, cannot be excluded. In spite of this fascinating rationale, we should&#xD;
      remember that ICI-induced CRS is a quite rare phenomenon as well as that the cytokine storm&#xD;
      is not an early event in the COVID-19 pathogenesis, indeed characterizing the late phase of&#xD;
      its most severe manifestation, occurring in a minority of patients. It is not likely that&#xD;
      cancer patients are still receiving ICI during this phase of the viral illness. Obviously, in&#xD;
      the current pandemic scenario, careful attention should be dedicated in delaying treatment&#xD;
      for those patients presenting flu-like symptoms at the time of the intended ICI treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Considering this background, we propose a global registry to describe and monitor head and&#xD;
      neck cancer patients with COVID-19; identify factor associated with severe complications;&#xD;
      develop a tailored risk assessment strategy for head and neck cancer patients; and develop&#xD;
      treatment recommendations for head and neck cancer patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Demographic features</measure>
    <time_frame>Nov 1 2019 to January 31 2021</time_frame>
    <description>age, performance status etc</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>prevalence of comorbidities in head and neck cancer patients with COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>Nov 1 2019 to January 31 2021</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>proportion of head and neck cancer patients experiencing severe adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Nov 1 2019 to January 31 2021</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>proportion of head and neck cancer patients by COVID-19 clinical course severity</measure>
    <time_frame>Nov 1 2019 to January 31 2021</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>proportion of head and neck cancer patients with COVID-19 who received chemotherapy, surgery, radiotherapy, immune check point inhibitors in the last 3 months before, as well as during, COVID-19 infection</measure>
    <time_frame>Nov 1 2019 to January 31 2021</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>predictive factors of severe adverse events in head and neck cancer patients with COVID-19 including cancer-related treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Nov 1 2019 to January 31 2021</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>prognostic factors of head and neck cancer patients with COVID-19 including cancer related treatment including Human papilloma virus(HPV).</measure>
    <time_frame>Nov 1 2019 to January 31 2021</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">750</enrollment>
  <condition>Head and Neck Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>non interventional study</intervention_name>
    <description>There is no intervention</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This is a longitudinal multi-centre study on head and neck cancer patients (any age, sex,&#xD;
        histology, stage, in active treatment as well as in clinical follow-up) who contract&#xD;
        COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Information on clinical features, clinical course, management and outcomes will be&#xD;
        collected for both, head and neck cancers and COVID-19 infection. Considering the limited&#xD;
        data available about COVID-19 evolution, the sample size will be not anticipated. However,&#xD;
        with about 150 centers and a median of 5 patients at every center, a sample size of 750&#xD;
        patients approximately can produce a confidence interval for the categorical estimate of&#xD;
        +/-2%. Clinical data will be extracted from medical records of consecutive patients from&#xD;
        November 1st, 2019 until January 31 2021.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any head and neck cancer patients (including salivary gland, thyroid, nasal and paranasal&#xD;
        cancer with a COVID-19 diagnosis defined as any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Laboratory confirmed [Real Time - Polymerase Chain Reaction (RT-PCR) technique]&#xD;
             COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suspected COVID-19 cases; diagnosed clinically based on symptoms (fever &gt;37.5°,&#xD;
             decrease of oximeter saturation of at least 5 %, cough, diarrhoea, otitis, dysgeusia,&#xD;
             anosmia, myalgia, arthralgia, conjunctivitis and rhinorrhea and exposure to confirmed&#xD;
             COVID-19 positive case (laboratory confirmation).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically diagnosed cases; suspected cases with lung imaging features consistent with&#xD;
             coronavirus pneumonia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Asymptomatic cases; diagnosed based on positive viral nucleic acid test results but&#xD;
             without any COVID- 19 symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Evita Fragou</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>HeCOG</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Amanda Psyrri, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+302105831664</phone>
    <email>psyrri237@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lisa Licitra, MD</last_name>
    <email>lisa.licitra@istitutotumori.mi.it</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 15, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hellenic Cooperative Oncology Group</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Amanda Psyrri</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Medical Oncology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

