<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="81">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04706403</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H00022244</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04706403</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Views on COVID-19 and Vaccination</brief_title>
  <official_title>If We Build It, Will They Come? A Pilot Study to Develop and Test Messages to Maximize Uptake of Coronavirus Vaccine When Available</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Massachusetts, Worcester</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Massachusetts, Worcester</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this study is to develop evidence-based messages that effectively mitigate&#xD;
      concerns of people at risk for not being vaccinated against COVID-19, with the ultimate goal&#xD;
      of maximizing vaccine uptake in vulnerable populations. The investigators will collect data&#xD;
      on COVID-19 disease and vaccine knowledge, beliefs, and intent to be vaccinated from an&#xD;
      existing online panel. Results from this data collection will be used to develop effective&#xD;
      messages and communication strategies. The investigators will test alternate versions of&#xD;
      messages intended to reduce vaccine hesitancy and promote vaccine uptake among&#xD;
      vaccine-hesitant individuals. This project will ultimately result in a set of tested,&#xD;
      evidence-derived messages about vaccination for COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) has rapidly instigated a&#xD;
      global pandemic. As of this writing, there are approximately 65 million documented cases of&#xD;
      infection worldwide, and over 1.5 million deaths. In the United States (US), coronavirus&#xD;
      disease 2019 (COVID-19) has disrupted the economy, overwhelmed healthcare system, led to&#xD;
      widespread school cancellations, and caused more than 274,000 deaths since March 2020. A&#xD;
      vaccine against COVID-19 is widely viewed as the key to controlling the pandemic and enabling&#xD;
      a return to &quot;normal&quot; life. Vaccine development is proceeding at an unprecedented pace with 10&#xD;
      vaccines currently in phase 3 trials. Experts have projected that a safe and effective&#xD;
      vaccine may be available by mid-2021. At the same time, a growing body of evidence indicates&#xD;
      that a significant proportion of adults in the U.S. may not accept vaccination against&#xD;
      COVID-19. Even more alarming, COVID-19 vaccine hesitancy (refusal or reluctance to accept a&#xD;
      vaccine) appears to be increasing as the vaccine approval process becomes increasingly&#xD;
      politicized. Just as efforts to develop vaccine production and delivery capacity have been&#xD;
      undertaken in advance of having a proven effective vaccine, parallel efforts are needed to&#xD;
      identify effective messages and communication strategies to overcome COVID-19 vaccine&#xD;
      hesitancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study team recently surveyed a nationally representative sample of approximately 1,000&#xD;
      adults in the United States and found that only 57% intended to be vaccinated when a&#xD;
      coronavirus vaccine becomes available. This percentage was even lower among people who&#xD;
      identified as Black or Hispanic (39% and 43% respectively), those with a high school&#xD;
      education or less (46%), and those in the lowest income groups (49% of those reporting a&#xD;
      household income of $30,000 or less, compared to 72% of those reporting a household income of&#xD;
      $100,000 or more). The investigators asked those who indicated they would not or might not&#xD;
      get vaccinated for their reasons and found that some individuals may be willing to be&#xD;
      vaccinated if provided specific information about the vaccine such as side effects and&#xD;
      effectiveness. Others expressed generalized skepticism, fear, and distrust of vaccines, with&#xD;
      some even referring to anti-vaccine conspiracy theories. These findings are consistent with&#xD;
      an extensive body of research documenting that people often do not behave rationally and&#xD;
      highlight the urgent need to proactively develop and test interventions to maximize&#xD;
      vaccination rates when a coronavirus vaccine becomes available. To address this need, in the&#xD;
      present study, the investigators aim to create and test targeted messages to address the&#xD;
      concerns of subgroups of people at risk for not being vaccinated, with the ultimate goal of&#xD;
      maximizing vaccine uptake when a vaccine for COVID-19 becomes available. The investigators&#xD;
      will accomplish this by working with an existing online panel of volunteers, which will allow&#xD;
      efficient, focused data gathering. Results of the survey will provide a nuanced, current&#xD;
      description of how vulnerable adults perceive the coronavirus and available vaccines, which&#xD;
      will be used as the basis for developing messages and communication strategies. Participants&#xD;
      will be randomized to receive one of five different versions of a message from a healthcare&#xD;
      provider regarding vaccination. Specific wording and content of these messages will vary&#xD;
      systematically in order to address concerns of those at risk for not being vaccinated. This&#xD;
      project will ultimately result in a set of tested, evidence-derived messages about&#xD;
      vaccination for COVID-19. The investigators will make these messages available, together with&#xD;
      evidence of how these influence members of vulnerable populations' understanding of&#xD;
      vaccination, and disease risk, as well as intent to be vaccinated. The messages will be&#xD;
      freely available for use by organizations and providers seeking to improve communication&#xD;
      about a coronavirus vaccine.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 26, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intent to be vaccinated against COVID-19.</measure>
    <time_frame>Through survey completion, an average of 12 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The survey includes questions that assess participants' intent to be vaccinated when a vaccine for COVID-19 becomes available.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Predictors of intent to be vaccinated against COVID-19.</measure>
    <time_frame>Through survey completion, an average of 12 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The survey includes questions that assess participants' knowledge, beliefs, and attitudes about COVID-19, vaccines in general, and a COVID-19 vaccine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">3000</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Message 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be randomized to receive version #1 of 5 different versions of a message from a healthcare provider regarding vaccination.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Message 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be randomized to receive version #2 of 5 different versions of a message from a healthcare provider regarding vaccination.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Message 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be randomized to receive version #3 of 5 different versions of a message from a healthcare provider regarding vaccination.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Message 4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be randomized to receive version #4 of 5 different versions of a message from a healthcare provider regarding vaccination.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Message 5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be randomized to receive version #5 of 5 different versions of a message from a healthcare provider regarding vaccination.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive a control version of a message from a healthcare provider regarding vaccination.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Healthcare Providers' Communication about the COVID-19 Vaccine</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants who express hesitation about getting vaccinated for COVID-19 will be randomized to receive one of five different versions of messages from a healthcare provider (experimental groups) or a control message (control group). The messages that participants in each experimental group receive will vary slightly and systematically. Specific content and wording of these messages will be developed to address and mitigate concerns of those at risk for not being vaccinated.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Message 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Message 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Message 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Message 4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Message 5</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult (age 18 and over) who are members of an online panel (Prolific). Members of this&#xD;
             panel joined the panel specifically to receive invitations to participate in research&#xD;
             surveys and similar activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to complete an online survey in English.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kimberly Fisher, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Massachusetts, Worcester</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kimberly Fisher, MD</last_name>
    <phone>508-791-7392</phone>
    <email>kimberly.fisher@umassmemorial.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kathleen Mazor, EdD</last_name>
    <phone>508-791-7392</phone>
    <email>kathleen.mazor@umassmed.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fisher KA, Bloomstone SJ, Walder J, Crawford S, Fouayzi H, Mazor KM. Attitudes Toward a Potential SARS-CoV-2 Vaccine : A Survey of U.S. Adults. Ann Intern Med. 2020 Dec 15;173(12):964-973. doi: 10.7326/M20-3569. Epub 2020 Sep 4.</citation>
    <PMID>32886525</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brewer NT, Chapman GB, Rothman AJ, Leask J, Kempe A. Increasing Vaccination: Putting Psychological Science Into Action. Psychol Sci Public Interest. 2017 Dec;18(3):149-207. doi: 10.1177/1529100618760521.</citation>
    <PMID>29611455</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Godinho CA, Yardley L, Marcu A, Mowbray F, Beard E, Michie S. Increasing the intent to receive a pandemic influenza vaccination: Testing the impact of theory-based messages. Prev Med. 2016 Aug;89:104-111. doi: 10.1016/j.ypmed.2016.05.025. Epub 2016 May 25.</citation>
    <PMID>27235605</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mowbray F, Marcu A, Godinho CA, Michie S, Yardley L. Communicating to increase public uptake of pandemic flu vaccination in the UK: Which messages work? Vaccine. 2016 Jun 14;34(28):3268-74. doi: 10.1016/j.vaccine.2016.05.006. Epub 2016 May 8.</citation>
    <PMID>27166824</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nowak GJ, Sheedy K, Bursey K, Smith TM, Basket M. Promoting influenza vaccination: insights from a qualitative meta-analysis of 14 years of influenza-related communications research by U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Vaccine. 2015 Jun 4;33(24):2741-56. doi: 10.1016/j.vaccine.2015.04.064. Epub 2015 Apr 28. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25936726</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Redelings MD, Piron J, Smith LV, Chan A, Heinzerling J, Sanchez KM, Bedair D, Ponce M, Kuo T. Knowledge, attitudes, and beliefs about seasonal influenza and H1N1 vaccinations in a low-income, public health clinic population. Vaccine. 2012 Jan 5;30(2):454-8. doi: 10.1016/j.vaccine.2011.10.050. Epub 2011 Oct 30.</citation>
    <PMID>22044740</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Massachusetts, Worcester</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kimberly Fisher</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>M.D</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Covid-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Vaccination</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

