<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="521">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04610138</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CNMZnAg.202</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04610138</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of ZnAg Liquid Solution to Treat COVID-19 Symptomatic Participants</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Study of the Efficacy and Safety of ZnAg Liquid Solution to Treat COVID-19 in Acutely Symptomatic Non-Hospitalized Participants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Clene Nanomedicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>ICL Pharma</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Azidus Brazil</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Clene Nanomedicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a multi-site, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study assessing the&#xD;
      efficacy and safety of ZnAg liquid solution in symptomatic participants with acute COVID-19&#xD;
      that are not hospitalized at the time of enrollment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a multi-site, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study assessing the&#xD;
      efficacy and safety of ZnAg liquid solution in symptomatic participants with acute COVID-19&#xD;
      (PCR documented SARS-CoV-2 infection) that are not hospitalized at the time of enrollment&#xD;
      (e.g., present to an emergency room without being admitted to the hospital or diagnosed in an&#xD;
      outpatient clinic setting).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants must have presented with two or more symptoms of acute COVID-19 (within 96 hours&#xD;
      prior to the Baseline visit) self-reported as moderate or severe at the Baseline visit,&#xD;
      including fever, myalgia, fatigue, chest tightness, chills, cough, diarrhea, gastrointestinal&#xD;
      distress, headache, sore throat, congestion or runny nose, ageusia, anosmia, nausea, tingling&#xD;
      or numbness in the extremities, or shortness of breath. SARS-CoV-2 infection must be&#xD;
      confirmed by polymerase chain reaction (PCR) testing within 96 hours prior to the Baseline&#xD;
      visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants who meet all inclusion criteria and none of the exclusion criteria and who&#xD;
      formally consent to participate will be randomized 1:1:2 to receive ZnAg (low dose) : ZnAg&#xD;
      (high dose) placebo in a double-blind fashion in addition to standard supportive care. Within&#xD;
      the active treatment arm, participants will be randomized to receive either low or high dose&#xD;
      ZnAg.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Active treatment with 60 ml low-dose ZnAg (Zn 6 ug/ml and Ag 10 ug/ml; equivalent to 0.6&#xD;
           mg Ag, 0.36 mg Zn), po q12 hours or;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Active treatment with 60 ml high-dose ZnAg (Zn 12 ug/ml and Ag 20 ug/ml; equivalent to&#xD;
           1.2 mg Ag, 0.72 mg Zn), po q12 hours;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  60 ml matching placebo, po q12 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants who become clinically unstable during the course of the study (e.g., requiring&#xD;
      high-flow supplemental oxygen or mechanical ventilatory support) per the judgement of the&#xD;
      site investigator will be admitted to a hospital and their clinical status (e.g., vital&#xD;
      status, hospitalization status, respiratory status, COVID-19 ordinal scale) will continue to&#xD;
      be tracked per protocol.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants will be randomized 1:1:2 to receive ZnAg (low dose): ZnAg (high dose) placebo in a double-blind fashion in addition to standard supportive care. Within the active treatment arm, participants will be randomized to receive either low or high dose ZnAg.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>All participants, investigators, and coordinators will be blinded to the investigational product. The study data will remain blinded until database lock and authorization of data release according to standard operating procedures.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of participants who require COVID-19 related hospitalization, are hospitalized for COVID-19 related medical support, or are deceased within 28-days following randomization.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days.</time_frame>
    <description>Hospitalization will be determined by Investigator's clinical judgement. Where applicable, Investigators should follow local recommendations for hospitalization of patients with COVID-19 within their institution.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to substantial alleviation of COVID-19 symptoms.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days.</time_frame>
    <description>Confirmed symptom resolution over a continuous period ≥ 48 hours, defined as PGI-Severity of 'Normal' in Participants whose Baseline PGI-Severity value was 'Mild'; or, a PGI-Severity of 'Normal' or 'Mild' in participants whose Baseline PGI-Severity value was 'Moderate' or 'Severe'.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of alive hospital free days at Day 28.</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Days from baseline participant remains alive.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Mean change from Baseline to Day 14, Day 21, and Day 28 in SARS-CoV-2 viral load.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Cycle Thresholds assessed by RT-qPCR.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline to Day 8, Day 14, Day 21, and 28 in the slope of oxygen saturation levels (SpO2) assessed per protocol.</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Oxygen saturation will be obtained after the participant has been resting for 5 minutes.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Global Impression (CGI) Severity and Change measures from Baseline to Day 8, Day 14, Day 21, and 28.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by changes in participant rated Clinical Global Impression.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Global Impression (PGI) Severity and Change measures from Baseline to Day 8, Day 14, Day 21, and 28.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by changes in participant rated Patient Global Impression.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the area under the curve for Net Symptom Burden from Baseline to Day 8, Day 14, Day 21, and 28.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Summary measure integrating semi-daily serial assessments of a subject's symptom count and severity over the duration of the study.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in clinical status from Baseline to Day 8, Day 14, Day 21, and Day 28.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the Clinical Status Ordinal Scale established in the remdesivir ACTT study. Scale is 1-8, with 1 being the least severe and 8 being the most severe (death).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>All-cause mortality rate at Day 28.</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of deceased participants at day 28.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">276</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active treatment with 60 ml low-dose ZnAg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>(Zn 6 ug/ml and Ag 10 ug/ml; equivalent to 0.6 mg Ag, 0.36 mg Zn), po q12 hours</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active treatment with 60 ml high-dose ZnAg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>(Zn 12 ug/ml and Ag 20 ug/ml; equivalent to 1.2 mg Ag, 0.72 mg Zn), po q12 hours;</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>60 ml matching placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>60 ml matching placebo, po q12 hours</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CNM-ZnAg</intervention_name>
    <description>ZnAg liquid solution</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active treatment with 60 ml high-dose ZnAg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Active treatment with 60 ml low-dose ZnAg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Water</description>
    <arm_group_label>60 ml matching placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adults, aged 40 - 90 years (inclusive)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Acute onset (within 96 hours of the Baseline visit) of two or more COVID-19 symptoms&#xD;
             self-rated as moderate-to-severe, including fever, myalgia, fatigue, chest tightness,&#xD;
             chills, cough, diarrhea, gastrointestinal distress, headache, sore throat, congestion,&#xD;
             or runny nose, ageusia, anosmia, nausea, tingling or numbness in the extremities, or&#xD;
             shortness of breath.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Laboratory-confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection as determined by positive PCR in a sample&#xD;
             collected ≤ 96 hours prior to the Baseline visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. PGI-Severity and CGI-Severity assessments of 'Mild', 'Moderate, or 'Severe' at the&#xD;
             Screening visit (e.g., cannot be 'Normal').&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participant (or legally authorized representatives) provides informed consent prior to&#xD;
             the initiation of any study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Participant is willing and able to follow all study procedures and assessments&#xD;
             according to the study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Participant is able to consume 60 ml of fluid orally twice daily.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Women of childbearing potential must agree to either abstinence or use at least one&#xD;
             primary form of contraception, not including hormonal contraception from the time of&#xD;
             screening through the end of study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Unable or unwilling to take ZnAg liquid solution or matching placebo as directed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Hospitalized prior to Baseline for COVID-19 management.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Need for hospitalization and/or ventilatory support at Baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The emergence of any disease during study, other than COVID-19 that could better&#xD;
             explain the participants' signs and symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Severe disease: respiratory distress, or requiring supplemental oxygen, or SpO2 ≤ 93%&#xD;
             on room air, or tachypnea (respiratory rate ≥ 30 breaths/min) at Baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History or presence of serious or acute heart disease such as uncontrolled cardiac&#xD;
             dysrhythmia or arrhythmia, uncontrolled angina pectoris, cardiomyopathy, or&#xD;
             uncontrolled congestive heart failure (NYHA class 3 or 4).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Legal incapacity or limited legal capacity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Women of childbearing potential who do not agree to use either abstinence or at least&#xD;
             one primary form of contraception, not including hormonal contraception from the time&#xD;
             of screening through the end of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Participation in another clinical study with an investigational product within the&#xD;
             prior 12 months (per Resolution 251/1997).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Renata Lourencini</last_name>
    <phone>+55 (11) 9.9383-6275</phone>
    <email>renata.lourencini@iclpharma.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Robert Glanzman, MD</last_name>
    <phone>801-676-9695</phone>
    <email>robert@clene.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Corona Virus</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

