<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3140">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04625114</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EudraCT number: 2020-003475-18</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04625114</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Potential of Oral Camostat in Early COVID-19 Disease in an Ambulatory Setting to Reduce Viral Load and Disease Burden</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Potential of Oral Camostat in Early COVID-19 Disease in an Ambulatory Setting to Reduce Viral Load and Disease Burden</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Ghent</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Ghent</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators are conducting a pilot trial where they will study safety, efficacy and&#xD;
      compliance in a cohort of ambulatory patients in the Ghent region with confirmed COVID-19&#xD;
      infection, in both an early stage of disease, defined as less than 5 days of symptoms and who&#xD;
      at presentation do not meet any criteria for hospitalisation as well as asymptomatic&#xD;
      individuals with a PCR CT value below 30.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint is to assess the efficacy of the drug in terms of change from day 0 to&#xD;
      day 5 in respiratory (oropharyngeal swab RT-PCR) log10 viral load.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the study is to assess whether Camostat, a serine protease inhibitor available in&#xD;
      an oral formulation has the potential to be studied as an antiviral drug in a large scale&#xD;
      ambulatory setting to prevent transmission by decreasing viral load, to prevent symptoms&#xD;
      after exposure (PEP) in asymptomatic individuals or to prevent disease progression in the&#xD;
      occurrence of early symptomatology.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Core study After eligibility assessment participants will be randomized and will receive the&#xD;
      study drugs. We will define D1 as the first dose of the medication which can be the morning,&#xD;
      midday or evening dose. They will be treated for 5 consecutive days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In patients with a positive PCR at D5 (CT value with threshold below 30) and/or presence of&#xD;
      clinical symptoms after exclusion of hospitalization criteria (flowchart emergency department&#xD;
      appendix 4), the treatment will be extended up to D10 at the same dosage in both treatment&#xD;
      arms for 5 consecutive days: D6 and D10).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up will be as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  D1-&gt;D14: The study participants will be asked to fill in daily questionnaires assessing&#xD;
           symptoms (cfr daily self-score). They will receive a kit enabling to monitor heart rate&#xD;
           (HR), respiratory rate (RR), temperature and oxygen saturation 3 times per day (every&#xD;
           4-8 hours, preferentially at the timing of medication intake at D1 to D5 or D10). This&#xD;
           will be extended to D28 if patients are still symptomatic at D14.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Compliance and tolerance will be assessed during the treatment period, D0-&gt;D5 (or&#xD;
           D0-&gt;D10 if the treatment is prolonged).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  During the study D1-D28: If indicated in the opinion of the investigator, a physical&#xD;
           exam and biochemistry will be performed through a consultation at the clinic. This can&#xD;
           be requested at any time during the study based on clinical symptoms or signs.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Consultation at D0, D5, (D10) and D28 at our COVID consultation facility. This will be&#xD;
           done by a study nurse and/or a study physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At D0 (screening and inclusion) a standardized history, clinical exam will be performed,&#xD;
      including blood pressure (BP), heart rate (HR), respiratory rate (RR), blood oxygen&#xD;
      saturation, temperature. Socio-demographic parameters such as age, gender, treatment, smoking&#xD;
      status, BMI, diabetes, race and comorbidities will be assessed. If unavailable, a COVID&#xD;
      screening test will be performed to confirm COVID 19 infection. A baseline lab for toxicity&#xD;
      will be done on D0 (max 21ml).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In case of negative screening test and suggestive clinical picture as described above, the&#xD;
      test can be completed with additional blood analysis, arterial blood gas and/or lung imaging&#xD;
      to assess the probability of COVID-19. The additional tests are SOC. It is the treating&#xD;
      physician who will decide whether these test are valuable. In this case the study physician&#xD;
      can decide to rescreen the patient (with PCR) after minimum 24h and within the 5 days of&#xD;
      occurrence of symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The medication will be initiated as soon as possible after inclusion and randomisation. D1 is&#xD;
      defined as the first dose of the study medication at whatever point of time during that day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At D1 up to D14 (or until D28 if they still have symptoms at D14), participants will be asked&#xD;
      for the presence of symptoms and signs by a questionnaire and to monitor temperature, blood&#xD;
      oxygen saturation, heart rate and respiratory rate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If indicated in the opinion of the investigator, a physical exam and biochemistry will be&#xD;
      performed through a consultation at the clinic. This can be requested at any time during the&#xD;
      study based on clinical symptoms or signs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At D5 a scheduled study visit is planned with a clinical exam including BP, RR, HR,&#xD;
      temperature, blood oxygen saturation. Nasopharyngeal (or combined nose/throat) swab will be&#xD;
      taken for PCR. CRP can be assessed by point of care test or routine lab when clinically&#xD;
      relevant as part of SOC. A toxicity screening will be performed through a venous blood draw&#xD;
      (max 21ml). At the day of consultation the time point at the hospital will replace the&#xD;
      monitoring measurement at home.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At any given time between D1 and D28 an additional blood draw (max. 21 ml) can be asked by&#xD;
      the study team to assess severity of infection (peripheral blood count, inflammation,&#xD;
      electrolytes, kidney and liver function.) If CRP values are available at baseline and/or&#xD;
      follow-up they will be analyzed as part of the study, however this will only be performed as&#xD;
      SOC. If HRCT or a lung X ray are available at baseline or follow-up, they will be analyzed as&#xD;
      part of the study, however they will only be performed as SOC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At D28 an additional blood draw (9 ml) will be done for neutralizing antibodies (Nabs) titer&#xD;
      assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At D10 an additional study visit will be planned in individuals that are retested with&#xD;
      positive PCR at D5 and when treatment is prolonged after D5 up to D10. This will include a&#xD;
      clinical exam including BP, RR, HR, temperature, blood oxygen saturation. At the day of&#xD;
      consultation the time point at the hospital will replace the measurement at home.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At D10 and D28 an additional nasopharyngeal swab or combined nose/throat swab will be&#xD;
      performed in individuals that still had a positive PCR result at day 5 and D10 respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Questionnaires will be sent through email and can be filled in online and transferred&#xD;
      directly to the eCRF or will be filled in on paper and handed to the study personnel at the&#xD;
      time of consultation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Home monitoring of heart rate, respiratory rate, temperature and oxygen saturation will be&#xD;
      done through a kit provided by Byteflies. A manual with usage instructions will be delivered&#xD;
      to the patients. The patient will be asked to register these parameters 3 times a day through&#xD;
      an online platform. If they are unable to register the parameters themselves, a back-up&#xD;
      through email or phone can be proposed. If these parameters are not within normal range as&#xD;
      defined by cut-off criteria (appendix 8), the system will ask either to remeasure or to&#xD;
      contact the study-team based on the reported values. The study will be interrupted in&#xD;
      participants that meet hospitalization criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PK substudy Participants will be asked to participate in a PK substudy. The aim is to include&#xD;
      50 patients samples in the Camostat treatment arm, therefore sampling approx. half of the&#xD;
      participants in both arms. When 50 participants have been included in the camostat arm,&#xD;
      inclusions will be stopped. Drop-outs however will be replaced. If the participant agrees, PK&#xD;
      samples will be taken during the treatment phase between D1 and D5. 4 additional blood&#xD;
      samples will be taken between two intakes of the study medication: at 30', 60', 2-4h, and&#xD;
      4-8h (on the same day, between D1 and D5). The samples will be deblinded during the study by&#xD;
      an unblinded person. After unblinding, only the samples from patients in the Camostat group&#xD;
      will be sent for analysis. Samples that are not used for PK analysis, will be stored in the&#xD;
      prospective Biobank for future studies. 2x3ml of blood will be taken per sampling point&#xD;
      =24ml.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Odor substudy: Odor sampling SARS-CoV-2 patients All participants will be asked to&#xD;
      participate in a substudy analysing odor samples from COVID 19 infected individuals. The goal&#xD;
      of this study is to take odor samples at the arm pit and between the legs, in order to train&#xD;
      dogs to identify COVID-19 infected individuals. In this way, dogs can be trained to identify&#xD;
      COVID 19 infected individuals in groups and avoid transmissions. If participants consent, at&#xD;
      D5 a cotton pad will be put in the arm pits and between the legs to capture the odors for&#xD;
      approx 60 minutes. The samples will be sent to the dog training centre (K9 Training Centrum,&#xD;
      Brugsesteenweg 105 8450 Bredene, responsible: Johan Weckhuyzen (CEO)) where they will be used&#xD;
      to train dogs to identify COVID-19 infected individuals. These samples will be used one time&#xD;
      and will be destroyed after usage at the training centre.&#xD;
&#xD;
      COVIM2.0 substudy: Immunological and virological assessment Deep characterization of&#xD;
      patients' inflammatory profile offers a unique opportunity for comprehensive understanding of&#xD;
      the pathophysiological mechanisms behind SARS-CoV2. All participants will be therefore asked&#xD;
      for additional blood sampling at D0 and D28 (8X9ml). The lipidomics analysis will be&#xD;
      performed at the laboratory of Dr. Jesmond Dalli. In addition, immunological functions on the&#xD;
      level of both adaptive and innate immunity will be studied by performing extensive&#xD;
      immunophenotyping, cytokine analysis and RNA sequencing analysis. Biomarker analysis will be&#xD;
      performed on protein and on RNA single cell level. Infectivity of different cell types&#xD;
      including macrophages will performed. These analyses will be performed at the HCRC&#xD;
      laboratory, the laboratory of Prof. Rafick-Pierre Sékaly and the VIB-UGent Center for&#xD;
      Inflammation Research. To gain a deeper understanding of pathways potentially leading to&#xD;
      severe disease courses, and also to chart where in the body there is tissue damage (apart&#xD;
      from the lungs), aim to analyze patient plasma samples with several other analytics&#xD;
      technologies as well. Bacterial extracellular vesicles, due to microbial translocation after&#xD;
      hyperinflammation, will be quantified from plasma in the laboratory of Experimental Cancer&#xD;
      Research of Ghent University. Furthermore, normal cell turnover in tissues results in the&#xD;
      release of some of their nucleic acid content into the blood. This can then be found as&#xD;
      circulating free RNA and DNA (cfRNA and cfDNA). These analyses will be performed at the&#xD;
      laboratory of Prof. Jo Vandesompele (Biogazelle). Virological evaluations will be based on&#xD;
      nasopharyngeal (or nose-throat) swab samples, used to diagnose and quantify SARS-CoV2. In&#xD;
      addition a swab will be taken to culture the SARS-CoV2 virus at D0. This will be repeated at&#xD;
      D5, D10 and D28 if PCR is positive on these timepoints (an extra swab will be taken). On a&#xD;
      selection of nasopharyngeal swab samples from patients whole genome sequencing of the&#xD;
      SARS-CoV2 virus will be performed to study the viral diversity and trace patterns of spread&#xD;
      across multiple epidemiological scales. In addition, a viral metagenomics analysis using&#xD;
      Nanopore sequencing will be used to reveal the presence of other viruses besides SARS-CoV2&#xD;
      (lab of Hans Nauwynck).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Screening failures substudy Asymptomatic individuals with positive PCR and high CT values&#xD;
      that are not eligible for the clinical trial and drug administration, but who otherwise meet&#xD;
      all in- and exclusion criteria, can participate in a substudy, wherethe investigators want to&#xD;
      see whether these individuals, despite their high CT values and therefore low viral load can&#xD;
      carry viable virus and therefore can transmit the disease. This implicates whether or not&#xD;
      they should be isolated. Furthermore, in individuals with low viral load there is a&#xD;
      possibility that they do not develop antibodies against SARSCOV2. Therefore the investigators&#xD;
      want to 1) culture virus from throat/nose swabs from these individuals at D0 2) measure&#xD;
      antibodies at D28.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 4, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>double blinded placebo controlled</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy in terms of viral load or surrogate</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>The primary endpoint is to assess the efficacy of the drug in terms of change from day 0 to day 5 in respiratory (oropharyngeal swab RT-PCR) log10 viral load.&#xD;
Surrogate market CT value will be used as well.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Camostat</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>camostat 100mg 3 tablets 3x/day D1-&gt;D5 (+ possible extension D6-&gt;D10)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo 3 tablets 3x/day D1-&gt;D5 (+ possible extension D6-&gt;D10)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Camostat</intervention_name>
    <description>Standard of care (SOC) + Camostat mesilate (Foipan) 100mg 3 tablets 3 times a day for 5 consecutive days (D1-&gt;D5);</description>
    <arm_group_label>Camostat</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>SOC + placebo 500 mg 3 tablets 3 times a day for five consecutive days (D1-&gt;D5).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Camostat</intervention_name>
    <description>Standard of care (SOC) + Camostat mesilate (Foipan) 100mg 3 tablets 3 times a day for 5 consecutive days (D6-&gt;D10);</description>
    <arm_group_label>Camostat</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>SOC + placebo 500 mg 3 tablets 3 times a day for five consecutive days (D6-&gt;D10).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged ≥18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to participate and fill out a daily symptom diary&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to take the parameters such as blood oxygenation and temperature&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to attend follow-up visits both by phone as at the clinic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capable of understanding the commitment in the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signs and symptoms suggestive of COVID disease in absence of hospitalization criteria&#xD;
             as defined by the flowchart used at the emergency department of our institution&#xD;
             (appendix 4), present for maximum 5 days and confirmed by PCR.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  OR documented COVID-19 infection by PCR with CT value below the threshold of 30 in&#xD;
             asymptomatic individuals.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For women of childbearing potential*: they should be willing to use highly effective&#xD;
             method of contraception during treatment and until the end of study defined as having&#xD;
             a failure rate of less than 1% per year when used consistently and correctly.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Such methods include:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  combined (estrogen and progestogen containing) hormonal contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  associated with inhibition of ovulation: oral, intravaginal or transdermal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  progestogen-only hormonal contraception associated with inhibition of ovulation: oral,&#xD;
             injectable or implantable&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  intrauterine device (IUD) and intrauterine hormone-releasing system ( IUS)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  bilateral tubal occlusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  vasectomised partner&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  sexual abstinence&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  For men of reproductive potential**: condom should be used as contraception&#xD;
                  during treatment and until the end of study when having a partner of childbearing&#xD;
                  potential&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  a woman is considered of childbearing potential (WOCBP), i.e. fertile,&#xD;
                       following menarche and until becoming post-menopausal unless permanently&#xD;
                       sterile. Permanent sterilisation methods include hysterectomy, bilateral&#xD;
                       salpingectomy and bilateral oophorectomy. A postmenopausal state is defined&#xD;
                       as no menses for 12 months without an alternative medical cause. A high&#xD;
                       follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) level in the postmenopausal range may be&#xD;
                       used to confirm a post-menopausal state in women not using hormonal&#xD;
                       contraception or hormonal replacement therapy. However in the absence of 12&#xD;
                       months of amenorrhea, a single FSH measurement is insufficient.&#xD;
&#xD;
                         -  a man is considered fertile after puberty unless permanently sterile by&#xD;
                            bilateral orchidectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to make a decision to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to take oral medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to provide informed written consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity towards Camostat or other Serine protease inhibitors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that, in the Investigator's opinion, prevents adequate compliance with&#xD;
             study therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any COVID infection at risk for hospitalisation as described in the emergency&#xD;
             department flowchart (cfr appendix 4)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With regard to exclusion of women of child-bearing potential, women who tell us they&#xD;
             know they are pregnant are excluded. All women of child-bearing potential who test&#xD;
             positive for pregnancy by urine test at first visit are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe chronic pancreatitis requiring suction of gastric juice, fasting or abstention&#xD;
             from drinking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Postoperative reflux oesophagitis due to reflux or gastric juice&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Postoperative reflux oesophagitis (if improvement of symptoms is not observed).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Linos Vandekerckhove</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UZ Gent</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Marie-Angélique De Scheerder</last_name>
    <phone>+32476937613</phone>
    <email>marie-angelique.descheerder@uzgent.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ghent University Hospital, Algemene Inwendige Ziekten</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gent</city>
        <zip>9000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marie-Angélique De Scheerder</last_name>
      <phone>0476937613</phone>
      <email>marie-angelique.descheerder@uzgent.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 10, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 10, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>antiviral</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gabexate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Camostat</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

