<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="863">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04643522</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>E1-20-1237</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04643522</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Semen Parameters and COVID-19 in Infertile Men</brief_title>
  <official_title>Does COVID-19 Worsen the Semen Parameters? Early Results of a Tertiary Health Center</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ankara City Hospital Bilkent</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ankara City Hospital Bilkent</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus Disease-19 (COVID-19) is a global pandemics which affects many organs and systems&#xD;
      with a range of morbidities and high mortality rates. There are a number of studies revealed&#xD;
      that COVID-19 may affect the testes and male genital tract which may in turn disrupt the&#xD;
      gonadal functions.The current study aimed to evaluate the effect of COVID-19 on semen&#xD;
      parameters and sex-related hormone levels.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In this current study, the investigators aimed to elucidate the alteration in semen&#xD;
      parameters of the infertile male patients who had been infected with SARS-CoV-2, through the&#xD;
      comparison of the spermiogram results which were reported before and after the diagnosis of&#xD;
      COVID-19. The investigators also aimed to evaluate the impact of COVID-19 on the sex-related&#xD;
      hormone levels as follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH), luteinizing hormone (LH), and&#xD;
      testosterone (T). The current study is conducted in Ankara City Hospital, the highest&#xD;
      capacity tertiary health care center of the capital town of Turkey. The study included 21&#xD;
      patients who applied to Ankara City Hospital, Andrology Clinic for male infertility up to 05&#xD;
      October, 2020 and have had the semen analyses reported before and after the clinically&#xD;
      confirmed diagnosis of COVID-19 through reverse transcriptase PCR. Besides the semen&#xD;
      analyses, 8 of these 21 patients have also the had the reported levels of T, FSH and LH which&#xD;
      were also analyzed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 7, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 10, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 5, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Semen analyses parameters including sperm motility (total, progressive, non-progressive and immotile</measure>
    <time_frame>first 1 hour</time_frame>
    <description>cell count percentage</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Semen analyses parameters including sperm concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>first 1 hour</time_frame>
    <description>cell count per milliliters of semen sample.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Semen analyses parameters including sperm morphology</measure>
    <time_frame>first 1 hour</time_frame>
    <description>percentage of normal forms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Semen analyses parameters including semen volume</measure>
    <time_frame>first 1 hour</time_frame>
    <description>milliliters</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sex-related hormone levels including testosterone</measure>
    <time_frame>20 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>nanograms per deciliter</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sex-related hormone levels including follicle stimulating hormone and luteinizing hormone</measure>
    <time_frame>20 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Units per liter</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">21</enrollment>
  <condition>Sperm Count, Low</condition>
  <condition>Hormone Disturbance</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Before COVID-19</arm_group_label>
    <description>The semen parameters and sex-related hormone levels of the patients which were performed before the diagnosis of COVID-19.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>After COVID-19</arm_group_label>
    <description>The semen parameters and sex-related hormone levels of the patients which were performed after the diagnosis of COVID-19.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Clinical assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>Comparison of semen analysis results and sex-related hormone levels between the dependent groups which were defined as before COVID-19 and after COVID-19 (the data of the same patient group were compared as before and after the diagnosis of COVID-19).</description>
    <arm_group_label>After COVID-19</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Before COVID-19</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The data of overall 25 patients who applied to our clinic for infertility evaluation and&#xD;
        have had the semen analysis results reported before, and after the diagnosis of COVID-19&#xD;
        were reviewed. The 4 of the patients were found to have azoospermia. Due to the difficulty&#xD;
        to compare the change at semen parameters in case of azoospermia as before and after&#xD;
        results, these 4 patients were excluded. The study included 21 patients in final analyses.&#xD;
        The results were presented through the two dependent group analyses, based on the patients'&#xD;
        data collected before and after the diagnosis of COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The diagnosis of COVID-19 had been established according to the detection of SARS-CoV-2 in&#xD;
        the sample taken from nasopharynx with a cotton swap, which was examined through the&#xD;
        RT-PCR. None of the patients were at active phase of the COVID-19 at time of the semen&#xD;
        sampling.The serum samples for hormone analyses were obtained on the same days with the&#xD;
        semen samplings.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Reproductive age Infertile men Clinically confirmed (with reverse transcriptase polymerase&#xD;
        chain reaction-RT PCR) COVID-19 history Semen analyses performed before and after the&#xD;
        diagnosis of COVID-19 (must be applicable for all patients) Sex-related hormone levels&#xD;
        including FSH, LH, and T which were reported before and after the diagnosis of COVID-19&#xD;
        (was applicable for some of the patients)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Azoospermia Semen analyses performed only before or after the diagnosis of COVID-19 Semen&#xD;
        analysis performed in another hospital RT-PCR results which were reported in another&#xD;
        hospital Chronical renal disease Chronical liver failure Patient age lower than 18 years&#xD;
        old&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Erdem Koç</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ankara City Hospital Bilkent</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ankara City Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ankara</city>
        <zip>06100</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Holtmann N, Edimiris P, Andree M, Doehmen C, Baston-Buest D, Adams O, Kruessel JS, Bielfeld AP. Assessment of SARS-CoV-2 in human semen-a cohort study. Fertil Steril. 2020 Aug;114(2):233-238. doi: 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2020.05.028. Epub 2020 May 29.</citation>
    <PMID>32650948</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ma L, Xie W, Li D, Shi L, Ye G, Mao Y, Xiong Y, Sun H, Zheng F, Chen Z, Qin J, Lyu J, Zhang Y, Zhang M. Evaluation of sex-related hormones and semen characteristics in reproductive-aged male COVID-19 patients. J Med Virol. 2020 Jul 4. doi: 10.1002/jmv.26259. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>32621617</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Achua JK, Chu KY, Ibrahim E, Khodamoradi K, Delma KS, Iakymenko OA, Kryvenko ON, Arora H, Ramasamy R. Histopathology and Ultrastructural Findings of Fatal COVID-19 Infections on Testis. World J Mens Health. 2021 Jan;39(1):65-74. doi: 10.5534/wjmh.200170. Epub 2020 Nov 3.</citation>
    <PMID>33151050</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Yang M, Chen S, Huang B, Zhong JM, Su H, Chen YJ, Cao Q, Ma L, He J, Li XF, Li X, Zhou JJ, Fan J, Luo DJ, Chang XN, Arkun K, Zhou M, Nie X. Pathological Findings in the Testes of COVID-19 Patients: Clinical Implications. Eur Urol Focus. 2020 Sep 15;6(5):1124-1129. doi: 10.1016/j.euf.2020.05.009. Epub 2020 May 31.</citation>
    <PMID>32563676</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 24, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 25, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 25, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 25, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 30, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ankara City Hospital Bilkent</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Erdem Koç</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Medical Doctor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Male infertility</keyword>
  <keyword>Semen parameters</keyword>
  <keyword>Sex-related hormone levels</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Oligospermia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endocrine System Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data belonging to participants will be available to any researcher or editorial reviewer board if needed.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

