<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3956">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04632368</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00106191</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04632368</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Targeting the Health Care Provider (HCP) Burnout Crisis During the COVID-19 Pandemic</brief_title>
  <official_title>Targeting the Health Care Provider (HCP) Burnout Crisis During the COVID-19 Pandemic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Duke University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Duke University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This single blind, randomized, controlled trial (RCT) evaluates, a nonpharmacological&#xD;
      intervention, TM (Transcendental Meditation) for improving burnout (, as measured by&#xD;
      self-reporting (survey), physiologic, and neuro-functional imaging studies in health care&#xD;
      providers (HCPs) when practiced over 3 months' time. The investigators define HCPs as any&#xD;
      physician, physician trainee, nurse, physician assistant, nurse practitioner or respiratory&#xD;
      therapist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HCPs will be screened by a single-item stress scale and Columbia Suicide Severity Rating&#xD;
      Scale (CSSRS) to understand their stress level and exclusion criteria respectively. The&#xD;
      Global Severity Index of the Brief Symptom Inventory (BSI)-18 Global Severity score will be&#xD;
      used as the primary outcome for pre- and post-TM training (baseline, 1 vs. 3 months). In&#xD;
      addition, the investigators will evaluate physiological markers of stress and cardiovascular&#xD;
      resiliency such as 1) changes (pre/post-treatment) in heart rate variability (HRV) through&#xD;
      wearables, 2) Galvanic Skin Response (GSR) - changes in sweat gland activity that result from&#xD;
      changes in an emotional state. fMRI will be performed by the Duke Brain Imaging and Analysis&#xD;
      Center (BIAC) on a subset of participants to evaluate changes A specifically developed mobile&#xD;
      app will aid data collection as well as reminders for providers to aid compliance for&#xD;
      meditation&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      OVERALL HYPOTHESIS: HCPs who learn and practice TM will demonstrate significantly improved&#xD;
      symptoms of burnout within 3 months, as measured by self-report (survey), physiologic, and&#xD;
      neuro-functional imaging studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SPECIFIC AIM 1: To conduct a single-blind, randomized, controlled trial (RCT) of TM (N=40)&#xD;
      vs. Control (CTL, N=40) in frontline HCPs. HCPs will be screened by a single-item stress&#xD;
      scale and Columbia Suicide Severity Rating Scale (CSSRS). The Global Severity Index of the&#xD;
      Brief Symptom Inventory (BSI)-18 Global Severity score will be used as the primary outcome&#xD;
      for pre- and post-TM training (baseline, 1 vs. 3 months). SPECIFIC AIM 2: Evaluate changes&#xD;
      (pre/post-treatment) in heart rate variability (HRV), a physiological measure of stress, and&#xD;
      overall cardiovascular resilience) in response to TM practice versus CTL. Participants will&#xD;
      be asked to wear an Apple Watch throughout trial participation to assess changes in resting&#xD;
      HRV during meditative practice. Galvanic Skin Response (GSR) refers to the changes in sweat&#xD;
      gland activity that result from changes in an emotional state. A portable GSR device (e-Sense&#xD;
      Skin Response) will be used to evaluate GSR score (baseline and 3 months). fMRI (N=20 for&#xD;
      each group) will be performed by the Duke Brain Imaging and Analysis Center (BIAC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      fMRI Protocol: The first 20 eligible (exclusion criteria: pregnancy, claustrophobia,&#xD;
      reluctance to participate) patients from each group will be randomly assigned to get fMRI at&#xD;
      baseline and at the end of the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 20, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Eligible participants, on enrollment in the study, would be randomly assigned to meditation intervention group vs control group. Control group will be offered intervention at the end of the study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change in self reported Stress symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 month, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in brief symptom inventory as evaluated by BSI 18</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in self reported resilience</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 month, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>These will include secondary outcomes as measured by the Connor Davidson Resilience Scale-25 (CD-RISC).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in symptoms of depression</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 month, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in symptoms of depression will be measured by PHQ 9 scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in insomnia symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 month, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in insomnia symptoms as measured by Insomnia severity Index(ISI)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in anxiety symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 month, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in anxiety symptoms as measured by GAD-7</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in psychological distress</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 1 month, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>change in psychological distress as measured by the Global Severity Index of the Brief Symptom Inventory (BSI)-18 questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in self reported burnout symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Time Frame: Baseline, 1 month, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in burnout symptoms in HCPs as measured by Maslach Burnout Inventory( MBI)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Burnout, Professional</condition>
  <condition>Stress, Psychological</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Transcendental Meditation Intervention Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>TM, a mind-body intervention that can reduce sympathetic arousal and promote a state of relaxation and calm, will be offered to a randomized group of eligible HCPs ( N=40)providing care during COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual(TAU) Control Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control group consists of eligible HCPs who are randomized to control group(N=40) and would not receive any intervention. At the end of 3 month study period, control group participants would be eligible for TM training.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Transcendental Meditation</intervention_name>
    <description>TM, a mind-body intervention that can reduce sympathetic arousal and promote a state of relaxation and calm, will be offered to HCPs dealing with COVID-19 pandemic</description>
    <arm_group_label>Transcendental Meditation Intervention Arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        HCPs including physicians, trainee physicians, nurses, nurse practitioners, Physician&#xD;
        Assistants, and respiratory therapists providing patient care during the COVID-19 pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A single-item stress scale will be used as a screen for eligibility; a minimum score&#xD;
             of 6 on a 10-point response scale will be needed to meet inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have at least a 5% increase from baseline in heart rate after exposure to&#xD;
             a personalized stressful script OR at least a 33% increase in skin conductance after&#xD;
             exposure to the script&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to address burnout symptoms by non-pharmacological means&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All subjects must provide Informed Consent prior to enrollment in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to wear the provided Apple Watch for the data collection process&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Antipsychotic medications or beta-blockers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current suicidal or homicidal ideation (suicidal ideation as screened by C-SSRI survey&#xD;
             pre-enrollment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous instruction in TM&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Taylor Clinical Research Co-ordinator</last_name>
    <phone>919-479-0743</phone>
    <email>taylor.ardito@duke.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Catherine Clinical Research Co-ordinator</last_name>
    <phone>919 613 7627</phone>
    <email>catherine.foss@duke.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University health system</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Taylor Ardito, CRC</last_name>
      <phone>919-479-0743</phone>
      <email>taylor.ardito@duke.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Catherine Foss</last_name>
      <email>catherine.foss@duke.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 11, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Burnout, Professional</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Burnout, Psychological</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stress, Psychological</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

