<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1923">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04695301</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>34170820.0.1001.0071</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04695301</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Functional Outcomes in COVID-19 Survivors and Use of a Digital Platform for Rehabilitation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Functional Outcomes in COVID-19 Survivors and Use of a Digital Platform for Rehabilitation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital Israelita Albert Einstein</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital Israelita Albert Einstein</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      COVID-19, an acute respiratory disease caused by coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2), and in most&#xD;
      cases, causes mild to moderate symptoms of fever, cough and dyspnea. However, a not&#xD;
      insignificant portion, given the total number of people affected, will present symptoms of&#xD;
      severe acute respiratory failure and multiple organ failure, requiring hospitalization under&#xD;
      intensive care, use of mechanical ventilation, prolonged period of immobilization and,&#xD;
      consequently, physical, cognitive and psychological damage, which may affect survivors for a&#xD;
      long period after hospitalization. All of these factors are known to have an impact on&#xD;
      various areas of life: personal, social and economic, which makes the need for continued&#xD;
      specific care after hospital discharge relevant. In this context, the role of rehabilitation&#xD;
      programs is fundamental, aiming not only at a safer dehospitalization, but also at the&#xD;
      continuity of care with the objective of restoring the biopsychosocial skills of these&#xD;
      individuals, allowing functional independence for activities of daily life and a shorter&#xD;
      return physical and social activities performed before the disease. However, the big&#xD;
      challenge for the health system is how to offer this on a large scale. Therefore, knowing the&#xD;
      clinical and functional profile of these patients at discharge and verifying the viability of&#xD;
      a digital platform for rehabilitation and monitoring of these patients is the first step to&#xD;
      allow the creation of a new form of continuity of care and access to affected patients with&#xD;
      serious diseases such as COVID-19 and other syndromes capable of generate functional&#xD;
      impairment. Therefore,the investigators objective is to characterize and monitor the&#xD;
      functional profile and exercise capacity of patients affected by COVID-19 at the hospital&#xD;
      discharge, as well as to verify the viability and compliance of patients to the use of a&#xD;
      digital platform for the application of a distance rehabilitation program.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigators proposal is to characterize and evaluate the impact of the disease on the&#xD;
      clinical, functional and social aspects in these patients affected by COVID-19 and to propose&#xD;
      the continuity of specific care after hospital discharge with a physical rehabilitation&#xD;
      program through a digital platform, remotely for a period of 3 months. The proposed&#xD;
      hypothesis is that patients convalescing from COVID-19 and undergoing the rehabilitation&#xD;
      program will have a gain in functional skills and quality of life. The professional team&#xD;
      involved in this study will be responsible for managing, monitoring and evaluating the&#xD;
      participating patients and monitoring the performance of the proposed functional exercises.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Men and women affected by COVID-19, over 18 years of age, admitted to HIAE partner hospitals who have been in hospital for more than 10 days or in need of treatment in semi-intensive or intensive care units will be selected. Follow-up will be carried out for 3 months, with remote reevaluations. During this period, the rehabilitation program will be offered for 3 months, through a digital platform.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterize the clinical function profile of patients affected by COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Characterize the clinical functional profile of patients affected by COVID-19 by data from medical records</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterize the exercise capacity of patients affected by COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Characterize the exercise capacity of patients affected by COVID-19 by 2-minute step test</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess clinical and demographic data</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assess clinical and demographic data</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess functional level at hospital discharge</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assess functional level at hospital discharge and 3 months after discharge by physical test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess patient compliance of the rehabilitation program using the digital platform</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assess patient compliance of the rehabilitation program using the digital platform checking your adherence to the program</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <condition>Coronavirus Infections</condition>
  <condition>Exercise Therapy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>digital platform rehabilitation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Rehabilitation program through a digital platform for 3 months</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients without access to technology will do the exercises using booklets and will compose the control group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rehabilitation protocol through a digital platform</intervention_name>
    <description>During 3 months the patients will participate in a rehabilitation program through a digital platform</description>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>digital platform rehabilitation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men and women affected by COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  over 18 years of age, admitted to HIAE partner hospitals&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  presence of a physical or cognitive condition that makes it impossible or&#xD;
             contraindicated to perform the 2-minute stride test and perform the proposed&#xD;
             exercises.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a more severe clinical and functional profile,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Luciana D Matos, MD,PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hospital Israelita Albert Einstein</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Luciana D Matos, MD,PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+5511 983260690</phone>
    <email>lucinana.matos@einstein.br</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Instituto Israelita de Ensino e Pesquisa Albert Einstein 's (IIEP)</name>
      <address>
        <city>São Paulo</city>
        <zip>05652-000</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Luciana Diniz Nagem Janot de Matos</last_name>
      <phone>00551121514100</phone>
      <email>luciana.matos@einstein.br</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Telemedicine</keyword>
  <keyword>exercise therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>coronavirus infections</keyword>
  <keyword>stress disorders traumatic</keyword>
  <keyword>fatigue</keyword>
  <keyword>quality of life</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>all IPD that underlie results in a publication</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>when to published</ipd_time_frame>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

