<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="116">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04334291</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20/241-E</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>EUPAS34399</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04334291</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>International COVID19 Clinical Evaluation Registry,</brief_title>
  <acronym>HOPE COVID 19</acronym>
  <official_title>International COVID19 Clinical Evaluation Registry: HOPECOVID19. (Health Outcome Predictive Evaluation for COVID19)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>IVAN J NUÑEZ GIL</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>St Carlos Hospital, Madrid, Spain</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators propose to select all COVID 19 patients attended in any health center (with&#xD;
      in hospital beds), who have been discharged or have died at the time of the evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective of the present study is to carefully characterize the clinical profile of&#xD;
      patients infected with COVID-19 in order to develop a simple prognostic clinical score&#xD;
      allowing, in selected cases, rapid logistic decision making (discharge with follow-up,&#xD;
      referral to provisional/field hospitals or admission to more complex hospital centers).&#xD;
&#xD;
      As secondary objectives, the analysis of the risk-adjusted influence of treatments and&#xD;
      previous comorbidities of patients infected with the disease will be performed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      INTRODUCTION. The disease caused by the new respiratory virus (coronavirus) designated as&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 has recently been classified as a pandemic by the WHO.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With an increasing number of confirmed cases in most countries worldwide, it is responsible&#xD;
      for a significant morbidity and mortality and has motivated the implementation of measures at&#xD;
      national and international levels with a great impact on the way of life of people throughout&#xD;
      the whole planet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, this condition currently threatens many countries with the collapse of health&#xD;
      systems, producing serious logistical problems due to extensive affectation of the&#xD;
      population, which can worsen the prognosis of those primarily affected by COVID 19 and other&#xD;
      patients with different pathologies and who may have difficulties to get healthcare.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Limited clinical information is available and generally limited to the Asian population,&#xD;
      since the first cases were identified in Wuhan (Hubei, China).&#xD;
&#xD;
      PURPOSE. The main objective of the present study is to carefully characterize the clinical&#xD;
      profile of patients infected with COVID-19 in order to develop a simple prognostic clinical&#xD;
      score allowing, in selected cases, rapid logistic decision making (discharge with follow-up,&#xD;
      referral to provisional/field hospitals or admission to more complex hospital centers).&#xD;
&#xD;
      As secondary objectives, the analysis of the risk-adjusted influence of treatments (ie.&#xD;
      ACEIs, ARBs) and previous comorbidities of patients infected with the disease will be&#xD;
      performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DESIGN AND STATISTICAL ANALYSIS Cross-sectional and ambispective registry, a real life &quot;all&#xD;
      comers&quot; type, with voluntary participation, without funding or conflicts of interest. It is a&#xD;
      study initiated by researcher that will have advanced statistical support from the IMAS&#xD;
      foundation (Institute for the Improvement of Health Care, Madrid, Spain), that will serve as&#xD;
      statistical core.&#xD;
&#xD;
      International level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PARTICIPANTS PROTOCOL. The study has been approved by Hospital Clinico San Carlos Ethic´s&#xD;
      Committee (20/241-E) and the institutional board of each participating center. It has&#xD;
      received an AEMPS classification (EPA-0D).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The researchers aimto select all the patients attended in any health center (with in hospital&#xD;
      beds), who have been discharged or have died at the time of the evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All will be considered eligible with a positive COVID 19 test (any type) or if their&#xD;
      attending physicians consider them highly likely to have presented the infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given the anonymous characteristics of the registry and the health alarm situation generated&#xD;
      by the virus, in principle, it is not considered necessary to provide written informed&#xD;
      consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Inclusion criteria Patients discharged (deceased or alive) from any hospital center with a&#xD;
      confirmed diagnosis or a COVID-19 high suspicion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are no exclusion criteria, except for the patient's explicit refusal to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DATA BASE. An anonymized database is presented in electronic format, to be filled in at each&#xD;
      participating center (www.HopeProjectMD.com).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In theory, all information could be obtained from electronic records (medical history).&#xD;
&#xD;
      If deemed necessary, the investigator may call patients in order to establish their vital&#xD;
      status (strongly warranted), as well as the results of the RNA test (or antibody) , if they&#xD;
      were pending during their stay.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SAMPLE SIZE. It would not be possible to estimate for the sample size based on literature&#xD;
      reports. Thus, HOPE will aim to get the maximum numbers of patients possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTCOMES. Primary: All-cause mortality. The major contributors of increased mortality will be&#xD;
      assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary: In stay events, defined by the attending physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In hospital stay.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Heart failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Renal failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Respiratory Insufficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Upper respiratory tract involvement.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pneumonia.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Sepsis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Systemic inflammatory response Syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Clinically relevant bleeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hemoptysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Embolic event&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Other complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Causes of death. Depending the results of the main interim analysis, the main DB could&#xD;
           be slightly modified and several sub analyses could be proposed after sensitivity&#xD;
           analyses.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 23, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 1, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>2 Weeks</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Death</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>All cause</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>In hospital stay.</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Heart failure</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>According the attending physician.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Renal failure</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>According the attending physician.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Respiratory Insufficiency.</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>According the attending physician.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Upper respiratory tract involvement</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>According the attending physician.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pneumonia</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>According the attending physician.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sepsis</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>According the attending physician.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Systemic inflammatory response Syndrome.</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>According the attending physician.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinically relevant bleeding</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>According the attending physician.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Other complications.</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 month</time_frame>
    <description>According the attending physician.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">8168</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID 19</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Observational (registry)</intervention_name>
    <description>Observational study.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Confirmed diagnosis or a COVID-19 high suspicion.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients discharged (deceased or alive) from any hospital center with a confirmed&#xD;
             diagnosis or a COVID-19 high suspicion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  There are no exclusion criteria, except for the patient's explicit refusal to&#xD;
             participate.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Lclinico San Carlos</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28040</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://hopeprojectmd.com/en/</url>
    <description>HOPE WEB PAGE AND E-CRD</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Núñez-Gil IJ, Estrada V, Fernández-Pérez C, Feltes G, Vedia O, Vergara-Uzcategui CE, Moreno-Menguía VH, Cerrato E, D'Ascenzo F, Raposeiras-Roubin S, Martín-Sánchez FJ, Alfonso-Rodríguez E, Huang J, Ramakrishna H, Gil-Higes E, Fernández-Ortiz A, Macaya C. Health Outcome Predictive Evaluation for COVID 19 international registry (HOPE COVID-19), rationale and design. Contemp Clin Trials Commun. 2020 Dec;20:100654. doi: 10.1016/j.conctc.2020.100654. Epub 2020 Sep 23.</citation>
    <PMID>32989425</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Rivera-Caravaca JM, Núñez-Gil IJ, Vivas D, Viana-Llamas MC, Uribarri A, Becerra-Muñoz VM, Trabattoni D, Fernández Rozas I, Feltes G, López-Pais J, El-Battrawy I, Macaya C, Fernandez-Ortiz A, Estrada V, Marín F; HOPE COVID-19 Investigators. Clinical profile and prognosis in patients on oral anticoagulation before admission for COVID-19. Eur J Clin Invest. 2021 Jan;51(1):e13436. doi: 10.1111/eci.13436. Epub 2020 Nov 7.</citation>
    <PMID>33080051</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Núñez-Gil IJ, Fernández-Pérez C, Estrada V, Becerra-Muñoz VM, El-Battrawy I, Uribarri A, Fernández-Rozas I, Feltes G, Viana-Llamas MC, Trabattoni D, López-País J, Pepe M, Romero R, Castro-Mejía AF, Cerrato E, Astrua TC, D'Ascenzo F, Fabregat-Andres O, Moreu J, Guerra F, Signes-Costa J, Marín F, Buosenso D, Bardají A, Raposeiras-Roubín S, Elola J, Molino Á, Gómez-Doblas JJ, Abumayyaleh M, Aparisi Á, Molina M, Guerri A, Arroyo-Espliguero R, Assanelli E, Mapelli M, García-Acuña JM, Brindicci G, Manzone E, Ortega-Armas ME, Bianco M, Trung CP, Núñez MJ, Castellanos-Lluch C, García-Vázquez E, Cabello-Clotet N, Jamhour-Chelh K, Tellez MJ, Fernández-Ortiz A, Macaya C; HOPE COVID-19 Investigators. Mortality risk assessment in Spain and Italy, insights of the HOPE COVID-19 registry. Intern Emerg Med. 2020 Nov 9. doi: 10.1007/s11739-020-02543-5. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>33165755</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Núñez-Gil IJ, Estrada V, Fernández-Pérez C, Fernández-Rozas I, Martín-Sánchez FJ, Macaya C. The COVID-19 curve, health system overload, and mortality. Emergencias. 2020 Ago;32(4):293-295. English, Spanish.</citation>
    <PMID>32692012</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Uribarri A, Núñez-Gil IJ, Aparisi A, Becerra-Muñoz VM, Feltes G, Trabattoni D, Fernández-Rozas I, Viana-Llamas MC, Pepe M, Cerrato E, Capel-Astrua T, Romero R, Castro-Mejía AF, El-Battrawy I, López-País J, D'Ascenzo F, Fabregat-Andres O, Bardají A, Raposeiras-Roubin S, Marín F, Fernández-Ortiz A, Macaya C, Estrada V; HOPE COVID-19 Investigators. Impact of renal function on admission in COVID-19 patients: an analysis of the international HOPE COVID-19 (Health Outcome Predictive Evaluation for COVID 19) Registry. J Nephrol. 2020 Aug;33(4):737-745. doi: 10.1007/s40620-020-00790-5. Epub 2020 Jun 29.</citation>
    <PMID>32602006</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Signes-Costa J, Núñez-Gil IJ, Soriano JB, Arroyo-Espliguero R, Eid CM, Romero R, Uribarri A, Fernández-Rozas I, Aguado MG, Becerra-Muñoz VM, Huang J, Pepe M, Cerrato E, Raposeiras S, Gonzalez A, Franco-Leon F, Wang L, Alfonso E, Ugo F, García-Prieto JF, Feltes G, Abumayyaleh M, Espejo-Paeres C, Jativa J, Masjuan AL, Macaya C, Carbonell Asíns JA, Estrada V; HOPE COVID-19 investigators. Prevalence and 30-Day Mortality in Hospitalized Patients With Covid-19 and Prior Lung Diseases. Arch Bronconeumol. 2020 Dec 16. pii: S0300-2896(20)30535-4. doi: 10.1016/j.arbres.2020.11.012. [Epub ahead of print] English, Spanish.</citation>
    <PMID>33423874</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Núñez-Gil IJJ, Fernández-Ortiz A, Maroud Eid C, Huang J, Romero R, Becerra-Muñoz VM, Uribarri A, Feltes G, Trabatoni D, Fernandez-Rozas I, Viana-Llamas MC, Pepe M, Cerrato E, Bertaina M, Capel Astrua T, Alfonso E, Castro-Mejía AF, Raposeiras-Roubin S, D'Ascenzo F, Espejo Paeres C, Signes-Costa J, Bardaji A, Fernandez-Pérez C, Marin F, Fabregat-Andres O, Akin I, Estrada V, Macaya C. Underlying heart diseases and acute COVID-19 outcomes. Cardiol J. 2020 Dec 21. doi: 10.5603/CJ.a2020.0183. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>33346365</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Becerra-Muñoz VM, Núñez-Gil IJ, Eid CM, Aguado MG, Romero R, Huang J, Mulet A, Ugo F, Rametta F, Liebetrau C, Aparisi A, Fernández-Rozas I, Viana-Llamas MC, Feltes G, Pepe M, Moreno-Rondón LA, Cerrato E, Raposeiras-Roubín S, Alfonso E, Carrero-Fernández A, Buzón-Martín L, Abumayyaleh M, Gonzalez A, Ortiz AF, Macaya C, Estrada V, Fernández-Pérez C, Gómez-Doblas JJ. Clinical profile and predictors of in-hospital mortality among older patients admitted for COVID-19. Age Ageing. 2020 Nov 17. pii: afaa258. doi: 10.1093/ageing/afaa258. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>33201181</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 1, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 3, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 6, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>St Carlos Hospital, Madrid, Spain</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>IVAN J NUÑEZ GIL</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator. Attending Physician. MD, PhD, FESC</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>IPD are to be share among HOPE researchers. However, the HOPE Steering committee is open to collaborative proposals.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

