<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2822">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04616846</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020/20</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04616846</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Thromboembolic Risk Screening in Patients With Cancer and COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>NEOTHROCOVID</acronym>
  <official_title>Thromboembolic Risk Screening in Patients With Cancer and COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Antoine Lacassagne</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Antoine Lacassagne</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Study Rational&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since December 2019, outbreak of COVID-19 caused by a novel virus SARS-Cov-2 has spread&#xD;
      rapidly around the world and became a pandemic issue. First data report high mortality in&#xD;
      severe patients with 30% death rate at 28 days. Exact proportions of the reasons of death are&#xD;
      unclear: severe respiratory distress syndrome is mainly reported which can be related to&#xD;
      massive cell destruction by the virus, bacterial surinfection, cardiomyopathy or pulmonary&#xD;
      embolism. The exact proportion of all these causes is unknown and venous thromboembolism&#xD;
      could be a major cause because of the massive inflammation reported during COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      High levels of D-dimers and fibrin degradation products are associated with increased risk of&#xD;
      mortality and some authors suggest a possible occurrence of venous thromboembolism (VTE)&#xD;
      during COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Indeed, COVID-19 infected patients are likely at increased risk of VTE. In a multicenter&#xD;
      retrospective cohort study from China, elevated D-dimers levels (&gt;1g/L) were strongly&#xD;
      associated with in-hospital death, even after multivariable adjustment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Also, interestingly,the prophylactic administration of anticoagulant treatment was associated&#xD;
      with decreased mortality in a cohort of 449 patients, with a positive effect in patients with&#xD;
      coagulopathy (sepsis-induced coagulopathy score ≥ 4) reducing the 28 days mortality rate&#xD;
      (32.8% versus 52.4%, p=0.01).&#xD;
&#xD;
      However the presence/prevalence of VTE disease is unknown in COVID-19 cancer patients with&#xD;
      either mild or severe disease. Cancer patients are at a higher risk of VTE than general&#xD;
      population (x6 times) and could be consequently at a further higher of VTE during COVID-19,&#xD;
      in comparison with non-cancer patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The exact rate of VTE and pulmonary embolism during COVID-19 was never evaluated, especially&#xD;
      in cancer patients, and is of importance in order to understand if this disease needs&#xD;
      appropriate prophylaxis against VTE.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The largest series of cancer patients so far included 28 COVID-19 infected cancer patients:&#xD;
      the rate of mortality was 28.6%. 78.6% of them needed oxygen therapy, 35.7% of them&#xD;
      mechanical ventilation. Pulmonary embolism was suspected in some patients but not&#xD;
      investigated due to the severity of the disease and renal insufficiency, reflecting the lack&#xD;
      of data in this situation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the present study is to analyze the rate of symptomatic/occult VTE in a cohort of&#xD;
      patients with cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Expected benefits Anticipated benefits of the research are the detection of VTE in order to&#xD;
      treat it for the included patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For all COVID-19 positive cancer patients it will enable to provide some guidelines and&#xD;
      determine which patient are at risk for VTE and which will need ultrasound to detect occult&#xD;
      VTE.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Foreseeable risks Foreseeable risks for patients are non-significant because the additional&#xD;
      procedures needed are ultrasound exam, and blood sample test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology&#xD;
&#xD;
      Retrospective and prospective (ambispective), multicentric study to evaluate the occurrence&#xD;
      of venous thromboembolism during COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Indeed, because the outbreak can end within the next 3-6 months, Investigators may not be&#xD;
      able to answer the question if Investigators only focus on patients investigated&#xD;
      prospectively. Investigators then decided to include patients from medical team who are&#xD;
      already systemically screening patients with COVID-19 disease for VTE.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Trial objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main objective To evaluate the rate of venous thromboembolism at 23 days during COVID-19&#xD;
      infection in cancer patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Rational&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since December 2019, outbreak of COVID-19 caused by a novel virus SARS-Cov-2 has spread&#xD;
      rapidly around the world and became a pandemic issue. First data report high mortality in&#xD;
      severe patients with 30% death rate at 28 days. Exact proportions of the reasons of death are&#xD;
      unclear: severe respiratory distress syndrome is mainly reported which can be related to&#xD;
      massive cell destruction by the virus, bacterial surinfection, cardiomyopathy or pulmonary&#xD;
      embolism. The exact proportion of all these causes is unknown and venous thromboembolism&#xD;
      could be a major cause because of the massive inflammation reported during COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      High levels of D-dimers and fibrin degradation products are associated with increased risk of&#xD;
      mortality and some authors suggest a possible occurrence of venous thromboembolism (VTE)&#xD;
      during COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Indeed, COVID-19 infected patients are likely at increased risk of VTE. In a multicenter&#xD;
      retrospective cohort study from China, elevated D-dimers levels (&gt;1g/L) were strongly&#xD;
      associated with in-hospital death, even after multivariable adjustment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Also, interestingly, the prophylactic administration of anticoagulant treatment was&#xD;
      associated with decreased mortality in a cohort of 449 patients, with a positive effect in&#xD;
      patients with coagulopathy (sepsis-induced coagulopathy score ≥ 4) reducing the 28 days&#xD;
      mortality rate (32.8% versus 52.4%, p=0.01).&#xD;
&#xD;
      However the presence/prevalence of VTE disease is unknown in COVID-19 cancer patients with&#xD;
      either mild or severe disease. Cancer patients are at a higher risk of VTE than general&#xD;
      population (x6 times) and could be consequently at a further higher of VTE during COVID-19,&#xD;
      in comparison with non-cancer patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The exact rate of VTE and pulmonary embolism during COVID-19 was never evaluated, especially&#xD;
      in cancer patients, and is of importance in order to understand if this disease needs&#xD;
      appropriate prophylaxis against VTE.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The largest series of cancer patients so far included 28 COVID-19 infected cancer patients:&#xD;
      the rate of mortality was 28.6%. 78.6% of them needed oxygen therapy, 35.7% of them&#xD;
      mechanical ventilation. Pulmonary embolism was suspected in some patients but not&#xD;
      investigated due to the severity of the disease and renal insufficiency, reflecting the lack&#xD;
      of data in this situation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the present study is to analyze the rate of symptomatic/occult VTE in a cohort of&#xD;
      patients with cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Expected benefits Anticipated benefits of the research are the detection of VTE in order to&#xD;
      treat it for the included patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For all COVID-19 positive cancer patients it will enable to provide some guidelines and&#xD;
      determine which patient are at risk for VTE and which will need ultrasound to detect occult&#xD;
      VTE.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Foreseeable risks Foreseeable risks for patients are non-significant because the additional&#xD;
      procedures needed are ultrasound exam, and blood sample test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology&#xD;
&#xD;
      Retrospective and prospective (ambispective), multicentric study to evaluate the occurrence&#xD;
      of venous thromboembolism during COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Indeed, because the outbreak can end within the next 3-6 months, Investigators may not be&#xD;
      able to answer the question if Investigators only focus on patients investigated&#xD;
      prospectively. Investigators then decided to include patients from medical team who are&#xD;
      already systemically screening patients with COVID-19 disease for VTE.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Trial objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main objective To evaluate the rate of venous thromboembolism at 23 days during COVID-19&#xD;
      infection in cancer patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To determine the 23-days rate of hospitalization due to venous thromboembolism;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To determine the 23-days Overall Survival (OS);&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To determine the 23-days Specific Survival (SS, death due to venous thromboembolism);&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. To evaluate the global safety of antineoplastic treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. To determine the predictive factors of venous thromboembolism;&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. To compare the rate of symptomatic venous thromboembolism between the COVID-19 negative&#xD;
           and COVID-19 positive patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ancillary study Collection of blood sample in order to detect thrombophilia in case of venous&#xD;
      thromboembolism.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Description of specifics procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the prospective cohort:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Day 1 = Day when COVID-19 test is performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood sample (Day 1 for every patient tested for COVID19 infection) three 1.8ml citrate&#xD;
           tubes, three 3ml Heparin and two 4 ml EDTA tubes:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Count of Hb, platelet, leukocytes, neutrophils, lymphocytes,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  LDH, CRP, Procalcitonin, D-dimers, ferritin, fibrin degradation product, sodium,&#xD;
           potassium, ASAT, ALAT, GGT, PAL, TP, TCA,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Bilirubin, calcium, protein, albumin, fibrinogen, troponin, BNP.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  2 Peripheral venous Ultrasound (if positivity for COVID19 and if positive D-dimers, at&#xD;
           day 1-10 after diagnosis and day 20-23):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  analysis of femoral, popliteal, tibial and peroneal venous,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  analysis of venous where there is material/central catheters,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  analysis of any venous where there is symptom of VTE.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ECG (the day of peripheral venous ultrasound)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Computed-tomography scan with iodin contrast injection: if suspicion of pulmonary&#xD;
           embolism&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Transthoracic ultrasound (the day of peripheral venous ultrasound): if pulmonary emboly&#xD;
           signs and no availability or possibility to do computed-tomography scan: clinical emboly&#xD;
           sign are dyspnea, hemoptysis, chest pain, tachycardia, palpitations, ECG signs.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ancillary study = thrombophilia analysis if occurrence of VTE, five 10ml citrate tubes&#xD;
           and two 10 ml EDTA tubes : anti-thrombin 3, protein S deficit, protein C deficit,&#xD;
           homocystein, circulating anticoagulant, Antibody against beta 2 gp1, Antibody against&#xD;
           cardiolopin, Activated protein C resistance, mutation of Factor V and II of Leiden. The&#xD;
           thrombophilia analysis, as part of the routine practice, will be also performed in the&#xD;
           retrospective cohort and if occurrence of VTE.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  For patient negative for COVID-19 infection, a second test will be performed between&#xD;
           Day20-Day23 to confirm the negativity of COVID-19 exposure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Of note: dedicated ultrasound device will be used only for COVID-19 infected patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis plan&#xD;
&#xD;
      All statistical analyses will be performed at alpha risk=5% in bilateral hypothesis by the&#xD;
      statistician of the Center Antoine Lacassagne using R.3.6 and SAS 9.4 software for windows.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The cumulative rate of VTE is about 2-4% over a period of 70 days in patients treated for&#xD;
      cancer and at the start of chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Major well known risk factors for VTE are: certain type of cancer (stomach, pancreas, lung,&#xD;
      lymphoma, gynecologic, genitourinary without prostate), body mass index ≥ 35, platelets count&#xD;
      ≥ 350 000/mm3, Hemoglobin level &lt; 10 gr/dL (or use of red cell growth factors), leucocyte&#xD;
      cell count &gt; 11 000/mm3. 27% of patients present with low risk Khorana score (score 0) that&#xD;
      is 0.8% occurrence of VTE, 60.2% with intermediate risk (Khorana score of 1-2) that is 1.8%&#xD;
      occurrence of VTE and 12.8% high risk (Khorana score ≥ 3) that is 7.1% risk of VTE. Of note&#xD;
      the rate of occult VTE in patients with high risk is about 9% in a cohort of 35 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the study is to describe the proportion of VTE in patients with cancer presenting&#xD;
      a COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We estimate that forty patients are needed to have an appropriate overview of the incidence&#xD;
      in COVID-19 patients. In order to compare with a similar non-infected cohort Investigators&#xD;
      will also include patients with cancer tested negative for COVID-19 during the same period&#xD;
      (as soon as possible, a serology will be used thereafter to confirm it). All patients with&#xD;
      cancer tested negative for COVID-19 will be included. Investigators estimate that 80 patients&#xD;
      are needed to have an appropriate overview of the rate of VTE in the control cohort. This&#xD;
      negative cohort will be further tested with serology as soon as available, to check if they&#xD;
      were tested as false negative.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 4, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Retrospective and prospective (ambispective), multicentric study to evaluate the occurrence of venous thromboembolism during COVID-19 infection.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of venous thromboembolism</measure>
    <time_frame>From Day 9 to Day 42</time_frame>
    <description>Deep venous thrombosis and/or pulmonary embolism.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospitalization due to venous thromboembolism</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 23</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of hospitalization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 23</time_frame>
    <description>Time between the date of inclusion and the date of death for any reason.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Specific survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 23</time_frame>
    <description>Time between the date of inclusion and the date of death for venous thromboembolism.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety profile using the common toxicity criteria from the NCI CTCAE V5.0</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 23</time_frame>
    <description>Common toxicity criteria from the NCI CTCAE V5.0</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Predictive factors for venous thromboembolism</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 23</time_frame>
    <description>Khorana score (low risk (score=0), medium risk (score=1 ou 2) and high risk (score ≥ 3)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Predictive factors for venous thromboembolism</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 23</time_frame>
    <description>Caprini score (very low risk (score=0), low risk (score=1 or 2), medium risk (score=3 or 4)and high risk (score ≥ 5)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>rate of symptomatic venous thromboembolism between the COVID-19 negative and COVID-19 positive patients</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 23</time_frame>
    <description>Common toxicity criteria from the NCI CTCAE V5.0</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Neoplasms Malignant</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Thromboembolism</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Infected cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Peripheral venous ultrasound</intervention_name>
    <description>Screening for VTE from D7 to 42</description>
    <arm_group_label>Infected cohort</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 testing ;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years old ;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient treated for histologically proven cancer (under treatment or last&#xD;
             anti-neoplastic treatment &lt; 3 months at the time of COVID-19 testing);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For the infected cohort: patient being screened for VTE at least one time 7 weeks&#xD;
             after the COVID-19 diagnosistwo time point (day 1-10 after COVID-19 testing, and day&#xD;
             20-25 after COVID-19 testing) for retrospective cohort only;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Complete blood count available at time of COVID-19 testing (+/-14 days) to be able to&#xD;
             calculate the Khorana score;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient informed and not opposed to the data processing;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient affiliated with a health insurance system.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient not able to give free consent;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient not able to understand the protocol;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For the infected patients: VTE screening not performed (for retrospective cohort&#xD;
             only);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No available complete blood count at time of COVID-19 testing; Medical file and&#xD;
             clinical follow-up not available during the study period (76 weeks after the COVID-19&#xD;
             test);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under 18 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vulnerable persons as defined by article L1121-5-8:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Pregnant women, women in labour or breast-feeding mothers, persons deprived of&#xD;
                  their freedom by judicial or administrative decision, persons hospitalized&#xD;
                  without their consent by virtue of articles L. 3212-1 and L. 3213-1 and who are&#xD;
                  not subject to the provisions of article L. 1121-8&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Persons admitted to a social or health facility for reasons other than research&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Adults subject to a legal protection order or unable to give their consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jérôme DOYEN, MD-PHD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre Antoine Lacassagne</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Céline CELLIER-COËLLE</last_name>
    <phone>0492031778</phone>
    <email>celine.coelle@nice.unicancer.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinique Saint-Jean</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cagnes-sur-Mer</city>
        <state>Alpes-Maritimes</state>
        <zip>06800</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jérome BARRIERE, MD-PHD</last_name>
      <phone>04.92.03.11.12</phone>
      <email>docteurbarriere@outlook.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jérome BARRIERE, MD-PHD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Azuréen de Cancérologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mougins</city>
        <state>Alpes-Maritimes</state>
        <zip>06250</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Benjamin HOCH, MD-PHD</last_name>
      <phone>04.92.92.37.37</phone>
      <email>dr.hoch@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Benjamin HOCH, MD-PHD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Nice</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nice</city>
        <state>Alpes-Maritimes</state>
        <zip>06000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Denis DOYEN, MD-PHD</last_name>
      <email>doyen.d@chu-nice.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Denis DOYEN, MD-PHD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinique Saint-Georges</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nice</city>
        <state>Alpes-Maritimes</state>
        <zip>06105</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ophélie CASSUTO, MD-PHD</last_name>
      <phone>04.92.03.10.29</phone>
      <email>ophelie.cassuto@nice.unicancer.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ophélie CASSUTO, MD-PHD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Antoine Lacassagne</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nice</city>
        <state>Alpes-Maritimes</state>
        <zip>06189</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Céline CELLIER-COËLLE</last_name>
      <phone>0492031778</phone>
      <email>celine.coelle@nice.unicancer.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jérôme DOYEN, MD-PHD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHPG</name>
      <address>
        <city>Monaco</city>
        <zip>98000</zip>
        <country>Monaco</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christophe PERRIN, MD-PHD</last_name>
      <phone>377.97.98.36.95</phone>
      <email>christophe.perrin@chpg.mc</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christophe PERRIN, MD-PHD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Monaco</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 4, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Covid19</keyword>
  <keyword>Thromboembolism</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thromboembolism</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

