<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4076">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04587414</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MySteps ETL 303/2017</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04587414</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>eHealth Intervention on Physical Activity for Type 2 Diabetics - Frustrated by COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>MySteps-CoV</acronym>
  <official_title>Personalized eHealth Intervention in Patients With Type 2 Diabetes to Promote Daily Physical Activity Utilizing 24h Self-monitoring - Implementation Frustrated by COVID-19 Epidemic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>UKK Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>North Karelia Hospital District</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Eastern Finland</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>UKK Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This pragmatic 3-arm randomized controlled trial is conducted within the primary health care&#xD;
      setting. The trial evaluates the effectiveness of a personalized eHealth intervention based&#xD;
      on a hip-worn accelerometer, smartphone application and cloud service (www.exced.com) with or&#xD;
      without face-to-face and telephone counselling contacts on physical activity (PA) compared to&#xD;
      usual care in increasing daily PA and reducing sedentary behavior (SB) among type 2 diabetes&#xD;
      (T2D) patients.The duration of the intervention period is 6 months, after which there is a 6&#xD;
      month follow-up for evaluating the maintenance of anticipated intervention effects. The&#xD;
      primary goal of the intervention is that the T2D patients increase their daily number of&#xD;
      steps by replacing SB with low intensity PA. The secondary goal is to increase short bouts of&#xD;
      moderate-to-vigorous PA according to personal goals. It is expected that the eHealth&#xD;
      intervention complemented by individual counselling is the most effective in reaching the&#xD;
      goals, and the eHealth intervention is more effective than usual care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Measurements are done at baseline, after the 6-month intervention, and after the 6-month&#xD;
      follow-up. Participants' one-week PA and SB are measured with a hip-worn triaxial&#xD;
      accelerometer and analyzed with validated algorithms. Cardiorespiratory fitness is assessed&#xD;
      with a validated 6-minute walk test. Diabetes-related metabolic biomarkers (HbA1C, LDL-c,&#xD;
      HDL-c, oxidized LDL and HDL lipids) and cardiovascular risk factors (blood pressure, BMI,&#xD;
      waist circumference) are measured with standard laboratory methods. Quality of life is&#xD;
      assessed by RAND-36 method. The interventions are evaluated with RE-AIM (Reach,&#xD;
      Effectiveness, Adoption, Implementation and Maintenance) method. Besides effectiveness,&#xD;
      RE-AIM methods evaluates the target group reach and adherence; provider adoption;&#xD;
      intervention fidelity; maintenance of the changes in PA and SB behavior, biomarkers and CVD&#xD;
      risk factors; intervention transferability to clinical practice; adverse events; and patient&#xD;
      and provider satisfaction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Unexpectedly, the COVID-19 pandemic in spring 2020 led to substantial restrictions in&#xD;
      outdoors mobility of T2D patients and their access access to health care in Finland, facts&#xD;
      that frustrated the planned implementation of the original intervention, related measurements&#xD;
      and their scheduling. This means that not all planned measurements could be done at all or at&#xD;
      the scheduled time point. Irrespective of the time of recruitment, all follow-up measurements&#xD;
      are done from June to September 2020. Notwithstanding the COVID-19 pandemic annulled the&#xD;
      original intervention, the collected data yet provides unique insights into measured physical&#xD;
      activity, fitness and metabolic biomarkers of T2D patients before and during the COVID-19&#xD;
      pandemic and consequent restrictions.In addition, the data allows to evaluate the&#xD;
      implementation of eHealth approach and face-to-face and telephone PA counselling contacts&#xD;
      within the primary health care setting.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 6, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The study is a pragmatic three-arm randomized controlled trial carried out within the primary health care setting. Besides the usual care given to type 2 diabetics, the patients may be assigned either into a 6-month eHealth intervention complemented by face-to-face and telephone counselling contacts on physical activity or into a 6-month eHealth intervention without counselling contacts. After the 6-month intervention, there is a 6-month follow-up period.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total mean daily step count</measure>
    <time_frame>At 6 and 12 months compared to baseline (0 months). N.B. Because of COVID-19, the schedule and contents of measurements may change individually depending on the time of recruitment.</time_frame>
    <description>Step count during one week is measured with a hip-worn accelerometer at baseline, 6 months, and 12 months</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in total mean daily time of sedentary, low intensity PA and moderate-to-vigorous PA</measure>
    <time_frame>at 6 and 12 months compared to baseline (0 months). N.B. Because of COVID-19, the schedule and contents of measurements may change individually depending on the time of recruitment.</time_frame>
    <description>Sedentary time and PA time at different intensity ranges are measured with a hip-worn accelerometer at baseline, 6 months and 12 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in the mean daily number of moderate-to-vigorous PA bouts lasting at least 1, 5 and 10 minutes.</measure>
    <time_frame>at 6 and 12 months compared to baseline (0 months). N.B. Because of COVID-19, the schedule and contents of measurements may change individually depending on the time of recruitment.</time_frame>
    <description>Durations of moderate-to-vigorous PA bouts measured with a hip-worn accelerometer at baseline, 6 months and 12 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">122</enrollment>
  <condition>Type2 Diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>eHealth + counselling contacts</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>6-month eHealth physical activity intervention complemented by face-to-face and telephone counselling contacts on physical activity..</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>eHealth</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>6-month eHealth physical activity intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Usual care of type 2 diabetics within the primary health care setting.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>eHealth +counselling contacts</intervention_name>
    <description>The 6 month eHealth intervention comprises continuous self-monitoring of PA and SB using hip-worn accelerometer and ExSed application, which gives cloud-computed personal feedback about accelerometer-measured PA and SB on smartphone and provides a platform for a health care professional to set and monitor patient's personal activity goals as well as give personalized feedback to the patient. In addition, instructions and video-demonstrations on how to reach the goals are provided via Internet. The eHealth intervention is complemented by face-to-face and telephone counselling on physical activity which comprises 4 to 6 contacts between a health care professional and the patient as well as at least 3 telephone contacts during 6 months.</description>
    <arm_group_label>eHealth + counselling contacts</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>eHealth</intervention_name>
    <description>The 6 month eHealth intervention comprises continuous self-monitoring of PA and SB using hip-worn accelerometer and ExSed application, which gives cloud-computed personal feedback about accelerometer-measured PA and SB on smartphone and provides a platform for a health care professional to set and monitor patient's personal activity goals as well as give personalized feedback to the patient. In addition, instructions and video-demonstrations on how to reach the goals are provided via Internet. No telephone calls nor face-to-face counselling contacts on physical activity are taken.</description>
    <arm_group_label>eHealth</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Usual care</intervention_name>
    <description>Usual care and councelling given to type 2 diabetics within the primary health care setting.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Usual care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>eHealth</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>eHealth + counselling contacts</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a diagnosed type 2 diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a prescheduled appointment with a health care professional regarding PA counselling in&#xD;
             primary care settings of North Karelia Hospital District, Finland&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  body mass index &lt;40&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  does not meet the current PA recommendation for health&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  is able to conduct six minute walk test.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any problem that limits ability to walk without an aid&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any health problem that hinders participation in light to moderate intensity PA,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  not able or willing to use smartphone&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  not willing to wear the research accelerometer at the baseline&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>69 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tommi Vasankari, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UKK Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>North Karelia Hospital District</name>
      <address>
        <city>Joensuu</city>
        <zip>80210</zip>
        <country>Finland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Finland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 8, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 13, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 13, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>UKK Institute</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Harri Sievanen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Research Director</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>physical activity</keyword>
  <keyword>sedentary behavior</keyword>
  <keyword>accelerometer</keyword>
  <keyword>eHealth</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

