<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3705">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04696679</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-38</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-A01631-38</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04696679</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Quality of Life of Very Preterm Children With Dysexecutive Disorders at Elementary School Age During the Confinement-deconfinement Period of Covid-19 Pandemic</brief_title>
  <acronym>GPE-QolVID</acronym>
  <official_title>Quality of Life of Very Preterm Children With Dysexecutive Disorders at Elementary School Age During the Confinement-deconfinement Period of Covid-19 Pandemic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique Hopitaux De Marseille</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique Hopitaux De Marseille</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Since March 2020, a new HCoV, SARS-Cov2, originating in China, has been spreading around the&#xD;
      world. As of 13 may 2020, almost 4.2 million cases of infections and 292 000 died were&#xD;
      reported worldwide (140 000 infection cases and 27 000 died in France). Human coronaviruses&#xD;
      (HCoV) usually cause common upper respiratory tract infections in children and sometimes&#xD;
      exacerbate lung and asthma diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To minimize the risk of contamination of SARS-Cov2 (Covid-19), the French government has put&#xD;
      in place directives that modified the daily lives of students, teachers and families. The&#xD;
      societal change imposed by the state of health emergency with a confinement and deconfinement&#xD;
      period could strongly impact the quality of life of very preterm children with dysexecutive&#xD;
      disorders. These children are a population vulnerable to changes, especially during the&#xD;
      pivotal period of elementary school. The executive dysfunctions disrupt children's learning&#xD;
      and schooling, as well as their social adaptation, compromising their personal development&#xD;
      and therefore, their quality of life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 19, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of the quality of life using the questionnaire Kidscreen 10 Index</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>The questionnaire Kidscreen 10 Index was developed in several European countries including France. It comprises 10 items from a version of 27 items, which explore the following domains: physical well-being, psychological well-being (positive and negative), autonomy and parents, peers and social support, and school environment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of the quality of life using The VSP-A questionnaire (Life and Perceived Health of the Adolescent and the Child)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>The VSP-A questionnaire (Life and Perceived Health of the Adolescent and the Child) which groups together nine dimensions (vitality, psychological well-being, friendships, recreation, family relationships, physical well-being, relationships with teachers, schoolwork, and self-esteem)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Specific data concerning the period of confinement-deconfinement</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>continuation of parental employment and current modalities: face-to-face, teleworking, part-time employment, etc.&#xD;
possible schooling and current modalities: continued schooling, interruption of schooling, etc.&#xD;
related ad hoc items to the state of health of the family unit, to medical events that have occurred (including family member(s) with a Covid-19 infection), to a history of hospitalization related to Covid-19 reasons, (reasons, consequences, frequency) between the beginning of the confinement and the moment they complete the questionnaire; as well as ad hoc items of anxiety related to Covid-19</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Data on children behavioral disorders:</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>assessed by the Goodman questionnaire (Strengths and Difficulties Questionnaire)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Data concerning the anxiety symptoms of the parent completing the survey questionnaire:</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>assessed by the Spielberger questionnaire, as a personality trait and as an emotional state linked to the health protocol (State-Trait Anxiety Inventory, STAI)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">170</enrollment>
  <condition>Very Preterm Children With Dysexecutive Disorders</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Very preterm children group</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Patient Quality of life assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>Other: Patient questionnaire about quality of life assessment and their determinants during the confinement-deconfinement period of Covid-19 pandemic in France</description>
    <arm_group_label>Very preterm children group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control group Quality of life assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>Other: Patient questionnaire about quality of life assessment and their determinants during the confinement-deconfinement period of Covid-19 pandemic in France relationships with teachers, schoolwork, and self-esteem)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Children aged between 7 and 9&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Very preterm children group :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children at elementary school age 7 to 9&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children included in the cohort of EPIREMED study, born between 24 and 34 weeks' GA&#xD;
             (gestational amenorrhea) and having visuospatial Working Memory impairment defined by&#xD;
             a working memory index &lt;85 from the WPPSI IV&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children able to read, write and comprehend;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children whose parents are not opposed to the participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children affiliated to the French social security system&#xD;
&#xD;
        Control group :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children at elementary school age 7 to 9&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children born at full-term and without dysexecutive disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children from the staff of the Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Marseille (AP-HM) /&#xD;
             from the staff of the French Mediterranean network (PERINAT-MED) / from the close&#xD;
             entourage of EPIREMED children&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children able to read, write and comprehend&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children whose parents are not opposed to the participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children affiliated to the French social security system&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>9 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Assistance Publique des Hopitaux de Marseille</name>
      <address>
        <city>Marseille</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 3, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

