<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4731">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04418934</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CLIN-0004</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04418934</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Investigation to Evaluate the Hemanext® Red Blood Cell Processing System for Extended Storage of Leukoreduced Red Blood Cells</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Investigation to Evaluate the Hemanext® Red Blood Cell Processing System for Extended Storage of Leukoreduced Red Blood Cells With CP2D Anticoagulant and AS-3 Additive - Pivotal Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hemanext</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hemanext</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary goal of Hemanext Inc. is to improve the safety and efficacy of transfusion&#xD;
      therapy through novel storage methods potentially improving their quality across the storage&#xD;
      cycle. Based on our review of the pertinent literature, there is substantial evidence&#xD;
      suggesting that prolonged exposure to oxygen during storage results in oxidative damage to&#xD;
      the red blood cells (RBC) over the course of storage leading to decreased therapeutic&#xD;
      potential. Therefore, removal of oxygen from red blood cell products prior to storage has&#xD;
      potential to preserve the cells in a more physiologically relevant state and improve the&#xD;
      clinical outcomes of patients that receive blood transfusions in a variety of therapeutic&#xD;
      realms1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Currently, Hemanext Inc. has focused on the design and development of a dual compartment bag&#xD;
      system designated as the Hemanext Red Blood Cell Processing System (Hemanext). After standard&#xD;
      processing of donated whole blood units into leukoreduced packed red blood cells (LR-RBCs) in&#xD;
      AS-3 additive solution, the LR-RBCs would then be placed in the oxygen reduction bag (ORB)&#xD;
      processing bag which allows for the rapid diffusion of oxygen out of the blood, through a&#xD;
      sterile, oxygen-permeable membrane, and into iron-based oxygen sorbents. After processing,&#xD;
      the blood is transferred again from the ORB into the Hemanext Storage Bag (HSB) which will&#xD;
      preserve the hypoxic state of the LR-RBC product for the duration of cold storage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The COVID-19 crisis has placed unprecedented pressure on the US blood supply security. The&#xD;
      pandemic has caused blood supplies to fall precipitously, placing all transfusion recipients&#xD;
      at acute risk. Hemanext has developed a technology over 12 years with support from 6 NIH&#xD;
      grants and contracts that can substantially mitigate the damage done to the blood supply by&#xD;
      this COVID-19 crisis and strengthen the ability of the US blood supply to withstand the&#xD;
      effects of future crises. Limited shelf life is a key component in exacerbating the current&#xD;
      blood supply crisis. Successful completion of this project will allow earliest possible&#xD;
      availability (within 9-12 months) of the high quality Hemanext RBC with significantly&#xD;
      extended shelf life. Even without shelf life extension, the higher quality Hemanext RBC&#xD;
      showed a reduction of &gt;50% of blood volume required for resuscitation from hemorrhage in a&#xD;
      pre-clinical rodent model. Further enhancement of the quality of Hemanext RBC is expected to&#xD;
      improve still further the efficacy of Hemanext blood and further to reduce the transfusion&#xD;
      volume needed to achieve treatment objectives. In addition, extending the shelf life of the&#xD;
      Hemanext RBC will provide greater inventory flexibility to avoid the devastating impact of&#xD;
      major blood shortages due to reduced donor activity during threats to blood security such a&#xD;
      COVID-19 pandemics and other crises.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Grant application for study was rejected&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>% of Red Blood Cells With Hemolysis</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 56 of storage</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of packed Red Blood Cell units with hemolysis at day 56 of storage.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dual Label 24 Hour In Vivo % Recovery of Red Blood Cells</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 56 of storage</time_frame>
    <description>The mean 24-hour, post-transfusion, in vivo red blood cell recovery.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>% Red Blood Cells Recovered Post-Filtration</measure>
    <time_frame>Post-Filtration on Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of red blood cells recovered after the filtration process.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Whole Blood Donations and Leukoreduction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Investigational Product</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Blood product from these donors will be processed and stored using the Hemanext One device.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Product</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Blood product from these donors will be stored in a Haemonetics Leukotrap Whole Blood System.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hemanext One</intervention_name>
    <description>Leukoreduced red blood cell product from donors in the Investigational Product arm will be processed in the Hemanext Oxygen Reduction Bag for 3 hours and then transferred to the Hemanext Storage Bag and stored for 56 days at 1-6°C.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Investigational Product</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study donor must be ≥ 18 years of age. Study donor must be ≥ 110 pounds. Study donor's body&#xD;
        temperature must be ≤ 37.5°C / 99.5°F (oral). Study donor's hemoglobin must be ≥12.5 g/dL&#xD;
        if female and ≥13.0 g/dL if male. Study donor's hematocrit must be ≥ 38% if female and ≥39%&#xD;
        if male.Study participants must meet EITHER hemoglobin or hematocrit criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study donor must meet all criteria per respective site's Research Blood Donation Record&#xD;
        (BDR).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study donor's most recent single RBC unit donation must have been ≥56 days prior to study&#xD;
        donation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study donor's most recent double RBC unit donation must have been ≥ 112 days prior to study&#xD;
        donation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study donor must have consented to study participation by reviewing and having expressed&#xD;
        understanding the site-respective IRB-approved informed consent form prior to undergoing&#xD;
        any study related procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study donor's testing results from collected blood does not indicate a risk of&#xD;
        transfusion-transmitted disease (TTD)*.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study donors must agree to report adverse events from the time of signing the informed&#xD;
        consent to twenty-four hours following the end of their active study involvement.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Female study donors must not be pregnant, expected to be pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Female donors who participate in the in vivo portion of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Women of child-bearing age must not be pregnant as determined by a negative pregnancy test&#xD;
        prior to each re-infusion. If acceptable by local procedures, post-menopausal or surgically&#xD;
        sterile women may be exempt from the pregnancy testing requirement.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study donor is &lt; 18 years of age. Study donor &lt; 110 pounds. Study donor's body temperature&#xD;
        is &gt; 37.5°C / 99.5°F (oral). Study donor's hemoglobin is &lt; 12.5 g/dL if female and &lt; 13.0&#xD;
        g/dL if male. Study donor's hematocrit is &lt; 38% if female and &lt; 39% if male. Study donor&#xD;
        does not meet all criteria per respective site's Research Blood Donation Record (BDR).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study donor's most recent single RBC unit donation was &lt; 56 days prior to study donation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study donor's most recent double RBC unit donation was &lt; 112 days prior to study donation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study donor has not consented to study participation. Study donor's testing results from&#xD;
        collected blood does indicate a risk of transfusion-transmitted disease (TTD)*.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Female donors who participate in the in vivo portion of the study: study donor is pregnant,&#xD;
        expected to be pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jose Cancelas, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hoxworth Blood Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Philip Howard, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>American Red Cross Mid-Atlantic Research Facility</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hoxworth Blood Center, University of Cincinnati</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cincinnati</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>45267-0055</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>American Red Cross Mid-Atlantic Research Facility</name>
      <address>
        <city>Norfolk</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23510</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 26, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 5, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 30, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 30, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Red Blood Cells</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

