<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2344">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04701606</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SP-PA-COV-203</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04701606</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Safety and Efficacy of Pyronaridine-artesunate (Pyramax® or Artecom®)in COVID-19 Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>PROVIDENCE</acronym>
  <official_title>A Multi-center, Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled Phase 2/3 Clinical Trial to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of Pyronaridine-artesunate (Artecom®) in COVID-19 Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Shin Poong Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Shin Poong Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a multi-center, randomized, Phase 2/3 study to evaluate the safety and efficacy of&#xD;
      pyronaridine-artesunate in participants with corona virus disease 2019 (COVID-19).&#xD;
      Pyronaridine-artesunate has been approved in Europe, Asia and Africa under brand name of&#xD;
      Pyramax® or Artecom® as a treatment for malaria. The study will be conducted in two stages:&#xD;
      open-label (Stage 1) and double-blind (Stage 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Up to approximately 402 participants (20 participants in Stage 1 and 382 participants in&#xD;
      Stage 2) are planned to be enrolled in the study and will be randomized to receive either&#xD;
      Artecom® or matching placebo at a ratio of 1:1 in Stage 2. The dose of Artecom® will be&#xD;
      determined by the participant's body weight, according to previously established guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An independent Drug Safety Monitoring Board (DSMB) will be established to review the safety&#xD;
      at regular intervals during the conduct of the trial. The DSMB will be subject to a Charter&#xD;
      and will review after 20 participants have been recruited, and thereafter when 191&#xD;
      participants have been recruited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ad-hoc DSMB meetings may be held at any time during the study if there are any major safety&#xD;
      concerns. A final DSMB will be conducted when all participants have been recruited in the&#xD;
      trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      &lt;Stage 1&gt; In Stage 1, the trial will be conducted in 20 participants for 28 days in a single&#xD;
      arm, open-label design. Artecom® will be administered orally once a day for 3 consecutive&#xD;
      days. All subjects will be evaluated for efficacy and safety for 28 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the completion of the final participant in Stage 1, the DSMB will review the safety&#xD;
      data from Stage 1 and determine whether to proceed to Stage 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      &lt;Stage 2&gt; In Stage 2, a total of 382 participants will be enrolled and randomized in a double&#xD;
      blinded manner to receive either Artecom® or placebo (1:1 ratio) orally once a day for 3&#xD;
      consecutive days. All subjects will be evaluated for efficacy and safety for 28 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A second DSMB meeting and review of all available blinded safety data will occur after 191&#xD;
      participants have completed Day 28. A final DSMB meeting will be held after the completion of&#xD;
      a study assessment by the last participant.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Stage 1: Single Group (Experimental drug only)&#xD;
Stage 2: Parallel (Placebo control and Experimental drug)</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants with clinical improvement as defined by an improvement of categories on the WHO Ordinal Scale of clinical status until Days 28.</measure>
    <time_frame>follows up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>* WHO Ordinal scale: 0. No clinical or virological evidence of infection&#xD;
No limitation of activities&#xD;
Limitation of activities&#xD;
Hospitalized, no oxygen therapy&#xD;
Oxygen by mask or nasal prongs&#xD;
Non-invasive ventilation or high-flow oxygen&#xD;
Intubation and mechanical ventilation&#xD;
Ventilation + additional organ support - Pressers, Renal replacement therapy (RRT), extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO)&#xD;
Death</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to clinical improvement was defined as time from randomization to an improvement of categories on the WHO Ordinal Scale of clinical status.</measure>
    <time_frame>follows up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical improvement within 28 days since start of treatment, defined as a decrease of at least 2 point from baseline of a nine-point WHO ordinal scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in the WHO Ordinal Scale for Clinical Improvement until Days 28 compared to Baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>follows up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Compare statistical results of an increase or decrease in a nine-point WHO ordinal scale between two groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in National Early Warning Score (NEWS) until Days 28 compared to Baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>follows up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>NEWS determines the degree of illness of a patient and promotes critical care intervention. The score range from 0-20, with a higher score representing a higher risk of morbidity. Compare statistical results of an increase or decrease in NEWS between two groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants with negative for COVID-19 as determined by real-time RT-PCR test until Days 14.</measure>
    <time_frame>follows up to 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of subjects who are RT-PCR negative for COVID-19</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in viral load until Days 14 compared to Baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>follows up to 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Viral load reduction of COVID-19 until Days 14 compared to the baseline.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The time to body temperature normalization after the administration of investigational Product (IP).</measure>
    <time_frame>follows up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Maintaining underarm ≤36.7 °C, or oral ≤36.9°C, or rectal ≤37.3°C, or eardrum ≤37.2°C, for at least 24 hours without administering fever reducing medication after the administration of IP.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The time to respiratory rate normalization after the administration of IP.</measure>
    <time_frame>follows up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Maintain 12/min ≤ respiratory rate ≤ 20/min for at least 24 hours.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The time to oxygen saturation (SpO2) normalization after the administration of IP.</measure>
    <time_frame>follows up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>SpO2 ≥95% for at least 24 hours.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality rate at Day 28.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Compare the mortality rate between two groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of hospitalization (Day 1 to Day 28).</measure>
    <time_frame>follows up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days the subject from the start of treatment to hospital discharge.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The incidence of adverse events (AEs).</measure>
    <time_frame>follows up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>The incidence rate of adverse events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The incidence of serious adverse events (SAEs).</measure>
    <time_frame>follows up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>The incidence rate of serious adverse events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">402</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Artecom® (pyronaridine-artesunate)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Artecom® is treated orally once a day for 3 consecutive days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo is treated orally once a day for 3 consecutive days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Artecom® (pyronaridine-artesunate)</intervention_name>
    <description>* Participant body weight (Artecom® dose)&#xD;
≥ 65kg (Artecom® 4 tablets: Pyronaridine 720mg/ Artesunate 240mg)&#xD;
≥ 45kg and &lt; 65kg (Artecom® 3 tablets: Pyronaridine 540mg/ Artesunate 180mg)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Artecom® (pyronaridine-artesunate)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Pyramax® (pyronaridine-artesunate)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>* Participant body weight (Placebo dose)&#xD;
≥ 65kg (Placebo 4 tablets)&#xD;
≥ 45kg and &lt; 65kg (Placebo 3 tablets)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male and female adults age (≥19 years at the time of informed consent)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Body weight (≥ 45 kg at Screening)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participants must be confirmed as having COVID-19 using real-time reverse&#xD;
             transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) test and specimens collected from&#xD;
             upper airway (nasopharyngeal specimen) within 72 hours prior to randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Females must be non-pregnant and non-lactating, and must use an acceptable, highly&#xD;
             effective double contraception from Screening until study completion, including the&#xD;
             follow-up period. Males must be surgically sterile (&gt;30 days since vasectomy with no&#xD;
             viable sperm), abstinent, or if engaged in sexual relations with a woman of&#xD;
             childbearing potential (WOCBP), the participant and his partner must be surgically&#xD;
             sterile (e.g., tubal occlusion, hysterectomy, bilateral salpingectomy, bilateral&#xD;
             oophorectomy) or using an acceptable, highly effective contraceptive method from&#xD;
             Screening until study completion, including the follow-up period.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hormonal contraception (with approved oral contraceptives, long-acting&#xD;
                  implantable hormones, injectable hormones), intra uterine device, condoms ,&#xD;
                  sterilization (vasectomy, tubal occlusion, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participants with clinically significant cardiovascular disease (including arrhythmia,&#xD;
             corrected QT interval prolongation [QTcF&gt; 470 msec for females, or &gt;450 msec for&#xD;
             males, at Screening])&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participants with clinically significant anemia (Hemoglobin &lt;8.0 g/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participants who have hypersensitivity to main ingredients (pyronaridine&#xD;
             tetraphosphate, artesunate) and any excipient in the IP&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participants who have gastrointestinal disease or surgical participant that may affect&#xD;
             absorption, distribution, metabolism and excretion of drugs, current active gastritis,&#xD;
             gastrointestinal /rectal bleeding, gastric ulcers, pancreatic abnormalities such as&#xD;
             pancreatitis, etc. (simple appendectomy or hernia surgery not excluded)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participants who have received antiviral drugs for the treatment of COVID-19 infection&#xD;
             or other indications within 28 days prior to participation in the study or who have&#xD;
             not had sufficient wash-out period of the antiviral drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Participants with severe renal impairment (estimated glomerular filtration rate ≤30&#xD;
             mL/min/1.73 m2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Participants with severe hepatic impairment (Alanine aminotransferase or Aspartate&#xD;
             aminotransferase ≥5x upper limit of normal) or have symptoms of abdominal pain or&#xD;
             vomiting associated with Jaundice or Child-Pugh Stage B or C&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Viral infections other than COVID-19 that requires administration of other antiviral&#xD;
             agents (for example but not limited to human immunodeficiency virus, hepatitis B&#xD;
             virus, hepatitis C virus)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Participants requiring mechanical ventilation (e.g. non-invasive ventilation, invasive&#xD;
             mechanical ventilation, extracorporeal membrane oxygenation etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Participants with chronic underlying diseases (such as uncontrolled diabetes, chronic&#xD;
             kidney disease, chronic liver disease, chronic lung disease [including asthma, chronic&#xD;
             obstructive pulmonary disease and tuberculosis], chronic cardiovascular disease, blood&#xD;
             cancer, cancer participants with anti-cancer treatment, participants taking&#xD;
             immunosuppressants, etc.), participants with high obesity (BMI &gt; 40), dialysis&#xD;
             participants, transplant participants whom are inadequate to participate in clinical&#xD;
             trials based on the Investigator's discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Pregnant or lactating at Screening or planning to become pregnant (self or partner) at&#xD;
             any time during the study, including the follow-up period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Participants who participated in another clinical trial / medical device clinical&#xD;
             trial within 28 days from the date of signing the consent and received drug / operated&#xD;
             medical device for clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Participants who the Investigator has deemed inappropriate for inclusion in this study&#xD;
             for any other reason.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Prior or ongoing medical conditions, medical history, physical findings, or laboratory&#xD;
             abnormality that, in the Investigator's (or delegate's) opinion, could adversely&#xD;
             affect the safety of the participant.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Belen L Dofitas, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Philippine General Hospital, University of the Philippines</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Belen L Dofitas, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+63-917-629-4329</phone>
    <email>belendofitas@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Byung Su Kim, MS</last_name>
    <phone>+82-31-348-9354</phone>
    <email>135kbs@shinpoong.co.kr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Philippine General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Manila</city>
        <state>Taft Ave, Ermita, Manila, 1000 Metro</state>
        <country>Philippines</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Belen L Dofitas, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+63-917-629-4329</phone>
      <email>belendofitas@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Belen L Dofitas, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Philippines</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 6, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pyramax</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>pyronaridine-artesunate</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>Artecom</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Artesunate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pyronaridine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

