<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4911">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03301922</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2015/1794</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03301922</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Metacognitive Therapy and Work Interventions for Patients on Sick Leave Due to Common Mental Disorders</brief_title>
  <official_title>Metacognitive Therapy and Work Interventions for Patients on Sick Leave Due to Common Mental Disorders: A Randomized Waiting List Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Norwegian University of Science and Technology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Diakonhjemmet Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Norwegian University of Science and Technology</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Common mental health disorders such as anxiety and depression are leading causes of sickness&#xD;
      absence and disability in Norway. Despite tremendous costs for individual and society,&#xD;
      effective treatment is lacking. Mental health interventions do not typically target work&#xD;
      situation, despite its importance for patient well-being. On a policy level, effective&#xD;
      measures are impeded by a paucity of scientific data, and programs designed to address the&#xD;
      issue such as Faster Return to Work (&quot;Raskere tilbake&quot;) lack evaluation. The present project&#xD;
      will test the effectiveness of Metacognitive therapy and work-focused interventions for&#xD;
      reducing sick leave in patients with common mental disorders.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Common mental health disorders (CMD) such as anxiety and depression are leading contributors&#xD;
      to the global burden of disease , generating substantial costs for societies in reduced&#xD;
      productivity and increased benefit pay outs. In 2010, the worldwide cost of mental health&#xD;
      disability was estimated at US$2.5-8.5 trillion in lost output, and the sum is projected to&#xD;
      double by 2030 unless effective policy measures are implemented. For middle- and high-income&#xD;
      countries, 30-50 % of disability applications stem from mental health issues, and the&#xD;
      proportion is likely greater among the younger part of the work force. In Europe, depression&#xD;
      is responsible for 13.7 % of all years lived with disability, and anxiety disorders likely&#xD;
      have similar impact. Mental health issues are among the leading causes of disability and&#xD;
      early retirement across the European region.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For affected individuals, anxiety and depression reduces quality of life, decreases&#xD;
      functioning and increases the risk of further health problems. Sick leave is often used for&#xD;
      adults with CMD, but may not always be helpful. Avoidance and isolation are behavioural&#xD;
      strategies that maintain anxiety and depression. Absenteeism from work, an important social&#xD;
      arena, may strengthen this behaviour, impeding recovery. Even when controlling for the impact&#xD;
      of ill health, short term sick leave may in itself increase the risk of future long term&#xD;
      absence. In addition, employment rates are 10-15% lower for people with mental ill health&#xD;
      than the rest of the population. Exclusion from the work force is in turn associated with&#xD;
      poorer mental health, and can heighten the risk of futures depression and even suicide. The&#xD;
      relationship between CMD and reduced work-participation is therefore likely bidirectional,&#xD;
      and sick leave may not work as intended despite its high cost for society.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The individual and societal burden from sick leave and mental health represents a key policy&#xD;
      challenge on the global agenda and the need for efficient measures is urgent. Norway&#xD;
      exemplifies this urgent need as expenditure on disability and sickness absence totals 5 % of&#xD;
      GDP, by far the highest in the OECD. Efforts have been made to address the issue through&#xD;
      several policy initiatives, such as the nationwide Faster Return to Work (FRW) program. The&#xD;
      program facilitates buying treatment from different actors to reduce waiting times and thus&#xD;
      potentially the duration of sick leave. The impact of the program is uncertain, as little&#xD;
      research has been done on its efficacy. Scientific data on Norwegian sick leave follow up is&#xD;
      mostly absent. Despite the magnitude of the challenge, there is a clear knowledge gap.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investment in sick leave follow up has not been equally distributed amongst patient groups.&#xD;
      Sixty per cent of all working days lost to disability or sick leave are due to mental health&#xD;
      issues and musculoskeletal complaints. Sick leave due to CMD is growing. When caused by&#xD;
      mental health issues, disability pension is awarded on average nine years earlier than for&#xD;
      somatic reasons, resulting in more working years lost to disability. Though prevalent in the&#xD;
      statistics, few CMD patients on sick leave receive treatment. Only 1.4 % of employees on sick&#xD;
      leave are referred to specialized mental health treatment. As many as one in three people&#xD;
      awarded disability pension for mental illness have never received any form of treatment prior&#xD;
      to disability being granted. This shows a severe under-referral and under-treatment for this&#xD;
      patient group despite being responsible for the majority of sick leave and disability costs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A more targeted approach, integrating work-focused interventions with effective CMD treatment&#xD;
      is needed for this patient group. Two recent studies have examined such an approach. In the&#xD;
      Netherlands, Lagerveld and Blonk conducted a randomized controlled trial where 168 patients&#xD;
      on sick leave due to CMD received either cognitive behavioural therapy (CBT), or CBT with an&#xD;
      integrated work-focused intervention. Their results showed a 20 % decrease in sickness&#xD;
      absence for patients receiving the work-focused intervention, while maintaining effective&#xD;
      symptom reduction. In Germany, similar results were found with a smaller sample size. A&#xD;
      multicentre trial in Norway looked at registry data for 1193 CMD patients receiving a&#xD;
      variation of work-specific interventions, showing a clear reduction in sick leave and&#xD;
      disability. Integrated work-focused treatment for CMD is thus a promising avenue of research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Metacognitive therapy (MCT) is a treatment based on more recent theoretical developments. It&#xD;
      has shown excellent results for anxiety and depression, and the treatment protocol for&#xD;
      generalized anxiety disorder and social phobia is recommended in the NICE guidelines. Rather&#xD;
      than challenging and changing specific thought content (CBT), metacognitive treatment aims to&#xD;
      change and challenge maladaptive cognitive processes, among these rumination and worry, which&#xD;
      are key components in CMD and sick leave.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be a randomized controlled trial. Participants will be persons with a primary&#xD;
      diagnosis of common mental disorders, anxiety and depression. Experienced independent&#xD;
      diagnosticians will assess all patients by using structural interviews MINI (MINI&#xD;
      International Neuropsychiatric Interview).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will be randomized in blocks to two groups in order to compare the following&#xD;
      conditions: MCT and work-focused interventions, and a wait list control condition. After the&#xD;
      waiting period of either 8 or 12 weeks, the patients in the wait-list condition will be&#xD;
      allocated to the treatment condition. Both between-subjects and within-subjects comparisons&#xD;
      will be conducted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Questions that will be addressed are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. MCT and work-focused interventions will be superior to the wait-list condition in make&#xD;
           participants return to work&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Which changes in predictors related to treatment predict return to work&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. MCT and work-focused interventions will be superior to the wait-list condition for&#xD;
           improving mental health&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. MCT and work-focused interventions will be more cost-efficient than the wait-list&#xD;
           condition&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Evaluate the sustainability of return to work for patients on sick leave due to common&#xD;
           mental disorders after MCT and work-focused interventions&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Examine impact of different potential prognostic factors on work function, both at the&#xD;
           end of treatment and at one year follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. If the effect of MCT and work-focused interventions will sustain one year after the end&#xD;
           of therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Explore if patients will have reduced use of sick leave in the four years following&#xD;
           after treatment compared to the two years prior to treatment based on register data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The meta-cognitive treatment program is based on Wells' manual. The work-focused intervention&#xD;
      is based on an adopted Norwegian version of Lagerveld and Blonk. The interventions are run in&#xD;
      parallel. The patients who are receiving MCT and work-focused interventions will be treated&#xD;
      up to maximum 12 sessions, with weekly session of 45-60 minute duration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The treatment will be administered according to the originators published treatment protocols&#xD;
      for MCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. All patients referred to the clinic will be consecutively assessed at intake (MINI).&#xD;
           Based on diagnosis and criteria for inclusion and exclusion, the patients will be asked&#xD;
           to volunteer to participate in the study and confirm by signing a form of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Patients will be randomized to one of the two conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Patients will be asked to self-rate symptoms on a battery of self-report questionnaires.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Work-focused meta-cognitive therapy will be given to patients in group 1, while group 2&#xD;
           is a waiting list control. Waiting list controls will be rated but not treated and will&#xD;
           wait for treatment for either 8 or 12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. After waiting they will be transferred to the treatment group.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. The patients will be assessed prior to treatment, by at end of treatment weeks in&#xD;
           treatment, and at six months and at, one and two years of follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Reassessment of the diagnosis and symptom severity is made by post-treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Criteria for recovery will be: Jacobsen criteria of a minimum change and patients crossing&#xD;
      the cut-off point on two measures: The BDI and BAI. Other outcome measures will include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Reduction of depressive symptoms as measured by self-report questionnaires&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Number of patients with no diagnosis based on MINI after treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Relapse rate during six months and at, one year follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
      A comparison between the two groups of patients will be conducted at post-treatment.&#xD;
      Follow-up data will be analysed based on 6 month and at one year of follow up for the&#xD;
      treatment condition with self-report and a four year follow-up with register data. A within&#xD;
      group analyses will be conducted in order to estimate effect sizes and significant clinical&#xD;
      change estimates.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be randomized in patients divided on three conditions in a 1:2 ratio. One&#xD;
      factors are controlled for in the randomization, namely, gender. A computer program provided&#xD;
      by NTNU WebCRF will generate the randomization list.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 31, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomised Controlled Trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in degree of sick leave</measure>
    <time_frame>From 2 years prior to intervention - to 4 years after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>data from National registers</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in degree of sick leave</measure>
    <time_frame>From 2 years prior to intervention - to 4 years after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>data from patients self-report</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in anxiety symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>From pre treatment, to post treatment (12 weeks), 6 months and 1 year follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in depressive symptoms measured by Beck Anxiety Inventory (BAI)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in depressive symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>From pre treatment, to post treatment (12 weeks), 6 months 1 year follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in depressive symptoms measured by Beck Depression Inventory II (BDI-II)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in metacognitions</measure>
    <time_frame>From pre treatment, to post treatment (12 weeks), 6 months and 1 year follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in metacognitions symptoms measured by the Metacognitions Questionnaire 30 (MCQ-30)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in subjective health complaints</measure>
    <time_frame>From pre treatment, to post treatment (12 weeks), 6 months and 1 year follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in symptoms measured by Subjective Health Complaints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in bullying and victimisation at work</measure>
    <time_frame>From pre treatment, to post treatment (12 weeks), 6 months and 1 year follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in measured Negative Acts Questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in self-efficacy</measure>
    <time_frame>From pre treatment, to post treatment (12 weeks), 6 months and 1 year follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Changes measured with Return to work self-efficacy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in resilience</measure>
    <time_frame>From pre treatment, to post treatment (12 weeks), 6 months and 1 year follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Changes measured with The resilience scale for adults (RSA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>From pre treatment, to post treatment (12 weeks), 6 months and 1 year follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Changes measured with EQ-5D-5L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>MINI - diagnostic interview</measure>
    <time_frame>From pre treatment, to post treatment (12 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Diagnostic evaluations using MINI - International Neuropsychiatric Interview</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary analysis related to the onset of Covid-19</measure>
    <time_frame>From pre treatment, to post treatment (12 weeks), 6 months and 1 year follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Sub-analyses taking into consideration the onset of Covid-19 in Norway by mid March 2020</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">240</enrollment>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Work-focused metacognitive therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Work-focused metacognitive therapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Waiting list</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Waiting list</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Metacognitive therapy and work-focused interventions</intervention_name>
    <description>Metacognitive therapy and work-focused interventions, up to maximum 12 sessions, with weekly session of 45-60 minute duration. The metacognitive treatment program is based on Wells' manual. The work-focused intervention is based on Lagerveld and Blonk. The interventions are run in parallel.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Waiting list</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Work-focused metacognitive therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Waiting list</intervention_name>
    <description>Waiting list</description>
    <arm_group_label>Waiting list</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  on sick leave either partial or full, due to&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  clinically relevant level of anxiety and depression, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  eligible for work-related sick leave pay outs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  given consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious mental illness (such as bipolar disorder or schizophrenia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Substance abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cluster A and B personality disorder&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Odin Hjemdal, prof</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Norwegian University of Science and Technology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ragne GH Gjengedal</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Diakonhjemmet Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Odin Hjemdal, prof</last_name>
    <phone>0047 73597889</phone>
    <email>odin.hjemdal@ntnu.no</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Poliklinikken Raskere Tilbake, Diakonhjemmet Sykehus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oslo</city>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Odin Hjemdal, phd prof</last_name>
      <email>odin.hjemdal@ntnu.no</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Norway</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 29, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 29, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 14, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 14, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 18, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Occupational Health Services</keyword>
  <keyword>Metacognitive therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Work focused interventions</keyword>
  <keyword>Sick leave</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

