<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2778">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04650087</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00107078</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04650087</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19 Thrombosis Prevention Trials: Post-hospital Thromboprophylaxis</brief_title>
  <official_title>COVID-19 Post-hospital Thrombosis Prevention Trial: An Adaptive, Multicenter, Prospective, Randomized Platform Trial Evaluating the Efficacy and Safety of Antithrombotic Strategies in Patients With COVID-19 Following Hospital Discharge</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Thomas Ortel, M.D., Ph.D.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Duke University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A multicenter, adaptive, randomized platform trial evaluating the efficacy and safety of&#xD;
      antithrombotic strategies in patients with COVID-19 following hospital discharge&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is an adaptive, prospective, randomized platform trial designed to compare the&#xD;
      effectiveness and safety of antithrombotic therapy with no antithrombotic therapy after&#xD;
      hospitalization for 48 hours or longer for COVID-19. For Stage 1 of this study, participants&#xD;
      will be randomized to either prophylactic anticoagulation or matching placebo for 30 days,&#xD;
      and then followed for an additional 60 days after the completion of treatment (total duration&#xD;
      of follow-up, 90 days).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective is to determine the most effective and safe antithrombotic strategy to&#xD;
      prevent the composite outcome of symptomatic deep vein thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, other&#xD;
      venous thromboembolism, ischemic stroke, myocardial infarction, other arterial&#xD;
      thromboembolism, and all-cause mortality by 30 days following discharge from the hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biobanking of samples for future biomarker and mechanistic studies will be available for&#xD;
      centers able to participate and collect samples from eligible participants. Samples will be&#xD;
      collected at the time of enrollment and after the completion of 30 days of therapy&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Double Blind</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Composite outcome of symptomatic deep vein thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, other venous thromboembolism, ischemic stroke, myocardial infarction, other arterial thromboembolism, and all-cause mortality as measured by hospital records.</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after hospital discharge</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The composite outcome of symptomatic deep vein thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, other venous thromboembolism, ischemic stroke, myocardial infarction, other arterial thromboembolism, and all-cause mortality as measured by hospital records.</measure>
    <time_frame>45 days after hospital discharge</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The composite outcome of symptomatic deep vein thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, other venous thromboembolism, ischemic stroke, myocardial infarction, other arterial thromboembolism, and all-cause mortality as measured by hospital records.</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days after hospital discharge</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>New, symptomatic VTE (inclusive of DVT, PE, or other venous thrombosis) for up to 30 days after randomization as measured by hospital records.</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after reandomization</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>New, symptomatic ATE (inclusive of ischemic stroke, MI, or peripheral arterial thromboembolism) for up to 30 days after randomization as measured by hospital records.</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after randomization</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The incidence of all-cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days following discharge from hospital</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The incidence of all-cause rehospitalization for up to 30 days after randomization</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days following discharge from hospital</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">5320</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Apixaban</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Drug: Apixaban 2.5 MG Participants will be given study medication at the time of discharge from the hospital. Participants will take Apixaban 2.5 MG twice a day, once in the morning and once in the evening, for 30 days. Participants will be contacted (electronic or telephone) 2 days after starting the study medication and contact will continue up to day 90 after starting study treatment. Follow up will be through electronic and/or telephone contact depending on the participant's preference, compliance, and medication adherence. Participants will be queried for any clinically relevant endpoints, especially major bleeding or a need to seek healthcare attention for any reason. Follow-up will occur from the time of discharge and through the 30 day study period, with contacts 2 days, 10 days, 20 days, and 30 days after discharge. Two additional study contacts will take place 45 days and 90 days after discharge.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Drug: Placebo Participants will be given study medication at the time of discharge from the hospital. Participants will take the Placebo twice a day, once in the morning and once in the evening, for 30 days. Participants will be contacted (electronic or telephone) 2 days after starting the study medication and contact will continue up to day 90 after starting study treatment. Follow up will be through electronic and/or telephone contact depending on the participant's preference, compliance, and medication adherence. Participants will be queried for any clinically relevant endpoints, especially major bleeding or a need to seek healthcare attention for any reason. Follow-up will occur from the time of discharge and through the 30 day study period, with contacts 2 days, 10 days, 20 days, and 30 days after discharge. Two additional study contacts will take place 45 days and 90 days after discharge.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Apixaban 2.5 MG</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will take Apixaban 2.5 MG twice a day, once in the morning and once in the evening for 30 days. Participants will be contacted (electronic or telephone) 2 days after starting the study medication and will continue up to day 90 after starting study treatment. Followup will occur from the time of discharge through the 30 day study period with contacts at 2 days, 10 days, 20 days and 30 days after discharge. Two additional study contacts will take place 45 days and 90 days after discharge.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Apixaban</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Eliquis</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will take placebo twice a day, once in the morning and once in the evening for 30 days. Participants will be contacted (electronic or telephone) 2 days after starting the study medication and will continue up to day 90 after starting study treatment. Followup will occur from the time of discharge through the 30 day study period with contacts at 2 days, 10 days, 20 days and 30 days after discharge. Two additional study contacts will take place 45 days and 90 days after discharge.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  PCR-positive COVID-19 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hospitalized for two or more days&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-existing indication for anticoagulation (e.g., pulmonary embolism or deep vein&#xD;
             thrombosis; atrial fibrillation; mechanical cardiac valve)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to antithrombotic therapy (e.g., known bleeding within the last 30&#xD;
             days requiring emergency room presentation or hospitalization; major surgery within 14&#xD;
             days; ischemic stroke, intracranial bleed or neurosurgery within 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count &lt; 50,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &lt;8 gm/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal insufficiency (eGFR &lt; 30 mL/min/1.73 m2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prison inmate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy less than 90 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling or unable to provide informed consent/unwilling or unable to complete the&#xD;
             study protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dual antiplatelet therapy that cannot be discontinued&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant need for strong inducers/inhibitors of p-gp or CYP3A4&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tracy Wang, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Duke University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tracy Wang, MD</last_name>
    <phone>919-668-8907</phone>
    <email>tracy.wang@duke.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Thomas L. Ortel, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>919-684-5350</phone>
    <email>thomas.ortel@duke.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 30, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 2, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Duke University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Thomas Ortel, M.D., Ph.D.</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Apixaban</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

