<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1075">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04643860</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DEP_042020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04643860</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Differential Leucocyte Count and Covid-19 Diagnosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A New Point-of-care Test Based on Differential Leucocyte Count, Suitable for a Mass Screening Program to Detect SARS-CoV-2: A Diagnostic Accuracy Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Neuromed IRCCS</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Neuromed IRCCS</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To date, the diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2 infection is made by identifying the viral RNA in&#xD;
      samples collected through a nasopharyngeal swab or other respiratory samples but this&#xD;
      technique, has several limitations for its application in a mass screening. Recently, it has&#xD;
      been developed a new method of acquitting the occurrence of severe Sar-COV-2 infection,&#xD;
      detecting the early rise in leukocyte levels which has a characteristic set of ratios of&#xD;
      leukocyte types, which identify the pathogen. Primary aim of the Diagnostic Accuracy study is&#xD;
      to validate the use of the point-of-care characteristic Differential Leucocyte Count (CLDC)&#xD;
      device and algorithm to detect SARS-CoV-2 infection as a preliminary approach to a mass&#xD;
      screening program. Secondary aims are to define if CLCD methods is able to detect SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      infection earlier as compared to swab molecular testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects at low and high risk of Sar-Cov-2 infection will be tested, at the same time of the&#xD;
      nasopharyngeal swab procedure in the morning, each recruited subject will be also tested&#xD;
      using CLDC device and algorithm. On a voluntary base, subjects will also undergo blood&#xD;
      drawing (3 ml) for hematological cytometric analyses, research personnel will administer a&#xD;
      questionnaire on COVID 19 symptoms and risk factors and for contact traicing. Subjects&#xD;
      testing positive on either CLDC test but negative at the swab will undergo on a voluntary&#xD;
      basis new swab testing after two, 5 and possibly 8 days if still negative.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It estimates to find between 150 and 200 positives in a population of 1000 subjects at&#xD;
      different risk of infection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction. In June 3rd, 2020, the Italian government started the so-called &quot;Phase 2&quot;,&#xD;
      which included the re-opening of working and social activities. In this framework, the issue&#xD;
      of how to identify the asymptomatic individuals who, unwittingly, can spread SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      infection and pose a threat to public health has been raised worldwide. The mondial&#xD;
      population are now experiencing the phase 3 of the pandemic with a rapid increase in the&#xD;
      spreading of infection and in the occurrence of new cases. It is now imperative to guarantee&#xD;
      the health and safety of the people called back to work and to create a safety protocol in&#xD;
      commercial and meeting spaces, which means preventing infected people from causing new&#xD;
      epidemic outbreaks. For this purpose, a well-established mass screening program is required&#xD;
      to meet several needs: first, it should provide the result in a few minutes, it should be&#xD;
      easily delivered on the territory, non-medical healthcare professionals should perform it in&#xD;
      a simple way also, and should be non-invasive, repeatable and reliable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To date, the diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2 infection is made by identifying the viral RNA in&#xD;
      samples collected through a nasopharyngeal swab or other respiratory samples. This technique,&#xD;
      however, has several limitations for its application in a mass screening, among which the&#xD;
      most important ones are the time necessary for the diagnosis, the crowding of those centers&#xD;
      appointed to analyze the specimens, and the non-negligible risk of viral transmission to the&#xD;
      healthcare workers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Point-of-care testing with rapid turnaround times would allow more effective triage in&#xD;
      settings where patient management and infection control decisions need to be made rapidly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, it has been developed a new method of acquitting the occurrence of severe Sar-COV-2&#xD;
      infection and resulting COVID-19, detecting the early rise in leukocyte levels which has a&#xD;
      characteristic set of ratios of leukocyte types, which identify the viral pathogen and&#xD;
      distinguish it from a number of others. This test allows prediction of positives from full&#xD;
      blood count results, sensitive up to 14 days earlier than real-time quantitative PCR&#xD;
      (RT-qPCR), at a cost at least an order of magnitude lower than other tests such as RT-qPCR&#xD;
      and antibody tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim of the study. Primary aim of the Diagnostic Accuracy study is to validate the use of the&#xD;
      point-of-care characteristic Differential Leucocyte Count (CLDC) device and algorithm to&#xD;
      detect SARS-CoV-2 infection in both symptomatic and asymptomatic individuals as a preliminary&#xD;
      approach to a mass screening program. The comparison is represented by the nasopharyngeal&#xD;
      swab molecular testing, the gold standard of COVID-19 diagnosis, for algorithm validation and&#xD;
      hematological cytometric analyses by Coulter HMX, Beckman Coulter, for device validation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary aims are to define if CLCD methods is able to detect SARS-CoV-2 infection earlier&#xD;
      as compared to swab molecular testing and to perform a contact tracing study on all&#xD;
      double-positive patients to estimate their original date of infection to determine the curve&#xD;
      of test sensitivity against initial infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods. Subjects who undergo the nasopharyngeal swab procedure for the diagnosis of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 infection will be consecutively recruited at the Clinic Laboratory of IRCCS&#xD;
      Neuromed in Pozzilli and Diagnostica Medica Spa in Avellino, Italy. Subjects at low and high&#xD;
      risk of Sar-Cov-2 infection will be tested: healthcare workers, patients to be electively&#xD;
      hospitalization for reason other than COVID-19 or other infectious disease, persons who had&#xD;
      direct contact with infected patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the same time of the nasopharyngeal swab procedure in the morning, each recruited subject&#xD;
      will be also tested using CLDC device and algorithm (CLCD 2). On a voluntary base, subjects&#xD;
      will also undergo blood drawing (3 ml) for hematological cytometric analyses by Coulter HMX,&#xD;
      Beckman Coulter and will be tested using only CLDC algorithm (CLCD 1).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The outcome assessors are blinded, since the results of the rRT-PCR analysis require at least&#xD;
      6 hours before being available. Research personnel will administer a questionnaire on COVID&#xD;
      19 symptoms and risk factors and for contact traicing (day, mode) Subjects testing positive&#xD;
      on either CLDC test but negative at the swab will undergo on a voluntary basis new swab&#xD;
      testing after two, 5 and possibly 8 days if still negative.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Independent blinded clinicians through real-time reverse transcription (rRT)-PCR, will&#xD;
      analyse the nasopharyngeal swab accordingly to the International guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For device validation, Full Blood Count (FBC) will be analyzed both by measuring Full Blood&#xD;
      Count and entering the results into the Medichain CLDC-1 portal for rapid analysis and&#xD;
      through the point-of-care device connected to the smart-phone (the Medichain CLDC-2&#xD;
      smartphone microscope - the Adstock Test).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Medichain CLDC-2 smartphone microscope, a device that clip onto a standard smartphone&#xD;
      will be used to analyse drops of blood of approximately 1µl smeared on a microscope slide&#xD;
      (version 2 - Adstock Test) illuminated in phase-contrast mode. Images will then be sent from&#xD;
      the devices to Medichain for analysis on servers in the UK and manual cross-checking.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Then a preparatory algorithm Athena S3ER capable of measuring input specific FBC parameters&#xD;
      analyzes data from this result and returning an output; taking into account abnormal&#xD;
      occurrence in numbers of specific FBC parameters at the onset of infection. The basic test&#xD;
      portal for this study (known as the S3ER algorithm) would be at http://cldc.medichain.online.&#xD;
      The preferred extended portal is the research portal at http://cldc.medichain.online/research&#xD;
      Nasopharyngeal swab analysis. Samples will be subjected to viral thermal inactivation for 1&#xD;
      minute at 90 °C. RNA extraction from the nasopharyngeal swab will be performed with the&#xD;
      Abbott mSample Preparation System (Promega corporation) and an automated extraction system&#xD;
      (Extraction m2000SP, Abbott Molecular). The extracted RNA will be amplified with GeneFinderTM&#xD;
      COVID19 Plus RealAmp PCR kit (ELITechGroup), a one-step rRT-PCR system targeting SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      RdRp, E, and N genes. All recruited subjects will undergo the nasopharyngeal swab, thus&#xD;
      Partial verification bias will beabsent. The CLDC test and nasopharyngeal swab procedures&#xD;
      will be performed at the same moment to avoid disease progression bias. Being the CLCD test&#xD;
      and the nasopharyngeal swab analyzed by independent blinded clinicians, information bias will&#xD;
      be avoided when interpreting the rate-PCR results of the swabs. The index test is completely&#xD;
      independent of the reference test, so to avoid the Incorporation bias. Inconclusive results&#xD;
      will be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size and statistical analysis. The incidence of positivity for COVID-19 is presently&#xD;
      estimated at 15% in the general population and 20% in high-risk people. Therefore, it&#xD;
      estimates to find between 150 and 200 positives in a population of 1000 subjects at different&#xD;
      risk of infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A sample size of 1000 with a prevalence of 15% of positive nasopharyngeal swabs would suffice&#xD;
      to estimate a sensitivity of around 0.75 with a precision of 0.15 for the 95% confidence&#xD;
      interval and a power of 0.8.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Demographic and clinical features of the eligible participants will be summarized by using&#xD;
      mean and standard proportion, or absolute and relative frequencies, for continuous and&#xD;
      discrete variables, respectively. For descriptive purposes only, the same statistical&#xD;
      analyses will be reported also in positive and negative nasopharyngeal swab subjects. In case&#xD;
      of technical failure of testing without the possibility to repeat the procedure, the&#xD;
      participants will be excluded from further analyses. In the other subjects, the sensitivity&#xD;
      and specificity for the CLDC (index test) when compared to the nasopharyngeal swab (reference&#xD;
      test 1) or to FBC (reference test 2) will be estimated, and their 95% confidence interval&#xD;
      will be calculated from the exact binomial distribution. These analyses will be also&#xD;
      replicated according to main subject characteristics. The participants will be characterizing&#xD;
      as true positives (TP), false positives (FP), as well as false negatives (FN) and true&#xD;
      negatives (TN), in terms of prevalence of positive CLDC-PCR, CLDC-FBC results. The null&#xD;
      association of no difference across TP, FP, FN and TN will test using a Kruskal-Wallis test.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>validation</measure>
    <time_frame>4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Primary aim is to validate the use of the point-of-care characteristic Differential Leucocyte Count (CLDC) device and algorithm to detect SARS-CoV-2 infection as a preliminary approach to a mass screening program.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>test sensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Secondary aims are to define if CLCD methods is able to detect SARS-CoV-2 infection earlier as compared to swab molecular testing and to perform a contact tracing study on all double-positive patients to estimate their original date of infection to determine the curve of test sensitivity against initial infection.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV-2 Infection Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>General population</arm_group_label>
    <description>Subjects, at low and high risk of SARS-Cov-2, who undergo the nasopharyngeal swab procedure for the diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2 infection will be consecutively recruited at the Clinic Laboratory of IRCCS Neuromed in Pozzilli and Diagnostica Medica Spa in Avellino, Italy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Differential Leucocyte Count (CLDC) device and algorithm</intervention_name>
    <description>Boold sample that detecting the early rise in leukocyte levels which has a characteristic set of ratios of leukocyte types, which identify the viral pathogen and distinguish it from a number of others. This test allows prediction of positives from full blood count results.</description>
    <arm_group_label>General population</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood sample will be taken for testing the leucocytes count to identified the presence of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 and blood drawing (3 ml) for hematological cytometric analyses&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Subjects at low and high risk of Sar-Cov-2 infection, who undergo the nasopharyngeal swab&#xD;
        procedure for the diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2 infection will be consecutively recruited at the&#xD;
        Clinic Laboratory of IRCCS Neuromed in Pozzilli and Diagnostica Medica Spa in Avellino,&#xD;
        Italy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signing a written consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IRCCS INM Neuromed, Department of Epidemiology and Prevention</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pozzilli</city>
        <state>IS</state>
        <zip>86077</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 24, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 25, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 25, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 25, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 30, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Neuromed IRCCS</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Licia Iacoviello</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2 Leucocyte General population</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

