<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1551">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04729452</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CT 269506</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04729452</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Characterisation of the Immune Response to SARS-CoV-2</brief_title>
  <official_title>Characterisation of the Immune Response to SARS-CoV-2 Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Lucy Jones</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cardiff University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Oxford</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cwm Taf University Health Board (NHS)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Emerging clinical details of the current SARS-CoV-2 pandemic have illustrated that there are&#xD;
      multiple clinical presentations and outcomes of this viral infection. People with an&#xD;
      infection have been reported to have a spectrum of disease from severe acute respiratory&#xD;
      distress requiring ventilation, to mild respiratory or gastrointestinal symptoms and&#xD;
      asymptomatic presentations. Mechanisms explaining the heterogeneity of host response to&#xD;
      infection are yet to be characterised.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this project is to understand the host immune response to infection with&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 over time in convalescent adults, including acquired immune responses, circulating&#xD;
      levels of immune signalling molecules, gene expression profiling in peripheral blood and to&#xD;
      identify host genetic variants associated with disease progressions or severity. Participants&#xD;
      will be healthcare workers who had a diagnosis of COVID-19 (confirmed by positive RT-PCR&#xD;
      assay) more than 28 days ago and have recovered and are employed by Cwm Taf Morgannwg&#xD;
      University health board. Samples will be processed and analysed to explore immunological,&#xD;
      host genetic factors and virological factors that explain pathogenesis and predict outcomes&#xD;
      of infection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      AIMS AND OBJECTIVES The objective of this project is to understand the host immune response&#xD;
      to infection with SARS-CoV-2 over time in convalescent adults, including acquired immune&#xD;
      responses, gene expression profiling in peripheral blood and to identify host genetic&#xD;
      variants associated with disease progressions or severity. We would like to ascertain why&#xD;
      different people experience different disease phenotypes with this coronavirus infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our primary objective is to determine key protective cellular immune parameters (e.g. T cell&#xD;
      responses) and confirm whether there are host genetic factors that provide protection from&#xD;
      disease. We aim to define immunodominant SARS-CoV-2 T-cell epitopes by screening overlapping&#xD;
      peptides from the viral proteome and mapping responses to individual COVID proteins expressed&#xD;
      intracellularly in antigen-presenting cells (to confirm processing and presentation at the&#xD;
      cell surface). Peptide-HLA multimers will be constructed for confirmed immunodominant&#xD;
      responses. These reagents will allow rapid enumeration and tracking of COVID-specific T cell&#xD;
      responses in patient samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our secondary objective is to determine whether there are public (shared) T-cell receptor&#xD;
      responses to SARS-CoV-2. We will also examine whether pre-existing T-cells responses to other&#xD;
      viruses protect against SARS-CoV-2-induced disease (COVID-19). T-cells generated will be used&#xD;
      to test and verify detection reagents. These reagents will be developed for various projects&#xD;
      in Oxford University including monitoring of T-cell responses induced by COVID vaccines. We&#xD;
      will also establish whether pre-existing cross-reactive immunity to other coronaviruses&#xD;
      correlates with disease severity as seen with the 2009 swine flu pandemic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determination of key protective cellular immune parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Our primary objective is to determine key protective cellular immune parameters (e.g. T cell responses) and confirm whether there are host genetic factors that provide protection from disease. We aim to define immunodominant SARS-CoV-2 T-cell epitopes by screening overlapping peptides from the viral proteome and mapping responses to individual COVID proteins expressed intracellularly in antigen-presenting cells (to confirm processing and presentation at the cell surface). Peptide-HLA multimers will be constructed for confirmed immunodominant responses. These reagents will allow rapid enumeration and tracking of COVID-specific T cell responses in patient samples.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determination of public T-cell receptor response to SARS-CoV-2</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Our secondary objective is to determine whether there are public (shared) T-cell receptor responses to SARS-CoV-2. We will also examine whether pre-existing T-cells responses to other viruses protect against SARS-CoV-2-induced disease (COVID-19). T-cells generated will be used to test and verify detection reagents. These reagents will be developed for various projects in Oxford University including monitoring of T-cell responses induced by COVID vaccines. We will also establish whether pre-existing cross-reactive immunity to other coronaviruses correlates with disease severity as seen with the 2009 swine flu pandemic.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>blood test</intervention_name>
    <description>blood test to test immune response to SARS-CoV-2</description>
    <other_name>serial blood tests over 6 months</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Health care workers who had a positive SARS-CoV-2 nasopharyngeal swab test more than 28&#xD;
        days before recruitment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The study will enrol eligible participants with confirmed COVID-19 PCR-based test 28 or&#xD;
        more days prior to recruitment and be convalescent. Participants must be 18 years old and&#xD;
        must have the capacity to provide written consent after discussing the participant&#xD;
        information sheet. Participants must be health care workers for Cwm Taf Morgannwg&#xD;
        University Health board.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants who are acutely unwell with COVID. Participants who cannot provide informed&#xD;
        written consent. Participants who have a clear co-infection with a relevant pathogen.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lucy Jones, DM (Oxon) MA BM BCh</last_name>
    <phone>07792244418</phone>
    <email>Lucy.Jones14@wales.nhs.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health board</name>
      <address>
        <city>Llantrisant</city>
        <state>Rhondda Cynon Taf</state>
        <zip>CF82 7XR</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rhian Beynon</last_name>
      <phone>01443443421</phone>
      <email>Rhian.Beynon@wales.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cwm Taf University Health Board (NHS)</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lucy Jones</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Honorary Clinical Lecturer and Associate Specialist in GU and HIV</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

