<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4734">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04445194</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCV-Ⅰ-healthy</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04445194</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase I Clinical Study of Recombinant Novel Coronavirus Vaccine</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multi-center, Double-blind, Randomized, Placebo Parallel Controlled, Safety and Tolerability Phase I Clinical Trial of Recombinant Novel Coronavirus Vaccine (CHO Cells) in Healthy People Between 18 and 59 Years of Age</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Anhui Zhifei Longcom Biologic Pharmacy Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Second Affiliated Hospital of Chongqing Medical University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Beijing Chao Yang Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Anhui Zhifei Longcom Biologic Pharmacy Co., Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this trial, a total of 50 subjects were recruited; the test vaccines were divided into 3&#xD;
      groups, low-dose vaccine groups, high-dose vaccine groups, and placebo groups. The&#xD;
      first-stage randomized participants in the low-dose group (20 cases) and the placebo group (5&#xD;
      cases) were evaluated for 7 days. After the 7-day safety data was evaluated and agreed by the&#xD;
      DSMB, the second-stage study was conducted. Into the high-dose group (20 cases) and placebo&#xD;
      group (5 cases) subjects; follow-up to 30 days, after the safety assessment by the&#xD;
      investigator and consent, then inoculate the second dose. Observation was performed for 1.0&#xD;
      hour after the second dose. The researchers conducted a safety evaluation and agreed to&#xD;
      follow-up after discharge.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In this trial, a total of 50 subjects were recruited; the test vaccines were divided into 3&#xD;
      groups, low-dose vaccine groups, high-dose vaccine groups, and placebo groups. The&#xD;
      first-stage randomized participants in the low-dose group (20 cases) and the placebo group (5&#xD;
      cases) were evaluated for 7 days. After the 7-day safety data was evaluated and agreed by the&#xD;
      DSMB, the second-stage study was conducted. Into the high-dose group (20 cases) and placebo&#xD;
      group (5 cases) subjects; follow-up to 30 days, after the safety assessment by the&#xD;
      investigator and consent, then inoculate the second dose. Observation was performed for 1.0&#xD;
      hour after the second dose . The researchers conducted a safety evaluation and agreed to&#xD;
      follow-up after discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this trial, all adverse events (AE), all AEs from 0-7 days, and all AEs from 8-30 days&#xD;
      will be collected 30 minutes after each dose, and all AEs will be collected from the first&#xD;
      dose to 30 days after the entire vaccination, and the first dose will be inoculated to the&#xD;
      full course All serious adverse events (SAE) 6 months after vaccination.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 22, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 20, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 22, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The number of adverse events after intramuscular injection</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to one year after the last vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>The main observation methods of adverse reactions mainly include laboratory examination, local reactions and systemic reactions at the administration site, vital signs, blood routine, blood biochemistry, and urine routine.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenic end point</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 6 months after the last dose of vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>All subjects The levels of IL-2, IL-4, IL-5, IL-6 and IFN-γ levels before each vaccination, day 14 after the first vaccination, day 7 after the second vaccination, and 1 and 6 months after the entire vaccination.&#xD;
All subjects before each dose of vaccination, on the 14th day after the first dose, on the 7th day after the second and 1 month and 6 months after the full vaccination That Positive rate of New coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) neutralizing antibody、S protein binding antibody (IgG) and RBD protein binding antibody (IgG).&#xD;
All subjects before each dose of vaccination, on the 14th day after the first dose, on the 7th day after the second and 1 month and 6 months after the full vaccination That Titer level and its multiplier than before exemption of New coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) neutralizing antibody、S protein binding antibody (IgG) and RBD protein binding antibody (IgG).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronavirus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Population I</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Population I has 20 subjects and is considered negative for SARS-COV-2 and fluorescent RT-PCR nucleic acids. Population I is intramuscular injection of deltoid muscle of upper arm with low dose of vaccine.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Population II</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Population II has 20 subjects and is considered negative for SARS-COV-2 and fluorescent RT-PCR nucleic acids. Population II is a high-dose vaccine intramuscular injection of deltoid muscle of the upper arm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Population Ⅲ</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Population Ⅲ has 10 subjects and is considered negative for SARS-COV-2 and fluorescent RT-PCR nucleic acids. Population Ⅲ is a placebo intramuscular injection of deltoid muscle of the upper arm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cell) low-dose group</intervention_name>
    <description>Intramuscular injection of deltoid muscle of upper armof 25μg/0.5ml/person doseRecombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Population I</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells) high-dose group</intervention_name>
    <description>Intramuscular injection of deltoid muscle of upper armof 50μg/0.5ml/person doseRecombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Population II</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Recombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells) placebo group</intervention_name>
    <description>Intramuscular injection of deltoid muscle of upper armof 0.5ml/person doseRecombinant new coronavirus vaccine (CHO cells).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Population Ⅲ</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Comply with the observation age of this clinical trial: 18-59 years old (both&#xD;
             included) adults.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subjects themselves voluntarily agreed to participate in the study, and signed an&#xD;
             informed consent form, and can provide legal identification; understand and abide by&#xD;
             the requirements of the trial protocol; can participate in a half-year follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body temperature under armpit &lt;37.3 ℃.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index (BMI) at 18-28kg / m² (inclusive).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female and male subjects of childbearing age took effective contraception during the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The vital signs, physical examination and laboratory test indicators of the population&#xD;
             specified in the plan are abnormal and have clinical significance as determined by the&#xD;
             clinician;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a history of severe allergies to any component of the research vaccine, including&#xD;
             aluminum preparations, such as: anaphylactic shock, allergic laryngeal edema, allergic&#xD;
             purpura, thrombocytopenic purpura, local allergic necrosis (Arthus reaction); or any&#xD;
             previous History of serious side effects of vaccines or drugs, such as allergies,&#xD;
             urticaria, skin eczema, dyspnea, angioedema, etc .&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with a history of SARS and COVID-19, meet any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. previous history of SARS-CoV and SARS-CoV-2 infection or morbidity;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. during the current SARS-CoV-2 epidemic, there is a diagnosis with the new crown&#xD;
                  Patient / suspected patient contact history;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. positive for SARS-CoV-2 IgM and / or IgG antibodies;&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. positive for real-time fluorescent RT-PCR nucleic acid.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have taken antipyretics or painkillers within 24 hours before the first dose of&#xD;
             vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inoculate subunit vaccine and inactivated vaccine within 14 days before the first dose&#xD;
             of vaccination, and inoculate live attenuated vaccine within 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People with the following diseases:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Acute febrile illness;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Digestive system diseases (eg, diarrhea, abdominal pain, vomiting, etc.) in the&#xD;
                  past 7 days;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Congenital malformations or developmental disorders, genetic defects, severe&#xD;
                  malnutrition, etc .;&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Congenital or acquired immunodeficiency or autoimmune disease history or within 6&#xD;
                  months of receiving immunomodulator treatment, such as hormones; or monoclonal&#xD;
                  antibodies; or thymosin; or interferon, etc .; but local medications (such as&#xD;
                  ointment are allowed , Eye drops, inhalation or nasal spray), local&#xD;
                  administration should not exceed the dosage recommended in the instructions or&#xD;
                  have any signs of systemic exposure;&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. The chest imaging examination is clinically significant if the investigator&#xD;
                  judges that the abnormality is clinically positive, or any positive of hepatitis&#xD;
                  B surface antigen, hepatitis C virus antibody, human immunodeficiency virus HIV&#xD;
                  antibody or syphilis specific antibody;&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Neurological diseases or neurodevelopmental disorders (eg, migraine, epilepsy,&#xD;
                  stroke, seizures in the last three years, encephalopathy, focal neurological&#xD;
                  deficit, Guillain-Barré syndrome, encephalomyelitis or transverse myelitis );&#xD;
                  History of mental illness or family history;&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Functional spleenlessness, and spleenlessness or splenectomy for any reason;&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. There are serious chronic diseases or conditions that cannot be controlled&#xD;
                  smoothly in the advanced stage, such as diabetes and thyroid disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Severe liver and kidney diseases; respiratory diseases that currently require&#xD;
                  daily medication (eg, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease [COPD], asthma) or&#xD;
                  any treatment that exacerbates respiratory diseases (eg, exacerbated asthma)&#xD;
                  within the last 5 years; suffers History of severe cardiovascular disease (such&#xD;
                  as congestive heart failure, cardiomyopathy, ischemic heart disease, arrhythmia,&#xD;
                  conduction block, myocardial infarction, pulmonary heart disease) or myocarditis&#xD;
                  or pericarditis;&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. have thrombocytopenia, any coagulopathy, or receive anticoagulant treatment, etc&#xD;
                  .;&#xD;
&#xD;
              11. Cancer patients;&#xD;
&#xD;
              12. Have received blood or blood-related products, including immunoglobulin within 3&#xD;
                  months; or plan to use it during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lactating women or pregnant women (including blood or urine pregnancy test positive).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any research or unregistered product (medicine, vaccine, biological product or device)&#xD;
             other than the research product was used within 3 months before the application of the&#xD;
             test drug / vaccine, or planned to be used during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People with halo and halo needles.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The investigator believes that the presence of any disease or condition in the subject&#xD;
             may put the subject at an unacceptable risk; the subject cannot meet the protocol&#xD;
             requirements; and interfere with the assessment of vaccine response.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>59 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hong Ren, master</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The Second Affiliated Hospital of Chongqing Medical University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Second Affiliated Hospital of Chongqing Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chongqing</city>
        <state>Chongqing</state>
        <zip>400010</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 1, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 1, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 3, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Recombinant Novel Coronavirus Vaccine</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

