<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3248">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04657484</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>INT/IEC/2020/SPL-1528</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04657484</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of Two Corticosteroid Regimens for Post COVID-19 Diffuse Lung Disease</brief_title>
  <acronym>COLDSTER</acronym>
  <official_title>Comparison of the Efficacy and Safety of Two Corticosteroid Regimens in the Treatment of Diffuse Lung Disease After Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Pneumonia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A proportion of patients with COVID-19 pneumonia have a prolonged course of illness. Some of&#xD;
      these patients continue to have considerable respiratory symptoms or persistent hypoxemia.&#xD;
      The CT abnormalities in these patients are often a combination of ground-glass opacities and&#xD;
      patchy multifocal consolidation consistent with a pattern of OP. In several patients, these&#xD;
      radiologic abnormalities persist. As with other forms of OP, patients with post-COVID OP or&#xD;
      post COVID diffuse lung disease (PC-DLD) may benefit from treatment with oral&#xD;
      glucocorticoids. The ideal dose of glucocorticoids for treating PC-DLD is unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, we aim to compare the efficacy and safety of a medium dose and a low dose of&#xD;
      prednisolone (as the initial dose) for the treatment of post-COVID. diffuse lung disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A proportion of patients with COVID-19 pneumonia (with or without ARDS) have a prolonged&#xD;
      course of illness. Some of these patients continue to have considerable respiratory symptoms&#xD;
      or persistent hypoxemia. The CT abnormalities in these patients are often a combination of&#xD;
      ground-glass opacities and patchy multifocal consolidation consistent with a pattern of OP.&#xD;
      In several patients, these radiologic abnormalities persist even after the symptoms of active&#xD;
      COVID-19 have subsided and swabs from the upper respiratory tract for SARS-CoV-2 have turned&#xD;
      negative. Such patients may be classified as having a secondary form of OP, namely&#xD;
      post-infectious OP. Some of the patients also start developing signs of fibrosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As with other forms of OP, patients with post-COVID OP or post COVID diffuse lung disease&#xD;
      (PC-DLD) may benefit from treatment with oral glucocorticoids.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Glucocorticoids may be a double-edged sword in this clinical situation. Steroids reduce&#xD;
      inflammation associated with OP with a resultant resolution of symptoms, improvement in gas&#xD;
      exchange (resulting in the resolution of hypoxemia), and potentially preventing the&#xD;
      progression of early parenchymal abnormalities to irreversible fibrosis. However, they are&#xD;
      associated with adverse effects such as hyperglycemia, delayed viral clearance, and increased&#xD;
      susceptibility to infections. The ideal dose of glucocorticoids for treating PC-DLD is&#xD;
      unknown. As PC-DLD is likely to get recognised early (much earlier than the average duration&#xD;
      between onset of symptoms and diagnosis in other forms of OP, i.e., about 3-6 months), there&#xD;
      is a possibility a lower intensity of glucocorticoids may be sufficient for treatment than&#xD;
      the usual regimens, with the advantage of lesser adverse effects. A previous retrospective&#xD;
      study that compared two regimens (higher dose intensity [DI] of glucocorticoids alone vs.&#xD;
      glucocorticoids at a lower dose intensity along with clarithromycin), however, found that a&#xD;
      complete radiologic response was higher in the prednisone alone (higher DI) group (81% vs.&#xD;
      63%) than in the combination group (with a lower DI of prednisone). Statistical significance&#xD;
      was however not achieved (p=0.38), mainly due to the small sample size.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We hypothesize that in PC-DLD a higher intensity (i.e., starting with a medium dose of&#xD;
      prednisolone) will be more effective than a lower dose intensity (i.e., starting with a low&#xD;
      dose of prednisolone) of glucocorticoids in effecting a radiologic response at six weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 8, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 7, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 7, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects with a complete radiologic response</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Complete response is defined as complete disappearance or ≥90% reduction in the lung parenchymal abnormalities on a high-resolution CT scan</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects with a complete or good response radiologic response</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Complete response is defined as complete disappearance or ≥90% reduction in the lung parenchymal abnormalities on a high-resolution CT scan. Good response is defined as ≥50% but less than 90% reduction in the lung parenchymal abnormalities on a high-resolution CT scan.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects with a good composite response</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Complete or good radiologic resolution along with no oxygen desturation on exercise testing</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Forced vital capacity as a percentage of the predicted</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Forced vital capacity will be measured using spirometry. The predicted value will be calculated based on standard reference equations.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in resting oxygen saturation</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The change in resting oxygen saturation (measured by pulse oximetry) from the day of randomization to 6 weeks</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects with oxygen desaturation on exercise testing</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Oxygen desaturation will be defined as a fall in oxygen saturation by 4% or more on exercise testing (by one-minute sit-to-stand test and six-minute walk test)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in dyspnea score</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The change in dyspnea score assessed using the modified Medical Research Council (mMRC) scale from the day of randomization to 6 weeks</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Severity of dyspnea</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Severity of dyspnea assessed using the FACIT-Dyspnea scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Respiratory health status</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Respiratory health status assessed using the King's Brief ILD questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health-related quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Health-related quality of life assessed using Short Form-36 questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse effects of prednisolone</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The adverse effects of treatment (acne, weight gain, hyperglycemia, hypertension, abdominal pain, dyspepsia, Cushingoid facies, skin thinning and bruising, mood changes, muscular weakness and any other adverse effects related to prednisolone)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Post COVID-19 Diffuse Lung Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Medium dose prednisolone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>An initial dose of 40 mg/day will be administered for 1 week, followed by 30 mg/day for 1 week, 20 mg/day for 2 weeks, 10 mg/day for 2 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Low dose prednisolone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>A dose of 10 mg/day of prednisolone will be administered for 6 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Medium dose prednisolone</intervention_name>
    <description>Same as arm description</description>
    <arm_group_label>Medium dose prednisolone</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Low dose prednisolone</intervention_name>
    <description>Same as arm description</description>
    <arm_group_label>Low dose prednisolone</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed to have COVID-19 by means of a real-time reverse transcription polymerase&#xD;
             chain reaction (rRT-PCR) test performed on a respiratory (upper or lower respiratory)&#xD;
             sample or the detection of COVID-19 antigen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having significant respiratory symptoms (cough and breathlessness) or persistent&#xD;
             hypoxemia or oxygen desaturation on exercise and CT chest showing residual changes of&#xD;
             post-COVID parenchymal involvement of any extent OR having CT chest showing residual&#xD;
             changes of post-COVID parenchymal involvement &gt;20% of the lung parenchyma on visual&#xD;
             inspection of the scans between 3-8 weeks of the onset of symptoms of COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving ventilatory or respiratory support (invasive or non-invasive mechanical&#xD;
             ventilation or high flow nasal cannula) or supplemental oxygen with FiO2&gt;0.35&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Requiring intensive care due to acute COVID-19 pneumonia or its complications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having a known lung parenchymal lung disease before the onset of COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having absolute contraindication for prednisolone in a dose of 40 mg/day (this&#xD;
             includes untreated glaucoma, uncontrolled diabetes mellitus, signs of an uncontrolled&#xD;
             or untreated infection or sepsis, pulmonary mycosis, untreated severe psychiatric&#xD;
             disorders)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to provide informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sahajal Dhooria, MD, DM</last_name>
    <phone>+919530661388</phone>
    <email>sahajal@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chandigarh</city>
        <zip>160012</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ritesh Agarwal, MD, DM</last_name>
      <phone>+911722756825</phone>
      <email>agarwal.ritesh@outlook.in</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 5, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 8, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 18, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 18, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 22, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sahajal Dhooria</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>diffuse parenchymal lung disease</keyword>
  <keyword>interstitial lung disease</keyword>
  <keyword>organizing pneumonia</keyword>
  <keyword>coronavirus disease-2019</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-Co-V-2</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Acetate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Methylprednisolone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Methylprednisolone Hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone acetate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone hemisuccinate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone phosphate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

