<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4862">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04713748</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00107313</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04713748</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Tasso-SST OnDemand Comparator Pilot Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pilot Study to Compare Serology Results From Blood Collected Using Tasso-SST OnDemand Device Compared to Venipuncture</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Duke University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Duke University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Purpose and objective: The purpose of this pilot study is participant user acceptance testing&#xD;
      of the Tasso-SST OnDemand device to collect blood for antibody testing. The study will also&#xD;
      compare antibody testing results from blood collected using the Tasso-SST OnDemand device&#xD;
      compared to blood collected by phlebotomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study activities and population group: All participants enrolled in the MURDOCK C3PI Study&#xD;
      (Pro Pro00105703), and actively participating in the testing cohort (n=300), will be emailed&#xD;
      about the study. One or more reminder emails may be sent. The study seeks to enroll up to 100&#xD;
      participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will collect blood using the Tasso-SST OnDemand at the same visit where blood&#xD;
      will be collected via phlebotomy for the MURDOCK C3PI study. Blood samples will be spun and&#xD;
      processed for serum, which will be shipped frozen to analytical lab at Duke. Participants&#xD;
      will complete a short survey about their experience using the Tasso-SST OnDemand device.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data analysis and risk/safety issues: The study team will evaluate correlation between&#xD;
      results from blood collected by the two methods and qualitatively exam participant survey&#xD;
      results. There are no risk/safety issues. Risk of reaction at the collection site is similar&#xD;
      to that of phlebotomy and is described in the electronic consent form.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Purpose: The purpose of this pilot study is participant user acceptance testing of the&#xD;
      Tasso-SST OnDemand device to collect blood for antibody testing. The study will also compare&#xD;
      antibody testing results from blood collected using the Tasso-SST On-Demand device compared&#xD;
      to blood collected by phlebotomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design and Procedure: Participants will collect a small blood sample using the Tasso-SST&#xD;
      OnDemand device during a serology blood draw visit already scheduled for the MURDOCK C3PI&#xD;
      Study (Pro00105703). Participants will be provided a kit that includes written, step-by-step&#xD;
      instructions that include pictures. Participants will also have the option to watch a brief&#xD;
      video on using the device, available online, prior to collection. The Tasso-SST OnDemand&#xD;
      device collects whole capillary blood, at a minimum volume of 80ul.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A standard blood draw will also be done and both blood samples will be spun and processed for&#xD;
      serum. Serum will be frozen and shipped to the lab at Duke for antibody testing. Antibody&#xD;
      results will be compared between the two methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be sent a brief survey to learn about their experience using the Tasso-SST&#xD;
      OnDemand device.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Selection of Subject:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subject Recruitment: All participants meeting eligibility criteria will be emailed about the&#xD;
      study. One or more reminder emails may be sent about the study. The study seeks to enroll up&#xD;
      to 100 participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Tasso-SST OnDemand device sticks to the skin with a light adhesive. When the button is&#xD;
      pressed, a vacuum forms and a lancet pricks the surface of the skin. The vacuum draws blood&#xD;
      out of the capillaries and into a tube attached to the bottom of the device. The Investigator&#xD;
      Brochure is attached to this submission.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Risk and Benefit Assessment: The Tasso-SST OnDemand device uses an adhesive - the device&#xD;
      should be removed immediately if there are any signs of an allergic reaction. There is risk&#xD;
      of bruising or soreness at the site where blood is drawn. There is also a slight possibility&#xD;
      of infection, and a rare risk of fainting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants can minimize risk by closely following the instructions provided with the kits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Trained staff will be present should the participant have any concerns or issues.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study does not have a direct benefit to participants. The information learned could lead&#xD;
      to future use of the Tasso-SST OnDemand device to collect blood safely at home.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Analysis and Data Safety Monitoring: The study team will evaluate correlation between&#xD;
      results from blood collected by the two methods in this pilot study and qualitatively exam&#xD;
      participant survey results. Summary statistics will be generated for survey responses, and&#xD;
      qualitative data will be reviewed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants will collect a small blood sample using the Tasso-SST OnDemand device during a serology blood draw visit already scheduled for the MURDOCK C3PI Study (Pro00105703). Participants will be provided a kit that includes written, step-by-step instructions that include pictures. Participants will also have the option to watch a brief video on using the device, available online, prior to collection.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent sensitivity with the Tasso-SST device compared with a gold standard.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the sensitivity of the COVID-19 antibody test run on Tasso-SST Device serum compared with results from COVID-19 antibody testing of serum obtained by routine phlebotomy as the gold standard.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent specificity with the Tasso-SST device compared with a gold standard.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the specificity of the COVID-19 antibody test run on Tasso-SST Device serum compared with results from COVID-19 antibody testing of serum obtained by routine phlebotomy as the gold standard.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>C3PI Study Testing Group</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Tasso- SST blood collection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>About 100 participants will have blood collected by two methods-regular phlebotomy and Tasso-SST, in this pilot study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Regular Venipuncture</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>About 100 participants will have blood collected by two methods-regular phlebotomy and Tasso-SST, in this pilot study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tasso-SST on Demand</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will collect a small blood sample using the Tasso-SST OnDemand device during a serology blood draw visit already scheduled for the MURDOCK C3PI Study (Pro00105703). Participants will be provided a kit that includes written, step-by-step instructions that include pictures. Participants will also have the option to watch a brief video on using the device, available online, prior to collection. Both blood samples will be spun and processed for serum. Serum will be frozen and shipped to the lab at Duke for antibody testing. Antibody results will be compared between the two methods.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Tasso- SST blood collection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Regular Phlebotomy</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will have a small blood sample collected via regular venipuncture.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Regular Venipuncture</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be a study participant enrolled in the MURDOCK C3PI Study (Pro00105703),&#xD;
             participating in the testing cohort of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants are therefore 18 years of age or older, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  willing to read and complete the consent process.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No exclusion criteria; however, only up to 100 participants will be enrolled. If more&#xD;
             than 100 participants sign consent, some interested participants may not take part in&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>L.Kristin Newby, MD, MHS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Duke University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Abha Singh, MSCR</last_name>
    <phone>9105549370</phone>
    <email>abha.singh@duke.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Douglas Wixted, MMCI</last_name>
    <phone>7038615918</phone>
    <email>douglas.wixted@duke.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke CTSI Translational Population Health Office</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kannapolis</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28081</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Abha Singh</last_name>
      <phone>910-554-9370</phone>
      <email>abha.singh@duke.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 15, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Tasso-SST</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

