<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="680">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04590794</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UTHDA-AC03</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04590794</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SuPAR in Adult Patients With Covid-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>SPARCOL</acronym>
  <official_title>A Prospective Observational Study on Assessment of the Soluble Urokinase Plasminogen Activator Receptor in Adult Patients With Covid-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Thessaly</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Thessaly</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The biomarker soluble urokinase plasminogen activator receptor (suPAR) is the soluble form of&#xD;
      the cell membrane-bound protein urokinase plasminogen activator receptor (uPAR), which is&#xD;
      expressed mainly on immune cells, endothelial cells, and smooth muscle cells. SPARCOL is a&#xD;
      multi-center prospective observational study aiming to investigate if suPAR measured at&#xD;
      admission can predict the risk of future complications and mortality in adults patients with&#xD;
      Covid-19. The study will include approximately 500 patients and will be one of the largest so&#xD;
      far. The study has been registered at Clinical Trials.gov and has been approved by the&#xD;
      Institutional Review Board of the University Hospital of Larisa.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consecutive adult patients (≥ 18 years ) who are admitted to the Hospital due to Covid-19&#xD;
      will be screened for inclusion. Participants will undergo sampling of peripheral venous&#xD;
      blood, immediately after admission. Blood samples drawn from all patients and EDTA plasma&#xD;
      will be stored at -80° C until later measurement. Plasma suPAR levels will be determined&#xD;
      using the suPARnostic® ELISA assay (ViroGates, Denmark).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint will be the presence of respiratory complications, admission to ICU, and&#xD;
      survival at 30 days. Secondary endpoints are also included, such as organ injury, hospital&#xD;
      length of stay, and survival.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data analysis will be based on predefined data points on a prospective data collection form.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      BACKGROUND&#xD;
&#xD;
      Soluble urokinase plasminogen activator receptor&#xD;
&#xD;
      The biomarker soluble urokinase plasminogen activator receptor (suPAR) is the soluble form of&#xD;
      the cell membrane-bound protein urokinase plasminogen activator receptor (uPAR), which is&#xD;
      expressed mainly on immune cells, endothelial cells, and smooth muscle cells. uPAR is&#xD;
      released during inflammation or immune activation, and therefore the suPAR level reflects the&#xD;
      extent of immune activation in the individual. All human beings have a baseline level of&#xD;
      suPAR that is individually determined and increases with age. Studies have shown that the&#xD;
      suPAR level is associated with morbidity and mortality in a number of acute and chronic&#xD;
      diseases and in the general population. The suPAR level is elevated across diseases, and not&#xD;
      solely associated with one specific disease. Therefore, suPAR is applicable as a prognostic&#xD;
      marker and not as a diagnostic marker. This characteristic may be utilized for risk&#xD;
      stratification in unselected patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Originally, uPAR was proven a receptor for urokinase (uPA) which splits plasminogen into&#xD;
      active plasmin. Moreover, uPAR interacts with other proteins and plays a role in several&#xD;
      important cell processes like migration, adhesion, angiogenesis, proliferation, and&#xD;
      chemotaxis. The suPAR protein was discovered in 1991, when it was found to be a marker of&#xD;
      cancer progression. In recent years, several studies have shown that suPAR is associated with&#xD;
      a number of chronic diseases (including cardiovascular, hepatic, renal, and pulmonary&#xD;
      diseases), and that the level is a predictor of a negative outcome of various infectious&#xD;
      diseases (tuberculosis, HIV, malaria, sepsis, meningitis, pneumonia) and in critically ill&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Across diseases, the suPAR level discriminates non-survivors from survivors. suPAR reflects&#xD;
      the level of chronic inflammation, and therefore it has been studied as a potential marker of&#xD;
      development of diseases, and studies have shown that an elevated level predicts development&#xD;
      of chronic diseases and cancer in the general population. The suPAR blood level is stable&#xD;
      with no diurnal variation and no changes following fasting, while suPAR can be measured in&#xD;
      blood, plasma, urine, cerebrospinal fluid, ascites fluid and pleural fluid. The level&#xD;
      increases and decreases with progression and improvement of a disease, respectively, but more&#xD;
      slowly compared to e.g. C-reactive protein (CRP). The normal suPAR plasma level is 2-3 ng/mL&#xD;
      in healthy individuals, about 3-4 ng/mL in unselected patients in emergency departments, and&#xD;
      about 9-10 ng/mL in critically ill patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      suPAR in intensive care&#xD;
&#xD;
      In critically ill patients, the suPAR level is significantly increased. suPAR is an&#xD;
      independent prognostic marker, and the change over time correlates with organ dysfunction.&#xD;
      suPAR is elevated and has a prognostic value in patients with: SIRS (systemic inflammatory&#xD;
      response syndrome), sepsis/septic shock, burn injuries, and traumatic brain injuries. The&#xD;
      suPAR level reflects the body's immune response to infections, and the level increases with&#xD;
      the severity of the infection. In patients with organ dysfunction, the suPAR value is often a&#xD;
      two-digit value. In particular hepatic and renal dysfunction affects the suPAR level. suPAR&#xD;
      has been studied in patients with SIRS who were acutely admitted to the emergency department&#xD;
      (n=902). The studies showed that suPAR is a stronger marker of 2-day, 30-day, and 90-day&#xD;
      mortality than age, CRP, IL-6, creatinine, and procalcitonin. However, for diagnostic&#xD;
      purposes, IL-6 and CRP are superior to suPAR in predicting a positive blood culture. A Greek&#xD;
      multicenter study including 1914 patients with sepsis showed that suPAR is a strong predictor&#xD;
      of mortality, and that a suPAR level above 12 ng/mL is linked to a &gt;80% sensitivity for&#xD;
      mortality and a negative predictive value of 94.5%. In addition, the prognostic value of&#xD;
      suPAR in patients with sepsis is independent of relevant covariates like APACHE score, CRP,&#xD;
      etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In patients with burn injuries and inhalation trauma requiring mechanical ventilation, the&#xD;
      plasma suPAR level and bronchoalveolar lavage fluid level correlate to IL-6 and coagulation&#xD;
      factors. An elevated plasma suPAR level is associated with prolonged Intensive Care Unit&#xD;
      (ICU) stay and the duration of mechanical ventilation. The suPAR level is elevated in&#xD;
      patients with traumatic brain injury. In trauma patients who suffered a brain injury within&#xD;
      12 hours prior to blood sampling, the mean suPAR level is 14.9 ng/mL ± 6.9 vs. 2.8 ng/mL ±&#xD;
      0.7 in control subjects. In these patients suPAR is associated with severity of the brain&#xD;
      injury and with mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      suPAR and acute respiratory distress syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mortality rates of patients with the acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) are high.&#xD;
      Biological markers as well as disease severity scoring systems may be useful for risk&#xD;
      stratification and the creation of homogenous patient groups in clinical trials. However,&#xD;
      currently no single biological marker has been found to have sufficient discriminative value&#xD;
      for accurate prediction of mortality or bedside decision making in ARDS patients in the&#xD;
      clinical setting The first study that investigated the association between plasma suPAR and&#xD;
      mortality in a cohort of ARDS patients was published in 2015. In that study, plasma levels of&#xD;
      suPAR were higher with increasing severity of ARDS, and higher in patients who died in the&#xD;
      ICU. Furthermore, higher plasma suPAR levels were associated with less ventilator- and&#xD;
      ICU-free days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a prospective, multicenter, observational study including mechanically ventilated ICU&#xD;
      patients, low concentrations of suPAR were predictive for survival and high concentrations&#xD;
      for renal replacement therapy and mortality. The authors concluded that SuPAR may be used for&#xD;
      screening for patients with potentially good survival, while its association with renal&#xD;
      replacement therapy may supply an early warning sign for acute renal failure. Several other&#xD;
      authors have evaluated the predictive value of suPAR regarding the risk of ARDS in sepsis&#xD;
      patients, and reported a correlation/association with disease severity, inflammation and&#xD;
      mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      AIM&#xD;
&#xD;
      SPARCOL is a multi-center observational study aiming to investigate if suPAR measured at&#xD;
      admission can predict the risk of future complications and mortality in adults patients with&#xD;
      Covid-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a prospective observational study designed in accordance with the declaration of&#xD;
      Helsinki. The study will be registered at Clinical Trials.gov and has been approved by the&#xD;
      Institutional Review Board of the University Hospital of Larisa, under the reference number&#xD;
      17543.The study will be approved by the IRB of each of the participating centers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient eligibility&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consecutive adult patients (≥ 18 years ) who are admitted to the Hospital due to Covid-19&#xD;
      will be screened for inclusion. Exclusion criteria will be age &lt;18 years, any infection&#xD;
      within the previous 4 weeks, patients on renal replacement therapy pre-operatively, patients&#xD;
      who had previously received a transplant, patients with allergies, inflammatory or immune&#xD;
      system disorders, and/or connective tissue disease including rheumatoid arthritis, ankylosing&#xD;
      spondylitis, and systemic lupus erythematosus, administration of steroid, antipsychotic, or&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory/immunomodulatory medication during the last 3, administration of opioids&#xD;
      during the past week, asthma, obesity (BMI ≥ 30 kg m-2), mental disability or severe&#xD;
      psychiatric disease, alcohol or other abuse, legal incapacity or limited legal capacity,&#xD;
      subjects within the exclusion period of another study ,and any treatments for sepsis prior to&#xD;
      enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sampling and laboratory measurements&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will undergo sampling of peripheral venous blood, immediately after admission.&#xD;
      Blood samples drawn from all patients and EDTA plasma will be stored at -80° C until later&#xD;
      measurement. Plasma suPAR levels will be determined using the suPARnostic® ELISA assay&#xD;
      (ViroGates, Denmark), which is based on a simplified double monoclonal antibody sandwich&#xD;
      ELISA assay whereby samples and peroxidase-conjugated anti-suPAR are first mixed together and&#xD;
      then incubated in anti-suPAR pre-coated micro wells. The recombinant suPAR standards of the&#xD;
      kit are calibrated against healthy human blood donor samples. suPAR concentrations are&#xD;
      determined as ng/mL plasma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcomes&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint will be the presence of respiratory complications [need of non-invasive&#xD;
      ventilation (CPAP-BiPAP), hi-flow nasal oxygen, or mechanical ventilation], admission to ICU,&#xD;
      and survival at 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary endpoints will be hypotension (defined as systolic blood pressure &lt;90 mmHg or mean&#xD;
      arterial pressure &lt;65 mmHg for 3 minutes or more), need for vasoactive drugs (need for&#xD;
      vasoactive drugs not planned before and/or continuous infusion), and/or acute new&#xD;
      cardiovascular disorder (atrial fibrillation, sustained ventricular tachycardia,&#xD;
      supraventricular tachycardia, myocardial infarction, pericarditis, myocarditis, cardiogenic&#xD;
      shock, and/or cardiac arrest), renal failure, duration of mechanical ventilation,&#xD;
      reintubation, hospital length of stay, length of stay in ICU and readmission.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Collection and Monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data analysis will be based on predefined data points on a prospective data collection form.&#xD;
      The staff will be blinded to measurements until the end of the study and all data are&#xD;
      analyzed. Clinical monitoring throughout the study will be performed to maximize protocol&#xD;
      adherence, while an independent Data and Safety Monitoring research staff will monitor&#xD;
      safety, ethical, and scientific aspects of the study. Data collection will also include&#xD;
      demographics, general blood count, C-reactive protein, APACHE II, and SOFA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data management&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of the clinical data management plan is to provide high-quality data by adopting&#xD;
      standardized procedures to minimize the number of errors and missing data, and consequently,&#xD;
      to generate an accurate database for analysis. Remote monitoring will be performed to signal&#xD;
      early aberrant patterns, issues with consistency, credibility and other anomalies. Any&#xD;
      missing and outlier data values will be individually revised and completed or corrected&#xD;
      whenever possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will include approximately 500 patients. Based on international and national&#xD;
      epidemiological data, we anticipate that approximately 30% of the included patients will&#xD;
      reach the primary endpoints.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethics and dissemination&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be performed according to national and international guidelines. The study&#xD;
      will begin after approval has been obtained from the Hospital's Institutional Review Board,&#xD;
      according to local regulation. Prospective written informed consent will be requested before&#xD;
      inclusion of all eligible patients based on the Review Board's decision.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Competing interests None declared.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 11, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>respiratory complications</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>need of non-invasive ventilation (CPAP-BiPAP), hi-flow nasal oxygen, or mechanical ventilation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hypotension</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>systolic blood pressure &lt;90 mmHg or mean arterial pressure &lt;65 mmHg for 3 minutes or more</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>need for vasoactive drugs</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>need for vasoactive drugs not planned before and/or continuous infusion</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with acute new cardiovascular disorder</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with atrial fibrillation, sustained ventricular tachycardia, supraventricular tachycardia, myocardial infarction, SPARCOL Study April 12, 2020 7 pericarditis, myocarditis, cardiogenic shock, and/or cardiac arrest</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with organ failure</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with any organ failure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with overall survival up to 8 weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who survive up to 8 weeks</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">500</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>covid 19</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients admitted with covid 19</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Soluble Urokinase Plasminogen Activator Receptor</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will undergo sampling of peripheral venous blood, immediately after admission. Blood samples drawn from all patients and EDTA plasma will be stored at -80° C until later measurement. Plasma suPAR levels will be determined using the suPARnostic® ELISA assay (ViroGates, Denmark), which is based on a simplified double monoclonal antibody sandwich ELISA assay whereby samples and peroxidase-conjugated anti-suPAR are first mixed together and then incubated in anti-suPAR pre-coated micro wells. The recombinant suPAR standards of the kit are calibrated against healthy human blood donor samples. suPAR concentrations are determined as ng/mL plasma.</description>
    <arm_group_label>covid 19</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>suPAR</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Consecutive adult patients who are admitted to the Hospital due to Covid-19&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age ≥18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients hospitalized primarily for Covid 19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection diagnosed through RT-PCR test of nasopharyngeal or&#xD;
             oropharyngeal samples&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  at least one blood sample collected during the hospitalization and stored for&#xD;
             biomarker testing&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age &lt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection who were not primarily admitted for Covid&#xD;
             19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any infection within the previous 4 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  renal replacement therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who had previously received a transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  allergies, inflammatory or immune system disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  connective tissue disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  administration of steroid, antipsychotic, or anti-inflammatory/immunomodulatory&#xD;
             medication during the last 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  administration of opioids during the past week&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  asthma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  obesity (BMI ≥ 30 kg m-2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mental disability or severe psychiatric disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  alcohol or other abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  legal incapacity or limited legal capacity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  subjects within the exclusion period of another study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any treatments for covid or sepsis prior to enrolment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Athanasios Chalkias, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Thessaly</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital of Larisa, Department of Anesthesiology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Larissa</city>
        <state>Thessaly</state>
        <zip>41110</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chalkias A, Mouzarou A, Samara E, Xanthos T, Ischaki E, Pantazopoulos I. Soluble Urokinase Plasminogen Activator Receptor: A Biomarker for Predicting Complications and Critical Care Admission of COVID-19 Patients. Mol Diagn Ther. 2020 Oct;24(5):517-521. doi: 10.1007/s40291-020-00481-8.</citation>
    <PMID>32613288</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Azam TU, Shadid HR, Blakely P, O'Hayer P, Berlin H, Pan M, Zhao P, Zhao L, Pennathur S, Pop-Busui R, Altintas I, Tingleff J, Stauning MA, Andersen O, Adami ME, Solomonidi N, Tsilika M, Tober-Lau P, Arnaoutoglou E, Keitel V, Tacke F, Chalkias A, Loosen SH, Giamarellos-Bourboulis EJ, Eugen-Olsen J, Reiser J, Hayek SS; International Study of Inflammation in COVID-19. Soluble Urokinase Receptor (SuPAR) in COVID-19-Related AKI. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2020 Nov;31(11):2725-2735. doi: 10.1681/ASN.2020060829. Epub 2020 Sep 22.</citation>
    <PMID>32963090</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ge H, Wang X, Yuan X, Xiao G, Wang C, Deng T, Yuan Q, Xiao X. The epidemiology and clinical information about COVID-19. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2020 Jun;39(6):1011-1019. doi: 10.1007/s10096-020-03874-z. Epub 2020 Apr 14. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32291542</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 14, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Thessaly</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Athanasios Chalkias, MD, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Asst. Professor of Anesthesiology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>covid 19</keyword>
  <keyword>organ injury</keyword>
  <keyword>outcome</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Plasminogen</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>There is not a plan to make IPD available</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

