<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="613">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04621123</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>COnV-ert</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04621123</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Plasma for Early Treatment in Non-hospitalised Mild or Moderate COVID-19 Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Convalescent Methylene Blue Treated (MBT) Plasma for Early Treatment in Non-hospitalised Mild or Moderate COVID-19 Patients: a Randomized Double Blind Study (COnV-ert)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fundación FLS de Lucha Contra el Sida, las Enfermedades Infecciosas y la Promoción de la Salud y la Ciencia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Germans Trias i Pujol Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>IrsiCaixa</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Banc de Sang i Teixits</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Grifols Biologicals, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fundación FLS de Lucha Contra el Sida, las Enfermedades Infecciosas y la Promoción de la Salud y la Ciencia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, randomized (1:1), double blind study of Convalescent anti-SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      MBT Plasma (also known as convalescent plasma) plus standard medical treatment (SMT) versus&#xD;
      placebo plus SMT in mild or moderate COVID-19 patients who are non-hospitalised. Subjects&#xD;
      with confirmed infection by SARS-CoV-2 will receive SMT plus a total of 200-250 mL of&#xD;
      convalescent plasma that has been pathogen-inactivated using MBT or placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 474 individuals will be randomized (1:1) with an interim analysis after the&#xD;
      first 60 subjects (30 in each arm).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample size will be re-assessed upon interim analysis. Approximately 135 individuals from&#xD;
      selected study sites will be included in the substudy to assess the immune response and the&#xD;
      methods of sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a prospective, randomized (1:1), double blind study of Convalescent anti-SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      MBT Plasma (also known as convalescent plasma) plus standard medical treatment (SMT) versus&#xD;
      placebo plus SMT in mild or moderate COVID-19 patients who are non-hospitalised. Subjects&#xD;
      with confirmed infection by SARS-CoV-2 will receive SMT plus a total of 200-250 mL of&#xD;
      convalescent plasma that has been pathogen-inactivated using MBT or placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 474 individuals will be randomized (1:1) with an interim analysis after the&#xD;
      first 60 subjects (30 in each arm).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample size will be re-assessed upon interim analysis. Approximately 135 individuals from&#xD;
      selected study sites will be included in the substudy to assess the immune response and the&#xD;
      methods of sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigational product will be administered by IV infusion at baseline. Participants&#xD;
      will continue their standard medical treatment (SMT) for SARS-CoV-2 infection as prescribed&#xD;
      by their regular physician. If applicable, SMT may be modified during the study, depending on&#xD;
      personal requirements, the severity and progression of the disease, and need for&#xD;
      hospitalization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects' participation (from inclusion/baseline visit to the end-of-study visit) will be up&#xD;
      to 60 days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, randomized (1:1), double blind study of Convalescent anti-SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      MBT Plasma (also known as convalescent plasma) plus standard medical treatment (SMT) versus&#xD;
      placebo plus SMT in mild or moderate COVID-19 patients who are non-hospitalised. Subjects&#xD;
      with confirmed infection by SARS-CoV-2 will receive SMT plus a total of 200-250 mL of&#xD;
      convalescent plasma that has been pathogen-inactivated using MBT or placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study candidates will voluntarily express their interest in participating in the study&#xD;
      through the study website or will be offered to participate at the emergency (ER) and&#xD;
      out-patient departments (OPD) of the participating hospitals. Candidates registered on the&#xD;
      website will be contacted by study physicians by phone to inform them about the study and&#xD;
      check their suitability for the study. Suitable candidates will be scheduled an&#xD;
      inclusion/baseline visit in which informed consent will be obtained (i.e., the paper informed&#xD;
      consent will be signed), and their eligibility will be confirmed. Candidates identified&#xD;
      through ER and OPD departments will undergo an inclusion/baseline visit, where the informed&#xD;
      consent will be obtained and eligibility will be checked. A subgroup of eligible candidates&#xD;
      from selected study sites will be offered participation in the substudy to assess the immune&#xD;
      response and the methods of sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood and nasopharyngeal samples will be obtained from all eligible candidates. Eligible&#xD;
      candidates will be randomized and administered an intravenous (IV) infusion at baseline&#xD;
      (convalescent plasma or placebo). Both the investigator and the participant will be blinded&#xD;
      to the study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specifically, subjects randomized to combination convalescent anti-SARS-CoV-2 MBT plasma plus&#xD;
      SMT will undergo an ABO compatibility test and will receive a single infusion of 200 to 250&#xD;
      ml of ABO-compatible convalescent plasma. Subjects randomized to placebo plus SMT will&#xD;
      receive a single infusion of 200 to 250 ml of sterile saline solution 0.9%. Infusion will be&#xD;
      administered at baseline, using standard procedures for administration of fresh frozen&#xD;
      plasma. Small adults weighing less than 45 kg will receive one infusion of 5 ml of&#xD;
      convalescent plasma or placebo per kilogram of body weight.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be trained on the completion of symptoms diary card and safety diary card.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participants of the substudy will be drawn an extra tube of blood sample and will be&#xD;
      trained on self-collection of middle turbinate (MT) swabs and saliva, and self-collected&#xD;
      samples will be obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The symptoms and safety diary card will be filled by the participants daily from baseline to&#xD;
      day 14. On follow-up visits on days 3, 7, 14, and 28, all participants will be assessed for&#xD;
      clinical and safety outcomes. These visits will be all by telephone except for the day 7 and&#xD;
      day 28 visits that will be at home and at hospital, respectively, where additionally blood&#xD;
      samples (only on day 7) and nasopharyngeal swabs will be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At day 60 visit, all participants will be assessed by telephone for health-status outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the participants of the substudy, on day 7, an extra tube of blood sample will be&#xD;
      obtained and they will be asked to self-collect MT swabs and saliva. And on day 60, an extra&#xD;
      tube of blood sample will be obtained during an additional home or hospital visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 474 individuals will be randomized (1:1) with an interim analysis after the&#xD;
      first 60 subjects (30 in each arm).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample size will be re-assessed upon interim analysis. Approximately 135 individuals from&#xD;
      selected study sites will be included in the substudy to assess the immune response and the&#xD;
      methods of sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigational product will be administered by IV infusion at baseline. Participants&#xD;
      will continue their standard medical treatment (SMT) for SARS-CoV-2 infection as prescribed&#xD;
      by their regular physician. If applicable, SMT may be modified during the study, depending on&#xD;
      personal requirements, the severity and progression of the disease, and need for&#xD;
      hospitalization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects' participation (from inclusion/baseline visit to the end-of-study visit) will be up&#xD;
      to 60 days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 30, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective, randomized (1:1), double blind study of Convalescent anti-SARS-CoV-2 MBT Plasma (also known as convalescent plasma) plus standard medical treatment (SMT) versus placebo plus SMT in mild or moderate COVID-19 patients who are non-hospitalised. Subjects will be followed up to 60 days after infusion</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospitalization rate (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the therapeutic potential of early administration of convalescent MBT plasma in reducing the rate of hospitalization in non-hospitalised mild or moderate COVID-19 patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SARS-CoV-2 viral load (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the therapeutic potential of early administration of convalescent MBT plasma in reducing SARS-CoV-2 viral load at day 7, measured by quantitative RT-PCR (RT-qPCR) in non-hospitalised mild or moderate COVID-19 patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 WHO Clinical progression scale score (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 60</time_frame>
    <description>Change in COVID-19 World Health Organization WHO Clinical progression scale score to assess hospitalization rate (i.e. who reach a score ≥4).&#xD;
Minimum to maximum scores below:&#xD;
Score 0 (uninfected) - Uninfected; no viral RNA detected&#xD;
Score 1 (ambulatory mild disease) - Asymptomatic; viral RNA detected&#xD;
Score 2 (ambulatory mild disease) - Symptomatic; independent&#xD;
Score 3 (ambulatory mild disease) - Symptomatic; assistance needed&#xD;
Score 4 (hospitalised: moderate disease) - Hospitalised; no oxygen therapy&#xD;
Score 5 (hospitalised: moderate disease) - Hospitalised; oxygen by mask or nasal prongs&#xD;
Score 6 (hospitalised: severe diseases) - Hospitalised; oxygen by NIV or high flow&#xD;
Score 7 (hospitalised: severe diseases) - Intubation Score 8 (hospitalised: severe diseases) - Mechanical ventilation pO2/FiO2 &lt;150 (SpO2/FiO2 &lt;200) or vasopressors&#xD;
and mechanical ventilation, pO2/FiO2 ≥150 or SpO2/FiO2 ≥200</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 symptoms severity score (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 14</time_frame>
    <description>Change in COVID-19 symptoms severity score, assessed with the COVID-19 daily self-score tool (FLU- patient-reported outcome measure (FLU-PRO©) PLUS instrument), certified-Spanish translation. COVID-19 daily self-score tool to assess symptom severity across six body systems: nose, throat, eyes, chest/respiratory, gastrointestinal, and body/systemic. Data on the presence/absence of symptoms, symptom profiles, and change over time.&#xD;
Items 1-27 are Likert scale questions to score symptom severity (rated 0-4): 0=not at all;4=very much. Items 28-32 are also Likert scale questions (rated 0-4) measuring frequency of specific daily symptoms: 0=never or 0 times;4=always or 4 times. Items 33 and 34 measure the presence/absence of COVID-19 specific symptoms: 0=no;1=yes. Total maximum score of FLU-PRO© PLUS 134</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resolution of symptoms (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Time to complete resolution of symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Death rate (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 60</time_frame>
    <description>Death rate</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events (AE) (safety and efficacy) Adverse events (AE) Adverse events (AE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with adverse events (AE) and proportion of grade ≥4 AE, based on the FDA Toxicity Grading Scale for Healthy Adult and Adolescent Volunteers scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ferritin (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Change in inflammatory prognostic markers (ferritin)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prealbumin (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Change in inflammatory prognostic markers (prealbumin)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Interleukin 6 (IL-6) (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Change in inflammatory prognostic markers (Interleukin 6 (IL-6))</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>D-dimer (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Change in inflammatory prognostic markers (D-dimer)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>C reactive protein (CRP) (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Change in inflammatory prognostic markers (C reactive protein (CRP))</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Leukocyte count (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Change in inflammatory prognostic markers (Leukocyte count)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lymphocyte count (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Change in inflammatory prognostic markers (Lymphocyte count)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute neutralization titers against SARS-CoV-2 in plasma (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Intergroup comparison of absolute neutralization titers against SARS-CoV-2 in plasma in a subgroup of 135 participants</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Titers of neutralizing antibodies against SARS-CoV-2 in plasma (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Day 60</time_frame>
    <description>Change in titers of neutralizing antibodies against SARS-CoV-2 in plasma in a subgroup of 135 participants</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SARS-CoV-2 viral load of self-collected middle turbinate (MT) swab and saliva samples compared to nasopharyngeal swabs collected by a healthcare worker (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Agreement and SARS-CoV-2 viral load of self-collected middle turbinate (MT) swab and saliva samples compared to nasopharyngeal swabs collected by a healthcare worker in a subgroup of 135 participants&#xD;
Outcome 18: Secondary Outcome Measure:</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction of SARS-CoV-2 viral load (safety and efficacy)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Reduction of SARS-CoV-2 viral load in nasopharyngeal swabs at day 28 after start of treatment, as determined by RT-qPCR</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">474</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV-2 Infection</condition>
  <condition>Safety and Efficacy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects randomized to convalescent anti-SARS-CoV-2 MBT plasma plus SMT will receive one infusion of 200 to 250 ml of ABO-compatible convalescent plasma obtained from a convalescent donor.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects randomized to placebo plus SMT will receive one infusion of 200 to 250 ml of sterile saline solution 0.9%.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Convalescent anti-SARS-CoV-2 MBT plasma</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects randomized to combination convalescent anti-SARS-CoV-2 MBT plasma plus SMT will undergo an ABO compatibility test and will receive a single infusion of 200 to 250 ml of ABO-compatible convalescent plasma</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control Group</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects randomized to placebo plus SMT will receive one infusion of 200 to 250 ml of sterile saline solution 0.9%.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Sterile saline solution 0.9%</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. 1. Adult male or female individuals of ≥50 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. 2. In women of childbearing potential1, negative pregnancy test at inclusion/baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. 3. Has confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection as determined by PCR or validated antigen rapid&#xD;
             diagnostic test2 from nasopharyngeal swabs ≤5 days prior to inclusion/baseline visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. 4. Symptomatic with mild or moderate COVID-19 with symptoms onset date ≤ 7 days prior&#xD;
             to inclusion/baseline visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. a. Mild COVID-19: Individuals who have any of the common signs and/or symptoms of&#xD;
                  COVID-19 (i.e., fever, cough, sore throat, malaise, headache, muscle pain)&#xD;
                  without shortness of breath, dyspnoea, or abnormal chest imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Moderate COVID-19: Individuals who have evidence of lower respiratory disease by&#xD;
                  clinical assessment or imaging and a saturation of oxygen (SpO2) ≥94% on room air&#xD;
                  at sea level.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. 5. Willing to comply with the requirements of the protocol and available for follow-up&#xD;
             for the planned duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. 6. Has understood the information provided and capable of giving informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1 A woman will be considered of childbearing potential if not permanently sterilized nor&#xD;
        postmenopausal. Permanent sterilization methods include tubal ligation, hysterectomy and&#xD;
        bilateral oophorectomy. Postmenopausal is defined as 12 months with no menses without an&#xD;
        alternative medical cause.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2 PanbioTM COVID-19 Ag Rapid Test (Abbott), STANDARDTM Q COVID-19 Ag Test (Roche) or any&#xD;
        other CE marketed test for SARS-CoV-2 Ag detection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. If female, pregnant, breastfeeding, or planning a pregnancy during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Severe or critical COVID-19:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Severe COVID-19: respiratory frequency &gt;30 breaths per minute, SpO2 &lt;94% on room&#xD;
                  air at sea level, ratio of arterial partial pressure of oxygen to fraction of&#xD;
                  inspired oxygen (PaO2/FiO2) &lt;300 mmHg, or lung infiltrates &gt;50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Critical COVID-19: respiratory failure, septic shock, and/or multiple organ&#xD;
                  dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Current hospital admission for any cause.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of previous confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of significantly abnormal liver function (Child Pugh C).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of chronic kidney disease (CKD) ≥ stage 4, or need of dialysis treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any pre-existing condition that increases risk of thrombosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of allergic reactions to blood or plasma products or methylene blue.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Known IgA deficiency with anti-IgA antibodies.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Medical conditions for which 250 ml of intravenous fluid is considered dangerous&#xD;
             (i.e., decompensated heart failure or renal failure with fluid overload).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Inability to consent and/or comply with study requirements, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Currently participating or planning to participate in any interventional study for the&#xD;
             treatment of COVID-19 or SARS-CoV-2 infection until day 60.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Oriol Mitjà Villar, PhD, MD</last_name>
    <phone>934978849</phone>
    <email>omitja@flsida.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Germans Trias i Pujol Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Badalona</city>
        <state>Barcelona</state>
        <zip>08916</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>ORIOL Mitjà Villar, MD,Phd</last_name>
      <phone>934978849</phone>
      <email>omitja@flsida.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>ORIOL Mitjà Villar, MD,PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 6, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 6, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 6, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Convalescent anti-SARS-CoV-2 MBT Plasma</keyword>
  <keyword>Convalescent plasma</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>Safety</keyword>
  <keyword>Efficacy</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

