<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4995">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02868983</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>WLPS-1409-24372</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02868983</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Integrating Behavioral Health and Primary Care for Comorbid Behavioral and Medical Problems</brief_title>
  <acronym>IBHPC</acronym>
  <official_title>Integrating Behavioral Health and Primary Care for Comorbid Behavioral and Medical Problems</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Vermont</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Arizona State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>State University of New York at Buffalo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Case Western Reserve University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>DARTNet</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Committee for Quality Assurance</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Massachusetts, Worcester</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Vermont</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Behavioral problems are part of many of the chronic diseases that cause the majority of&#xD;
      illness, disability and death. Tobacco, diet, physical inactivity, alcohol, drug abuse,&#xD;
      failure to take treatment, sleep problems, anxiety, depression, and stress are major issues,&#xD;
      especially when chronic medical problems such as heart disease, lung disease, diabetes, or&#xD;
      kidney disease are also present. These behavioral problems can often be helped, but the&#xD;
      current health care system doesn't do a good job of getting the right care to these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Behavioral health includes mental health care, substance abuse care, health behavior change,&#xD;
      and attention to family and other psychological and social factors. Many people with&#xD;
      behavioral health needs present to primary care and may be referred to mental health or&#xD;
      substance abuse specialists, but this method is often unacceptable to patients. Two newer&#xD;
      ways have been proposed for helping these patients. In co-location, a behavioral health&#xD;
      clinician (such as a Psychologist or Social Worker) is located in or near the primary&#xD;
      practice to increase the chance that the patient will make it to treatment. In Integrated&#xD;
      Behavioral Health (IBH), a Behavioral Health Clinician is specially trained to work closely&#xD;
      with the medical provider as a full member of the primary treatment team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The research question is: Does increased integration of evidence-supported behavioral health&#xD;
      and primary care services, compared to simple co-location of providers, improve outcomes? The&#xD;
      key decision affected by the research is at the practice level: whether and how to use&#xD;
      behavioral health services.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators plan to do a randomized, parallel group clustered study of 3,000 subjects&#xD;
      in 40 practices with co-located behavioral health services. Practices randomized to the&#xD;
      active intervention will convert to IBH using a practice improvement method that has helped&#xD;
      in other settings. The investigators will measure the health status of patients in each&#xD;
      practice before and after they start using IBH. The investigators will compare the change in&#xD;
      those outcomes to health status changes of patients in practices who have not yet started&#xD;
      using IBH.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators plan to study adults who have both medical and behavioral problems, and get&#xD;
      their care in Family Medicine clinics, General Internal Medicine practices, and Community&#xD;
      Health Centers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The chronic diseases that drive the majority of mortality, morbidity and cost in America and&#xD;
      around the globe are largely behavioral in origin or management. Tobacco, diet, physical&#xD;
      inactivity, alcohol, substance abuse, non-adherence to treatment, insomnia, anxiety,&#xD;
      depression, and stress are major causes of morbidity, mortality and expense, especially when&#xD;
      chronic medical problems such as heart disease, lung disease, diabetes, or arthritis are also&#xD;
      present. Behavioral problems can often be effectively managed with improved outcomes for&#xD;
      patients, their families and the health care system, but the current health care system is&#xD;
      often unable to provide such care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Behavioral Health includes mental health care, substance abuse care, health behavior change,&#xD;
      and attention to family and other psychosocial factors. Many people with behavioral health&#xD;
      needs present to primary care and may be referred to mental health or substance abuse&#xD;
      specialists, but this method is often unacceptable to patients. Two newer models have been&#xD;
      proposed for helping these patients. In co-location, a behavioral health provider is located&#xD;
      in or near the primary practice to increase the likelihood of successful referral and&#xD;
      treatment initiation. An alternative is Integrated Behavioral Health (IBH) in which a&#xD;
      Behavioral Health Clinician is specially trained to work closely with the medical provider as&#xD;
      a full member of the primary treatment team. Although it is clear that the status quo of&#xD;
      under-diagnosis or inadequate referral and treatment is not acceptable, it is not known which&#xD;
      of the alternative models is best.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The research question is: Does increased integration of evidence-supported behavioral health&#xD;
      and primary care services, compared to simple co-location of providers, improve&#xD;
      patient-centered outcomes in patients with multiple morbidities? The key health decisions&#xD;
      affected by the research are those made at the practice level: whether and how best to&#xD;
      incorporate behavioral health (BH) services. At the patient level, the decision of whether to&#xD;
      seek out or accept offered BH services will be influenced by the manner they are made&#xD;
      available.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 1: Determine if increased integration of evidence-supported behavioral health and primary&#xD;
      care results in better patient-centered outcomes than simple co-location of behavioral&#xD;
      providers without systematic integration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2: Determine if structured improvement process techniques are effective in increasing BH&#xD;
      integration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 3: Explore how contextual factors affect the implementation and patient centeredness of&#xD;
      integrated BH care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 4: Assess the costs of implementing integration in this setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 5: Covid Enhancement: What is the effect of the pandemic upon the effectiveness of IBH?&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a prospective, cluster-randomized, mixed methods comparison of co-location of BH&#xD;
      services vs. IBH in 3,000 subjects in 40 primary care practices around the US.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Usual care (the control comparator) for practices attempting to deliver BH services is&#xD;
      co-location of a BH clinician within or adjacent to the primary care facility, without&#xD;
      increased integration. The active comparator (the intervention) is Integrated Behavioral&#xD;
      Health to support the delivery of protocol supported, stepped, data-driven,&#xD;
      evidence-supported, BH care. In both cases, the expenses (such as salaries for the Behavioral&#xD;
      Health Clinicians) will be paid by the practices. The intervention consists of training for&#xD;
      practice leaders, Behavioral Health Clinicians, primary care providers, and office staff, a&#xD;
      Structured Improvement Process support for practice redesign, and a toolkit of suggested&#xD;
      tactics for implementing BH.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The target patient population is adults with multiple comorbid medical and behavioral&#xD;
      problems receiving services in the target practice settings: Family Medicine clinics, General&#xD;
      Internal Medicine practices, and Community Health Centers. The investigators will enroll 40&#xD;
      practices from around the country to represent a broad spectrum of US primary care sites&#xD;
      including those serving racial and ethnic minority groups, low-income groups, women, seniors,&#xD;
      residents of rural areas, and patients with special health needs, disabilities, multiple&#xD;
      chronic diseases, low health literacy or numeracy and/or limited English proficiency. The&#xD;
      intervention will be directed at the practices and its impact measured in a randomly selected&#xD;
      sample of 75 patients with behavioral health needs from each practice for a total of 3000&#xD;
      patients followed for 2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome is the PROMIS-29, a patient-centered measure of global health and&#xD;
      functioning. Secondary analyses will assess other outcomes important to patients as well&#xD;
      subgroup analyses to allow exploration of what types of patients and practices benefit most&#xD;
      from Integrated Behavioral Health. Aim 2 will study the effect of the intervention on&#xD;
      practice structure and processes. Aim 3 will identify barriers and supports for successful&#xD;
      integration. Aim 4 will assess costs of implementation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The analyses for Aims 1 and 2 will use generalized linear mixed models of patient health&#xD;
      status to perform intention-to-treat analyses as a function of experimental condition&#xD;
      (co-location vs. integration), patient characteristics, and time of measurement, with&#xD;
      multiple measures clustered within patients and patients clustered within practices. The&#xD;
      parameters of interest are the central tendency (mean), statistical significance (P values)&#xD;
      and 95% confidence intervals (CI) of the adjusted change in PROMIS-29 domain score since&#xD;
      before the intervention. Each of the 8 outcome domains in the PROMIS-29 will be modeled&#xD;
      individually as 8 separate hypotheses with adjustment for multiple comparisons. Secondary&#xD;
      outcomes (Communication, Empathy, Adherence, etc.) will use similar models. Aim 3 will use&#xD;
      mixed methods analysis of surveys, focus groups, key informant interviews and other data&#xD;
      sources to explore the relationship between the context of the intervention and the&#xD;
      patient-centeredness of the resultant care. Aim 4 will use a survey of practice managers in a&#xD;
      subset of practices to collect information on staffing changes,staff time, supplies and&#xD;
      capital expenses incurred as part of implementation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS-29 v2</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in general health</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CAHPS 12-Month PCMH Adult Questionnaire 2.0</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of provider communication</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Consultation and Relational Empathy measure</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of provider empathy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Activation Measure-13</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Self-management</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Modified Self-reported Medication-taking Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Medication adherence</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Report of Utilization</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Health care utilization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Restricted Activity Days</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Time lost due to disability</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duke Activity Status Index</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Physical Function</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hgb A1C</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Glycemic control</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>30-day use</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Substance Use disorder &amp; Problem Drinking</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Global Appraisal of Individual Needs - Short Screener</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Substance Use disorder &amp; Problem Drinking</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Systolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Hypertension</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Asthma Symptom Utility Index</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Asthma symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Staff Burnout</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Ancillary study: What is the effect of the IBH-PC intervention on staff burnout?</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Practice Integration Profile</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Aim 2: Self-report by practice staff on degree of integration of behavioral and medical services</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Costs of Implementation</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Aim 4: Staff time, supplies, capital and other expenses</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Centeredness Index</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient-report of patient-centeredness of their Primary Care practice</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Covid-19 practice measures</measure>
    <time_frame>24-32 months</time_frame>
    <description>Impact of Covid-19 at the practice level</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Covid-19 patient measures</measure>
    <time_frame>24-32 months</time_frame>
    <description>Impact of Covid-19 at the patient level</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">4025</enrollment>
  <condition>Arthritis</condition>
  <condition>Asthma</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease</condition>
  <condition>Diabetes</condition>
  <condition>Heart Failure</condition>
  <condition>Hypertension</condition>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Pain</condition>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <condition>Fibromyalgia</condition>
  <condition>Insomnia</condition>
  <condition>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Problem Drinking</condition>
  <condition>Substance Use Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Integration</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The intervention consists of training for practice leaders, BHCs, PCPs, and office staff, a Protocolized Redesign Process support for practice redesign, and a toolkit of suggested tactics for implementing Tasks A through D:&#xD;
A. Identification B. Assessment C. Treatment D. Surveillance</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Co-Location</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>A Behavioral Health Clinician (BHC) such as a psychologist or counselor is housed in or near the primary care practice.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Integration</intervention_name>
    <description>The intervention consists of training for practice leaders, BHCs, PCPs, and office staff, a Protocolized Redesign Process support for practice redesign, and a toolkit of suggested tactics for implementing Tasks A through D:&#xD;
A. Identification B. Assessment C. Treatment D. Surveillance</description>
    <arm_group_label>Integration</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Over 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one target chronic medical condition:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  arthritis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  asthma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronic obstructive lung disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  heart failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  or hypertension.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of a behavioral problem or need:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  anxiety&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronic pain including headache&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  depression&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  fibromyalgia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  insomnia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  irritable bowel syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  problem drinking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  substance use disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  OR persistent use of certain medications used for behavioral concerns:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  antidepressants&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  anxiolytics&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  opioids&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  antineuropathy agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  OR persistent failure to attain physiologic control of a medical problem:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  blood pressure&gt;165 while on 3 or more medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A1C &gt; 9% for 6 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  OR the presence of three or more of the target chronic medical conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not seeking care at a participating practice&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to consent due to cognitive and/or developmental impairment/delays&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Living in the same household as a previously enrolled study participant&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Benjamin Littenberg, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Vermont</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Vermont</name>
      <address>
        <city>Burlington</city>
        <state>Vermont</state>
        <zip>05401</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 9, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 15, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 16, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Vermont</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Benjamin Littenberg</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fibromyalgia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>A complete, cleaned, de-identified copy of the final dataset used in conducting the final analyses will be made available within one year after the completion of the study. It will include a data dictionary with response and missing values defined as well as a complete set of survey instruments (excluding copyright protected material not licensed for transfer). The data will be available as an encrypted Stata data set or comma-separated file. The investigators will not make data from qualitative results available because of the potential for identifying individuals.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>One year after study completion for at least one year.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>All requests will be reviewed by the project's Ancillary Studies committee to ensure scientific validity and lack of overlap with ongoing analyses.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

