<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3066">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04700254</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Diabetes and COVID-19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04700254</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Anxiety, Depression and Eating Attitudes of Diabetes Mellitus Patients During COVID-19 Lockdown in Greece</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of COVID-19 National Lockdown on People With Diabetes Mellitus Regarding Their Anxiety, Depression and Eating Attitudes, in Relation to Adjusted Work and Family Conditions</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Chania General Hospital &quot;St. George&quot;</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>AHEPA University Hospital of Thessaloniki Thessaloniki, Greece</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Chania General Hospital &quot;St. George&quot;</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this observational, cross-sectional study is to evaluate the impact of the second&#xD;
      national COVID-19 lockdown in Greece, regarding the aspects of depression, anxiety and eating&#xD;
      habits, in relation to the adjusted work and family conditions, among diabetes mellitus&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The national Lockdown was an attempt by the Governments around the world to prevent the&#xD;
      spreading of the SARS-CoV-2. This pandemic turned out to be a major public health challenge.&#xD;
      In Greece two national lockdown were imposed in 2020, among other measures, in order to&#xD;
      minimize the spread of the SARS-CoV-2. The national lockdown consists of the temporary&#xD;
      closure of the sports arenas, theaters, cafeterias, restaurants, cinemas, archaeological&#xD;
      sites, schools, churches universities and most of the businesses . The first national&#xD;
      lockdown in Greece was imposed from March 23th to May 4th and the second one took place from&#xD;
      November 6th until now. Such a lockdown that forces the majority of individuals to stay at&#xD;
      home for a prolonged period of time, except the controlled movement of the individuals for&#xD;
      some cases, could expectedly enough have quite an impact on the daily life of people with&#xD;
      diabetes mellitus. Changes to dietary habits, limitation of physical activity, as well as the&#xD;
      psychological aspects like those of depression and anxiety have been detected. The aim of&#xD;
      this study is to evaluate the impact of the second national lockdown in Greece, regarding the&#xD;
      aspects of depression, anxiety and eating habits, in relation to the adjusted work and family&#xD;
      conditions, among diabetes mellitus patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 28, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 11, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 11, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>DASS (Depression)</measure>
    <time_frame>Time Frame: Brief standardised questionnaire not exceeding 8 minutes. Administered during the data collection phase, no intervention involved, this is a cross-sectional observation study.</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum score 0 maximum score 42 of the depression subscale of the DASS questionnaire Higher scores mean a worse outcome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>DASS (Anxiety)</measure>
    <time_frame>Time Frame: Brief standardised questionnaire not exceeding 8 minutes. Administered during the data collection phase, no intervention involved, this is a cross-sectional observation study.</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum score 0 maximum score 42 of the anxiety subscale of the DASS questionnaire Higher scores mean a worse outcome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Eating Attitudes Test (EAT-26)</measure>
    <time_frame>Time Frame: Brief standardised questionnaire not exceeding 8 minutes. Administered during the data collection phase, no intervention involved, this is a cross-sectional observation study.</time_frame>
    <description>Minimun score 0 maximum score 78 Scores greater than 20 indicate a need for further investigation by a qualified professional.&#xD;
Low scores (below 20) can still be consistent with serious eating problems.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <condition>SARS-CoV-2</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>working condition</arm_group_label>
    <description>In order to further explore the differences among working status the data will be categorized into three different groups: suspension of work, employment and unemployment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Family status</arm_group_label>
    <description>In order to xplore the differences among the family status, the data will be categorized into the married and the singles DM patients.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BMI status</arm_group_label>
    <description>In order to further explore BMI scale results, we divided the data obtained from the participants into normal (18.50 - 24.99 kg/m2), overweight (25-29.99 kg/m2) and obese (≥30 kg/m2), according to the international classification of the World Health Organisation (WHO).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>DASS questionnaire</intervention_name>
    <description>The DASS is a 42-item self report instrument designed to measure the three related negative emotional states of depression, anxiety and tension/stress</description>
    <arm_group_label>BMI status</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Family status</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>working condition</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>EAT-26 questionnaire</intervention_name>
    <description>The Eating Attitudes Test (EAT-26), is a self-report 26-item questionnaire of symptoms and concerns characteristic of eating disorders.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BMI status</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Family status</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>working condition</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study population will be recruited from the outpatient diabetes clinic of General&#xD;
        Hospital of Chania and the Diabetes Center of the1st Propaedeutic Department of Internal&#xD;
        Medicine of AHEPA General University Hospital of Thessaloniki in Greece. All participants&#xD;
        prior to completing the survey had to give their informed consent in order to continue.&#xD;
        Participants were free to abandon the survey at any time without any sanctions.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age ≥18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  MODY Diabetes Mellitus&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age &lt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  gestational Diabetes&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>General Hospital of Chania</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chania</city>
        <state>Crete</state>
        <zip>73100</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Aragona M, Rodia C, Bertolotto A, Campi F, Coppelli A, Giannarelli R, Bianchi C, Dardano A, Del Prato S. Type 1 diabetes and COVID-19: The &quot;lockdown effect&quot;. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2020 Dec;170:108468. doi: 10.1016/j.diabres.2020.108468. Epub 2020 Sep 25.</citation>
    <PMID>32987040</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sakelliadis EI, Katsos KD, Zouzia EI, Spiliopoulou CA, Tsiodras S. Impact of Covid-19 lockdown on characteristics of autopsy cases in Greece. Comparison between 2019 and 2020. Forensic Sci Int. 2020 Aug;313:110365. doi: 10.1016/j.forsciint.2020.110365. Epub 2020 Jun 12.</citation>
    <PMID>32563134</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sidor A, Rzymski P. Dietary Choices and Habits during COVID-19 Lockdown: Experience from Poland. Nutrients. 2020 Jun 3;12(6). pii: E1657. doi: 10.3390/nu12061657.</citation>
    <PMID>32503173</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ruiz-Roso MB, Knott-Torcal C, Matilla-Escalante DC, Garcimartín A, Sampedro-Nuñez MA, Dávalos A, Marazuela M. COVID-19 Lockdown and Changes of the Dietary Pattern and Physical Activity Habits in a Cohort of Patients with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus. Nutrients. 2020 Aug 4;12(8). pii: E2327. doi: 10.3390/nu12082327.</citation>
    <PMID>32759636</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Pellegrini M, Ponzo V, Rosato R, Scumaci E, Goitre I, Benso A, Belcastro S, Crespi C, De Michieli F, Ghigo E, Broglio F, Bo S. Changes in Weight and Nutritional Habits in Adults with Obesity during the &quot;Lockdown&quot; Period Caused by the COVID-19 Virus Emergency. Nutrients. 2020 Jul 7;12(7). pii: E2016. doi: 10.3390/nu12072016.</citation>
    <PMID>32645970</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 6, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diabetes Mellitus</keyword>
  <keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Eating attitudes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>contact via e-mail</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

