<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1443">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04733729</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EHA-IDWG</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04733729</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Covid-19 in Hematological Malignancies</brief_title>
  <acronym>EPICOVIDEHA</acronym>
  <official_title>Epidemiology of COVID-19 Infection in Patients With Hematological Malignancies: A European Haematology Association Survey</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sorveglianza Epidemiologica Infezioni Fungine Emopatie Maligne</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>European Hematology Association</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sorveglianza Epidemiologica Infezioni Fungine Emopatie Maligne</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The overall purpose of this project is to better understand the epidemiology of COVID-19 in&#xD;
      patients with hematological malignancies (including hematopoietic stem cell transplant&#xD;
      recipients) in the different European Countries. The results obtained will allow us to better&#xD;
      know the prevalence of this complication in the different categories of patients with&#xD;
      hematological malignancies (HMs). In order to attain the objectives previously described we&#xD;
      will develop a multicentre, international, observational, retrospective and prospective study&#xD;
      of consecutive cases of COVID-19 among HMs. There will be a clinical follow-up of the&#xD;
      patients included in this study to observe the survival rate. Data collected form this study&#xD;
      will be evaluated with a descriptive analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      At the moment, few data on the epidemiology of SARS-CoV-2 infection in patients suffering&#xD;
      from hematological malignancies are available. However, the COVID-19 pandemic presents unique&#xD;
      challenges and opportunities on hematological malignancies. The future trajectory of this&#xD;
      pandemic appears to be growing and hematology communities must continue to prepare for its&#xD;
      spread In this project, we will implement cooperation between all members of the hematology&#xD;
      departments both within the EHA and outside it, in order to evaluate the epidemiological data&#xD;
      on the incidence and outcome in patients with hematological malignancies infected with&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will provide useful information to inform the individualized plan for patients with&#xD;
      hematological malignancies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We aim to evaluate the epidemiology and outcomes of patients with HM infected with&#xD;
      COVID-19,estimate the incidence and type of disease, assess the acute and long-term mortality&#xD;
      rate and estimate the overall mortality rate of cases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a cohort retrospective/prospective survey. In the retrospective phase of the study,&#xD;
      participating centers will retrospectively review episodes of COVID-19 disease that occurred&#xD;
      in patients with hematological malignancies identified at their institutions from February&#xD;
      2020 to December 2020. In the prospective phase of the study, the researchers will include&#xD;
      episodes of COVID-19 disease from the start of the study through December 31, 2021.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study population will need to be over 18 with hematological malignancies and SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      An electronic database with anonymization will be created and available to collect all&#xD;
      information with single access for each participating institution. The data collected will be&#xD;
      demographic data,epidemiological factors, admission information, COVID-19 disease severity,&#xD;
      history of hematological malignancies, disease status with past / current treatments, and 30&#xD;
      days of diagnosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>2 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Epidemiology of COVID-19 infection in patients with hematological malignancies</measure>
    <time_frame>2020 (1 year)</time_frame>
    <description>to evaluate the epidemiology of COVID infection among all hema malignancies patients subgroups</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">3000</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19 Infection in Hematological Malignancies Patients</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        No formal sample size is planned for this study because not only the main hypothesis will&#xD;
        be assessed. However, this is a multicentre cohort study on a high incident disease, with&#xD;
        an elevated expected number of events (death, complications, and co-infections) to be&#xD;
        observed. So more than 2000 patients are expected to be included.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age equal to or greater than 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hematological malignancies (acute leukemias, myelodysplastic syndromes,&#xD;
             myeloproliferative neoplasms, lymphomas, myeloma, chronic myeloprolipherative&#xD;
             disorders) at any stage/status.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active hematological malignancies at any stage/status.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of hematological malignancy (acute leukemias, myelodysplastic syndromes,&#xD;
             myeloproliferative neoplasms, lymphomas, myeloma, chronic myeloprolipherative&#xD;
             disorders) at any stage/status.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SARS-CoV-2 positive test (nasopharyngeal, BAL, fecal), documented by Real-Time Reverse&#xD;
             Transcriptase (RT)-PCR Diagnostic Panels.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hematological diseases, other than hematological malignancies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not tested positive for SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients &quot;off therapy&quot; for more than 5 years&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>livio pagano, Prof</last_name>
    <phone>+390630154180</phone>
    <email>livio.pagano@unicatt.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Jon Salmanton Garcia, Dr</last_name>
    <email>jon.salmanton-garcia@uk-koeln.de</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>ASST-Spedali Civili</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brescia</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Chiara Cattaneo</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AOU Policlinico Federico II</name>
      <address>
        <city>Napoli</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marco Picardi</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fondazione Policlinico A. Gemelli IRCCS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rome</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Livio Pagano</last_name>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Marianna Criscuolo</last_name>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istituto Nazionale Tumori Regina Elena IFO</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rome</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Francesco Marchesi</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Osp. di Circolo-Fondazione Macchi</name>
      <address>
        <city>Varese</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Claudia Maria Basilico</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AOUI Verona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Verona</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gianpaolo Nadali</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://global.stjude.org/en-us/global-covid-19-observatory-and-resource-center-for-childhood-cancer/registry.html</url>
    <description>COVID-19 in pediatric malignancies</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.hematology.org/covid-19/ash-astct-covid-19-and-vaccines</url>
    <description>ASH webpage on COVID in hematology</description>
  </link>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Passamonti F, Cattaneo C, Arcaini L, Bruna R, Cavo M, Merli F, Angelucci E, Krampera M, Cairoli R, Della Porta MG, Fracchiolla N, Ladetto M, Gambacorti Passerini C, Salvini M, Marchetti M, Lemoli R, Molteni A, Busca A, Cuneo A, Romano A, Giuliani N, Galimberti S, Corso A, Morotti A, Falini B, Billio A, Gherlinzoni F, Visani G, Tisi MC, Tafuri A, Tosi P, Lanza F, Massaia M, Turrini M, Ferrara F, Gurrieri C, Vallisa D, Martelli M, Derenzini E, Guarini A, Conconi A, Cuccaro A, Cudillo L, Russo D, Ciambelli F, Scattolin AM, Luppi M, Selleri C, Ortu La Barbera E, Ferrandina C, Di Renzo N, Olivieri A, Bocchia M, Gentile M, Marchesi F, Musto P, Federici AB, Candoni A, Venditti A, Fava C, Pinto A, Galieni P, Rigacci L, Armiento D, Pane F, Oberti M, Zappasodi P, Visco C, Franchi M, Grossi PA, Bertù L, Corrao G, Pagano L, Corradini P; ITA-HEMA-COV Investigators. Clinical characteristics and risk factors associated with COVID-19 severity in patients with haematological malignancies in Italy: a retrospective, multicentre, cohort study. Lancet Haematol. 2020 Oct;7(10):e737-e745. doi: 10.1016/S2352-3026(20)30251-9. Epub 2020 Aug 13.</citation>
    <PMID>32798473</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>García-Suárez J, de la Cruz J, Cedillo Á, Llamas P, Duarte R, Jiménez-Yuste V, Hernández-Rivas JÁ, Gil-Manso R, Kwon M, Sánchez-Godoy P, Martínez-Barranco P, Colás-Lahuerta B, Herrera P, Benito-Parra L, Alegre A, Velasco A, Matilla A, Aláez-Usón MC, Martos-Martínez R, Martínez-Chamorro C, Susana-Quiroz K, Del Campo JF, de la Fuente A, Herráez R, Pascual A, Gómez E, Pérez-Oteyza J, Ruiz E, Alonso A, González-Medina J, Martín-Buitrago LN, Canales M, González-Gascón I, Vicente-Ayuso MC, Valenciano S, Roa MG, Monteliu PE, López-Jiménez J, Escobar CE, Ortiz-Martín J, Diez-Martin JL, Martinez-Lopez J; Asociación Madrileña de Hematología y Hemoterapia (AMHH). Impact of hematologic malignancy and type of cancer therapy on COVID-19 severity and mortality: lessons from a large population-based registry study. J Hematol Oncol. 2020 Oct 8;13(1):133. doi: 10.1186/s13045-020-00970-7.</citation>
    <PMID>33032660</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kuderer NM, Choueiri TK, Shah DP, Shyr Y, Rubinstein SM, Rivera DR, Shete S, Hsu CY, Desai A, de Lima Lopes G Jr, Grivas P, Painter CA, Peters S, Thompson MA, Bakouny Z, Batist G, Bekaii-Saab T, Bilen MA, Bouganim N, Larroya MB, Castellano D, Del Prete SA, Doroshow DB, Egan PC, Elkrief A, Farmakiotis D, Flora D, Galsky MD, Glover MJ, Griffiths EA, Gulati AP, Gupta S, Hafez N, Halfdanarson TR, Hawley JE, Hsu E, Kasi A, Khaki AR, Lemmon CA, Lewis C, Logan B, Masters T, McKay RR, Mesa RA, Morgans AK, Mulcahy MF, Panagiotou OA, Peddi P, Pennell NA, Reynolds K, Rosen LR, Rosovsky R, Salazar M, Schmidt A, Shah SA, Shaya JA, Steinharter J, Stockerl-Goldstein KE, Subbiah S, Vinh DC, Wehbe FH, Weissmann LB, Wu JT, Wulff-Burchfield E, Xie Z, Yeh A, Yu PP, Zhou AY, Zubiri L, Mishra S, Lyman GH, Rini BI, Warner JL; COVID-19 and Cancer Consortium. Clinical impact of COVID-19 on patients with cancer (CCC19): a cohort study. Lancet. 2020 Jun 20;395(10241):1907-1918. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31187-9. Epub 2020 May 28. Erratum in: Lancet. 2020 Sep 12;396(10253):758.</citation>
    <PMID>32473681</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 31, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 31, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Catholic University of the Sacred Heart</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>LIVIO PAGANO</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associated Professor of Hematology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hematologic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

