<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4695">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03651622</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>18-1025</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1DP3DK113358-01</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03651622</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>ACT1ON Phase 2 (SMART Pilot) and Phase 3 (Efficacy Trial Development)</brief_title>
  <acronym>ACT1ON DP3</acronym>
  <official_title>Accelerating Solutions to Optimize Glycemic Control and Weight Management In Young Adults With Type 1 Diabetes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      An initial pilot and feasibility study will be conducted using a Sequential, Multiple&#xD;
      Assignment, Randomized Trial (SMART) design to identify acceptable and effective dietary&#xD;
      strategies to optimize both glycemic control and weight management in young adults with Type&#xD;
      1 diabetes (T1D). This pilot trial will include a ten-and-a-half month behavioral&#xD;
      intervention, with co-primary outcomes of glycemic control (HbA1C and hypoglycemia) and&#xD;
      weight loss. The pilot trial will assess acceptability and adherence to three distinct,&#xD;
      evidence-based dietary approaches designed to address weight management and glycemic control.&#xD;
      Behavioral counseling strategies, use of carbohydrate counting for insulin dosing, and&#xD;
      encouragement of physical activity will be the same across the three dietary approaches.&#xD;
&#xD;
      COVID-19 PROVISIONS: Due to restrictions in place on in-person visits due to COVID-19&#xD;
      precautions, some subjects may remain in the study longer than 10.5 months. As of June 2020,&#xD;
      the study transitioned to a completely virtual format. Those who were due for a measurement&#xD;
      visit during the time that research activities were halted, prior to the approval of the&#xD;
      virtual procedures, remained on the diet they were currently assigned to, supported by&#xD;
      bi-weekly Registered Dietitian (RD) counseling, until they were able to be scheduled for a&#xD;
      virtual visit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Eight-four participants will be randomized in total; 42 at the University of North Carolina&#xD;
      (UNC), 42 at Stanford.&#xD;
&#xD;
      COVID-19 Provisions: Due to impacts of COVID-19, the study was forced to cease recruitment&#xD;
      early. 40 subjects were randomized at UNC and 29 were randomized at Stanford, for a total of&#xD;
      69 subjects across sites.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures (methods):&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three distinct dietary approaches will be tested. Dietary approaches are as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Diet 1: hypocaloric, moderate low fat (30% calories from fat) weight management based on the&#xD;
      Look AHEAD study Diet 2: hypocaloric, low carbohydrate (15-20% calories from carbohydrate,&#xD;
      59-63% as total fat (&lt;10% saturated fat, at least 37% monounsaturated fat, remaining as&#xD;
      polyunsaturated fat) Diet 3: advice to select a healthy Mediterranean dietary pattern with no&#xD;
      caloric restriction&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will complete measurement visits at baseline (-14 days), 3 mos, 6.5 mos, and 10&#xD;
      mos. All visits transitioned to a virtual format as of 6/2020 due to COVID-19 provisions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will complete a total of 23 intervention sessions over an approximately&#xD;
      10-and-a-half month period (Eight longer sessions (teleconference) and 15 telephone&#xD;
      check-ins)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be randomized to one of the three diets for a minimum of a three-and-a-half&#xD;
      month period. Re-randomization is possible following the 3 month and/or 6.5 month measurement&#xD;
      visits. Re-randomization is based on acceptability of diet (self-report), non-severe&#xD;
      hypoglycemic events (self-report), and not achieving significant weight change (defined as&#xD;
      losing at least 2% of body weight from previous study visit), and worsening glycemic control&#xD;
      (increase in Hemoglobin A1c of &gt;/= 0.5% from previous study visit). Re-randomization will&#xD;
      occur after the 14-day CGM wear period that will be initiated at each measurement visit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 12, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This initial pilot and feasibility study uses a Sequential, Multiple Assignment, Randomized Trial (SMART) design to identify acceptable and effective dietary strategies to optimize both glycemic control and weight management. The study will be done at UNC and Stanford. Sequential randomization will occur at 0, 3.5, and 7 months. Following the baseline measurement visit and two week run-in period, participants will be randomized to one of three diets (stratified by site with block size of 4). Using a priori decision rules at 3.5 and 7 months post-initial randomization, those for whom the assigned diet is not acceptable or effective will be re-randomized (or re-assigned if only one diet remains untried). 10.5 months of follow-up time allows for evaluation of the effect of diets on initial weight loss and on early maintenance of initial weight loss. Decision criteria for re-randomization will incorporate clinical outcomes (glycemic control and weight change) and acceptability of the diet.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in weight - Randomization 1</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (-14 Days prior to Randomization 1 Visit), 3 Month (Measurement 2) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>Weight in kilograms will be obtained at measurement visits at the beginning and end of this three-and-a-half month time period.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in weight - Randomization 2</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Month (Measurement 2) Visit, 6.5 Month (Measurement 3) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>Weight in kilograms will be obtained at measurement visits at the beginning and end of this three-and-a-half month time period.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in weight - Randomization 3</measure>
    <time_frame>6.5 Month (Measurement 3) Visit, 10 Month (Measurement 4) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>Weight in kilograms will be obtained at measurement visits at the beginning and end of this three-and-a-half month time period.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in HbA1C - Randomization 1</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (-14 Days prior to Randomization 1 Visit), 3 Month (Measurement 2) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>HbA1c will be measured from a blood sample collected from participants. Blood will be obtained at measurement visits at the beginning and end of this three-and-a-half month time period.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in HbA1C - Randomization 2</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Month (Measurement 2) Visit, 6.5 Month (Measurement 3) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>HbA1c will be measured from a blood sample collected from participants. Blood will be obtained at measurement visits at the beginning and end of this three-and-a-half month time period.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in HbA1C - Randomization 3</measure>
    <time_frame>6.5 Month (Measurement 3) Visit, 10 Month (Measurement 4) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>HbA1c will be measured from a blood sample collected from participants. Blood will be obtained at measurement visits at the beginning and end of this three-and-a-half month time period.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in Percent Time Spent in Hypoglycemia - Randomization 1</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks of wear from Baseline Visit (-14 Days), 2 weeks of wear from 3 Month (Measurement 2) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>Change in the percent of time spent in hypoglycemia during Continuous Glucose Monitor (CGM) wear time will be assessed between the two weeks of wear from CGM insertion at Baseline Visit (-14 days) and the two weeks of wear from the insertion of the CGM at Measurement Visit 2.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in Percent Time Spent in Hypoglycemia - Randomization 2</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks of wear from 3 Month (Measurement 2) Visit, 2 weeks of wear from 6.5 Month (Measurement 3) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>Change in the percent of time spent in hypoglycemia during CGM wear time will be assessed between the two weeks of wear from CGM insertion at Measurement 2 Visit and from CGM insertion at Measurement 3 Visit.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in Percent Time Spent in Hypoglycemia - Randomization 3</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks of wear from 6.5 Month (Measurement 3) Visit, 2 weeks of wear from 10 Month (Measurement 4) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>Change in the percent of time spent in hypoglycemia during CGM wear time will be assessed between the two weeks of wear from CGM insertion at Measurement 3 Visit and from CGM insertion at Measurement 4 Visit.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in percent body fat - Randomization 1</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (-14 Days prior to Randomization 1 Visit), 3 Month (Measurement 2) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>Percent fat mass and percent fat free mass will be measured via a dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA) scan at the beginning and end of this time three-and-a-half-month time period.&#xD;
COVID-19 PROVISIONS: Due to precautions required to prevent the spread of COVID-19, all in-person visits were discontinued as of 3/25/2020. As of this date, DXA scans at both sites were discontinued. Analysis on existing data will continue, but no new DXA data will be collected.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in percent body fat - Randomization 2</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Month (Measurement 2) Visit, 6.5 Month (Measurement 3) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>Percent fat mass and percent fat free mass will be measured via a dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA) scan at the beginning and end of this three-and-a-half-month time period.&#xD;
COVID-19 PROVISIONS: Due to precautions required to prevent the spread of COVID-19, all in-person visits were discontinued as of 3/25/2020. As of this date, DXA scans at both sites were discontinued. Analysis on existing data will continue, but no new DXA data will be collected.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in percent body fat - Randomization 3</measure>
    <time_frame>6.5 Month (Measurement 3) Visit, 10 Month (Measurement 4) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>Percent fat mass and percent fat free mass will be measured via a dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA) scan at the beginning and end of this three-and-a-half-month time period.&#xD;
COVID-19 PROVISIONS: Due to precautions required to prevent the spread of COVID-19, all in-person visits were discontinued as of 3/25/2020. As of this date, DXA scans at both sites were discontinued. Analysis on existing data will continue, but no new DXA data will be collected.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in time spent within target blood glucose range - Randomization 1</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks of wear from 3 Month (Measurement 2) Visit, 2 weeks of wear from 6.5 Month (Measurement 3) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>Change in percent of time spent in a pre-defined range of relative euglycemia (for a person with Type 1 diabetes) during CGM wear time, will be assessed between the two weeks of wear from CGM insertion at Baseline Visit (-14 days) and the two weeks of wear from CGM insertion at Measurement Visit 2.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in time spent within target blood glucose range - Randomization 2</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks of wear from 3 Month (Measurement 2) Visit, 2 weeks of wear from 6.5 Month (Measurement 3) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>Change in percent of time spent in a pre-defined range of relative euglycemia (for a person with Type 1 diabetes) during CGM wear time, will be assessed between the two weeks of wear from CGM insertion at Measurement 2 Visit and from CGM insertion at Measurement 3 Visit.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in time spent within target blood glucose range - Randomization 3</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks of wear from 6.5 Month (Measurement 3) Visit, 2 weeks of wear from 10 Month (Measurement 4) Visit</time_frame>
    <description>Change in percent of time spent in a pre-defined range of relative euglycemia (for a person with Type 1 diabetes) during CGM wear time, will be assessed between the two weeks of wear from CGM insertion at Measurement 3 Visit and from CGM insertion at Measurement 4 Visit.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">69</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</condition>
  <condition>Overweight and Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hypocaloric, low carbohydrate</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Behavioral intervention to include lifestyle counseling on hypocaloric, low carbohydrate diet (15-20% calories from carbohydrate, 59-63% as total fat (&lt;10% saturated fat, at least 37% monounsaturated fat, remaining as polyunsaturated fat). Using a priori decision rules at 3.5 and 7 months post-initial randomization, those for whom the diet assigned is not acceptable or is not effective will be re-randomized.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hypocaloric, moderate low fat</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Behavioral intervention to include lifestyle counseling on hypocaloric, moderate low fat diet (30% calories from fat) weight management based on the Look AHEAD study. Using a priori decision rules at 3.5 and 7 months post-initial randomization, those for whom the diet assigned is not acceptable or is not effective will be re-randomized.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mediterranean, no caloric restriction</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Behavioral intervention to include lifestyle counseling on selecting a healthy Mediterranean diet, no caloric restriction. Using a priori decision rules at 3.5 and 7 months post-initial randomization, those for whom the diet assigned is not acceptable or is not effective will be re-randomized.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hypocaloric, low carbohydrate diet</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be advised on use of a hypocaloric, low carbohydrate diet using lifestyle counseling to include motivational interviewing and problem solving skills training strategies.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hypocaloric, low carbohydrate</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Low carbohydrate diet</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hypocaloric, moderate low fat diet</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be advised on use of a hypocaloric, moderate low fat diet using lifestyle counseling to include motivational interviewing and problem solving skills training strategies.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hypocaloric, moderate low fat</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Low fat diet</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mediterranean diet, no caloric restriction</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be advised on use of a healthy Mediterranean-based eating plan using lifestyle counseling to include motivational interviewing and problem solving skills training strategies.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mediterranean, no caloric restriction</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Mediterranean diet</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals 19-30 years old at enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of Type 1 diabetes for greater than one year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Latest hemoglobin A1c less than 13%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI of 27-39&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with other metabolic disorders, unstable thyroid disease, diagnosed eating&#xD;
             disorder, prohibitive strict dietary restrictions or those with other serious&#xD;
             condition that renders participation inappropriate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who have experience diabetic ketoacidosis (DKA) or severe hypoglycemia&#xD;
             requiring outside assistance in the last 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females who are pregnant, breastfeeding, have delivered a baby in the last 12 months,&#xD;
             or are planning to become pregnant during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals unwilling to follow any of the three study diets&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who monitor blood glucose less than 3 times a day&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Elizabeth Mayer-Davis, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UNC Chapel Hill</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David M Maahs, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Stanford University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Richard Pratley, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Florida Hospital, Translational Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Palo Alto</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94304</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27599</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 27, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 27, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 29, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 27, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 27, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 29, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Type 1 diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>T1D</keyword>
  <keyword>Type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1DM)</keyword>
  <keyword>weight management</keyword>
  <keyword>overweight</keyword>
  <keyword>obese</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

