<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2156">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04646616</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>3R21MD012352-02S1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04646616</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>CRISOL Contigo: a Multi-level Intervention to Reduce the Disproportionate Toll of COVID-19 Among Latino Communities in Philadelphia.</brief_title>
  <acronym>CRISOL Contigo</acronym>
  <official_title>CRISOL: Building Community Resilience and Integrating Efforts to Understand and Address Syndemic Health Conditions Afflicting Young LatinoImmigrants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Drexel University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Drexel University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Latinos have been one of the racial/ethnic groups most impacted by the COVID-19 pandemic, and&#xD;
      evidence of effective strategies to curb the pandemic, reduce disparities, and mitigate its&#xD;
      impact is lacking and very urgent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of this competitive revision is to expand an ongoing academic-community partnership&#xD;
      to adapt, implement, and evaluate a multi-level intervention to mitigate the&#xD;
      multi-dimensional toll of COVID19 among Latino immigrant communities in Philadelphia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This goal of this competitive revision is to expand our original project to adapt, implement&#xD;
      and evaluate a multi-level intervention to mitigate the multi-dimensional toll of COVID19&#xD;
      among Latino immigrant communities in Philadelphia. Evidence of effective strategies to curb&#xD;
      the pandemic, reduce disparities and mitigate its impact is lacking and very urgent. In the&#xD;
      US, Latino immigrants are one of the groups hardest hit by this pandemic, with recent steep&#xD;
      increases in COVID-19 deaths among this group corroborating their continued increased risk of&#xD;
      infection and increased susceptibility. Latino immigrants have long exhibited disparities in&#xD;
      diabetes, obesity and hypertension, factors known to increase COVID-19 related severity, and&#xD;
      also in Substance Abuse, Violence exposure, HIV/AIDS, and MEntal health (SAVAME) syndemic.&#xD;
      These syndemic conditions have been worsened in the context of COVID-19. Latino immigrants&#xD;
      represent a hard-to-reach and marginalized population, with extremely limited access to&#xD;
      adequate health care and safety nets. This group faces many structural barriers, and social&#xD;
      vulnerabilities, that hinder their capacity to access COVID-19 testing and treatment services&#xD;
      and to adhere to public health interventions and measures to decrease the spread of COVID-19.&#xD;
      Latinos often rely on a thin and fragmented network of health and social services&#xD;
      organizations. Intervention to mitigate the impact of COVID-19 on this population will need&#xD;
      to have a broad stakeholder engagement and address a wide range of health determinants.&#xD;
      Peer-driven interventions have been effective for the prevention and control of infectious&#xD;
      diseases such as HIV, STIs among Latino populations. Strengthening the links between&#xD;
      community members and these organizations and promoting inter-organizational coordination to&#xD;
      meet syndemic health, behavioral, economic, and legal needs of Latino communities are&#xD;
      essential elements to mitigate the impact of COVID-19 on this low-resource population. In&#xD;
      direct response to the NOT-MD-20-022/PAR PA-18-935, our ongoing community-academic&#xD;
      partnership proposes to evaluate &quot;CRISOL Contigo,&quot; a multi-level intervention to address the&#xD;
      needs created or magnified by the COVID-19 pandemic among Latino communities in Philadelphia.&#xD;
      CRISOL Contigo includes a peer-driven program and mobilization of Latino-serving&#xD;
      organizations. In aim 1, the investigative team will adapt an ongoing Popular Opinion Leader&#xD;
      (POL) program to address the unique health, social, and economic needs related to COVID-19&#xD;
      and the SAVAME syndemic. In aim 2, the investigative team will assess the efficacy of CRISOL&#xD;
      Contigo to improve COVID-19 related preventive health behaviors and use and access to&#xD;
      COVID-19 related testing and care (co-primary outcomes). In aim 3, the investigative team&#xD;
      will examine the impact of CRISOL Contigo on community assets, interagency collaborations,&#xD;
      and coordination among the Latino-serving organizations in Philadelphia. There are almost 20&#xD;
      million Latino immigrants in the US, and they play a central role in sustaining the vital&#xD;
      parts of the US economy Tailored, multi-level interventions that consider the unique needs of&#xD;
      Latinos are urgently needed to mitigate the impact of this and future outbreaks of COVID-19&#xD;
      on this disadvantaged population.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 6, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Risk of exposure to COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The availability and/or usage of five modifiable risk factors: Use of mask, frequent hand washing, compliance with physical distance, ability to isolate, quarantine if needed, will be combined (added) to create a score.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Access to health care and testing</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The availability and/or access to the following 5 factors: Health insurance, regular health care provider, perception that lack of health insurance, money, or immigration status is a barrier for COVID-19 testing and/or care will be combined to create a score.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SAVAME-related factors and access to SAVAME services</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">800</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Mental Health Issue</condition>
  <condition>Violence</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Community popular opinion leader (POL)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>After successful completion of the new COVID-19 training module, POLs will reach out to members of their social networks to model and diffuse social norms to reduce the risk of COVID-19 infection and transmission, screen for symptoms and counsel regarding COVID-19, SAVAME syndemic factors, and refer at-risk or affected individuals to appropriate community services (e.g. free COVID-19 testing and treatment, mental health services, substance use services, violence prevention, support groups, etc.). As in other POL based interventions and pragmatic trials, POLs be asked to follow up with their community contacts to monitor their situation and provide additional support, but there will be flexibility with the frequency and number of follow up contacts depending on their needs identified and the preferences of the community contact. POLs will be continually supported by the research team via face-to-face biweekly booster sessions (if COVID-19 situation requires it) or by zoom.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Community popular opinion leader (POL) based intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>A community popular opinion leader (POL) based intervention to promote measures to reduce COVID-19 risk, transmission, access to testing and treatment, reduction of the impact of COVID-19, and addressing the Substance Abuse, Violence, HIV/AIDS, and MEntal health (SAVAME) syndemic in the community. POLs will interact within their networks counseling regarding COVID-19 and SAVAME factors. The POLs will refer individuals to appropriate community services. POLs will record basic sociodemographic characteristics of all community contacts, the issue addressed, and their response to it. The first 300 community contacts will be invited to complete a baseline and 3-month follow up surveys (via internet or phone). The content of the surveys includes: 1) COVID-19 related questions (knowledge, impact, symptoms, risk factors, access to testing and care, acceptability contact tracing, vaccine) 2) Biological risk factors, 3) Social determinants of health, 4) SAVAME outcomes and access to services.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Community popular opinion leader (POL)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-reported Latino or Hispanic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Living in Philadelphia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Drexel University Dornsife School of Public Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ana Martinez-Donate, PhD</last_name>
      <email>apm78@drexel.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Mariana Lazo, PhD</last_name>
      <email>ml3629@drexel.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ana Martinez-Donate, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mariana Lazo, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Amy Carroll-Scott, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Seth L. Welles, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 30, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 30, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 2, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Drexel University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ana Martinez Donate</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Community Health and Prevention</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Latino health</keyword>
  <keyword>Immigrant health</keyword>
  <keyword>Syndemic</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

