<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1088">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04632615</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Sleep&amp;Covid19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04632615</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sleep Behaviour in Athletes During Home Confinement Due to the Covid-19 Outbreak</brief_title>
  <acronym>Sleep&amp;Covid19</acronym>
  <official_title>Sleep Behaviour in Athletes During Home Confinement Due to the Covid-19 Outbreak</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istituto Ortopedico Galeazzi</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istituto Ortopedico Galeazzi</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      It is becoming increasingly evident that sleep plays an essential role for human health, and&#xD;
      it represents an important biophysiological variable for athletes' well-being and recovery.&#xD;
      The International Olympic Committee recently highlighted the importance of obtaining&#xD;
      sufficient sleep volume and quality among athletes, but acute sleep deprivation is not&#xD;
      unusual. Several factors, both endogenous and exogenous, are able to negatively influence&#xD;
      sleep in athletes: body temperature, altitude, chronotype, training volume, anxiety, westward&#xD;
      and eastward travels, and many others.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since December 2019, when a new coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) was originally revealed by an&#xD;
      ophthalmologist in Wuhan (Hubei province, China), a related severe acute respiratory syndrome&#xD;
      - namely COVID-19 - has been spreading at a pandemic rate, putting global health systems&#xD;
      under unprecedent pressure. Italy, as the first Western country tremendously hit by this&#xD;
      disease outbreak, has become the iconic resilient outpost under international policymakers'&#xD;
      attention. When initial clusters were identified, restrictive actions to curb isolated&#xD;
      upsurges of infection were taken by the health region system of Lombardy, thereafter, were&#xD;
      extended to all northern Italy and to the entire country. From February 21, when the first&#xD;
      Italian COVID-19 case was diagnosed in southern Lombardy, to March 22, when Italian's&#xD;
      government restrictions to contain the pandemic were extended, prohibiting all non-essential&#xD;
      business activities and banning all movements of people nationwide, the country faced an&#xD;
      unchartered scenario, from several standpoints, along with the psychosocial one.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inevitably, the Covid-19 outbreak has largely influenced the daily life of athletes too.&#xD;
      Therefore, the primary aim of this study was to examine the differences in athletes' sleep&#xD;
      quality, quantity and training volumes during the social confinement due to the virus&#xD;
      outbreak. For this purpose, a survey will be used. This variables will be evaluated in 3&#xD;
      different time frames: 1) May 2020; 2) September 2020; 3) January 2021.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 22, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Subjective sleep quality</measure>
    <time_frame>This outcome will be evaluated in 3 different time frames: 1) May 2020; 2) September 2020; 3) January 2021.</time_frame>
    <description>Subjective sleep quality of athletes will be evaluated by the completion of a survey.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Subjective sleep quantity</measure>
    <time_frame>This outcome will be evaluated in 3 different time frames: 1) May 2020; 2) September 2020; 3) January 2021.</time_frame>
    <description>Subjective sleep quantity of athletes will be evaluated by the completion of a survey.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Training volume</measure>
    <time_frame>This outcome will be evaluated in 3 different time frames: 1) May 2020; 2) September 2020; 3) January 2021.</time_frame>
    <description>Athletes' weekly training volume will be evaluated by the completion of a survey.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">230</enrollment>
  <condition>Sleep</condition>
  <condition>Athlete</condition>
  <condition>Training</condition>
  <condition>Exercise</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Isolation, Social</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Italian elite athletes will be recruited.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  male or female gender.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age between 18 and 40 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  elite athletes (competing at national or international level).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no cognitive impairments.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  at least 6 years of practice of a specific sport discipline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  affiliated to CONI (Comitato Olimpico Nazionale Italiano).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age under 18 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  part-time workers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  injury or any clinical condition affecting training routines (and sleep).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnant women.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jacopo Antonino Vitale, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0039 0266214980</phone>
    <email>jacopo.vitale@grupposandonato.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Stefano Borghi, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>0039 0266214980</phone>
    <email>stefano.borghi@grupposandonato.it</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IRCCS Istituto Ortopedico Galeazzi</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milan</city>
        <zip>20161</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jacopo Antonino Vitale, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>0039 0266214939</phone>
      <email>jacopo.vitale@grupposandonato.it</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vitale KC, Owens R, Hopkins SR, Malhotra A. Sleep Hygiene for Optimizing Recovery in Athletes: Review and Recommendations. Int J Sports Med. 2019 Aug;40(8):535-543. doi: 10.1055/a-0905-3103. Epub 2019 Jul 9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31288293</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vitale JA, Weydahl A. Chronotype, Physical Activity, and Sport Performance: A Systematic Review. Sports Med. 2017 Sep;47(9):1859-1868. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0741-z. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28493061</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vitale JA, Roveda E, Montaruli A, Galasso L, Weydahl A, Caumo A, Carandente F. Chronotype influences activity circadian rhythm and sleep: differences in sleep quality between weekdays and weekend. Chronobiol Int. 2015 Apr;32(3):405-15. doi: 10.3109/07420528.2014.986273. Epub 2014 Dec 3.</citation>
    <PMID>25469597</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vitale JA, La Torre A, Banfi G, Bonato M. Acute sleep hygiene strategy improves objective sleep latency following a late-evening soccer-specific training session: A randomized controlled trial. J Sports Sci. 2019 Dec;37(23):2711-2719. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2019.1661938. Epub 2019 Sep 6.</citation>
    <PMID>31608830</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vitale JA, Banfi G, Sias M, La Torre A. Athletes' rest-activity circadian rhythm differs in accordance with the sport discipline. Chronobiol Int. 2019 Apr;36(4):578-586. doi: 10.1080/07420528.2019.1569673. Epub 2019 Feb 14.</citation>
    <PMID>30760036</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Pillay L, Janse van Rensburg DCC, Jansen van Rensburg A, Ramagole DA, Holtzhausen L, Dijkstra HP, Cronje T. Nowhere to hide: The significant impact of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) measures on elite and semi-elite South African athletes. J Sci Med Sport. 2020 Jul;23(7):670-679. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2020.05.016. Epub 2020 May 19.</citation>
    <PMID>32448749</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Di Renzo L, Gualtieri P, Pivari F, Soldati L, Attinà A, Cinelli G, Leggeri C, Caparello G, Barrea L, Scerbo F, Esposito E, De Lorenzo A. Eating habits and lifestyle changes during COVID-19 lockdown: an Italian survey. J Transl Med. 2020 Jun 8;18(1):229. doi: 10.1186/s12967-020-02399-5.</citation>
    <PMID>32513197</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Håkansson A, Jönsson C, Kenttä G. Psychological Distress and Problem Gambling in Elite Athletes during COVID-19 Restrictions-A Web Survey in Top Leagues of Three Sports during the Pandemic. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020 Sep 14;17(18). pii: E6693. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17186693.</citation>
    <PMID>32937978</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

