<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4660">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04604977</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Be-Home-Kids</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04604977</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Feasibility and Effectiveness of Home-behavioral Program for Adolescents With Migraine</brief_title>
  <acronym>Be-Home-Kids</acronym>
  <official_title>Feasibility and Effectiveness of Home-behavioral Program for Adolescents With Chronic Migraine and High Frequency Migraine Without Aura After the Covid-19 Emergency</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fondazione I.R.C.C.S. Istituto Neurologico Carlo Besta</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fondazione I.R.C.C.S. Istituto Neurologico Carlo Besta</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chronic Migraine and Migraine without aura at high frequency are disabling conditions also in&#xD;
      adolescence age (2% of adolescents report chronic migraine) Common pharmacological treatments&#xD;
      are often inadequate. It has been reported that clinical results can be improved when&#xD;
      traditional therapies are combined with behavioral approaches in particular mindfulness, that&#xD;
      help patients to become more conscious about their symptoms and able to manage pain without&#xD;
      medication. Generally, according to standard clinical practice, young patients (12-17 yrs&#xD;
      old) treated by mindfulness practice come to the hospital to practice mindfulness in small&#xD;
      groups of patients for 6 weekly 45 minutes sessions. As the emergency situation due to the&#xD;
      Corona-virus pandemic phenomenon in Italy, patients missed the possibility to come for the&#xD;
      regular practice to the hospital: for this reason the investigators propose a small pilot&#xD;
      study to enforce the use of technology for patients so that they can continue to be followed&#xD;
      during their therapeutic process. This preliminary study will be conducted on 25 patients&#xD;
      They will be trained to practice mindfulness daily by a standard session of 12 minutes on&#xD;
      their smartphone recorded by the expert who generally manage their sessions at the hospital.&#xD;
      Also a weekly video-session will be performed to evaluate the clinical condition, to practice&#xD;
      guided mindfulness sessions and to encourage to use strategies for pain management . This&#xD;
      modality will allow patients to continue their therapeutic process and to be followed&#xD;
      regularly during the one year after treatment. Follow up sessions are planned every three&#xD;
      months: these meetings at the hospital will be face-to-face with every patient to check the&#xD;
      clinical condition by the patient's diary. Last follow up one year after treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background and significance Chronic Migraine is not so unusual in pediatric and adolescent&#xD;
      age and is about 2% of population in adolescent age. The literature of the last decades&#xD;
      confirmed the need to taking care of these patients susceptible to develop medication&#xD;
      overuse. There are different pharmacological treatments for migraine in young patients but no&#xD;
      one of them has specific indication for this category of patients and their efficacy reaches&#xD;
      30/40% leaving many side effects difficult to manage at this age. The feasibility and the&#xD;
      effectiveness of behavioral approaches has been already documented in clinical experiences of&#xD;
      the last decades: these approaches revealed efficacy in long-term studies and with control&#xD;
      groups and they are totally free of unpleasant effects. Mindfulness practice is one of the&#xD;
      most recent behavioral approaches that combined with Acceptance Commitment Therapy offer a&#xD;
      suitable and adequate treatment for adolescent patients. These approaches make patients more&#xD;
      conscious about their problem and able to learn techniques alternative to medications for&#xD;
      managing pain.. Mindfulness and other behavioral therapies have done significant results in&#xD;
      terms of clinical improvement for these patients and they are well accepted with a high&#xD;
      adherence level. This preliminary study will be performed considering that the Covid-19&#xD;
      emergency reduced significantly the possibility for patients to follow sessions at the&#xD;
      hospital and to move among the different Italian regions and the investigators organized a&#xD;
      program with education and support by mindfulness , delivered by video sessions. According to&#xD;
      the protocols at the Headache Center of the Besta Institute in Milan Italy, patients of this&#xD;
      category are followed with a standardized program including: education and support for&#xD;
      behavioral measures, behavioral sessions, by mindfulness, once per week for 45 minutes for 6&#xD;
      weeks which usually delivered in groups of 4 - 8 patients. This approach may be particularly&#xD;
      useful in helping patients to obtain a better outcome. All the above discussed considerations&#xD;
      are even more relevant in this emergency situation due to the Corona-virus pandemic&#xD;
      phenomenon in Italy, with its consequences on mobility of patients and clinical practice. In&#xD;
      order to promote different modalities to respond to the needs of patients suffering from this&#xD;
      disabling condition during the emergency, exercise-based telemedicine and smartphone&#xD;
      applications seem very appropriate, as they have been recently tested in the management of&#xD;
      chronic pain conditions. This preliminary study will be performed considering that the&#xD;
      Covid-19 emergency reduced significantly the mobility of patients, particularly those living&#xD;
      in other Italian regions than Lombardy, and in view of providing an effective and somewhat&#xD;
      innovative treatment program for this class of patients. The proposed treatment intervention&#xD;
      is based on investigators' experience, and on published reports, but it specifically includes&#xD;
      a home based program, visits performed as Video calls, and educational and support strategies&#xD;
      aimed to develop skills to reduce clinical symptoms and to cope with pain by a standardized&#xD;
      behavioural approach based on mindfulness -&#xD;
&#xD;
      which will be delivered mainly by telemedicine and smartphone applications . The aim of this&#xD;
      pilot study is to assess the feasibility and the effectiveness at long-term on relevant&#xD;
      outcomes of a specific protocol, designed to be appropriate during the emergency situation&#xD;
      due to COVID-19 epidemic, by an approach that is alternative to current practice,&#xD;
      particularly as far as reducing face-to-face hospital visits taking advantage of facilities&#xD;
      offered by new technologies, besides including innovative and emerging treatment choices,&#xD;
      namely a behavioural approach base on mindfulness&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>reduction of headache days</measure>
    <time_frame>at 6 months and 12 months follow-up compared with baseline (Headache Daily Diary)</time_frame>
    <description>reduction of at least 50 % of headache days during the treatment period</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>reduction of headache days until last follow up</measure>
    <time_frame>at 12 months from withdrawal program (assessed by Daily Diary Card)</time_frame>
    <description>reduction of at least 50 % of headache days until the last follow up (assessed by Daily Diary Card)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>disability score</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months - 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>decrease in disability score (Ped MIDAS) - (score of PedMIDAS: 0-10 little disability; 11-30 mild disability; 31-50 moderate disability; more than 50 severe disability)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>catastrophising attitude</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months - 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>decrease in catastrophising attitude (PCS) - Score more than 30 : clinically relevant level of catastrophising</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>depression symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months - 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>decrease in depression symptoms (Kovacs) - score =15 mild depression; 15-20 moderate depression; more than 25 severe depression);</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>trait-state anxiety symptoms (STAI X1-X2)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months - 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>decrease in trait-state anxiety symptoms (STAI X1-X2) - score more than 40 anxiety symptoms abnormal</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">25</enrollment>
  <condition>Headaches Chronic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mindfulness by Smartphone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>an approach that is alternative to current practice, particularly as far as reducing face-to-face hospital visits taking advantage of facilities offered by new technologies, besides including innovative and emerging treatment choices, namely a behavioural approach base on mindfulness</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mindfulness</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients are followed with a standardized program including: education and support for behavioral measures, behavioral sessions, by mindfulness, once per week for 45 minutes for 6 weeks which usually delivered in groups of 4 - 8 patients.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mindfulness by Smartphone</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  clinical diagnosis of Chronic Migraine or High Frequency Migraine without aura&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  co-existent severe medical or psychiatric illnesses, documented by specific previous&#xD;
             diagnoses&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  seizures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  use of opioids&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  participation to other projects with behavioral approaches in the last&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fondazione IRCCS Istituto Neurologico C. Besta, Neuroalgology Unit</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milano</city>
        <zip>20133</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Licia Grazzi, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+39022394</phone>
      <phone_ext>2366</phone_ext>
      <email>licia.grazzi@istituto-besta.it</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Renato Mantegazza, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+39022394</phone>
      <phone_ext>2321</phone_ext>
      <email>crc@istituto-besta.it</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Licia Grazzi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 25, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 25, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Headache</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

