<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3357">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04604145</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FWH20200198H</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04604145</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of Self-Collected Saliva Samples Without Viral Transport Media for SARS-CoV-2 Testing Via RT-PCR</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Self-Collected Saliva Samples Without Viral Transport Media for SARS-CoV-2 Testing Via RT-PCR</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>David Grant U.S. Air Force Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>David Grant U.S. Air Force Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a study that will attempt to validate the process for detecting SARS-CoV-2 (COVID19)&#xD;
      using self-collected saliva as the specimen. We will compare self-collected saliva samples&#xD;
      and healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples (Nasal swabs) to see if the&#xD;
      self-collected saliva samples are similar in terms of diagnostic accuracy. We will be&#xD;
      performing this testing at the site where patients regularly go for COVID19 testing. There&#xD;
      will be minimal risk of harm as consenting patients will only have to provide a small amount&#xD;
      of saliva into a tube.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a descriptive study that will attempt to validate the procedure for detecting&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 on the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler PCR system using self-collected saliva as the&#xD;
      specimen. We will calculate the percent agreement and the 95% confidence intervals (ie,&#xD;
      overall agreement, percent positive agreement, and percent negative agreement) between&#xD;
      self-collected saliva samples (evaluated on the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler PCR system) and&#xD;
      healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples (evaluated on either the BioFire®&#xD;
      FilmArray® Torch® system or the Cepheid® GeneXpert® as the gold standard). Participants&#xD;
      without usable results for both the saliva and nasopharyngeal methods will not be included in&#xD;
      the analyses. Currently, DGMC uses both FDA Emergency Use Authorization systems&#xD;
      interchangeably to test for SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Using human volunteers to obtain positive and negative nasopharyngeal and saliva specimens of&#xD;
      SARS-COV-2, this is a test validation study. It uses the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler PCR system&#xD;
      to compare the test performance of saliva as a specimen to the standard nasopharyngeal&#xD;
      specimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This protocol utilizes a convenience sample of patients presenting to the DGMC COVID&#xD;
      screening tent. Therefore, the study population will be comprised of active duty, DoD&#xD;
      dependents, retirees, DoD civilian, and contract personnel presenting to the COVID screening&#xD;
      test under their own accord for testing out of concern for exposure to, or symptoms related&#xD;
      to, COVID. This study will enroll up to 600 individuals. From that group, the results of&#xD;
      approximately 30 COVID-19 positive (by NP test) participants and a sequentially selected&#xD;
      sample of approximately 30 COVID-19 negative (by NP test) participants will be utilized to&#xD;
      compare NP swab to saliva sample results. The remaining samples collected will be stored for&#xD;
      future testing if authorized.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment and enrollment efforts for this study will be conducted at the DGMC COVID&#xD;
      Screening Tent as patients present for COVID-19 testing. COVID Tent personnel will provide an&#xD;
      informational flyer to all patients. Those interested in enrolling will be given an informed&#xD;
      consent and HIPAA Authorization form by COVID tent personnel to read, then instructed to&#xD;
      contact the study team using a cell phone. Study personnel will discuss the study, review&#xD;
      both documents with the patient, and answer questions to their satisfaction over the phone.&#xD;
      To minimize contact with potentially infected patients, study team members will not enter the&#xD;
      COVID tent. A study team member will meet outdoors nearby the COVID tent with the prospective&#xD;
      study participant to sign original versions of both documents to allow access to the medical&#xD;
      record in order to retrieve NP COVID-19 test results, and obtain the saliva sample. The study&#xD;
      team member will wear a lab coat, gloves, and mask. To minimize contact with potentially&#xD;
      infected participants, study team members will not enter the COVID tent but will primarily&#xD;
      discuss the study details, informed consent and HIPAA authorization by phone. The COVID tent&#xD;
      staff will provide patients who are interested in participating in the study with a flyer&#xD;
      stating the study team contact information and will provide interested patients with a copy&#xD;
      of the study informed consent document and HIPAA Authorization form. Interested participants&#xD;
      will be directed by the COVID tent staff to immediately call the study team. The participant&#xD;
      will keep the copy of the informed consent document provided by the COVID tent staff. At the&#xD;
      conclusion of the phone conversation regarding study details, a study team member will meet&#xD;
      outdoors with the prospective study participant. The study team member will wear a lab coat,&#xD;
      gloves, and mask. Specifically, the participants will be consented to allow their medical&#xD;
      record to be accessed in order to view their NP COVID-19 test results. At the same time&#xD;
      Demographic information (age, ethnicity, race and gender) will be captured and study staff&#xD;
      will ensure the participant has not smoked, eaten or drank anything for the previous 10&#xD;
      minutes. Then participants will be given a biohazard bag with a label (with a 6-numerical&#xD;
      code) and 25 ml plastic specimen tube without transport medium inside, then asked to fill it&#xD;
      with approximately 2mL of saliva. There will be a marking on the tube to ensure a sufficient&#xD;
      sample is collected. The participant will be instructed to close the lid, place the label on&#xD;
      the outside of the tube, then put the tube into the biohazard bag. The participant will then&#xD;
      place the bagged specimen inside a second biohazard bag held by the study team member. The&#xD;
      study team member will place the double-bagged saliva sample into the study cooler with ice.&#xD;
      The study team member will record the code on the consent and HIPAA authorization forms. All&#xD;
      items will then be transported to the CIF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will utilize the result of the standard of care NP COVID-19 test performed in the&#xD;
      COVID tent for comparison to the saliva sample obtained for research. Approximately 30&#xD;
      positive and 30 negative NP results from participants will be tested for COVID-19, since the&#xD;
      FDA advises this number for validation of new COVID-19 testing methodologies. The saliva&#xD;
      testing results and NP testing results will then be compared.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study goal is to obtain saliva samples from participants representing 30 positive and 30&#xD;
      negative NP COVID-19 samples, however, the participants will not be evenly distributed. More&#xD;
      negative than positive participants will be recruited. We will seek approval to enroll 600&#xD;
      participants. The results are expected to be 94% COVID-19 negative and 6% COVID-19 positive&#xD;
      based on the prevalence for Solano County in August 2020. It is therefore anticipated that&#xD;
      approximately 500 participants would need to be enrolled to obtain 30 positive results. To&#xD;
      balance the many negative test results from participants, the samples will be collected from&#xD;
      every participant, but only saliva samples from every 10th participant with a negative result&#xD;
      will be utilized in the study. Once 30 positive results and 30 negative results are&#xD;
      recruited, the study will be closed to recruitment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Testing will be performed on saliva samples using reverse-transcription polymerase chain&#xD;
      reaction (RTPCR). Natural and/or synthetic RNA will be acquired for use as a positive&#xD;
      control. RT-PCR will target the N-gene of SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Within 5 minutes of sample collection the sample will be put on ice for stabilization. A&#xD;
           cooler with ice will be taken to the outdoor location where the participant provides the&#xD;
           sample. The sample will be put in a biohazard bag, then immediately be placed into the&#xD;
           cooler for transport to the CIF Microbiology Laboratory.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Ribonucleic Acid (RNA) Extraction - Within 12 hours, RNA will be extracted from the&#xD;
           specimens using Invitrogen PureLink ® Viral RNA/DNA Mini Kit (Life Technologies). 3.&#xD;
           Sample RNA will be stored at -80oC until used.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. SuperScriptTM III One-Step RT-PCR with PlatinumTM Taq (Life Technologies) will be used&#xD;
           for detection and amplification of viral RNA present in specimens using Eppendorf&#xD;
           Mastercyler Pro S (Eppendorf). Seven primer pairs that are based from CDC and other&#xD;
           publications will be used 18-19. Three from the envelope protein gene and four from the&#xD;
           nucleocapsid protein gene.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Frozen samples will be tested and run in batches.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. PCR products will be evaluated with gel electrophoresis using the Mini-Protein® Tetra&#xD;
           Cell (Bio-Rad).&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Sequencing - All PCR reactions that produce acceptable amplicons will be stored at -80oC&#xD;
           for possible sequencing confirmation using the ABI 3130 (Life Technologies).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once testing is completed, specimens will be aliquoted and stored at -80C. All specimens in&#xD;
      the not to be ran cohort will also be aliquoted and stored at -80C.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent positive agreement between self-collected saliva samples and healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples</measure>
    <time_frame>within 1 day of SARS-CoV-2 testing</time_frame>
    <description>Percent positive agreement between self-collected saliva samples (evaluated on the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler PCR system) and healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples (evaluated on either the BioFire® FilmArray® Torch® system or the Cepheid® GeneXpert® as the gold standard).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent negative agreement between self-collected saliva samples and healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples</measure>
    <time_frame>within 1 day of SARS-CoV-2 testing</time_frame>
    <description>Percent negative agreement between self-collected saliva samples (evaluated on the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler PCR system) and healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples (evaluated on either the BioFire® FilmArray® Torch® system or the Cepheid® GeneXpert® as the gold standard).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent overall agreement between self-collected saliva samples and healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples</measure>
    <time_frame>within 1 day of SARS-CoV-2 testing</time_frame>
    <description>Percent overall agreement between self-collected saliva samples (evaluated on the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler PCR system) and healthcare-worker collected nasopharyngeal samples (evaluated on either the BioFire® FilmArray® Torch® system or the Cepheid® GeneXpert® as the gold standard).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV Infection</condition>
  <condition>Polymerase Chain Reaction</condition>
  <condition>Laboratory Testing</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Positive NP results</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>SARS-CoV-2 testing on self-collected saliva specimens, associated with a positive NP result, using the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) system</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>10th Negative NP results</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>SARS-CoV-2 testing on self-collected saliva specimens, associated with a 10th negative NP result, using the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) system</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SARS-CoV-2 testing on the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler PCR system using self-collected saliva as the specimen</intervention_name>
    <description>Obtain self-collected saliva sample, perform SARS-CoV-2 testing using the Eppendorf Thermal Cycler Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) system on every sample associated with a positive or 10th negative NP sample, then compare saliva results to healthcare worker collected NP sample results evaluated on either the BioFire® FilmArray® Torch® system or the Cepheid® GeneXpert® (gold standard).</description>
    <arm_group_label>10th Negative NP results</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Positive NP results</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients who present to the DGMC COVID tent to receive ambulatory SARS-COV-2&#xD;
             testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to provide a saliva sample on the same day, during study availability hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to a cellular phone so they are able to contact the study team after their&#xD;
             COVID tent nasopharyngeal SARS-COV-2 test is collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unwilling to wait or have eaten, drank or smoked within the past 10 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unwilling or unable to provide 2 mls of saliva&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are not DoD beneficiaries who are unwilling to provide department of&#xD;
             defense identification number for billing purposes.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Benjamin D Ramos, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>David Grant Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Antoinette McNeary-Garvin, MSN</last_name>
    <phone>707-423-7733</phone>
    <email>antoinette.m.mcneary-garvin.ctr@mail.mil</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fakheran O, Dehghannejad M, Khademi A. Saliva as a diagnostic specimen for detection of SARS-CoV-2 in suspected patients: a scoping review. Infect Dis Poverty. 2020 Jul 22;9(1):100. doi: 10.1186/s40249-020-00728-w.</citation>
    <PMID>32698862</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Azzi L, Carcano G, Gianfagna F, Grossi P, Gasperina DD, Genoni A, Fasano M, Sessa F, Tettamanti L, Carinci F, Maurino V, Rossi A, Tagliabue A, Baj A. Saliva is a reliable tool to detect SARS-CoV-2. J Infect. 2020 Jul;81(1):e45-e50. doi: 10.1016/j.jinf.2020.04.005. Epub 2020 Apr 14.</citation>
    <PMID>32298676</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>McCormick-Baw C, Morgan K, Gaffney D, Cazares Y, Jaworski K, Byrd A, Molberg K, Cavuoti D. Saliva as an Alternate Specimen Source for Detection of SARS-CoV-2 in Symptomatic Patients Using Cepheid Xpert Xpress SARS-CoV-2. J Clin Microbiol. 2020 Jul 23;58(8). pii: e01109-20. doi: 10.1128/JCM.01109-20. Print 2020 Jul 23.</citation>
    <PMID>32414838</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Takeuchi Y, Furuchi M, Kamimoto A, Honda K, Matsumura H, Kobayashi R. Saliva-based PCR tests for SARS-CoV-2 detection. J Oral Sci. 2020;62(3):350-351. doi: 10.2334/josnusd.20-0267.</citation>
    <PMID>32581183</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>David Grant U.S. Air Force Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Benjamin Ramos</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Maj, USAF, MC</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

