<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3612">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04532372</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20291</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2020-05746</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>20291</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>P30CA033572</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04532372</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Leflunomide for the Treatment of Severe COVID-19 in Patients With a Concurrent Malignancy</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1/2 Trial of Leflunomide for the Treatment of Severe COVID-19 in Patients With a Concurrent Malignancy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>City of Hope Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>City of Hope Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase I/II trial investigates the best dose and side effects of leflunomide and how well&#xD;
      it works in treating patients with COVID-19 and a past or present cancer. Leflunomide has&#xD;
      been used since the 1990s as a treatment for rheumatoid arthritis. Experiments done with&#xD;
      human cells that were given severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), the&#xD;
      virus causing COVID-19, showed that leflunomide was able to reduce the ability of the virus&#xD;
      to make copies of itself. The coronavirus uses ribonucleic acid (RNA), a very long molecule&#xD;
      that contains genetic information that is like a blueprint for making more copies of itself.&#xD;
      Leflunomide inhibits the formation of RNA. The information gained from this study may help&#xD;
      researchers to learn whether leflunomide is safe for use in treating patients with COVID-19,&#xD;
      and whether it is potentially effective against the disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Assess the safety and tolerability of leflunomide when combined with coronavirus disease&#xD;
      2019 (COVID-19) standard of care (SOC) by evaluation of toxicities including: type,&#xD;
      frequency, severity, attribution and duration. (Phase 1) II. Determine the maximum tolerated&#xD;
      dose (MTD) and recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) of leflunomide when given in combination with&#xD;
      SOC. (Phase 1) III. Evaluate the clinical activity of leflunomide plus SOC (Arm 1) and&#xD;
      placebo plus SOC (Arm 2) on the basis of clinical improvement (response) rate in each&#xD;
      treatment arm, as assessed by a 7-point ordinal scale. (Phase 2/Pilot) IV. Evaluate the&#xD;
      safety and tolerability of leflunomide plus SOC (Arm 1) and placebo plus SOC (Arm2). (Phase&#xD;
      2/Pilot)&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES I. Evaluate the clinical activity of leflunomide when combined with SOC&#xD;
      on the basis of clinical improvement (response) rate. (Phase 1)&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. Estimate the following (Phase 1 and Phase 2):&#xD;
&#xD;
      IIa.Time to clinical improvement (days). IIb. Time to peripheral capillary oxygen saturation&#xD;
      (SpO2) &gt; 93% on room air (days).&#xD;
&#xD;
      IIc. Time to first negative SARS-CoV-2 polymerase chain reaction (PCR) (days). IId. Duration&#xD;
      of oxygen therapy (days). IIe. Duration of hospitalization (days). IIf. Duration of&#xD;
      mechanical ventilation. IIg. All cause mortality at day 28. III. Measure trough plasma&#xD;
      concentrations of the active metabolite teriflunomide on days 1 through 14, day 21, and day&#xD;
      28, and evaluate relationships between teriflunomide levels and pharmacodynamic biomarkers&#xD;
      (e.g., viral load, cytokines), response, safety, and concomitant medications. (Phase 1 and&#xD;
      Phase 2)&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVES&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Investigate inflammatory response by measuring changes before and after leflunomide&#xD;
      treatment in:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ia. Circulating cytokines (e.g., IL-6, IL-8, TNF-alpha, IL-12, interferons [IFNs] and&#xD;
      granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor ([GM-CSF]).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ib. Immune effector cell phenotype associated with monocyte, T cell, and natural killer (NK)&#xD;
      cell activation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. Assess the kinetics of viral replication through serial measurements of viral load by&#xD;
      nasopharyngeal swab and tracheal aspirates (if on ventilator and can be safely obtained).&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: This is a phase I dose-escalation study, followed by a phase II study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PHASE I: Patients receive leflunomide orally (PO) once daily (QD) on days 1-14. Patients may&#xD;
      receive SOC drugs in addition to leflunomide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PHASE II: Patients are randomized to 1 of 2 arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM I (LEFLUNOMIDE + SOC): Patients receive leflunomide PO QD on days 1-14. Cycles repeat&#xD;
      every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients also&#xD;
      receive SOC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM II (PLACEBO + SOC): Patients receive placebo PO QD on days 1-14. Cycles repeat every 28&#xD;
      days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients also receive&#xD;
      SOC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up for 90 days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 7, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 18, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 18, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Phase I single-arm dose-escalation design followed by a phase II randomized two-arm design</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of toxicity, graded according to the NCI CTCAE version 5</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days after completion of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Observed toxicities will be summarized in terms of type (organ affected or laboratory determination), severity, time of onset, duration, probable association with the study of treatment and reversibility or outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose (MTD) (Phase 1)</measure>
    <time_frame>During the 28-day treatment period</time_frame>
    <description>Will be based on the assessment of dose limiting toxicity (DLT).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical activity (Response)(Phase 2)</measure>
    <time_frame>At day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as a &gt;= 2-point change in clinical status from day 1 on a 7-point ordinal scale.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Clinical activity (Response)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as time from start of treatment to &gt;= 2 point change in clinical status on a 7 point ordinal scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as time from start of treatment to death from any cause</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oxygen Saturation improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Time from start of treatment to peripheral capillary oxygen saturation (SpO2) &gt; 93% on room air</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SARS-CoV-2 resolution</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Time from start of treatment to first negative severe acute respiratory syndrome Coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) result assessed by polymerase chain reaction (PCR).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Hospitalized within first 90 days following start of treatment assessed as yes/no</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mechanical Ventilation required</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Indication as to whether or not the subject required mechanical ventilation at any time from start of treatment through 90 days post; assessed as yes/no</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mechanical Ventilation duration</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>If the subject required mechanical ventilation, indicate number of days for first occurrence; measured in days.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vital status (alive/dead)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Vital status will be reported as yes/no</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vital status (cause of death)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>If vital status is dead, cause of death will be documented.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Viral load</measure>
    <time_frame>from start of treatment to 90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by PCR assay of viral ribonucleic acid (RNA) from nasopharyngeal swab.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Hematopoietic and Lymphoid Cell Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Symptomatic COVID-19 Infection Laboratory-Confirmed</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I (leflunomide, SOC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive leflunomide PO QD on days 1-14. Patients may receive SOC drugs in addition to leflunomide.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II Arm I (leflunomide, SOC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive leflunomide PO QD on days 1-14. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients also receive SOC.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II Arm II (placebo, SOC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive placebo PO QD on days 1-14. Cycles repeat every 28 days in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Patients also receive SOC.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Best Practice</intervention_name>
    <description>Receive standard of care drugs</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I (leflunomide, SOC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II Arm I (leflunomide, SOC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II Arm II (placebo, SOC)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>standard of care</other_name>
    <other_name>standard therapy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Leflunomide</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase I (leflunomide, SOC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II Arm I (leflunomide, SOC)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Arava</other_name>
    <other_name>SU101</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo Administration</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II Arm I (leflunomide, SOC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Phase II Arm II (placebo, SOC)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented informed consent of the participant and/or legally authorized&#xD;
             representative. Assent, when appropriate, will be obtained per institutional&#xD;
             guidelines. Cognitively impaired subjects may enroll in the phase 2 portion if&#xD;
             adequate psychosocial support is provided&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SARS-CoV-2 infection confirmed by a PCR-based test within 4 days prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 disease baseline severity of Severe according to FDA guidance, as defined by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Symptoms suggestive of severe systemic illness with COVID-19, which could include&#xD;
                  any symptom of fever, cough, sore throat, malaise, headache, muscle pain,&#xD;
                  gastrointestinal symptoms, or shortness of breath at rest, or respiratory&#xD;
                  distress&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clinical signs indicative of severe systemic illness with COVID-19, such as&#xD;
                  respiratory rate &gt;= 30 per minute, heart rate &gt;= 125 per minute, SpO2 =&lt; 93% on&#xD;
                  room air at sea level or partial pressure of oxygen (PaO2)/the fraction of&#xD;
                  inspired oxygen (FiO2) &lt; 300&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active cancer requiring systemic treatment within the last 2 years. Subjects should&#xD;
             not have received the following therapies for their malignancy within the indicated&#xD;
             time frames:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Local radiation therapy within 2 weeks prior to enrollment. If the involved field&#xD;
                  is small (single nodal area), 7 days prior to enrollment is allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chemotherapy within 2 weeks prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Major surgery within 2 weeks prior to treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Autologous hematopoietic stem cell infusion within 12 weeks prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Antibody therapy, chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cells, or other biologic&#xD;
                  therapies within 12 weeks prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell infusion within 16 weeks prior to enrollment&#xD;
                  These time frames should be considered the minimum allowed interval and may be&#xD;
                  longer per the judgment of the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adverse events related to prior cancer therapy must have recovered to =&lt; grade 1 or to&#xD;
             baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must be able to forgo systemic cancer therapy for ~39 days (14 days&#xD;
             treatment/placebo + 14 days monitoring + ~ 11 days cholestyramine)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil cunt (ANC) &gt;= 500/mm^3 (to be performed within 4 days prior to day&#xD;
             1 of protocol therapy unless otherwise stated)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &gt;= 25,000/mm^3 (to be performed within 4 days prior to day 1 of protocol&#xD;
             therapy unless otherwise stated)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) (unless has Gilbert's disease)&#xD;
             (to be performed within 4 days prior to day 1 of protocol therapy unless otherwise&#xD;
             stated)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) =&lt; 2 x ULN (to be performed within 4 days prior to&#xD;
             day 1 of protocol therapy unless otherwise stated)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) =&lt; 2 x ULN (to be performed within 4 days prior to day&#xD;
             1 of protocol therapy unless otherwise stated)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine clearance of &gt;= 60 mL/min per 24-hour urine test or the Cockcroft-Gault&#xD;
             formula (to be performed within 4 days prior to day 1 of protocol therapy unless&#xD;
             otherwise stated)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agreement by females and males of childbearing potential* to use an effective method&#xD;
             of birth control or abstain from heterosexual activity for the course of the study&#xD;
             until teriflunomide levels are verified to be less than 0.02 mg/L (0.02 ug/mL) for&#xD;
             patients given leflunomide, or until unblinding occurs for those given placebo.&#xD;
             Contraception should also be used for the duration of administration of SOC drugs&#xD;
             during this study for the duration recommended in the prescribing information.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Childbearing potential is defined as not being surgically sterilized (men and&#xD;
                  women) or have not been free from menses for &gt; 1 year (women only)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), defined by at least one of the&#xD;
             following: endotracheal intubation and mechanical ventilation, oxygen delivered by&#xD;
             high-flow nasal cannula (heated, humidified, oxygen delivered via reinforced nasal&#xD;
             cannula at flow rates &gt; 20 L/min with fraction of delivered oxygen &gt;= 0.5),&#xD;
             noninvasive positive pressure ventilation, extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO),&#xD;
             or clinical diagnosis of respiratory failure (i.e., clinical need for one of the&#xD;
             preceding therapies, but preceding therapies not able to be administered in setting of&#xD;
             resource limitation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Shock (defined by systolic blood pressure &lt; 90 mm Hg, or diastolic blood pressure &lt; 60&#xD;
             mm Hg or requiring vasopressors)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of multi-organ dysfunction/failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-existing acute or chronic liver disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with indolent local malignancies or pre-malignant conditions including but&#xD;
             not limited to:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Smoldering multiple myeloma or monoclonal gammopathy of undetermined significance&#xD;
                  (MGUS)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Carcinoma in situ of the cervix or breast&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Incidental histologic finding of prostate cancer (T1a or T1b using the tumor node&#xD;
                  metastasis [TNM] clinical staging system) or prostate cancer that is curative&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to study agent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Secondary bacterial, fungal, or viral infections that are not adequately controlled&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other condition that would, in the Investigator's judgment, contraindicate the&#xD;
             patient's participation in the clinical study due to safety concerns with clinical&#xD;
             study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-positive: CD4+ T cell count &lt; 200&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive for tuberculosis antigen (e.g., T-spot test)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of liver metastasis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gastrointestinal (GI) malignancies associated with malabsorption and inability to take&#xD;
             cholestyramine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Steroids, except for low-dose replacement or high-dose for management of acute&#xD;
             symptoms such as ARDS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any new immunosuppressive medication in the 4 weeks prior to enrollment, excepting&#xD;
             agents used for treatment of COVID-19 that may also have immunosuppressive properties&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medications that are CYP1A2 inducers, CYP2C8 inhibitors, and vitamin K antagonists, if&#xD;
             these medications are not approved by the investigator. CYP1A2 inducers, CYP2C8&#xD;
             inhibitors, and vitamin K antagonists that are approved by the investigator are&#xD;
             allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent administration of live vaccines&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prospective participants who, in the opinion of the investigator, may not be able to&#xD;
             comply with all study procedures (including compliance issues related to&#xD;
             feasibility/logistics)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sanjeet S Dadwal</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>City of Hope Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>City of Hope Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Duarte</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sanjeet S. Dadwal</last_name>
      <phone>626-218-8202</phone>
      <email>sdadwal@coh.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sanjeet S. Dadwal</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 27, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Laboratory Infection</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leflunomide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

