<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4853">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04061785</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>J4B190723</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04061785</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Impact of Skills Acquired Through Judo Training on Risk Factors for Falling in Elderly Men and Women</brief_title>
  <acronym>J4BE</acronym>
  <official_title>Impact of Skills Acquired Through Judo Training on Risk Factors for Falling in Elderly Men and Women</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dalarna University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Swedish Judo Federation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sormland County Council, Sweden</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dalarna University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Falls and injuries from falls are one of the greatest threats to public health. One of the&#xD;
      risk factors for accidental falls is a low self-efficacy regarding the perceived capability&#xD;
      to perform activities without the risk of falling. Judo is a sport which include &quot;break fall&quot;&#xD;
      strategies where falls with correct landing strategies and rolling movements are in focus in&#xD;
      order to avoid injuries. The investigators expect that a judo inspired training&#xD;
      (Judo4Balance) will strengthen self-efficacy when it comes to the perceived ability to&#xD;
      perform daily tasks without the risk of falling and thereby reduce the risk for falling. Judo&#xD;
      based training also includes a well rounded training with focus on strength, balance,&#xD;
      explosive power, stamina, proprioception and flexibility. These physical qualities are of&#xD;
      importance for reducing the risk of falling. Therefore the investigators' hypothesis is that&#xD;
      a 12 week long judo inspired training program could be a suitable tool for reducing falls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the project is to evaluate and document whether a 12 week standardized judo&#xD;
      inspired exercise program including both the training of above mentioned physical qualities&#xD;
      as well as &quot;break fall&quot; techniques can influence the risk of falling as well as reduce the&#xD;
      negative consequences such as injuries from an accidental fall.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the evaluation of the 12 week intervention a validated test battery will be used which&#xD;
      gives an indication of the risk for falling in the near future. Furthermore, a specifically&#xD;
      designed &quot;Falling Competence&quot; Test has been developed by the investigators' M. Tonoknogi and&#xD;
      K Strömqvist Bååthe to measure &quot;break fall&quot; technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If it can be proven that the intervention group reaches the expected positive results then&#xD;
      the control group will be offered the same type of Judo4Balance training after that they have&#xD;
      been participating as a randomized control group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is evidence that the risk of falling can be reduced by training, nevertheless judo&#xD;
      based training has not to the investigator's knowledge been scientifically investigated among&#xD;
      the elderly with the aim of reducing the risk of falls. Neither has it been studied if this&#xD;
      type of group training is motivational for continuing physical activity after the&#xD;
      intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to the Covid-19 pandemic and the Swedish Govt. recommendations (in mid March 2020) to&#xD;
      avoid group exercises for older adults (to decrease the risk of the spread of Covid-19) the 9&#xD;
      exercise intervention groups where put on hold/paused after 6-9 weeks into the exercise&#xD;
      program.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We applied for and received an approval for an addition to the ethical approval (2019-03048),&#xD;
      in order to follow up with the study subject after 6-7 months of self-quarantine in the homes&#xD;
      with a self rating of: Fall EfficacyScale (FES), EQ3D as well as questionnaire about the&#xD;
      subjects perceived physical and mental health. These questionnaires were sent by post.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to evaluate and document whether a 12 week standardized judo based&#xD;
      exercise program which include both the physical as well as &quot;break fall&quot; technique can&#xD;
      influence the risk of falling as well as reduce the negative consequences of an accidental&#xD;
      fall.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Questions asked:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Can a 12 week standardized judo based exercise program improve the physical status with&#xD;
           regard to risks for falls among elderly ?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Can a 12 week standardized judo based exercise program improve the balance among&#xD;
           elderly.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Can a 12 week standardized judo based exercise program improve the self-efficacy among&#xD;
           elderly so they can perform their daily chores without the fear of falling&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Can a 12 week standardized judo based exercise program increase the level of physical&#xD;
           activity among elderly?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Can a 12 week standardized judo based exercise program decrease the risk of falls among&#xD;
           elderly?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Is there a difference between men and women regarding the effects on fall rate and on&#xD;
           physical factors influencing fall injuries after the completed sixteen week standardized&#xD;
           judo based training program&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intervention study is conducted in cooperation with the Swedish Judo Federation who has&#xD;
      developed as standardized exercise program for the elderly named Judo4Balance. The&#xD;
      recommended training is well in accordance with the physical exercises that are intrinsic to&#xD;
      a judo practice. Therefore the hypothesis is that a 12 week long judo inspired training&#xD;
      program could be a suitable tool for reducing falls and injuries from falls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the evaluation of the 12 week intervention a validated test battery which gives an&#xD;
      indication of the risk of falling for an individual in the near future will be used. There&#xD;
      will also be a specifically designed Falling Competence test to measure the effectiveness of&#xD;
      the &quot;break fall&quot; training.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Furthermore a follow up of the participants' physical status and break fall technique as well&#xD;
      as their level of physical activity will be conducted with the same set of tests two years&#xD;
      after the first intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The persons included in the study will where it is possible be followed up regarding fall&#xD;
      incidents for several years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If it can be proven that the intervention group reaches the expected positive results such as&#xD;
      improved physical status, higher self-efficacy with regards to falling and increased&#xD;
      technical &quot;break fall&quot; skills then the control group will be offered the same type of&#xD;
      Judo4Balance training one or two terms after that they have been participating as a&#xD;
      randomized control group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is evidence that the risk of falling can be reduced by training, nevertheless judo&#xD;
      based training has not to the investigators's knowledge been scientifically investigated&#xD;
      among the elderly with the aim of reducing the risk of falls. Neither has it been studied if&#xD;
      this type of group training is motivational for continuing physical activity after the&#xD;
      intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A randomized control study consisting of an intervention study and a control group that is&#xD;
      carried out between 2019 - 2021 at different places throughout Sweden.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment will be made at local health centers, judo clubs, and through cooperation with&#xD;
      clubs and activity centers for retired people.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Older adults interested in the intervention will be informed about the study both in written&#xD;
      form and verbally and are signing a consent form. Independent research assistants perform the&#xD;
      tests. After the tests are made the participants in the study will be randomized into one of&#xD;
      two groups. One group will participate in the standardized judo inspired 12 week practice and&#xD;
      one group will not participate. Practical tests and questionnaires are repeated again after&#xD;
      the 12 weeks regardless of group affiliation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The judo based exercise program (Judo4Balance)is divided into three blocks and is lead by&#xD;
      experienced and especially trained judo teachers during 12 - 16 weeks (12 -16 sessions)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Block 1) Good technique during break fall training and strength training, accustom the body&#xD;
      to regular training, find the right level of training for the group, build up load resistance&#xD;
      in muscles, tendons and bones, challenge the balance through new movements that are not used&#xD;
      during daily living activities such as getting down and up from the floor, flexibility&#xD;
      training för stiff joints such as neck, upper back and shoulders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Block 2) Improve &quot;break fall&quot; technique and strength exercises, increase the load in the&#xD;
      strength exercises, challenge the balance and coordination, increase the range of motion,&#xD;
      introduce &quot;power&quot; exercises when the participants master the technique, continue to build up&#xD;
      the load resistance in muscles, tendons, and bones.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Block 3) Train the skill of explosive power during strength exercises and break falls.&#xD;
      Challenge the balance with increased complexity and difficulty.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before the intervention and after the 12 week of standardized judo training program and for&#xD;
      the control group no specific program given the following tests will be made:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participants fill in a health declaration and a questionnaire that besides demographic&#xD;
      information also includes questions about motivation through two questions regarding&#xD;
      readiness for change and self-efficacy regarding performing daily tasks without fear of&#xD;
      falling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Modified Falls-Efficacy Scale - Swedish version (FES(S)) is a validated questionnaire which&#xD;
      measures the self confidence in performing an activity without falling on an 11 grade scale,&#xD;
      where 0 is not sure at all and 10 is totally confident when performing the activity without&#xD;
      falling. The participant rates oneself based on 13 described activities where maximum score&#xD;
      is 130 points.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The physical status with relevance to fall risk will be evaluated using the modified Short&#xD;
      Physical Performance Battery (SPPB) where each physical function, balance, strength and&#xD;
      walking is evaluated on a 4 grade scale. The test has a max points of 12 and has proven to&#xD;
      have a good reliability according to test - retest.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Mini-Balance Evaluation System Test (Mini-BESTest) is used to measure balance. The test&#xD;
      includes 14 different tasks on 4 sub-scales. All tasks are graded from 0 to 2 points, with a&#xD;
      total maximum score of 28 points. The test has high reported test-retest reliability and&#xD;
      inter rater reliability.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since there are no previously known tests for the evaluation of judo &quot;break fall&quot; techniques&#xD;
      for adults or elderly people, two tests have been designed by Professor M. Tonkonogi &amp;&#xD;
      Research Assistant K. Strömqvist Bååthe at Dalarna University in cooperation with The Swedish&#xD;
      Judo Federation to test the acquired skills for falling backwards as well as falling forwards&#xD;
      in a safe setting, with progressive difficulty. The judo fall techniques are graded on a 0-4&#xD;
      scale. Where 0 represents the minimum score and 4 the maximum score. Four judo puzzle mats&#xD;
      are needed for the exercises.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Frändin/Grimby Activity Scale will be used to measure the level of physical activity. The&#xD;
      scales range from 1 to 6, with 1 representing 'hardly active at all' and 6 representing&#xD;
      'intensive exercise regularly and several times per week.' The scale has been evaluated and&#xD;
      shown to have good validity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      European Quality of Life Questionnaire (EQ-5D or EQ3D) will be used to measure quality of&#xD;
      life in five dimensions, hygiene, main activities, pain, worry and mood/depression.&#xD;
      Furthermore an evaluation of the participant's health status is made on a vertical analogue&#xD;
      scale (VAS) graded 0-100. EQ-5D is proven to have a good test-retest reliability and a high&#xD;
      validity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The pattern of movement will be analyzed before, and after the intervention with the help of&#xD;
      &quot;surface - electromyograph electrodes placed bilaterally on the participant's back muscles&#xD;
      and accelerometer based mobility sensors placed on the perons's wrists, ankles and chest.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Change over time will be calculated with paired non-parametric statistics for nominal and&#xD;
      original data. Change over time for interval and quote data is calculated with parametric&#xD;
      statistics. Uni-variate data and multivariate data analysis will be used for calculating&#xD;
      change and outcome variables between the groups over time A p-Value &lt;0.05 is needed to show a&#xD;
      significant difference.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 30, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 21, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in &quot;break fall&quot; competence/skills</measure>
    <time_frame>Before and after 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Two tests by the name &quot;Judo4Balance - Falling Competence Test&quot; - Backward and forward have been developed to test skills for falling backwards as well as falling forwards in a safe setting, with progressive difficulty. The judo &quot;break-fall technique is graded on a 0-4 scale where 0 represents the minimum score and 4 represents the maximum score for each test .&#xD;
Minimum Score = 0 = The subject is unable to lay down on the mat and lift the head from the surface and then stand up independently.&#xD;
Maximum Score = 4 = the subejct is able to fall backwards or forwards from a standing up position without any dangerous maneuver&#xD;
* A dangerous maneuver is an action which could during a fall increase the risk of injury such as: not holding up the head, not lowering the center of gravity, putting out hand or elbow etc. If a dangerous maneuver is spotted the test will be stopped.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Participants' Falls Efficacy after 12 weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>Before and after 12 weeks of training (+addition after 7 months of self quarantine)</time_frame>
    <description>The change in participants' falls-efficacy will be measured through - Modified Falls-Efficacy Scale - Swedish version (FES(S))A validated questionnaire which measures the self confidence in performing an activity without falling on an 11 grade scale, where 0 is not sure at all and 10 is totally confident when performing the activity without falling.The subject rates oneself based on 13 described activities where maximum score is 130 points.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Physical Function, Balance, Strength and Walking</measure>
    <time_frame>Before and after 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>This outcome will be measured through: Short Physical Performance Battery (SPPB)A test where each physical function, balance, strength and walking is evaluated on a 4 grade scale. The test has a max points of 12 and has proven to have a good test-retest reliability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Balance</measure>
    <time_frame>Before and after 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The Mini-Balance Evaluation Test (Mini-BEST)- Is a test used to measure balance. The test includes 14 different tasks on 4 subscales. All tasks are graded from 0 to 2 points, with a total maximum score of 28 points. The test has high reported test-retest reliability and interrater reliability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in level of Physical Activity</measure>
    <time_frame>Before and after 12 weeks (+addition after 7 months of self quarantine after Covid pandemic)</time_frame>
    <description>Frändin/Grimby Activity Scale will be used to measure the level of physical activity. The scales range from 1 to 6, with 1 representing 'hardly active at all' and 6 representing 'intensive exercise regularly and several times per week.' The scale has been evaluated and shown to have good validity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>Before and after 12 weeks (+addition after 7 months of self quarantine during Covid pandemic)</time_frame>
    <description>European quality of life questionnaire (EQ-3D) will be used to measure quality of life in five dimensions, hygiene, main activities, pain, worry and mood/depression. Furthermore an evaluation of the persons health status is made on a vertical analogue s (VAS) graded 0-100. EQ-5D is proven to have a good test-retest reliability and a high validity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Identification of depressive symptoms after quarantine the last 2 weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>(addition after 7 months of self quarantine)</time_frame>
    <description>WHO 5</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in movement patterns when having fear of falling</measure>
    <time_frame>Before and after 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Optional on some of the subjects.&#xD;
The participant's pattern of movement will be analyzed before, and after the intervention with the help of &quot;surface-Electromyography (EMG) electrodes place bilaterally on the back muscles and accelerometer based mobility sensors placed on the participants's wrists, ankles and chest.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Aging Problems</condition>
  <condition>Frailty</condition>
  <condition>Fall Injury</condition>
  <condition>Accidental Fall</condition>
  <condition>Fear of Falling</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Participants in 12 week Judo Inspired Exercise program</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The subjects will participate in a 12 week judo inspired training program (45 minute sessions once a week) with the specific aim to increase physical qualities related to falls and injuries during falls.&#xD;
The subjects will be tested before and after the 12 week period</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The subjects will go about their normal life for 12 weeks without any intervention. The persons will be tested before and after the 12 week period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Judo4Balance - 12 week judo inspired exercise program</intervention_name>
    <description>12 weeks x 45 minute judo inspired exercise in lead by instructor in a group setting.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Participants in 12 week Judo Inspired Exercise program</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  55 - 110 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Understanding oral and written communication in Swedish&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cannot sit up without support&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not being able to hold up neck when laying on the floor or rolling backwards.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aortic aneurysm,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Angina pectoris&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cataract operation within the last 6 months&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>110 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michail Tonkonogi, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Dalarna University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Michail Tonkonogi, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+46 708 205 435</phone>
    <email>mtn@du.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Karin Strömqvist Bååthe</last_name>
    <phone>+46 730 89 61 62</phone>
    <email>ksb@du.se</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dalarna University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Falun</city>
        <state>Dalarna</state>
        <zip>SE-79188</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michail Tonkonogi, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>0708-206435</phone>
      <email>mtn@du.se</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Karin S Bååthe</last_name>
      <phone>0730896162</phone>
      <email>ksb@du.se</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://judo.se/fallprevention/falltrygghet-for-aldre/</url>
    <description>Description and film from the Swedish Judo4Balance exercise program for elderly</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Timsina LR, Willetts JL, Brennan MJ, Marucci-Wellman H, Lombardi DA, Courtney TK, Verma SK. Circumstances of fall-related injuries by age and gender among community-dwelling adults in the United States. PLoS One. 2017 May 4;12(5):e0176561. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0176561. eCollection 2017.</citation>
    <PMID>28472065</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hellström K, Sandström M, Heideken Wågert P, et al. Fall-Related Self-efficacy in Instrumental Activities of Daily Living is Associated with Falls in Older Community-Living People. Phys Occup Ther Geriatr. 2013;31(2):128-139.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Franchini, E, Kiss, MA, Sterkowicz S. Physical fitness and anthropometrical differences between elite and non elite judo players. Biol Sport 2005; 22: 315-328, 2005.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Guralnik JM, Simonsick EM, Ferrucci L, Glynn RJ, Berkman LF, Blazer DG, Scherr PA, Wallace RB. A short physical performance battery assessing lower extremity function: association with self-reported disability and prediction of mortality and nursing home admission. J Gerontol. 1994 Mar;49(2):M85-94.</citation>
    <PMID>8126356</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Frändin K, Grimby G. Assessment of physical activity, fitness and performance in 76-year-olds. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 1994; 4(1), 41</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hellström K, Lindmark B, Wahlberg B, Fugl-Meyer AR. Self-efficacy in relation to impairments and activities of daily living disability in elderly patients with stroke: a prospective investigation. J Rehabil Med. 2003 Sep;35(5):202-7.</citation>
    <PMID>14582550</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Franchignoni F, Horak F, Godi M, Nardone A, Giordano A. Using psychometric techniques to improve the Balance Evaluation Systems Test: the mini-BESTest. J Rehabil Med. 2010 Apr;42(4):323-31. doi: 10.2340/16501977-0537.</citation>
    <PMID>20461334</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 14, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 16, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 20, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Dalarna University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michail Tonkonogi</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Fall prevention</keyword>
  <keyword>Physical training</keyword>
  <keyword>judo</keyword>
  <keyword>exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>Judo4Balance</keyword>
  <keyword>Break falls</keyword>
  <keyword>Preventive Exercise</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Frailty</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

