<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="777">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04612972</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UPeruanaCH</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04612972</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy, Safety and Immunogenicity of Inactivated SARS-CoV-2 Vaccines (Vero Cell) in Healthy Adult Population In Peru</brief_title>
  <acronym>Cov-Peru</acronym>
  <official_title>Ensayo Clínico de Fase III, Aleatorio, Doble Ciego y Controlado Con Placebo Paralelo, Para Evaluar la Seguridad y la Eficacia Protectora de la Vacuna Inactivada Contra el SARS-CoV-2 en la Población Sana de 18 años o más, en Perú</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universidad Peruana Cayetano Heredia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National University of San Marcos, Peru</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universidad Peruana Cayetano Heredia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a multicenter, randomized, double blind, parallel placebo controlled, phase 3&#xD;
      clinical trial to evaluate the protective efficacy, safety and immunogenicity of inactivated&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 vaccines in healthy population 18 years old and above.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      WIBP:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The inactivated SARS CoV 2 Vaccine (Vero cell) is prepared by inoculating Verda Reno cells&#xD;
      (Vero cell) with SARS CoV 2 WIV04 strain, culturing, harvesting, inactivating, clarifying,&#xD;
      concentrating, second inactivating, purifying and adding aluminum hydroxide adjuvant BIBP:&#xD;
      The inactivated SARS CoV 2 Vaccine (Vero cell) is prepared by inoculating Verda Reno cells&#xD;
      (Vero cell) with SARS CoV 2 HB02 strain, culturing, harvesting, inactivating, clarifying,&#xD;
      concentrating, purifying and adding aluminum hydroxide adjuvant. After vaccination, the body&#xD;
      can produce immune response to prevent diseases caused by SARS CoV 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objective To evaluate the protective efficacy of inactivated SARS CoV 2 Vaccine (Vero&#xD;
      Cell) after full course of immunization in preventing diseases caused by the SARS CoV 2 in&#xD;
      healthy subjects aged 18 years old and above.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 10, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary endpoint</measure>
    <time_frame>One year beginning on day 14 after the second dose of immunization</time_frame>
    <description>Protective effect against COVID 19, after 14 days following the full course of vaccination among healthy population aged 18 years old and above. Comparison of the proportions of confirmed Covid-19 cases in the two vaccine groups and the placebo group. All confirmed cases are all confirmed by DSMB blind examination.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Secondary endpoint</measure>
    <time_frame>One year beginning on day 14 after the second dose of immunization</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the protective effect after 14 days following 2 doses of immunization of preventing severe cases of SARS CoV 2 pneumonia and deaths caused by COVID 19, among healthy population aged 18 years old and above. Comparison of the proportions of severe cases of SARS CoV 2 pneumonia and deaths in the two vaccine groups and the placebo group.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety endpoints</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Observe the incidence of any adverse reactions/events within 30 minutes after each dose of vaccine Observe the incidence of adverse reactions/events at 0 ~ 7 days and 8 ~ 21/30 days after each dose of vaccine. Observe the incidence of serious adverse events (SAE) from the beginning of the first dose to 6 months after the whole course of immunization.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">6000</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Investigational vaccine 1. Wuhan</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Investigational vaccine 2. Beijing</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo/Aluminum Adjuvant of Inactivated SARS CoV</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Inactivated SARS CoV 2 vaccine (Vero cell). Wuhan</intervention_name>
    <description>This clinical trial is conducted in randomized, blind, placebo controlled design Total sample size is 6 000, which are randomly allocated into investigational vaccine 1, investigational vaccine 2 and placebo control group.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Investigational vaccine 1. Wuhan</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Investigational vaccine 2. Beijing</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo/Aluminum Adjuvant of Inactivated SARS CoV</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Inactivated SARS CoV 2 vaccine (Vero cell). Beijijg</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age range: Healthy subjects aged 18 years old and above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  By asking for medical history and physical examination, the investigator judged that&#xD;
             the health condition is well&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects of childbearing age are not nursing or pregnant at the time of&#xD;
             enrolment (negative urine pregnancy test), and do not plan to become pregnant within&#xD;
             the first 3 months after enrolment . Effective contraceptive measures have been taken&#xD;
             within 2 weeks before inclusion and continued for at least three month s after last&#xD;
             dose&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  During the whole follow up period of the study, be able and willing to complete the&#xD;
             whole prescribed study plan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With self ability to understand the research procedures, with informed consent,&#xD;
             voluntarily sign an informed consent form, and be able to comply with the requirements&#xD;
             of the clinical study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SARS CoV 2 Infection Confirmed Cases, Suspected Cases or Asymptomatic Infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SARS CoV 2 Nucleic acid test positive&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a history of SARS , MERS infection (self report, on site inquiry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fever (axillary temperature &gt; 37.0 ℃), dry cough, fatigue, nasal obstruction, runny&#xD;
             nose, pharyngeal pain, myalgia, diarrhea, shortness of breath and dyspnea occurred&#xD;
             within 14 days before vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Axillary body temperature &gt; 37.0 ℃ before vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous severe allergic reactions to vaccination (such as acute allergic reactions,&#xD;
             urticaria, dyspnea, angioneurotic edema or abdominal pain) or allergy to known&#xD;
             ingredients of inactivated SARS CoV 2 vaccine have occurred.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a history of convulsion, epilepsy, encephalopathy or mental illness or family&#xD;
             history&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Congenital malformations or developmental disorders, genetic defects, severe&#xD;
             malnutrition, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe liver and kidney diseases, uncontrollable hypertension (systolic blood pressure&#xD;
             ≥ 140 mmHg, diastolic blood pressure ≥ 90 mmHg), diabetic complications, malignant&#xD;
             tumors, various acute diseases or acute attack period of chronic diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has been diagnosed with congenital or acquired immune deficiency, HIV infection,&#xD;
             lymphoma, leukemia or other autoimmune diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diseases known or suspected include severe respiratory diseases, severe cardiovascular&#xD;
             diseases, liver and kidney diseases, and malignant tumors. - Hist ory of coagulation&#xD;
             dysfunction (e.g. Coagulation factor deficiency, coagulation disease)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving anti TB therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving immunotherapy or inhibitor therapy within 3 months (continuous oral&#xD;
             or infusion for more than 14&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Live attenuated va ccine is inoculated within 1 month before this vaccination , other&#xD;
             vaccines are inoculated within 14 days before this vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received blood products within 3 months before this vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received other research drugs within 6 months before this vacc ination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Investigator judged other circumstances that are not suitable for this clinical trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>German Malaga, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Universidad Peruana Cayetano Heredia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>German Malaga, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+519-92768300</phone>
    <email>german.malaga@upch.pe</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Hugo García, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+519-93505197</phone>
    <email>hgarcia1@jhu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Av. Honorio Delgado 430, Urb. Ingeniería</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Martin De Porres</city>
        <state>Lima</state>
        <zip>L-031</zip>
        <country>Peru</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>German Malaga, MD</last_name>
      <phone>992768300</phone>
      <email>german.malaga@upch.pe</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Peru</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 29, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 29, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

