<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2800">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04603690</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LUMHS/REC/893</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04603690</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Investigate the Benefits of Colchicine in Patients With COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Open-labeled, and Controlled Trial to Study the Benefits of Colchicine in Patients With COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Liaquat University of Medical &amp; Health Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Universidad de Murcia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Liaquat University of Medical &amp; Health Sciences</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      COVID-19 is associated with a cytokine storm that leads to respiratory distress, multiorgan&#xD;
      failure and elevated mortality. Oral Colchicine exhibits high anti-inflammatory capacity&#xD;
      attributed to the inhibition of microtubules polymerization, inflammasome and production of&#xD;
      IL-1β and IL-6, which could prevent the inflammatory storm in COVID-19 patients at risk. The&#xD;
      investigators present a randomized, controlled, open-labeled, and pragmatic clinical trial to&#xD;
      study the treatment effect of Colchicine in COVID-19 patients requiring hospitalization, but&#xD;
      no intensive care yet. Colchicine will be started within the first 48 hours and continue for&#xD;
      14 days using a descending dose. The benefits will be studied in terms of clinical evolution&#xD;
      (WHO 7-point scale) and IL-6 levels, as well as other clinical and biochemical secondary&#xD;
      end-points. In the case of positive results, the clinical impact would be relevant given that&#xD;
      this oral medication is affordable and widely accessible which would help to prevent the&#xD;
      inflammatory complications associated with COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase III, prospective, pragmatic, randomized, controlled and open-label trial,&#xD;
      comparing standard of care vs. standard of care plus COLCHICINE for 14 days, in patients&#xD;
      hospitalized due to COVID-19 and confirmed infection by SARS-CoV-2, within the first 48 hours&#xD;
      after the hospital admission. Patients meeting severity criteria will be excluded, defined as&#xD;
      established limitation of therapeutic effort or need for invasive mechanical ventilation at&#xD;
      the time of inclusion. The Colchicine treatment includes an initial dose of 1.5 mg (1 mg and&#xD;
      0.5 mg two hours after), followed by 0.5 mg every 12 hours during the next 7 days and 0.5 mg&#xD;
      every 24 hours until the completion of 14 days of total treatment. In patients receiving&#xD;
      ritonavir or lopinavir or with reduced renal clearance (&lt;50 ml/min/1.37m2), weight &lt;70 kg or&#xD;
      age &gt;75 years old, the dose will be adjusted to the half.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patiens meeting all the inclusion criteria and none of the exclusion ones (see below), after&#xD;
      signing the informed consent, will be centrally randomized to &quot;Colchicine&quot; or &quot;Control&quot;&#xD;
      group. Patients in both groups will receive the standard therapy for COVID-19 as per the&#xD;
      hospital protocols. Randomization will be controlled by: age, sex, time from initiation of&#xD;
      symptoms, cardiovascular disease, the 7 point WHO and levels of C-reactive protein, ferritin,&#xD;
      D-dimer, IL-6 and lymphocyte levels.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    No funding available&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 14, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 14, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Phase III, prospective, randomized, controlled, open-label and pragmatic trial, comparing the administration of Colchicine plus standard treatment vs. standard therapy, in hospitalized patients with COVID-19, within the first 48 hours, and no severity criteria.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Improvement in the clinical status</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in the patients' clinical status through the 7 points ordinal scale (WHO R&amp;D Blueprint expert group)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in IL-6 concentrations</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement in the clinical status</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Improvement in the clinical status</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Time needed to reduce at least 2 points in the 7-point Ordinal Scale for Clinical Improvement by WHO R&amp;D Blueprint expert group (0-7)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in the score for the Sequential Organ Failure Assessment (SOFA score)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Sequential Organ Failure Assessment (SOFA score) (0-14)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in the punctuation in the National Early Warning Score</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>National Early Warning Score (NEWS scale)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of days with invasive mechanical ventilation or ECMO</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of days with high flow oxygen therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in other inflammatory markers (C-reactive protein, IL-6) from randomization</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in severity markers (D-dimer, lymphocytes, and ferritin) from randomization</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in myocardial damage and stress markers (hsTnT and NT-proBNP) from randomization.</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time until reaching a virus negative status by RT-PCR assay</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of hospital stay</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of days in the intensive care unit</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality by causes</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Colchicine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm will receive Colchicine + Standard care as per hospital guidelines.&#xD;
The Colchicine treatment includes an initial dose of 1.5 mg (1 mg and 0.5 mg two hours after), followed by 0.5 mg every 12 hours during the next 7 days and 0.5 mg every 24 hours until the completion of 14 days of total treatment. In patients receiving ritonavir or lopinavir or with reduced renal clearance (&lt;50 ml/min/1.37m2), weight &lt;70 kg or age &gt;75 years old, the dose will be adjusted to the half.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm will receive standard care as per the hospital guidelines.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Colchicine</intervention_name>
    <description>1 mg tablet</description>
    <arm_group_label>Colchicine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. SARS-CoV-2 infection confirmed by PCR.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Admitted in the hospital in the previous 48 hours, with clinical status 3, 4 or 5 of&#xD;
             WHO classification.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Age above 18 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Informed written consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Invasive mechanical ventilation needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Established limitation of the therapeutic effort&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD: Chron Syndrome or Ulcerative colitis), chronic&#xD;
             diarrhea or malabsorption.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Previous neuromuscular disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Other disease with an estimated vital prognosis under 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Severe renal insufficiency (glomerular filtration rate &lt;30 mL/min/1.73m2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Medical records of cirrhosis, active chronic hepatitis or severe hepatic disease&#xD;
             defined by GOT or GPT levels three times above the normal upper limit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients with previous colchicine treatment for other diseases (mainly chronic&#xD;
             prescriptions for familial Mediterranean fever or gout). Clearance period will not be&#xD;
             required for patients treated with colchicine who stopped the treatment before the&#xD;
             randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients with history of allergic reaction or significant sensitivity to colchicine.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Treatment with immunosuppressive agents, corticoids or interleukine-1 antagonists for&#xD;
             6 months before inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Pregnant or breastfeeding female, confirmed by a positive result in the human&#xD;
             chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) test.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Fertile woman, or post-menopausal during less than one year and non-surgically&#xD;
             sterilized. Women of fertile age may be included if using at least one contraceptive&#xD;
             method and preferably two complementary contraceptive methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Use of other investigational drugs in the moment of inclusion, or during 30 days&#xD;
             previous to inclusion.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <link>
    <url>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32579195/</url>
    <description>Effect of Colchicine vs Standard Care on Cardiac and Inflammatory Biomarkers and Clinical Outcomes in Patients Hospitalized With Coronavirus Disease 2019 The GRECCO-19 Randomized Clinical Trial</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://ard.bmj.com/content/79/10/1286</url>
    <description>Association between treatment with colchicine and improved survival in a single-centre cohort of adult hospitalised patients with COVID-19 pneumonia and acute respiratory distress syndrome</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32492478/</url>
    <description>Treating COVID-19 with colchicine in community healthcare setting</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 24, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 8, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 8, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 10, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Liaquat University of Medical &amp; Health Sciences</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Prof. Dr. Ikram Din Ujjan, MBBS, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Pathology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Colchicine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

