<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4086">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04698837</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-02768</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04698837</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Understanding Potential Airborne Transmission and the Protective Value of Type II Surgical Masks in SARS-CoV-2</brief_title>
  <acronym>aeroCOVID1</acronym>
  <official_title>AeroCOVID 1: Understanding Potential Airborne Transmission and the Protective Value of Type II Surgical Masks in SARS-CoV-2 Using Patient Proximity Environmental Sampling With a Highly Efficient Bioaerosol and Droplet Collection Dummy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital Inselspital, Berne</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Bern</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Lucerne University of Applied Sciences and Arts</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital Inselspital, Berne</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Modes of transmission of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) and&#xD;
      specifically the proportion of airborne transmission in this infection is unknown. In the&#xD;
      aeroCOVID study, a highly efficient bioaerosol and droplet sampling dummy is used to emulate&#xD;
      a susceptible healthcare worker (HCW) and to perform patient proximity sampling. The dummy&#xD;
      will measure the dummy-inhaled dose of SARS-CoV-2 in two particle size fractions in a&#xD;
      standardized interaction with hospitalized coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) patients. All&#xD;
      measurements are performed in a masked and unmasked dummy setup in parallel, in order to gain&#xD;
      further information on the protection of type II masks against the respective particle size&#xD;
      exposure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Modes of interpersonal transmission in SARS-CoV-2 are to date only incompletely understood&#xD;
      and require further investigation in order to define best preventive measures. Although a&#xD;
      dichotomization of inhaled particles by particle size is an oversimplification and a large&#xD;
      particle size does not exclude shortterm airborne behavior, the suspension time of virus&#xD;
      containing particles and the probability of particles to accumulate in room air is primarily&#xD;
      defined by particle size distribution. Particles with a size below 10 µm have a high&#xD;
      probability of accumulation due to their mean suspension time of minutes to hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study aims to measure the total amount of virus copies per particle size fraction inhaled&#xD;
      by a highly efficient sampling dummy emulating a susceptible HCW in a standardized&#xD;
      interaction with hospitalized COVID-19 patients. As a secondary endpoint, the proportion of&#xD;
      culturable virus in each setup is measured as well.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sampling is done in using two parallel bioaerosol and droplet sampling dummies - one type II&#xD;
      masked and one with an unmasked dummy head as inlet - in order to gain additional information&#xD;
      on the protective effect of type II surgical masks in a real-life exhaled particle size&#xD;
      distribution in hospitalized COVID patients. The sampling dummy consists of a real size face&#xD;
      relief connected to an 60° inlet cone, a cyclone for collection of particles &gt;10 µm and a&#xD;
      laminar flow water-based condensation bioaerosol collector for particle collection below 10&#xD;
      µm particle size.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After patient proximity sampling, a nasopharyngeal swab for SARS-CoV-2 polymerase chain&#xD;
      reaction (PCR) assay is performed. Relevant indoor climate parameters like temperature,&#xD;
      humidity and carbon dioxide (CO2) as well as room characteristics as air change rate are&#xD;
      recorded as well.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Total amount of dummy-inhaled virus copies per 30 minutes sampling per size fraction (&gt;10 µm, &lt;10 µm)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes sampling</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Viability of dummy-inhaled viable virus per size fraction (&gt;10 µm, and &lt;10 µm)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes sampling</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction of dummy-inhaled virus copies per 30 minutes sampling in a type II-masked setup, as compared to unmasked, per size fraction (&gt;10 µm, &lt;10 µm)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes sampling</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV-2</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Nasopharyngeal swab&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study is performed with hospitalized COVID-19 patients at Inselspital, Bern University&#xD;
        hospital. The study site hospital is a tertiary university hospital treating COVID-19&#xD;
        patients on normal hospital wards as well as in the intensive care unit.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  positive SARS-CoV-2 PCR or antigen test from a nasopharyngeal or oropharyngeal swab&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ability to give consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ability to follow simple instructions&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  symptom onset more than 14 days prior to inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  lack of written informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>110 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Philipp Jent, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+41 31 632 65 04</phone>
    <email>philipp.jent@insel.ch</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Bern</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bern</city>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Philipp Jent, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+41 31 632 65 04</phone>
      <email>philipp.jent@insel.ch</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Airborne transmission</keyword>
  <keyword>Aerosol transmission</keyword>
  <keyword>Surgical masks</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

