<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3446">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04721457</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1384</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04721457</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Efficacy of Pre-procedural Mouth Rinses on COVID-19 Saliva Viral Load</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Efficacy of Pre-procedural Mouth Rinses on SARS-CoV-2 Saliva Viral Load: A Randomized Control Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>King Abdulaziz University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>King Abdulaziz University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Preoperative antiseptic mouth rinses have been widely used as a standard protocol before&#xD;
      routine dental treatment reduces oral microorganism counts. During dental procedures,&#xD;
      aerosolized microorganisms contaminate the dental environment and nearby surfaces and remain&#xD;
      suspended for 4 hours. Thus, the reduction in the number of aerosolized microorganisms by&#xD;
      pre-procedural rinsing may reduce cross-contamination between dentists, office personnel, and&#xD;
      patients. Recent reviews have advocated the use of preoperative rinsing to control and reduce&#xD;
      the risk of SARS-CoV-2 transmission. However, no clinical studies have been done yet to&#xD;
      support the effectiveness of any pre-procedural oral rinses against SARS-CoV-2. The proposed&#xD;
      study will mitigate the spread of COVID-19 disease in dental health care facilities and&#xD;
      ensure the patients' good health and healthcare workers. The purpose of this clinical trial&#xD;
      is to determine and compare the effectiveness of four commercially available, pre-procedural&#xD;
      mouth rinses versus distilled water on viral load of SARS-CoV-2 found in the saliva of&#xD;
      COVID-19 positive patients and to measure the pre-rinsing viral load with the post-rinsing at&#xD;
      three-time points.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Saliva specimens will be collected from COVID-19-positive patients presenting to TETAMMAN&#xD;
      clinics from November 2020 to March 2021. The total number of participants in this study will&#xD;
      be 120 participants, with 20 per group (5 groups), 4 saliva specimens from each patient in&#xD;
      each group. The groups in this study will be as follows: Group 1: Negative Control (distilled&#xD;
      water); Group 2: PVP-I (1% w/v); Group 3: Hydrogen Peroxide (1.5 % w/v); Group 4: Sodium&#xD;
      Hypochlorite; Group 5: Cetylpyridinium Chloride CPC (0.075% w/v). Confirmed positive cases of&#xD;
      COVID-19 will be recruited randomly at each TETAMMAN clinic based on inclusion and exclusion&#xD;
      criteria to satisfy the total of 120 patients needed. Each participant will be introduced&#xD;
      briefly to the study aims and then asked to sign a consent form. Demographic data and medical&#xD;
      history will then be collected for each participant. The participants will be blinded to all&#xD;
      mouth rinses, which will be labeled with identification codes, and presented in similar&#xD;
      packages. Patients will be asked to pool saliva in their mouth (self-collected saliva) for&#xD;
      2-4 minutes before collection and then gently expectorate in a 25-mL sterile (RNase-DNase&#xD;
      free) collection container about 2 mL of whole non-stimulated saliva (1st sample). The first&#xD;
      saliva sample will be considered as a baseline sample that represents the baseline viral&#xD;
      load. Then patients will be instructed to gargle gently, for 15 seconds in the oral cavity&#xD;
      and the back of the throat with Distilled water, PVP-I, Hydrogen Peroxide, Sodium&#xD;
      Hypochlorite, and CPC. After that, the participants will spit the mouthwashes into a&#xD;
      disposable plastic cup. After that, different salivary samples will be collected using the&#xD;
      collection procedure, as mentioned earlier, at several time points from spitting the&#xD;
      mouthwashes: 5 minutes, 30 minutes, and then 60 minutes. Thus, a total of four saliva samples&#xD;
      will be gathered from each patient. Changes in saliva SARS-CoV-2 viral load in each sample&#xD;
      will be assessed using the quantification of gene expression using qRT-PCR.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 3, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This randomized, cross-sectional, triple-blinded, five-armed, interventional study compared Distalled water, Povidone-Iodine, Hydrogen Peroxide, Cetylpyridinium Chloride, and Sodium Hypochlorite Mouth Rinses in 120 Covid 19 positive subjects. Real time reverse transcriptase quantitative PCR measured viral loads.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Triple-Blinded. All mouth rinses vials are masked.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in SARS-Cov-2 viral load (Quantitative Real-Time Reverse-Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction (qRT-PCR))</measure>
    <time_frame>3 time points of viral load changes from the baseline. vs:5 minutes, 30 minutes and vs: 60 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Saliva load was expressed in copies x 10 8 of COVID-19 RNA</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ct values</measure>
    <time_frame>3 time points of viral load changes from the baseline. vs:5 minutes, 30 minutes and vs: 60 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>cycle thresholds</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV-2</condition>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <condition>Mouthwashes</condition>
  <condition>Viral Load</condition>
  <condition>Polymerase Chain Reaction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Distilled Water</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>15-second rinsing with 15 mL of Distilled Water</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Povidone Iodine (PVP-I)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>15-second rinsing with 15 mL of 1% PVP-I</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hydrogen Peroxide (H2O2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>15-second rinsing with 15 mL of 1.5 % Hydrogen Peroxide</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cetylpyridinium Chloride (CPC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>15-second rinsing with 15 mL of 0.075%CPC</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sodium Hypochlorite</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>15-second rinsing with 15 mL of 0.1% Sodium Hypochlorite</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Distilled Water</intervention_name>
    <description>Distilled Water placebo rinse</description>
    <arm_group_label>Distilled Water</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>WATER FOR INJECTION BP</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>1% Povidone Iodine (PVP-I)</intervention_name>
    <description>Over-the-counter antiseptic mouth rinse</description>
    <arm_group_label>Povidone Iodine (PVP-I)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Betadine Mouthwash/Gargle</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>1.5% Hydrogen Peroxide (H2O2)</intervention_name>
    <description>Over-the-counter antiseptic mouth rinse</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hydrogen Peroxide (H2O2)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Colgate Peroxyl Mouth Sore Rinse</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>0.075% Cetylpyridinium Chloride (CPC)</intervention_name>
    <description>Over-the-counter antiseptic mouth rinse</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cetylpyridinium Chloride (CPC)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Colgate Gum Health Mouthwash</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>0.1% Sodium Hypochlorite</intervention_name>
    <description>Over-the-counter antiseptic mouth rinse</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sodium Hypochlorite</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CLINISEPT+ MOUTHWASH</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adults age 18 years or older presented to TETAMMAN clinics, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. COVID-19 positive patients confirmed by RT-PCR and within two days of oral or&#xD;
             nasopharyngeal swabs&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Asymptomatic or within seven days of the onset of symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Has the ability to rinse and expectorate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participants who started hydroxychloroquine treatment or on antibiotics.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known allergy to one of the constituents of the mouth rinse&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Thyroid disease or on current radioactive iodine treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pregnant or breastfeeding women&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Lithium therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Participants on corticosteroid medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Has Sjogren's syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Immune-compromised (HIV/AIDS, cancer, organ transplant, or immunosuppressive&#xD;
             medications)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of radiotherapy or chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Use of mouthwash or MISWAK before presented to TETAMMAN clinics&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>MANAR M ALZAHRANI, MSD, FRCD(C)</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>King Abdulaziz University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>MANAR M ALZAHRANI, MSD, FRCD(C)</last_name>
    <phone>00966591040061</phone>
    <email>mmalzhrani@kau.edu.sa</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alhamra TETAMMAN clinic (PHC)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jeddah</city>
        <country>Saudi Arabia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Saudi Arabia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>To KK, Tsang OT, Yip CC, Chan KH, Wu TC, Chan JM, Leung WS, Chik TS, Choi CY, Kandamby DH, Lung DC, Tam AR, Poon RW, Fung AY, Hung IF, Cheng VC, Chan JF, Yuen KY. Consistent Detection of 2019 Novel Coronavirus in Saliva. Clin Infect Dis. 2020 Jul 28;71(15):841-843. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciaa149.</citation>
    <PMID>32047895</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ge ZY, Yang LM, Xia JJ, Fu XH, Zhang YZ. Possible aerosol transmission of COVID-19 and special precautions in dentistry. J Zhejiang Univ Sci B. 2020 May;21(5):361-368. doi: 10.1631/jzus.B2010010. Epub 2020 Mar 16. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32425001</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vergara-Buenaventura A, Castro-Ruiz C. Use of mouthwashes against COVID-19 in dentistry. Br J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2020 Oct;58(8):924-927. doi: 10.1016/j.bjoms.2020.08.016. Epub 2020 Aug 15. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32859459</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>O'Donnell VB, Thomas D, Stanton R, Maillard JY, Murphy RC, Jones SA, Humphreys I, Wakelam MJO, Fegan C, Wise MP, Bosch A, Sattar SA. Potential Role of Oral Rinses Targeting the Viral Lipid Envelope in SARS-CoV-2 Infection. Function (Oxf). 2020;1(1):zqaa002. doi: 10.1093/function/zqaa002. Epub 2020 Jun 5.</citation>
    <PMID>33215159</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Carrouel F, Conte MP, Fisher J, Gonçalves LS, Dussart C, Llodra JC, Bourgeois D. COVID-19: A Recommendation to Examine the Effect of Mouthrinses with β-Cyclodextrin Combined with Citrox in Preventing Infection and Progression. J Clin Med. 2020 Apr 15;9(4). pii: E1126. doi: 10.3390/jcm9041126.</citation>
    <PMID>32326426</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Wang W, Xu Y, Gao R, Lu R, Han K, Wu G, Tan W. Detection of SARS-CoV-2 in Different Types of Clinical Specimens. JAMA. 2020 May 12;323(18):1843-1844. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.3786.</citation>
    <PMID>32159775</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Bruch MK. Toxicity and safety of topical sodium hypochlorite. Contrib Nephrol. 2007;154:24-38. doi: 10.1159/000096812. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17099299</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>De Nardo R, Chiappe V, Gómez M, Romanelli H, Slots J. Effects of 0.05% sodium hypochlorite oral rinse on supragingival biofilm and gingival inflammation. Int Dent J. 2012 Aug;62(4):208-12. doi: 10.1111/j.1875-595X.2011.00111.x. Epub 2012 May 11.</citation>
    <PMID>23017003</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Seo HW, Seo JP, Cho Y, Ko E, Kim YJ, Jung G. Cetylpyridinium chloride interaction with the hepatitis B virus core protein inhibits capsid assembly. Virus Res. 2019 Apr 2;263:102-111. doi: 10.1016/j.virusres.2019.01.004. Epub 2019 Jan 9.</citation>
    <PMID>30639191</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Feres M, Figueiredo LC, Faveri M, Stewart B, de Vizio W. The effectiveness of a preprocedural mouthrinse containing cetylpyridinium chloride in reducing bacteria in the dental office. J Am Dent Assoc. 2010 Apr;141(4):415-22.</citation>
    <PMID>20354090</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Marui VC, Souto MLS, Rovai ES, Romito GA, Chambrone L, Pannuti CM. Efficacy of preprocedural mouthrinses in the reduction of microorganisms in aerosol: A systematic review. J Am Dent Assoc. 2019 Dec;150(12):1015-1026.e1. doi: 10.1016/j.adaj.2019.06.024.</citation>
    <PMID>31761015</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Pitten FA, Kramer A. Efficacy of cetylpyridinium chloride used as oropharyngeal antiseptic. Arzneimittelforschung. 2001;51(7):588-95.</citation>
    <PMID>11505791</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Osso D, Kanani N. Antiseptic mouth rinses: an update on comparative effectiveness, risks and recommendations. J Dent Hyg. 2013 Feb;87(1):10-8. Epub 2013 Feb 5. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23433693</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Caruso AA, Del Prete A, Lazzarino AI. Hydrogen peroxide and viral infections: A literature review with research hypothesis definition in relation to the current covid-19 pandemic. Med Hypotheses. 2020 Nov;144:109910. doi: 10.1016/j.mehy.2020.109910. Epub 2020 Jun 1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32505069</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Walsh LJ. Safety issues relating to the use of hydrogen peroxide in dentistry. Aust Dent J. 2000 Dec;45(4):257-69; quiz 289. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11225528</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Eggers M, Koburger-Janssen T, Eickmann M, Zorn J. In Vitro Bactericidal and Virucidal Efficacy of Povidone-Iodine Gargle/Mouthwash Against Respiratory and Oral Tract Pathogens. Infect Dis Ther. 2018 Jun;7(2):249-259. doi: 10.1007/s40121-018-0200-7. Epub 2018 Apr 9.</citation>
    <PMID>29633177</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kariwa H, Fujii N, Takashima I. Inactivation of SARS coronavirus by means of povidone-iodine, physical conditions and chemical reagents. Dermatology. 2006;212 Suppl 1:119-23.</citation>
    <PMID>16490989</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>King Abdulaziz University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>MANAR ALZAHRANI</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Povidone-Iodine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Listerine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hydrogen Peroxide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cetylpyridinium</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sodium Hypochlorite</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Eusol</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Povidone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sodium Fluoride</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

