<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1565">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04668625</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PRIMACOV</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04668625</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Risk of Infection of Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2), COVID-19, in a Massive Musical Show With Transmission Prevention Measures</brief_title>
  <official_title>Risk of Infection of SARS-CoV-2 in a Massive Musical Show With Transmission Prevention Measures: Randomized Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fundación FLS de Lucha Contra el Sida, las Enfermedades Infecciosas y la Promoción de la Salud y la Ciencia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dr. Bonaventura Clotet Sala</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dr. Josep Mª LLibre Codina</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dr. Boris Revollo Barriga</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dra. Lidia Ruiz Tabuenca</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dr. Ignacio Blanco Guillermo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dra. Andrea Alemany Ortiz</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dr. Roger Paredes Deiros</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fundación FLS de Lucha Contra el Sida, las Enfermedades Infecciosas y la Promoción de la Salud y la Ciencia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) outbreak, caused by the severe acute respiratory&#xD;
      syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), emerged in Wuhan in December 2019 and has spread&#xD;
      globally, representing a serious threat to public health. While waiting for highly effective&#xD;
      treatments or the development of an effective vaccine, it is necessary to reactivate key&#xD;
      economic activities that are related to leisure and culture in an environment that is safest&#xD;
      for the participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The use of a rapid screening test for SARS-CoV-2 viral antigens with high sensitivity could&#xD;
      be a useful tool to detect asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infected people, and thus be able to carry&#xD;
      out events related to leisure in a safe environment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to make a mass screening of asymptomatic infection of an (i)&#xD;
      experimental group (public attending a massive mass musical show) and (ii) a control group&#xD;
      (they will not enter the event) prior to entering to the event.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization 1: 1 by random blocks of the participants with a negative antigen test in the&#xD;
      experimental group (attending the event) and the control group (they will not enter the&#xD;
      event).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control with a new Polymerase Chain Reaction (PCR) test 8 days after the event (D8) in the&#xD;
      participants of both randomized groups Control of the appearance of symptoms through a&#xD;
      questionnaire 10 days after the event (D10), in the participants of both groups with a&#xD;
      negative result on day 8.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Validation of a rapid antigen detection test by comparison with the PCR technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The indoor activity will include an array of measures designed to reducing the contagion&#xD;
      risk, including: mandatory wearing a mask during the event, restricted outdoor areas of bar&#xD;
      and smoking, enhanced ventilation of the whole indoor area, and avoiding queues.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All subjects will have downloaded an app in their smart phones to help contact and place&#xD;
      tracing during the event, to trace potential transmissions. This app will remain active for 8&#xD;
      days, until the last virologic control.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The inclusion criteria will allow only subjects with an age &lt;60 years, without comorbidities,&#xD;
      and who do not live with old adults in their homes, to further reduce the risk of potential&#xD;
      complications and transmission to at risk individuals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) outbreak, caused by the severe acute respiratory&#xD;
      syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), emerged in Wuhan in December 2019 and has spread&#xD;
      globally, representing a serious threat to public health. While 80% of patients are&#xD;
      asymptomatic or have a mild illness, 20% develop a severe illness. The predominant symptoms&#xD;
      include fever, cough, and myalgia. Mild disease can resolve without medical attention or it&#xD;
      can progress to pneumonia and respiratory failure requiring hospitalization. Patients can&#xD;
      rapidly progress to acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) with multiple organ&#xD;
      dysfunction and death.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The degree to which the virus is infectious during the incubation period is uncertain, but it&#xD;
      has been shown that the pharynx reaches peak viral load before day 5, and this peak viral&#xD;
      load is 1,000 times higher than in severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV).&#xD;
      This active and high viral clearance from the pharynx at a time when symptoms are still mild&#xD;
      makes the transmission of SARS-CoV-2 more efficient than that of SARS-CoV. Later in the&#xD;
      disease, COVID-19 resembles SARS in terms of replication in the lower respiratory tract. The&#xD;
      decrease in viral load appears to be slow, and there is no sudden shedding of the virus at&#xD;
      the time of seroconversion. Seroconversion, at the beginning of week 2, has been observed to&#xD;
      coincide with a slow but steady decrease in sputum viral load. Prolonged viral shedding in&#xD;
      sputum is relevant not only for infection control in hospitals and discharge management, but&#xD;
      also for asymptomatic people who can transmit the virus for longer periods after infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although it is true that the majority of people infected by SARS-CoV-2 will have a benign&#xD;
      course with few symptoms, approximately 20% will require hospitalization and 5% will present&#xD;
      serious complications and admission to an intensive care unit, this is it translates into a&#xD;
      saturation and collapse of health systems, with a high percentage of mortality in relation to&#xD;
      it. Unprecedented confinement measures have been implemented that have been effective in&#xD;
      containing the progression of the number of infections, but these have had a great social and&#xD;
      economic impact, among others with a paralysis of most of the activities related to leisure&#xD;
      (concerts , music festivals, theaters, etc.) that are an important component in the economy&#xD;
      of most of the countries of the European community. While waiting for highly effective&#xD;
      treatments or the development of an effective vaccine, it is necessary to reactivate key&#xD;
      economic activities that are related to leisure and culture in an environment that is safest&#xD;
      for the participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The use of a rapid screening test for SARS-CoV-2 viral antigens with high sensitivity could&#xD;
      be a useful tool to detect asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infected people, and thus be able to carry&#xD;
      out events related to leisure in a safe environment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is necessary to implement versatile circuits in which diagnoses with rapid tests can be&#xD;
      carried out in the same place of the events in a massive way and to be able to communicate&#xD;
      the results of the tests to the assistants at the same time, in order to do this screening of&#xD;
      people that they give negative and carry out activities with them in a safe environment for&#xD;
      all participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to make a mass screening of asymptomatic infection of an (i)&#xD;
      experimental group (public attending a massive mass musical show) and (ii) a control group&#xD;
      (they will not enter the event) prior to entering to the event.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization 1: 1 by random blocks of the participants with a negative antigen test in the&#xD;
      experimental group (attending the event) and the control group (they will not enter the&#xD;
      event).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control with a new PCR test 8 days after the event (D8) in the participants of both&#xD;
      randomized groups Control of the appearance of symptoms through a questionnaire 10 days after&#xD;
      the event (D10), in the participants of both groups with a negative result on day 8.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Validation of a rapid antigen detection test by comparison with the PCR technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The indoor activity will include an array of measures designed to reducing the contagion&#xD;
      risk, including: mandatory wearing a mask during the event, restricted outdoor areas of bar&#xD;
      and smoking, enhanced ventilation of the whole indoor area, and avoiding queues.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All subjects will have downloaded an app in their smart phones to help contact and place&#xD;
      tracing during the event, to trace potential transmissions. This app will remain active for 8&#xD;
      days, until the last virologic control.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The inclusion criteria will allow only subjects with an age &lt;60 years, without comorbidities,&#xD;
      and who do not live with old adults in their homes, to further reduce the risk of potential&#xD;
      complications and transmission to at risk individuals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 30, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 8, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 20, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>All participants will be screened for a rapid Ag SARS-CoV-2 test detection. All negative subjects will be randomized to an experimental arm (participate in a massive musical event) or to a control arm (not participate in a massive musical event).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence rate of people infected with SARS-CoV-2 8 days after randomization</measure>
    <time_frame>At 8 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence rate of people infected with SARS-CoV-2 8 days after randomization, detected by PCR in nasopharyngeal aspirate, on the experimental and the control group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SARS-CoV-2 genome sequence</measure>
    <time_frame>At 8 days</time_frame>
    <description>Nasopharyngeal swab samples will be stored in case SARS-CoV-2 infections are documented for sequencing purposes to assess the possibility of spreading clusters during the event. Data will be matched with a Global Positioning System (GPS) smart phone tracking localization during the concert.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence rate of appearance of symptoms compatible with COVID 19</measure>
    <time_frame>At 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence rate of appearance of symptoms compatible with COVID 19 in those attending the event after 10 days (D10).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent in testing the total number of participants in the study.</measure>
    <time_frame>At day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Time spent in testing the total number of participants in the study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the diagnostic sensitivity of rapid antigen tests for SARS-CoV-2 compared to PCR in asymptomatic subjects.</measure>
    <time_frame>At day 0</time_frame>
    <description>We will compare the diagnostic sensitivity of rapid antigen tests for SARS-CoV-2 compared to PCR in asymptomatic subjects.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the diagnostic sensitivity of rapid antigen tests for SARS-CoV-2 using a nasopharyngeal swab sample compared to sample obtained trough saliva</measure>
    <time_frame>At day 0</time_frame>
    <description>We will compare the diagnostic sensitivity of rapid antigen tests for SARS-CoV-2 using a nasopharyngeal swab sample compared to sample obtained trough saliva, in positive cases by this technique.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Presence of viable SARS-CoV-2 from cell culture</measure>
    <time_frame>At day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Presence of viable SARS-CoV-2 from cell culture in all cases with negative Ag and positive PCR.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Satisfaction in relation to the test procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>At 10 days</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of the results obtained on satisfaction in relation to the test procedure of those attending the event through a questionnaire.&#xD;
Questions:&#xD;
I have had all the necessary prior information to participate in this study&#xD;
I have felt properly cared for by the health personnel&#xD;
I have felt properly cared for by the room staff&#xD;
I have behaved naturally without feeling conditioned by the measures of the protocol during the event&#xD;
I have been able to enjoy the performance in a satisfactory way&#xD;
I will attend other leisure events in closed spaces following this same protocol&#xD;
It can be answered with a scale from 0 to 10 (0 not satisfied at all, 10 extremely satisfied)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19 (SARS-CoV-2)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participate in a massive musical event</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Not participate in a massive musical event</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Participate in a massive musical event</intervention_name>
    <description>Participate in a massive musical event</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults (age 18-59 years) with interest to attend the scheduled musical event who agree&#xD;
             to participate in the study after signing the informed consent, including explicit&#xD;
             acceptance of the measures implemented to reduce the risk of transmission of&#xD;
             SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative antigen test performed up to 24 h before the event, in nasopharyngeal swab.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diabetes Mellitus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ischemic heart disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any type of Cancer in active treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic lung diseases such as chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and asthma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a positive test for detection of SARS-CoV-2 by the rapid antigen test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who have a body temperature higher than 37.0º on the same day of the event&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who have a confirmed diagnosis for SARS-CoV-2 in the two weeks prior to the event&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Report any symptoms suggestive of a SARS-CoV-2 infection in the 10 days prior to the&#xD;
             study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Who have been in contact with a person with a confirmed diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
             infection within two weeks prior to the event.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Living with a person over 70 years of age (inclusive).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>59 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bonaventura Clotet Sala, PhD, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Fundación FLS de Lucha Contra el Sida, las Enfermedades Infecciosas y la Promoción de la Salud y la Ciencia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Boris Revollo Barriga, PhD, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Fundación FLS de Lucha Contra el Sida, las Enfermedades Infecciosas y la Promoción de la Salud y la Ciencia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Josep Mª LLIBRRE CODINA, PhD, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Fundación FLS de Lucha Contra el Sida, las Enfermedades Infecciosas y la Promoción de la Salud y la Ciencia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Germans Trias i Pujol Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Badalona</city>
        <state>Barcelona</state>
        <zip>08916</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 14, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 16, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Coronavirus</keyword>
  <keyword>Superspreading event</keyword>
  <keyword>Concert</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

