<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4792">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04402034</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>03851012.7.0000.5390</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04402034</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Telerehabilitation in Disabled People: Proposal for Practical Intervention With Virtual Reality</brief_title>
  <official_title>Telerehabilitation in Disabled People: Proposal for Practical Intervention With Virtual Reality</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Sao Paulo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Sao Paulo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a cross-sectional study, that is going to be conducted during the quarantine, period&#xD;
      established by the state of São Paulo to reduce the transmission of COVID-19, between March&#xD;
      24 2020 and May 31 2020. Thus, the differential of this study is to use 100%&#xD;
      telerehabilitation, in which the rehabilitation team and participants only had telephone&#xD;
      contact, communication application (WhatsApp) and software interaction. 40 participants will&#xD;
      be included. Potential and interested volunteers will be assessed by a detailed screening&#xD;
      using the eligibility criteria and attended an initial selection for enrolment in the study.&#xD;
      It wiil be used a platform called MoveHero, available for free use in&#xD;
      https://movehero.com.br/. The individual needs access the internet, and once he gets online,&#xD;
      he had to create his own account, inserting his name, email and creating a password.&#xD;
      Considering that the platform presents different levels of difficulty, after the participant&#xD;
      is connected to the platform, the researcher directed the participant to the protocol bespoke&#xD;
      for each participant, playing 3 rounds of the game for 5 minutes each (total of 15 minutes).&#xD;
      During the intervention, it will be applied BORG scale in order to assess their perceived&#xD;
      effort.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Instrument In this study, it will be used a platform called MoveHero, available for free use&#xD;
      in https://movehero.com.br/. The individual needs access the internet, and once he gets&#xD;
      online, he had to create his own account, inserting his name, email and creating a password.&#xD;
      Considering that the platform presents different levels of difficulty, after the participant&#xD;
      is connected to the platform, the researcher directed the participant to the protocol&#xD;
      specially developed for cerebral palsy. MoveHero is considerate a timing coincident task and&#xD;
      present several spheres falling down on the computer screen, with a musical rhythm to&#xD;
      increase engagement. Thus, the participants will be positioned in front of a computer and&#xD;
      when the game started the webcam captures the participant movements and a representation of&#xD;
      the players appears on the computer screen as an avatar. The game goals are to intercept all&#xD;
      falling spheres using upper limb wave movements in the exact moment the spheres reached their&#xD;
      specific target in the bottom of computer screen. The game presented four columns with fixed&#xD;
      targets in parallel allocated in two height levels (e.g. two on the left - targets A and B;&#xD;
      two on the right - targets C and D). The game provides hit and miss feedback - if the&#xD;
      individual reaches the spheres correctly, the game presented a feedback with the spheres&#xD;
      changing the color for green (hit information). On the other hand, if the participant do not&#xD;
      touch the spheres properly, the spheres changing the color for red and the letter X appears&#xD;
      inside the target (miss information).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Software score During the game match (each game match lasts for 5 minutes) the participant&#xD;
      can follow the score determined by the number of spheres hit (i.e. the information from each&#xD;
      sphere hit appears in the bottom left side of the screen all the time) and at the end of each&#xD;
      game match the participant had feedback with their total score (when the game match finished&#xD;
      a total score appears in the middle of the computer screen). The game features 10 different&#xD;
      and progressive phases of difficulty, considering the number of balls falling. In this study,&#xD;
      all participants will start at the easiest phase (phase 1) and according to their own score,&#xD;
      the researcher should move forward to a more difficult phase. The progression in the phase&#xD;
      was established by the table below. Thus, each participant presents an individual&#xD;
      progression, considering their performance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessments&#xD;
&#xD;
      To characterize the participants it will be used some scales that characterize each disease&#xD;
      and can be applied such as Pediatric Evaluation of Disability Inventory (PEDI) for children&#xD;
      and Quality of Life and specific scales for adults. As well as sociodemographic Information:&#xD;
      some questions will be asked, such as age, sex, income to understand the studied population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To analyse the outcome Measures will be used: 1) Brunel Mood Scale (BRUMS) measures six&#xD;
      identifiable affective states (Tension, Depression, Anger, Vigor, Fatigue, and Confusion)&#xD;
      through a 24-item self-report inventory, with respondents rating a list of adjectives on a&#xD;
      5-point Likert scale ranging from 0 (not at all) to 4 (extremely), based on subjective&#xD;
      feelings. The instructions refer to how participants have been feeling in the past week,&#xD;
      including today. 2) BORG scale: is Rating of Perceived Exertion used to measure the&#xD;
      subjective intensity of effort. It is based on the sensations felt during exercise, such as&#xD;
      muscle fatigue, increased heart rate and increased breathing. 3) System Usability Scale&#xD;
      (SUS), was proposed by John Brooke in 1986 as the usability test tool. It is a simple scale&#xD;
      based on a questionnaire and has been widely adopted in product usability evaluations. The&#xD;
      statements cover a variety of aspects of system usability such as the need for support,&#xD;
      training, and complexity, and thus have a high level of face validity for measuring usability&#xD;
      of a system. The SUS instrument is generally used after the respondent has had an opportunity&#xD;
      to use the system being evaluated. This instrument is a highly robust and versatile tool for&#xD;
      usability professionals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      1.5 Procedure and Design&#xD;
&#xD;
      Contact and assessment scales&#xD;
&#xD;
      The parent's individuals (for children) or the individual itself will be contacted by phone&#xD;
      and asked to perform the task at home, they will be assisted by the researcher over the&#xD;
      phone, with a video call. Important to emphasized that all participants that need assistance,&#xD;
      will be assisted by their parents or their caregivers. First, they wiil receive a link with&#xD;
      research information and the assent and consent form to fill out and the inclusion criteria&#xD;
      will be checked by researcher. When they agree to participate, a link to access a questioner&#xD;
      will be sent with Brunel Mood Scale, BORG scale, PEDI and Sociodemographic Information. When&#xD;
      parents and participants finish those scales the gaming platform will be accessed and the&#xD;
      participant starts the protocol practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Practicing the task&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will perform the task individually in their own house with a family member&#xD;
      helping and giving support during all protocol. The researcher contacts the family member and&#xD;
      gives the following instructions using videocall (research interact with the family member&#xD;
      and the participant during all the protocol): 1) place the computer on a table and login to&#xD;
      the platform; 2) position the cell phone (to provide videocall) on the side of the computer&#xD;
      to receive instructions; 3) provide a comfortable sitting position in a chair (individual&#xD;
      should be positioned at a distance of approximately 1.5 m meters from the computer monitor)&#xD;
      and adjusted in height according to the needs of the individual (if applicable, participants&#xD;
      could use their own wheelchair); 4) after being seated and connected to the platform the&#xD;
      research will explain the task verbally for all participants and ask the family member to&#xD;
      play ones (demonstrations of how to perform the coincidence timing was given form the family&#xD;
      member during two minutes); 5) after demonstration, the family member should grab the mobile&#xD;
      phone (to have the opportunity to move the phone and show the participant performance to the&#xD;
      researcher during all the protocol) and 6) thus, the therapist (by video call) instructed the&#xD;
      participant to stay still and wait the first sphere appears on the screen. Once the first&#xD;
      sphere appears, the individual had to move his or her hand to either touch the sphere exactly&#xD;
      at the moment coinciding with the bottom target and the game should move on with different&#xD;
      spheres falling in the computer screen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
      As presented before the parent and participant should answer 4 assessments (Brunel Mood&#xD;
      Scale, BORG scale, PEDI and Demographic Information), and start to perform the first game&#xD;
      phase (phase 1), after 5 minutes playing the game the participant will answer the Borg scale&#xD;
      and researcher will analyze the game score (e.g. according to table 2 the participant should&#xD;
      repeat phase one or move forward for a more difficult phase); the participant started a&#xD;
      second practice and after 5 minutes answer the Borg scale (again- the participant should&#xD;
      repeat last phase or move forward for a more difficult phase); the participant started a&#xD;
      third and last practice and after 5 minutes had to answer the Borg scale and to finish the&#xD;
      protocol the BRUMS scale and the System Usability Scale (SUS).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 21, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 20, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Motor performance.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>The motor performance will be measured by the virtual game &quot;MoveHero&quot;, which gives data about accuracy, precision and directional trend of movement.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceived Exertion.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day.</time_frame>
    <description>The Perceived Exertion will me assessed by the Borg Rating of Perceived Exertion (RPE), based on a 6 to 20 rating scale, in which a rating of 6 perceiving &quot;no exertion at all&quot; to 20 perceiving a &quot;maximal exertion&quot; of effort.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Disability Physical</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Application of tele-rehabilitation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Individuals that will perform the protocol of virtual reality intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Application of tele-rehabilitation</intervention_name>
    <description>Individuals that will perform the virtual reality intervention.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Application of tele-rehabilitation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  agreement to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  clinical diagnosis of the disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age ranging from 7 to 80 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  do not understand the tasks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  motor difficulties that impede the completing of the virtual tasks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  do not have technology devices to perform the virtual task (computer) or to contact&#xD;
             the researcher (cell phone or a second computer)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  was precluded from completing the task due to some technological failure (such as&#xD;
             internet crash).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>7 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carlos BM Monteiro, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Sao Paulo</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Escola de Artes,Ciencias e Humanidades da Universidade d Sao Paulo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sao Paulo</city>
        <zip>03828-000</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 22, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 26, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 22, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 22, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Sao Paulo</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Carlos Bandeira de Mello Monteiro</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Disability Physical</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

