<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4770">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04742426</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PPE-TEAM</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04742426</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Personal Protective Equipment Affect Team Performance During Medical Emergencies</brief_title>
  <acronym>PPE-TEAM</acronym>
  <official_title>Does the Choice of Personal Protective Equipment Affect Team Performance During Medical Emergencies? Simulation-Based Randomised Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Roman Sýkora</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Charles University, Czech Republic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Safety of healthcare professionals working in high-risk environments is of upmost importance.&#xD;
      Personal protective equipment (PPE) may affect the performance of individuals and teams by&#xD;
      altering their senses, manual skills and ability to communicate. Current guidelines offer&#xD;
      flexibility in terms of which specific PPE components can safely be used. Yet, in some&#xD;
      organisations, healthcare workers become used to using PPE well above the recommended&#xD;
      standards (termed further in text as super-safe setup, SSS). Impact of this PPE policy on&#xD;
      team performance and in turn to patient safety is unknown. We hypothesise that SSS, as&#xD;
      compared to WHO PPE standard, would negatively impact team performance and patient outcomes&#xD;
      in a simulated crisis scenario.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Safety of healthcare professionals working in high-risk environments is of upmost importance.&#xD;
      Personal protective equipment (PPE) may affect the performance of individuals and teams by&#xD;
      altering their senses, manual skills and ability to communicate. Current guidelines (WHO, UK,&#xD;
      ECDC) offer flexibility in terms of which specific PPE components can safely be used. Yet, in&#xD;
      some organisations, healthcare workers become used to using PPE well above the recommended&#xD;
      standards (termed further in text as super-safe setup, SSS). Impact of this PPE policy on&#xD;
      team performance and in turn to patient safety is unknown. We hypothesise that SSS, as&#xD;
      compared to WHO PPE standard, would negatively impact team performance and patient outcomes&#xD;
      in a simulated crisis scenario.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods Design: prospective, open, randomised, controlled, parallel group trial, fully&#xD;
      compliant with CONSORT guidelines with extension for simulation studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study subjects: doctors and nurses routinely working in intensive care, written prospective&#xD;
      informed consent Setting: High-fidelity simulation centre, Third Faculty of Medicine, Charles&#xD;
      University in Prague&#xD;
&#xD;
      PPE tested&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  WHO group (CONTROL): uses polycarbonate safety spectacles, fluid-resistant (Type IIR)&#xD;
           surgical mask and disposable surgical gown. One pair of gloves. No head or foot cover.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  SSS group: Uses surgical cap, FFP3 respirator covered by surgical mask, face shield,&#xD;
           whole-body suit (Tyvec), 3 pairs of gloves typed to suit sleeves and disposable foot&#xD;
           cover&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study procedures: Teams consisting of one doctor and two nurses will be recruited. The&#xD;
      purpose of the study will be explained to them as a part of consent procedure, but details of&#xD;
      evaluation and scenarios will remain undisclosed. All team members will obtain standardized&#xD;
      educational materials focused on the solution of airway management and non-shockable rhythm&#xD;
      of sudden circulatory arrest in a critically ill patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Introduction to simulation centre and baseline team performance measurement: On the&#xD;
           study day the teams will undergo a standardised introduction to simulation centre and&#xD;
           perform a mock scenario without PPE apart from gloves and simple surgical masks. The&#xD;
           same parameters will be measured for mock scenario as for the test scenario.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Test scenario: This will be a COVID-19 patient on mechanical ventilator who suddenly&#xD;
           loses airways and develops profound hypoxia progressing to cardiac arrest. Team will be&#xD;
           wearing PPE according to their study group allocation at the beginning of the scenario.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcomes:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Primary outcome: Non-technical team performance measured as TEAM score and adjusted to&#xD;
      baseline team performance&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Secondary outcomes: Quality of CPR and work according to guidelines&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Exploratory qualitative objective: physiological functions of team members and&#xD;
      self-reported confidence defined on visual analogue scale&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome assessment methods: Performance indices will be observed by two independent, trained&#xD;
      assessors. Both assessors will have access to video recordings of scenarios and software&#xD;
      recordings. The final score will be an arithmetic mean of the scores of two observers.&#xD;
      Inter-rater variability will be calculated and reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size calculation and statistics: According to [ref] the TEAM performance score was&#xD;
      3.3±0.7 (mean±standard deviation). Therefore, n=22 (i.e. 11 teams per group) gives 80%&#xD;
      probability of detecting at p&lt;0.05 (two sided) 25% difference of TEAM scores between groups.&#xD;
      Primary outcome will be calculated by two sided Student t-test. Time-to-event outcomes will&#xD;
      be compared using Kaplan-Meier curves and Wilcoxon test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dissemination plan and implementation: Data will be published in a peer-reviewed journal. The&#xD;
      results have the potential to influence hospital hygiene policies as well as choices made by&#xD;
      individual healthcare professionals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>single-center, randomized (1:1), parallel-group, simulation study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Blinding of participants and researchers involved in the experiment is not possible. Only the outcome assessor and data analyst is kept blinded to the allocation of subjects.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Team Emergency Assessment Measure score (TEAM score)</measure>
    <time_frame>During the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The TEAM questionaire will be used and will address following items: 1) the team leader let the team know what was expected of them through direction and command, 2) the team leader maintained a global perspective, 3) the team communicated effectively, 4) the team worked together to complete tasks in a timely manner, 5) the team acted with composure and control, 6) the team morale was positive, 7)the team adapted to changing situations, 8) the team monitored and reassessed the situation, 9) the team anticipated potential actions, 10) the team prioritized tasks, 11) the team followed approved standards/guidelines and 12) the global score. The TEAM items 1 - 11 will be rated using a five-point scale (range 0-4; 0 never/hardly ever, 1 seldom, 2 about as often as not, 3 often, 4 always/nearly always). The item 12 (global score) - the overall performance will be rated on scale from 1 to 10 (best). The mean for each item will be calculated.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to first chest compression</measure>
    <time_frame>During the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Time to first chest compression from the start of the scenario will be measured in seconds. Time will be obtained from the software recording of the simulator as time to first compression to reach depth at least 5cm.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to first epinephrine dose administration</measure>
    <time_frame>During the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The time to to first epinephrine dose administration (seconds) will be measured by observer and checked from the simulator recording.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to first effective breath after reintubation</measure>
    <time_frame>During the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The time to perform the first effective breath (tidal volume of at least 400ml) after reintubation will be measured in seconds . The time will be obtained from the software recording of the simulator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Chest compression frequency</measure>
    <time_frame>During the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Average chest compression rate (per minute) will be calculated from from the software recording of the simulator. In addition, the percentage of time out of the total compression time, when the frequency of 100-120 per minute was reached, will be measured.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Chest compression depth</measure>
    <time_frame>During the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Average chest compression depth (cm) will be obtained from the software recording of the simulator. In addition, the percentage of compressions reaching a depth of 5 - 6 cm from the total number of compressions will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Blood pressure of team members</measure>
    <time_frame>During the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Blood pressure of all the team members will be monitored in two minutes intervals throughout the simulation.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Heart rate of team members</measure>
    <time_frame>During the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Heart rate of all the team members will be monitored continuously throughout the simulation.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Breathing frequency</measure>
    <time_frame>During the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The breathing frequency will be measured in all the team members in resting condition and than continuously throughout the simulation.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Body temperature of team members</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Blood temperature of all the team members will be measured in resting condition and at the end of the simulated scenario.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Self assessment of the team performance</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The self assessment of the team performance by all the teams members will be obtained. The score will be evaluated by the team members from one to ten points, where ten points indicate the best possible performance.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">22</enrollment>
  <condition>Safety Issues</condition>
  <condition>Communication</condition>
  <condition>Cardiopulmonary Arrest</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>WHO group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>minimal setting of personal protective equipment (COVID 19) recommended by WHO</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Super-safe setup</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>maximal super-safe setup of personal protective equipment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>WHO recommended PPE</intervention_name>
    <description>Uses polycarbonate safety spectacles, fluid-resistant (Type IIR) surgical mask and disposable surgical gown. No head or foot cover.</description>
    <arm_group_label>WHO group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Super-safe setup</intervention_name>
    <description>Uses surgical cap, FFP3 respirator covered by surgical mask, face shield, whole-body suit (Tyvec), 3 pairs of gloves typed to suit sleeves and disposable foot cover.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Super-safe setup</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Emergency Medicine (EM) and Anesthesiology and Critical Care (ACC) physicians&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Emergency Medicine (EM) and Anesthesiology and Critical Care (ACC) nurses&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preparation and study of sent educational materials&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fulfillment of the whole complete simulation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not giving or withdrawal of the informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not willing to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Incomplete data acqusition&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Frantisek Duska, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Third Medical Faculty and FNKV University Hospital, Charles University in Prague, Czech Republic</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Roman Sykora, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+420602524203</phone>
    <email>roman.sykora@lf3.cuni.cz</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Metodej Renza, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+420607554375</phone>
    <email>metodej.renza@seznam.cz</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mormando G, Paganini M, Alexopoulos C, Savino S, Bortoli N, Pomiato D, Graziano A, Navalesi P, Fabris F. Life-Saving Procedures Performed While Wearing CBRNe Personal Protective Equipment: A Mannequin Randomized Trial. Simul Healthc. 2021 Jan 8;Publish Ahead of Print. doi: 10.1097/SIH.0000000000000540. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>33428358</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Cooper S, Cant R, Porter J, Sellick K, Somers G, Kinsman L, Nestel D. Rating medical emergency teamwork performance: development of the Team Emergency Assessment Measure (TEAM). Resuscitation. 2010 Apr;81(4):446-52. doi: 10.1016/j.resuscitation.2009.11.027. Epub 2010 Feb 1.</citation>
    <PMID>20117874</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Charles University, Czech Republic</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Roman Sýkora</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>assistant professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Personal Protective Equipment</keyword>
  <keyword>Simulation Study</keyword>
  <keyword>Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-Technical Skills</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Arrest</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All data, forms, consents and protocols will be provided on reasonable request by investigators.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

