<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2910">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04444115</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>802810-1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04444115</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Loneliness During Strict and Lifted Social Distancing Protocols Against the COVID-19 Pandemic</brief_title>
  <official_title>Loneliness During the COVID-19 Pandemic: Change and Predictors of Change From Strict to Lifted Social Distancing Protocols</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Modum Bad</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Oslo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Modum Bad</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Description The aim of the present study is to investigate (a) changes in the levels of&#xD;
      loneliness in the general adult population from a period of strict distancing protocols&#xD;
      designed to impede transmission of the corona virus (T1) to a later period of lifted&#xD;
      distancing protocols period (T2), (b) the risk and resilience factors for persistence in&#xD;
      loneliness across these periods and (c) the associations between loneliness at T1 and changes&#xD;
      in loneliness from T1 to T2 and changes in psychopathology symptoms from T1 to T2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An investigation of loneliness persistence in addition to its association with risk factors&#xD;
      and the persistence of psychopathology provides a knowledge basis for employing interventions&#xD;
      that protect the general public against increased distress and dysfunction during and after&#xD;
      society's handling of pandemics.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Hypotheses and research questions:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypotheses (Hs) and explorative research questions of the present study were:&#xD;
&#xD;
      H1: The lifting of the social distancing protocols are associated with decreased loneliness.&#xD;
      Exploratory question 1. What is the proportion showing a reliable change in loneliness?&#xD;
      Exploratory question 2. What are the associations of the stable (demographic) factors age,&#xD;
      gender, educational level, civil status, employment status, psychiatric diagnosis status and&#xD;
      refugee status with change in loneliness from T1 to T2? H2: Of psychological factors, higher&#xD;
      level at T1 and less reduction from T1 to T2 in worry about job and/or economy, worry about&#xD;
      health (health anxiety), maladaptive mental and behavioral coping, and negative and positive&#xD;
      metacognitions will be associated with less reduction in loneliness from T1 to T2, above and&#xD;
      beyond the influence of pre-existing stable risk factors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Explorative question 3. What are the potential protective effects of doing new positive&#xD;
      activities at home, experiencing nature and performing aerobic physical exercise? That is, is&#xD;
      higher level at T1 and more increase from T1 and T2 of these activities related to more&#xD;
      reduction of loneliness from T1 to T2? H3: More loneliness at T1 will be associated with less&#xD;
      reduction of depressive and anxiety symptoms from T1 to T2. Less reduction in loneliness from&#xD;
      T1 to T2 will be associated with less reduction of symptoms in the same time frame. Because&#xD;
      variables related to loneliness may confound the relationship between loneliness and&#xD;
      psychopathology symptoms, the variables showing significant associations for Hypothesis 2 and&#xD;
      3 will be controlled for. However, psychiatric diagnosis will not be included as a control&#xD;
      variable because T1 level of depression and anxiety symptoms is controlled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design and participants The design is a longitudinal observational survey of the&#xD;
      general adult Norwegian population during the COVID-19 pandemic. Eligible participants are&#xD;
      all individuals of 18 years and above, who are living in Norway and thus experience identical&#xD;
      distancing protocols, and who provide informed consent to participate in the study. The&#xD;
      strict distancing protocols were implemented in Norway at March 12. 2020 and the first data&#xD;
      collection in this period has already been done. It lasted seven days and was between March&#xD;
      31st 2020 and April 7th 2020. Thus, the strict protocols had been held constant during the&#xD;
      two weeks prior to data collection, as well as during the data collection week. Furthermore,&#xD;
      no new information was given by the government during this period with regard to changes of&#xD;
      distancing protocols, keeping expectation effects constant. From June 15., the majority of&#xD;
      the strict distancing protocols will be lifted in Norway, and lifted distancing protocol&#xD;
      period is defined from this date. Data are set to be collected from the sample providing data&#xD;
      in the first collection (N = 10 084), starting one week after the lifting data, that is, from&#xD;
      22th of June. The collection will last until enough data has been collected, but no longer&#xD;
      than three weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethical approval of the study was granted by The Regional Committee for Medical and Health&#xD;
      Research Ethics and the Norwegian Centre for Research Data (reference numbers: 125510 and&#xD;
      802810, respectively, where the study protocol and analysis plan was approved prior to data&#xD;
      collection. The study is conducted in accordance with the guidelines of the Strengthening the&#xD;
      Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology statement (STROBE; Von Elm et al., 2007).&#xD;
      The pre-registered protocol for a study of loneliness based on the first T1 data collection&#xD;
      can be found at Clinicaltrials.gov (Identifier: NCT04365881). The study is part of The&#xD;
      Norwegian COVID-19, Mental Health and Adherence Project (Ebrahimi, Hoffart, &amp; Johnson, 2020).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures The survey was disseminated online in a systematic manner to give the adult&#xD;
      population an equal opportunity to participate in the study. The dissemination procedure&#xD;
      involved information about the survey through broadcasting on national, regional, and local&#xD;
      news channels and provision of the online survey to a random selection of Norwegian adults on&#xD;
      Facebook. The dissemination procedure is described in detail elsewhere (Ebrahimi et al.,&#xD;
      2020).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The stopping rule for the first data collection was designed to ensure that the social&#xD;
      distancing protocols were held constant for two weeks prior to and the week during the data&#xD;
      collection period, as well as controlling for expectation effects by stopping data collection&#xD;
      instantly once information concerning forthcoming modification of the protocols were given.&#xD;
      The second data collection will start one week after the social distancing protocols are&#xD;
      lifted (June 22.) and last three weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inference criteria Given the large sample size in this study, the investigators pre-define&#xD;
      their significance level: p &lt; 0.001 to determine significance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size and power The sample size T1 included 10 084 participants, ascertaining power for&#xD;
      the questions asked. For the present study, all these participants will be invited to&#xD;
      participate at T2 in accordance with the study plan.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analyses Repeated surveys like the present one typically have a lot of drop out&#xD;
      and missing data. Therefore, we will use mixed models instead of paired t-tests, repeated&#xD;
      measures ANOVAs, and ordinary least square regression to analyze the data. Mixed models use&#xD;
      maximum likelihood estimation, which is the state of the art approach to handle missing data&#xD;
      (Schafer &amp; Graham, 2002). Especially if data are missing at random, which is likely in our&#xD;
      survey, mixed models give more unbiased results than the other analytic methods (O'Connel et&#xD;
      al., 2017).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In preliminary analyses, and for each of the dependent variables (ULS-8, PHQ-9, GAD-7), the&#xD;
      combination of random effects and covariance structure of residuals that gives the best fit&#xD;
      for the &quot;empty&quot; model (the model without fixed predictors except the intercept) will be&#xD;
      chosen. Akaike's Information Criterion (AIC) will used to compare the fit of different&#xD;
      models. Models that give a reduction in AIC greater than 2 will be considered better (Burnham&#xD;
      &amp; Anderson, 2004). The program SPSS 25.0 will be used (IBM Corp, 2018).&#xD;
&#xD;
      First, H1 about decrease in ULS-8 will be tested by using ULS-8 as dependent variable in a&#xD;
      model using time (T1 = 0, T2 = 1) as a predictor. Second, demographic group variables will be&#xD;
      added as predictors. Third, the T1 levels of worry about job and/or economy, worry about&#xD;
      health (health anxiety), maladaptive mental and behavioral coping, and negative and positive&#xD;
      metacognitions as constant covariates will be added, together with the interactions of these&#xD;
      constant covariates with time. These interactions represent tests of H2 about the covariates&#xD;
      predicting change in loneliness. Finally, the T2 levels of worry about job and/or economy,&#xD;
      worry about health (health anxiety), maladaptive mental and behavioral coping, and negative&#xD;
      and positive metacognitions as constant covariates will be added, together with the&#xD;
      interactions of these constant covariates with time. These interactions represent tests of H2&#xD;
      about the change in the covariates from T1 to T2 predicting change in loneliness from T1 to&#xD;
      T2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To analyze the influence of level and change in loneliness on change in depression and&#xD;
      anxiety (H3), depression and anxiety are used as dependent variables in two mixed models,&#xD;
      with first the interaction of time with loneliness at T1 and then the interaction of time&#xD;
      with loneliness at T2 as covariates. The main effects of these variables are included as well&#xD;
      as all significant terms from the analyses of loneliness as dependent variable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Reliable change in loneliness will be assessed using the formula of Jacobson and Truax&#xD;
      (1991). The statistical analyses were done in the program SPSS 25.0 (IBM Corp, 2018).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sensitivity analyses Sensitivity analyses will be conducted after selecting a random sample&#xD;
      of participants to reflect the proportion of subgroups in the Norwegian adult population.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 22, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 13, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 13, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Ecologic or Community</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>UCLA Loneliness Scale-8 (ULS-8)</measure>
    <time_frame>From 22nd of June to 13th of July</time_frame>
    <description>The UCLA Loneliness Scale-8 (ULS-8; Hays &amp; DiMatteo, 1987) measures the frequency and intensity of aspects of the lonely experience, using a 1 (never), 2 (rarely), 3 (sometimes) and 4 (often) scale. A composite score is computed by summing the items after reverse coding when appropriate, with composites ranging from 8 to 32. A score greater than half the maximum score (16) has been used to indicate caseness (Shevlin, Murphy, Mallett, Stringer, &amp; Murphy, 2013). This implies that respondents at least sometimes experience at least one of the loneliness aspects described in the 8 items. The ULS-8 has demonstrated good psychometric properties (Hays &amp; DiMatteo, 1987; Hartshorne, 1993).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9)</measure>
    <time_frame>From 22nd of June to 13th of July</time_frame>
    <description>The Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9; Kroenke, Spitzer, &amp; Williams, 2001) consists of nine items covering the DSM-IV criteria for major depression scored on a four-point 0 (not at all) to 3 (almost every day) scale, with total scores ranging from 0 to 27. The PHQ-9 has revealed good psychometric properties, as demonstrated by Kroenke, Spitzer, and Williams (2001).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Generalized Anxiety Disorder-7 (GAD-7)</measure>
    <time_frame>From 22nd of June to 13th of July</time_frame>
    <description>The Generalized Anxiety Disorder-7 (GAD-7; Kroenke, Spitzer, Williams, Monahan &amp; Löwe, 2007) consists of seven items covering the DSM-IV criteria for GAD scored on a four-point 0 (not at all) to 3 (almost every day) scale, with total scores ranging from 0 to 21. The GAD-7 has revealed construct validity and reliability (Kroenke et al., 2007; Löwe et al., 2008).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10084</enrollment>
  <condition>Loneliness During COVID-19</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Eligible participants are all individuals of 18 years and above, who are living in Norway&#xD;
        and thus experience identical distancing protocols, and who provide informed consent to&#xD;
        participate in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  all adults residing in Norway&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  none&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Omid Ebrahimi, Cand Psychol</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Oslo and Modum Bad</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Asle Hoffart, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Modum Bad and University of Oslo</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sverre Urnes Johnson, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Oslo and Modum Bad</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Asle Hoffart, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+4790594733</phone>
    <email>asle.hoffart@modum-bad.no</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sverre Urnes Johnson, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+4741633313</phone>
    <email>Sverre.Johnson@modum-bad.no</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>June 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 20, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 23, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 20, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 20, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 23, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Modum Bad</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Asle Hoffart</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prof</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19, social distancing, loneliness, worry, rumination, depression, anxiety</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

