<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4760">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04563494</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-1742</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04563494</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effects of IV vs Oral Dexamethasone on Postoperative Nausea, Vomiting, and Pain</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effects of IV vs Oral Dexamethasone on Postoperative Nausea, Vomiting, Pain, and Drug Cost in Children Undergoing Tonsillectomy: A Randomized Controlled Prospective Non-inferiority Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Colorado, Denver</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Colorado, Denver</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The hypothesis being tested in this study is that perioperative oral administration of&#xD;
      dexamethasone, when compared to intravenous (IV) administration, offers a similar reduction&#xD;
      in postoperative nausea and vomiting (PONV), and reduction in postoperative pain in pediatric&#xD;
      patients undergoing tonsillectomy with or without adenoidectomy and/or tympanostomy tube&#xD;
      placement. The specific aim of this study is to demonstrate non-inferiority of oral&#xD;
      dexamethasone when compared to IV dexamethasone, given that there is currently a severe,&#xD;
      sudden, and world-wide shortage of IV dexamethasone given its recent use in treating patients&#xD;
      with covid19 disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      written consent, patients will be randomized at the time of arrival to the preoperative care&#xD;
      center on the day of surgery. One hundred twenty-six patients, 3 to 7 years of age undergoing&#xD;
      tonsillectomy with or without adenoidectomy and tympanostomy tube placement, will be included&#xD;
      in this study. Children who received antiemetics, steroids, anti-histaminic, or psychoactive&#xD;
      drugs during the week before surgery will be excluded. Patients will be prospectively&#xD;
      randomized to receive oral or IV dexamethasone 0.5 mg/kg (maximum dose 8 mg). Patients in the&#xD;
      IV group will receive the dose once an IV is placed in the operating room. They will receive&#xD;
      an oral placebo once consent is obtained on arrival to the preoperative center on the day of&#xD;
      surgery. Patients in the oral group will receive their dose once consent is obtained on&#xD;
      arrival to the preoperative center on the day of surgery. They will receive a placebo once&#xD;
      the IV is placed in the operating room. Randomization will be via a computer-generated table&#xD;
      of numbers. Study drugs will be marked only with a coded number label. The anesthesiologist,&#xD;
      surgeon, patient, and family will be unaware of drug identity. All medication preparation and&#xD;
      handling will be done by CHCO Investigational Drug Service.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be fasted for solid foods for eight hours before surgery; clear liquids will be&#xD;
      permitted until two hours before surgery. A standard anesthetic technique will be used.&#xD;
      Premedication with oral acetaminophen 12.5-15 mg/kg will be given on arrival to the&#xD;
      preoperative center. After obtaining consent study drug or placebo will be given at least 20&#xD;
      minutes before surgery. General anesthesia will be induced with sevoflurane and 60% nitrous&#xD;
      oxide in oxygen via mask followed by insertion of an intravenous (IV) cannula. Dexamethasone&#xD;
      or placebo will be given immediately following IV placement. Propofol 2 mg/kg and fentanyl 1&#xD;
      µg/kg will be given to facilitate intubation. Anesthesia will be maintained with a mixture of&#xD;
      sevoflurane and air (FiO2 &lt; 0.3All children will receive fentanyl 1-3 µg/kg (titrated to pain&#xD;
      response in the operating room) and dexmedetomidine 0.5 µg/kg once surgery starts. All&#xD;
      children will receive ondansetron 0.1 mg/kg (maximum dose 4 mg).All children will receive 20&#xD;
      mL/kg lactated Ringer's solution during surgery (maximum IV fluid 750 mL given short time of&#xD;
      surgical procedure). Routine monitoring including heart rate (ECG), arterial oxygen&#xD;
      saturation (SpO2), blood pressure, temperature and end-tidal CO2 will be used throughout&#xD;
      surgery. Surgical technique will be standardized, and all patients will have their stomachs&#xD;
      suctioned at the completion of surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each subject will be assessed by nursing staff utilizing standard of care practices in the&#xD;
      PACU and patients will stay in the PACU (phase one and two) for 4 hours after surgery.&#xD;
      Postoperative nausea and vomiting (PONV) will be defined as vomiting and/or retching without&#xD;
      expulsion of gastric content and will be treated with IV phenergan (0.25 mg/kg, maximum 25&#xD;
      mg) followed, if necessary, by IV diphenhydramine (1 mg/kg maximum 50 mg). Pain will be&#xD;
      assessed using the numeric pain scale 0-10, Faces, Legs, Arms, Crying, Consolability Scale&#xD;
      (FLACC Scale), or Revised Faces Scale.12,13 Pain scores &gt; 5 will be treated with IV fentanyl&#xD;
      0.5 µg/kg that can be repeated every 5 minutes for pain when necessary.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of post op nausea and vomiting</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours</time_frame>
    <description>post-op nausea and vomiting as evidenced by vomiting and/or retching without expulsion of gastric content</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>pain scores and surgical re-exploration for bleeding</measure>
    <time_frame>4 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Pain as evidenced by a numeric pain scale 0-10, Faces, Legs, Arms, Crying, Consolability Scale (FLACC Scale), or Revised Faces Scale.12,13 .&#xD;
surgical re-exploration as evidenced by the return to O.R. for bleeding</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">126</enrollment>
  <condition>Nausea and Vomiting, Postoperative</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IV Dexmethsone and oral placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Oral dexamethasone and IV placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>dexamethasone</intervention_name>
    <description>Prevention of post op nausea and vomiting</description>
    <arm_group_label>IV Dexmethsone and oral placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Oral dexamethasone and IV placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  3-7 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  tonsillectomy with or without adenoidectomy and tympanostomy tube placement&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects receiving one week before surgery:&#xD;
&#xD;
             •-antiemetics&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  steroids&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  anti-histaminic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  psychoactive drugs&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>7 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Melissa Brooks Peterson, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Colorado, Denver</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Melissa Brooks Peterson, MD</last_name>
    <phone>720-777-7068</phone>
    <email>melissa.brooks@childrenscolorado.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nausea</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Postoperative Nausea and Vomiting</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

