<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3152">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04694014</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IREC/2020/143 AN0003667W500G</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04694014</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Emotional Intelligence Skills Health Leaders Need During Covid-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Emotional Intelligence Skills Leaders and Managers Need to Engage Frontline Healthcare Professionals During Covid-19 Pandemic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>African Wood Inc</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Alupe University College</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>African Wood Inc</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Problem The study will address the problem that no studies have established the Emotional&#xD;
      Intelligence (EI) skills required by leaders and managers to engage frontline healthcare&#xD;
      professionals in crisis situation like Covid19 in Kenya Purpose The purpose of the&#xD;
      qualitative exploratory study is to identify the EI skills Leaders and managers need to&#xD;
      engage Frontline Healthcare Professionals in Crisis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Research Question is:&#xD;
&#xD;
      What are the EI skills leaders and managers need to engage frontline healthcare professionals&#xD;
      (FHP) during crisis situations such as the Covid19 pandemic?&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Hypothesis The Study hypothesis that Leaders and managers with appropriate emotional&#xD;
      intelligence skills will engage frontline healthcare professionals in crisis situations&#xD;
      resulting in desired outcomes Data Collection The data collection will start with a primer&#xD;
      survey on surveymonkey.com, behavioral and cognitive assessments through The Predictive&#xD;
      Index, emotional intelligence competence assessments through emco4.com, followed by&#xD;
      semi-structured face to face or virtual interviews with the participants. The Survey data,&#xD;
      Assessments and the transcribed semi-structured interviews will be depersonalized and made&#xD;
      available for subsequent researchers. The Videos if any will be destroyed three years after&#xD;
      transcription.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants The 20 Participants will be selected from the population. The Study population&#xD;
      is the number of experienced frontline healthcare professionals working in Busia County of&#xD;
      Kenya. The County Department of Health will help in recruiting participants from doctors,&#xD;
      nurses, and other frontline healthcare professionals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Analysis The Data will be analyzed using DiscoverText.com cloud-based platform applying&#xD;
      two rounds of coding: first in Vivo coding will be applied then prior codes will be enforced.&#xD;
      The Vivo codes will be in the participant's word and voice. Eight priori codes will be&#xD;
      adopted from EI literature.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Societal Benefits Society needs healthcare professionals to deal with crisis situations that&#xD;
      place them in imperilment. The leaders have constraints of resources, time and advanced&#xD;
      knowledge. This study seeks to seek out EI skills that will enable leaders to engage&#xD;
      healthcare professionals while recognizing the humanity in them.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Emotional Intelligence Competences Frontline Healthcare Professional need in their Leaders</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The EI Competences that the participants stated that are needed from their leaders by questioner</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EI Competence of Participants</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The Geneva Emotional Competence (GECO) test measure of EI for each participant compared the stated EI needed by Leaders</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Participant Behavioral Analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Behavioral Outcome by Predictive Index Proprietary scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Emotional Intelligence</condition>
  <condition>Leadership</condition>
  <condition>Health Personnel Attitude</condition>
  <condition>Covid-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Emotional Intelligence Skills study among frontline HCW managing Covid19 in Busia Kenya</arm_group_label>
    <description>Researchers from Alupe University College will select study participants as follows 6 Clinical officers, 2 nurses, 1 nutritionist, 1 lab technician, 2 lab technologists, 7 members on the sub county surveillance Matayos, Teso north and Bunyala 2 from UHC office</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>EI Open ended Pre-Survey and Semi Structured Interview</intervention_name>
    <description>Provide Interview questions via online survey with informed consent to the participants then contact a 60 minute member checking interview in person or virtually via recorded Zoom sessions for each participant</description>
    <arm_group_label>Emotional Intelligence Skills study among frontline HCW managing Covid19 in Busia Kenya</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Behavioral and Cognitive Assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>Use Predictive index for both cognitive and behavioral assessment of the paticipants</description>
    <arm_group_label>Emotional Intelligence Skills study among frontline HCW managing Covid19 in Busia Kenya</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Geneva Emotional Competence Test (GECO)</intervention_name>
    <description>Administer the Geneva Emotional Competence Test to each participant</description>
    <arm_group_label>Emotional Intelligence Skills study among frontline HCW managing Covid19 in Busia Kenya</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Experienced healthcare professionals practicing in Busia County Kenya. Their experience,&#xD;
        knowledge, and insights in the interface between leaders and frontline healthcare workers&#xD;
        will be very helpful to society at large. The 20 Participants will be selected from the&#xD;
        population. The Study population is the number of experienced frontline healthcare&#xD;
        professionals working in Busia County of Kenya. The County Department of Health will help&#xD;
        in recruiting participants from doctors, nurses, and other frontline healthcare&#xD;
        professionals&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Experience frontline healthcare professionals working in Busia County of Kenya&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None healthcare professionals&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  healthcare professionals not working in Busia county&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>67 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Fabian Esamai, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Alupe University College</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>William Okedi, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Alupe University College</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David F AMAKOBE, DBA</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>W500G Inc - Contract Research Organization</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alupe University College</name>
      <address>
        <city>Busia</city>
        <zip>50400</zip>
        <country>Kenya</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Kenya</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Boyatzis RE. The Behavioral Level of Emotional Intelligence and Its Measurement. Front Psychol. 2018 Aug 13;9:1438. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01438. eCollection 2018. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30150958</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Roth G, Vansteenkiste M, Ryan RM. Integrative emotion regulation: Process and development from a self-determination theory perspective. Dev Psychopathol. 2019 Aug;31(3):945-956. doi: 10.1017/S0954579419000403. Epub 2019 May 22. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31113502</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ng JY, Ntoumanis N, Thøgersen-Ntoumani C, Deci EL, Ryan RM, Duda JL, Williams GC. Self-Determination Theory Applied to Health Contexts: A Meta-Analysis. Perspect Psychol Sci. 2012 Jul;7(4):325-40. doi: 10.1177/1745691612447309.</citation>
    <PMID>26168470</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brackett MA, Salovey P. Measuring emotional intelligence with the Mayer-Salovery-Caruso Emotional Intelligence Test (MSCEIT). Psicothema. 2006;18 Suppl:34-41. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17295955</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schlegel K, Mortillaro M. The Geneva Emotional Competence Test (GECo): An ability measure of workplace emotional intelligence. J Appl Psychol. 2019 Apr;104(4):559-580. doi: 10.1037/apl0000365. Epub 2018 Oct 22.</citation>
    <PMID>30346195</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 31, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 31, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 31, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The data collection will start with a primer survey on surveymonkey.com, behavioral and cognitive assessments through The Predictive Index, emotional intelligence competence assessments through emco4.com, followed by semi-structured face to face or virtual interviews with the participants. The Survey data, Assessments and the transcribed semi-structured interviews will be depersonalized and made available for subsequent researchers. The Videos if any will be destroyed three years after transcription.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The Study report will be published six months after the end of the study. The Behavioral Assessment data, the interview results and the GECO will be depersonalized and made available on request from W500G Inc</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>On specific request and agreement to data safety and participant privacy</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

