<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4799">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04685759</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STU-2020-0948</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04685759</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Exercise Regimens and Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Assessing the Non-inferiority of Virtual vs. In-person Concurrent Exercise Regimens in Patients Receiving Neoadjuvant Therapy Prior to Surgical Resection of a Primary GI Tumor</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to assess the effectiveness of exercise therapy for patients&#xD;
      undergoing neoadjuvant chemotherapy for primary gastrointestinal (GI) tract cancer, providing&#xD;
      a reproducible exercise regimen designed to improve or preserve aerobic fitness, strength,&#xD;
      and quality of life. In addition, this study will address shifts in healthcare delivery&#xD;
      needed as a result of the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic, evaluating the&#xD;
      effectiveness of telehealth instruction as a method for exercise therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study hypotheses are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To evaluate the effectiveness of exercise therapy for cancer patients undergoing&#xD;
           neoadjuvant treatment when delivered via telehealth, as compared to an in-person&#xD;
           setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To assess stair test instrumentation, previously validated in a healthy population, as a&#xD;
           measure to gauge health status in cancer patients undergoing neoadjuvant treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To assess patient satisfaction with exercise therapy when delivered via telehealth, as&#xD;
           compared to an in-person setting.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      After being informed about the study and potential risks and benefits, all patients meeting&#xD;
      inclusion criteria who provide written informed consent will be randomized at the time of&#xD;
      enrollment to one of two cohorts engaged in a standardized exercise regimen based on delivery&#xD;
      method, either in-person or via telehealth. Patient function will be assessed using the Timed&#xD;
      Up and Go (TUG) test; Stairs Test; which evaluates aerobic ability, resistance, agility,&#xD;
      balance, and posture; and given a score on the Karnofsky Performance Status Scale. Patient&#xD;
      quality of life will be assessed using the Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy - General&#xD;
      (FACT-G) survey. Outcomes for the cohorts will be compared over time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in patient function as measured by Karnosfky Performance Status Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline prior to initial exercise therapy session, midpoint(at 12 sessions), neoadjuvant chemotherapy completion prior to surgery, and 30 days post-operative surgery for tumor removal.</time_frame>
    <description>The Karnosfky Performance Status Scale measures the ability of cancer patients to perform ordinary tasks. Possible scores range from 0 to 100 by increments of 10, with higher scores indicating that patients are better able to carry out daily activities.&#xD;
Patient function will be assessed using the Timed Up and Go (TUG) test, Stairs Test, which evaluate patient's aerobic ability, resistance, agility, balance, and posture, as well as the Karnosfky Performance Status Scale. Patient quality of life will be assessed using the Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy - General (FACT-G) survey. All assessments will be completed at baseline, prior to the initial exercise therapy session, at midpoint, and at the final session prior to surgery, as well as 30 days post-surgery. Exercise therapy will be deemed effective by preventing a reduction to patient function and quality of life over the course of enrollment in the study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean total Patient Satisfaction score of Telehealth Exercise Therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after administration of each exercise session</time_frame>
    <description>The Virtual Exercise Protocol Satisfaction Survey Scale (VEPSS1) measures patient satisfaction with the service delivery method of the exercise intervention. This is a researcher-designed survey for use in this study. Possible scores range from 0 to 20, with higher scores indicating a better outcome. The VEPSS1 will be used for telehealth cohort only.&#xD;
Satisfaction will be summarize as a continuous score for the participant populations. Median and interquartile ranges of the score will be recorded. Differences in comprehension will be measured between the In-Person Exercise Protocol Satisfaction Survey Scale and the VEPSS1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean total Patient Satisfaction score of In-Person Exercise Therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after administration of each exercise session</time_frame>
    <description>The In-Person Exercise Protocol Satisfaction Survey Scale (IPEPSS1) measures patient satisfaction with the in-person service delivery method of the exercise intervention. This is a researcher-designed survey for use in this study. Possible scores range from 0 to 20, with higher scores indicating a better outcome. The IPEPSS1 will be used for in-person exercise cohort only.&#xD;
Satisfaction will be summarize as a continuous score for the participant populations. Median and interquartile ranges of the score will be recorded. Differences in comprehension will be measured between the IPEPSS1 and the VEPSS1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean change of FACT-G Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline prior to initial exercise therapy session, midpoint(at 12 sessions), neoadjuvant chemotherapy completion prior to surgery, and 30 days post-operative surgery for tumor removal.</time_frame>
    <description>The Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy - General (FACT-G) survey measures patient quality of life. This validated survey contains 27 items measured by a 5 point Likert-type scale in 4 domains relevant to cancer patients: Physical, Social, Emotional, and Functional well-being.&#xD;
Possible scores range from 0 to 108, with higher scores indicating a better quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The mean change in Stair Test assessment score</measure>
    <time_frame>Evaluated at individual patient completion of the exercise protocol (at about Week 12 through Week 24)</time_frame>
    <description>The Stair Test is a validated measurement to estimate cardiorespiratory fitness. This test has been previously validated in a healthy population. To then validate as a measure to gauge health status in cancer patients undergoing neoadjuvant treatment, results will be compared to those collected in Timed Up and Go test, where the total score or scores will then be used to determine the measure of agreement using the Concordance Correlation Coefficient.&#xD;
Patients in both study cohorts will be evaluated in person. The score range will be determined for each participant and compared to all participants in order to validate the test in this population. Scores will be calculated based on age, Body Mass Index (BMI), time of the stair climb in seconds (CT), and heart rate at the end of the climb (HRend, in beats•min-1).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancer of Gastrointestinal Tract</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>In-Person Exercise Protocol (IPEP)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group will receive exercise instruction and monitoring in-person from the certified Cancer Exercise Trainer (CET) in the gym facility at Moncrief Cancer Institute (MCI). Study participants will be scheduled for exercise sessions twice a week with the oncology exercise trainer.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Virtual Exercise Protocol (VEP)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group will receive exercise instruction and monitoring from the CET via telehealth sessions at home. Study participants will be scheduled for exercise sessions twice a week with the oncology exercise trainer.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>In-Person Exercise Protocol</intervention_name>
    <description>Supervised aerobic, resistance, flexibility, balance, and agility exercises, which could include yoga for a total of approximately 75 minutes per in-person session.</description>
    <arm_group_label>In-Person Exercise Protocol (IPEP)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Virtual Exercise Protocol</intervention_name>
    <description>Supervised aerobic, resistance, flexibility, balance, and agility exercises, which could include yoga for a total of approximately 75 minutes each virtual session. A TheraBand (resistance band) will be provided to patients in this group to be used for resistance and flexibility training.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Virtual Exercise Protocol (VEP)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 to 75 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary language is either English or Spanish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary cancer diagnosis of GI cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing neoadjuvant chemotherapy prior to surgical resection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients are being treated by medical oncologist at Simmons Cancer Center at Moncrief&#xD;
             Cancer Institute in Fort Worth&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has had systemic cancer treatment in the past year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient initiated neoadjuvant chemotherapy treatment prior to study enrollment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jay Lohrey</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Jay.Lohrey@UTSouthwestern.edu</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Emily Berry</last_name>
    <phone>817-288-9892</phone>
    <email>Emily.Berry@moncrief.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Melissa Irek</last_name>
    <phone>817-288-9884</phone>
    <email>Melissa.irek@moncrief.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 28, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 21, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 21, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 28, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jay Lohrey</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor, Internal Medicine / Harold S. Simmons Comprehensive Cancer Center</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Exercise Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer of Gastrointestinal Tract</keyword>
  <keyword>Neoadjuvant Therapies</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

