<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1301">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04659889</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LCV</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04659889</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical and Haematological Phenotypes in Long COVID</brief_title>
  <official_title>Analysis of the Relationship Between Clinical and Haematological Phenotypes in Long COVID</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>HCA International Limited</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>HCA International Limited</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Analysis of the relationship between clinical characteristics and haematological parameters&#xD;
      in long COVID.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The novel coronavirus (Covid19) pandemic declared by the World Health Organisation in March&#xD;
      2020 has had an enormous huge impact upon health, health systems and society. Early research&#xD;
      has focused on the acute illness caused by the virus. It is now clear that significant&#xD;
      numbers of patients infected with Covid19 continue to suffer with multiple, often severe,&#xD;
      unexplained symptoms for months after initial infection, so-called long-Covid.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Long-Covid symptoms are typically multi-system in their presentation comprising&#xD;
      constitutional changes (e.g. fever and fatigue), neuropsychiatric disturbance (e.g. anxiety,&#xD;
      insomnia and brain fog), neurosensory symptoms (e.g. headaches and pins and needles),&#xD;
      cardiorespiratory effects (e.g. breathlessness and chest pain), gastrointestinal dysfunction&#xD;
      (e.g. diarrhoea and food intolerances) and dermatological changes (e.g. rashes and vascular&#xD;
      changes).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objectives of this observational, cross-sectional, case-control study are to describe&#xD;
      long-Covid clinical phenotypes and to explore whether clinical symptom presentations&#xD;
      correlate with haematological and other inflammatory blood abnormalities that might shed&#xD;
      insight into underlying pathogenic mechanisms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will require the participation of long-Covid patients, seen in an outpatient&#xD;
      setting at The Physicians' Clinic, and will correlate clinical symptom phenotypes with&#xD;
      laboratory parameters we believe might be relevant to long-Covid. Recruitment of asymptomatic&#xD;
      patients, who have recovered from Covid19 infection, will provide a control patient group.&#xD;
      Eligible patients will be sent a patient information sheet, describing the study objectives&#xD;
      and protocol, inviting them to participate in the study and seeking consent for their&#xD;
      participation, which will require analysis of their [anonymised] clinical and laboratory&#xD;
      data. Clinical information will be retrieved from patient case records and patients will be&#xD;
      asked to complete a symptom questionnaire. All patients will require one blood sample to be&#xD;
      taken which will typically form part of their clinical care. Recruitment will occur over a 6&#xD;
      month period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      There are estimated to be tens of thousands of long-Covid patients in the UK, and the number&#xD;
      is set to grow as the pandemic continues. Little is known about the cause of long-Covid&#xD;
      clinical syndromes and there are no evidence-based treatments available to patients. There is&#xD;
      therefore an urgent need to undertake research into long-Covid.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Long-Covid referral to our general medical outpatient clinics has been growing, as these&#xD;
      patients typically present with multiple symptoms that require a holistic approach to patient&#xD;
      care. Patients are often distressed and disabled by their symptoms, exacerbated by the lack&#xD;
      of any detailed understanding about their condition, and the absence of specific treatment&#xD;
      strategies. Anecdotal reports of ongoing inflammation in long-Covid, not typically measurable&#xD;
      in routine blood tests, have prompted interest in exploring the nature of this inflammation&#xD;
      further. In addition, some long-Covid patients have reported clinical improvement following&#xD;
      empiric treatment with anti-inflammatory medications including anti-histamines and&#xD;
      corticosteroids. These clinical observations, and the enthusiasm expressed by the long-Covid&#xD;
      patient community for further research to be conducted, have been the key drivers for this&#xD;
      study. Patients attending our clinics have all without exception expressed their interest in&#xD;
      participating in this work.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This small sample size study sets out to explore whether there are identifiable abnormalities&#xD;
      in the blood cells of long-Covid patients that might correlate with patients' clinical&#xD;
      presentations which may in turn trigger further avenues of investigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study participants are all patients with a history of Covid19 infection and who either&#xD;
      have ongoing symptoms or who have fully recovered. The clinical information is available in&#xD;
      case records as part clinical care and patients' blood samples are sent for analysis as part&#xD;
      of ongoing clinical care. Patients are informed about their blood test results as part of&#xD;
      ongoing clinic care. All patients are provided with information about the study and asked to&#xD;
      consent to their anonymised clinical and laboratory data being used as part of this&#xD;
      observational study. We also seek consent to save serum for additional blood analysis&#xD;
      depending on the results of the initial study. No genetic investigations will be conducted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study does not involve any treatment intervention, and there is no risk of harm to&#xD;
      patients. The use of person-identifiable information will be restricted to an absolute&#xD;
      minimum, and all data will be anonymised for purposes of our study analysis. The members of&#xD;
      the research team all work within one organisation adhering to GDPR standards, and all email&#xD;
      communication remains within that organisation and is password-protected. No conflicts of&#xD;
      interest have been identified. We have undertaken to share individual results with&#xD;
      participating patients by the end of the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Observation of frequency of abnormal haematological parameters and association with long-Covid clinical phenotypes versus controls.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Long Covid</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with clinical features of Long Covid</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients who have had COVID-19 (PCR proven and/or clinical features of COVID-19) who are currently displaying symptoms of long Covid</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with no symptoms of Long Covid</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients who have had COVID-19 (PCR proven and/or clinical features of COVID-19) who are not displaying symptoms of long Covid</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Blood sampling (venesection)</intervention_name>
    <description>All study participants will have a single blood test to analyse the following parameters:&#xD;
(i) Serum biochemistry, CRP, Thyroid function and liver enzymes (ii) FBC, d-Dimer, ESR, Blood film (iii) SARS-CoV2 antibody status and serum save (iv) Peripheral blood immunophenotyping.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with clinical features of Long Covid</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with no symptoms of Long Covid</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The first group will be patients post documented SARS-CoV-2 infection displaying symptoms&#xD;
        of long Covid and the second group will be patients who are asymptomatic post documented&#xD;
        SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients post documented SARS-CoV-2 infection displaying symptoms of long Covid&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Asymptomatic post documented SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. All patients will be aged 18 or over&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients below the age of 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who have not previously had COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any adult deemed to trigger consideration of being a Vulnerable Adult.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Paul Glynne, Dr</last_name>
    <phone>07949252985</phone>
    <email>paulglynne@thephysiciansclinic.co.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Natasha Tahmasebi, Miss</last_name>
    <phone>07982999022</phone>
    <email>natasha.tahmasebi@hcahealthcare.co.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Physicians' Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>W1G 7AE</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mr Glynne, Dr</last_name>
      <email>paulglynne@thephysiciansclinic.co.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Natasha Tahmasebi, Miss</last_name>
      <phone>07982999022</phone>
      <email>natashatahmasebi@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rajeev Gupta, Dr</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Paul Glynne, Dr</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Vanya Gant, Dr</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Natasha Tahmasebi, Miss</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 7, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 7, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 7, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>HCA International Limited</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr Paul Glynne</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Consultant Physician</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

