<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3450">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on February 08, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04673318</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2151</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04673318</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Physical Rehabilitation of COVID-19 Survivors by Heat Therapy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Physical Rehabilitation of COVID-19 Survivors by Heat Therapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Massachusetts, Amherst</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Massachusetts, Amherst</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Older adults and people with underlying medical conditions are at higher risk for developing&#xD;
      serious complications related to SARS-CoV-2 resulting in prolonged sequelae. The goal of this&#xD;
      proposal is to compare the benefits of home-based lower limb heat therapy to exercise&#xD;
      training on cardio-metabolic function and mobility in older adults during their convalescence&#xD;
      from hospitalization due to SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The novel coronavirus (severe acute respiratory syndrome [SARS]-CoV-2), first identified in&#xD;
      December 2019 in Wuhan, China, has since spread worldwide. Older adults and people with&#xD;
      underlying medical conditions are at higher risk for developing serious complications and&#xD;
      death related to SARS-CoV-2. However, another challenge is arising in regards to the&#xD;
      long-term prognosis of COVID-19 survivors. Although limited, the available data on the&#xD;
      medium-term outcomes of patients who survived COVID-19 all indicate prolonged symptom&#xD;
      duration and disability in a large proportion of adults hospitalized with severe symptoms. In&#xD;
      addition, these patients, a majority of whom were older adults or patients with pre-existing&#xD;
      health conditions, spent ~10-15 days bedridden and under intensive treatment, which can have&#xD;
      lasting consequences on metabolism and cardiovascular functions, mobility, and eventually&#xD;
      lead to long-term disabilities. Upon discharge from the hospital, the main option for&#xD;
      physical rehabilitation involves exercise training. Although, exercise training can be&#xD;
      effective to restore physical function, it is oftentimes associated with low adherence.&#xD;
      Considering the severe deconditioning accompanying hospitalization related to COVID-19, there&#xD;
      is a critical need for the development of a rehabilitation strategy that is home-based and&#xD;
      practical to individuals with diminished physical function. Accordingly, the goal of this&#xD;
      project is to compare the benefits of home-based lower limb chronic heat therapy to exercise&#xD;
      training on skeletal muscle metabolism, vascular function and functional capacity in older&#xD;
      adults during their convalescence from hospitalization due to SARS-CoV-2. Late middle-age and&#xD;
      older adults that have been discharged from a COVID-19 hospitalization will be randomly&#xD;
      allocated to an exercise intervention group (EX, low resistance ~40 min, 3 times a week at&#xD;
      home), a heat-treated group (HT, leg heated garments with skin temperature reaching ~40˚C,&#xD;
      40-55 min, 5 times a week at home), or a control group (CT) for 8 weeks. Specific Aim 1 will&#xD;
      test the hypothesis that local heat therapy in previously hospitalized COVID-19 patients can&#xD;
      (i) enhance functional capacity, resulting in improvements in mobility and quality of life&#xD;
      compared to a non-treated control group, and (ii) that these changes will be similar in&#xD;
      magnitude to an exercise intervention. Specific Aim 2 will test the hypothesis that local&#xD;
      heat therapy in the same patients can (i) enhance insulin sensitivity as a consequence of&#xD;
      improvements in mitochondrial and vascular function compared to a non-treated control group,&#xD;
      and (ii) that these changes will be similar in magnitude to an exercise intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Gait speed</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>6-min walking distance</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Motor function</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Short Physical Performance Battery score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Glucose control</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>insulin and glucose levels during oral glucose tolerance test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Skeletal muscle mitochondrial function</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in phosphocreatine recovery kinetics measured by 31-PMRS</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vascular function</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in reactive hyperemia</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">87</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Physical Disability</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Course of recovery with standard of care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Exercise training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>low resistance velocity based exercise training ~40 min, 3 times a week at home for 8 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>heat therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>heat therapy (~40C skin temperature) with a leg garment 5 times a week for 40-55 min for 8 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>heat therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>leg heated garments with circulating water to conduct heat therapy at home</description>
    <arm_group_label>heat therapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>exercise training</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>exercise training</intervention_name>
    <description>A velocity based training program will be implemented at home using a mobile app allowing for the quantification the relative intensity.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Exercise training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women must not be taking hormone therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have been hospitalized for, at least, 5 days for a COVID-19 related infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have been discharged from the hospital for, at least, 14 days&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Orthopedic limitations that would prohibit from performing plantar-flexion or&#xD;
             knee-extension exercise&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to MRI (pacemaker, metal implants, or certain types of heart valves),&#xD;
             or be at medical risk from undergoing an MRI examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Enrolled in a rehabilitation program&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI &lt;40 kg/m2 and weigh &lt;400lbs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  prior history of pulmonary embolism or deep vein thrombosis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>55 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 16, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 16, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>physical rehabilitation</keyword>
  <keyword>cardio-vascular function</keyword>
  <keyword>metabolism</keyword>
  <keyword>heat therapy</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

